and please welcome your hosts Sean
pruden
and Jon Garland see the good afternoon
and thank you for joining us
yet thanks for
for coming thru spend time with the into
this long day
it's a for many view
who are out there last night when I was
leaving the student event and put all
your chairs the got real cool
on the sidewalk I'm sure and you spent a
whole long night waiting for this day
in you been here and now you join us to
celebrate
them excellent house at your place
though award excellence in innovation on
both via Web and a with can
and every year it gets more and more
difficult to pick
are to find winners because there are so
many great our
yeah so many have you
we shared that they think this morning
that seventy percent of the audience
here
at WC are new to the show and so many
have you have never been to this shell
the design awards it so we've got pic we
take a moment to explain how we pick the
winners
how we we judge the winning aP's using
through three major
we judge if they're winning ups in three
major areas:
the first is around design so
for design we look at perhaps that or
we're looking perhaps the easy to use
I caps that are familiar that are
consistent within themselves but
consistent with the operating system as
well
they have a great game looks a really
excellent gameplay
their intuitive and understandable and
immediately usable by the people who
they were built for
and then we look at maps are in the
technology
we judge apt around technology so we're
were
evaluating the app's on their use a I
was through with 10 frameworks
to do really cool stuff for dad really I
really valuable functionality I or
looking
we're also looking at whether the app
launches quickly is it responsive
does it take a you know there's that
work the way you would expect it to work
and and are there you know our is their
smooth scrolling
I we look at whether or not the app runs
on the latest OS is
weather takes advantage of the newest
hardware and that takes advantage of
things like em 7 a.m.
a seven on i OS or multi-core other
technologies and hardware technologies
on OS 10
and then thirdly mmm we're looking at
ups
from the point of view innovation and
innovation really is that
that spark a brilliance rate that
uniqueness
the the clever implementation of
something that you wouldn't have
expected
in the first place but then when you see
it I your blown away by it
and and there's so many ways the talk
about innovation it really comes down to
the implementation of something that is
just so
crash and so are compelling and done in
a unique way
so those three areas are how we judge
the app's there's so many more things we
look at
but in a nutshell their their group in
those three in there was three years
so let's talk about the private the R
word winners
will be given to take home it's pretty
much wanna every piece of hardware that
we make
a Mac Pro with Retina Display a 27-inch
iMac
an Apple TV a MacBook Air and MacBook
Pro and iPad and iPod touch
not a bad haul
and
and last but not least probably the most
coveted
a party the award is yeah I get to take
home what are these
eighty a trophy cubes and a these
are you know statically early detect
touch the touch-sensitive
see touch them they light up on the top
just like the backup your your MacBook
Pro the Apple logo light up
and I these are to die for must have
I Apple products and a few if you're
going to get one tonight
so without any further ado let that get
to the winners
we're gonna start with a few student
winners in
students have been part up w BBC for
many many years
in fact we have got a student
scholarship program were rewarded
200 students this year yeah 200 students
appear in the house
and your student scholarship winner this
we could you stand up for a moment we
just want to award you
with some recognition the
they fear
thank you would be litigated we're
delighted done some
you guys have done some great work got
to get here and
the app's that we looked at were were
really impressive
and so you you deserve to be here
this week and we hope that you're gonna
continue to press a some incredible out
that put the more veteran developers
were in the audience
a you know give them a run for the money
right like the that
who have been like somebody that these
were a student winners that we
highlighted in previous years
we demo you're on stage some other maybe
have changed names or what-have-you but
they were great aP's
written by students over the past three
years so
let's move on to our first winner our
first winner
is panel perfect by have peeled and two
bros
winners we've come up but there are 150
here
number here
gone
make fifty you again
graduation panel perfect is a fun and
simple way to share beautiful panoramic
photos these are two
former high school students but it ended
up with a beefy in 2012 instant
scholarship
I and built this out when they were
inspired by our own fix announcement
panoramic and John gonna show it now
yeah it's great stories in the you know
watching something and then deciding to
write an app up
I think that I got a great story so
had a perfect is this app that allows
you to view panoramic photos
and its a there's just the
are a community of people who love
panoramas that are
submitting up photos to the into the app
so the very familiar user interface
just rolling through this these guys are
using you like it dynamics an image
effects for blurs
on a on summer the UI which will get you
in a moment
so this not explore this is kinda
curated set panoramas
if we go to nearby the zinc or location
determine where you are
and that we're gonna go in here
hopefully unload some panels
yeah there's some panels that are nearby
couple imposed by the creators are the
up
but I let this go into this one we
double top you can favored it
you can like it you can comment on it
and then you can double top and just go
in
and gesture through Puri to go and look
at the entire panorama
and they're doing a lower res
thumbnails in the feed that you see here
and then they're going to the high res
for panoramas um when you go and look in
up to the individual up to the
individual image so
super cool app that really with was
created to address
the experiences that at the time there
was no support for panoramic images in a
lot of social networking aP's
and so these guys stepped up and made
some really cool regulation natural can
have a car
he alright
the next app is up was created because
I'll them the incredible movement and
growth
iPad in education and a
you know people are changing iPad is
change the way that we're learning in
the classroom
changing the way that adults are
learning and kids are learning and that
the mix of iPad
in education is really taking off
because the
the incredible new aP's they're
available interactive textbooks
really tremendous content and other
creators of this next app
I solve that saw the growth that was
going on and also saw specific need that
they wanted to step up to
and and salt so our winner does that
and they are animal adventure by Keith
Lee
the
like
Graham played him
you're welcome animal adventure is a fun
and engaging
out the key to the single digit addition
money from here the area am
it was created by grad been from
Columbia University who are involved in
research in cognition
learning and the way kids learn and
technology sinister professor possum
have
the story tell from Otto and is building
a robot that could ruin the world
join the outermost to win back blocking
rebuild the Golden City to its former
glory
John right thing earlier this happened
so I'm not going to get into this
sinister I you know situation getting
that whole game play
but these folks worked with a from
Sesame Workshop
I am and to create some really great
artwork in the app
the app is focused on teaching children
basic addition
and a for a lot of kids this is a real
struggle and so
his the developer a set out to solve
this problem
so we're going to get into the app will
skip over the narrative at the beginning
here
is pretty straightforward stuff from
both your gonna get the answers right
without even yeah but I'm the key here
is that the app is teaching children
addition and when you're first morning
edition
wanna you just you know the first thing
you do is you cannot thinkers you just
kinda like 123 you count them off
individually install the app
let you do that and so I can just tap
you know I get five I get some be back
in the UI
I move the slider bar with the packed
I'll deal 25
and I get confirmation that it's the
right answer or I don't was wrong answer
I can also do count on just second
edition it also wants the child has
learned to basically count through the
numbers
you know are the numbers then they can
start moving onto
different times in addition where
they're gonna take a a big number and
add some smaller numbers to it so
in this case weekends with the child
gonna start to learn that you can start
with three
and then do one more get four right
they're getting in the app continues to
go on and teach all kinds of other tools
and techniques for learning
addition another one is doubles where
you're based we start off with a
I you know three and four seven and so
first the chosen you can cut before
in two or three into Creed 3 in 1870 ap
us for these kinds of techniques think
they can manage it by Wes technologies
to do a really great experience with
large text great colors
and an experience I think that is really
going to resonate with little kids
so congratulations extremely well done
thank you very much
can we get the flight back truck
there we are
alright everybody loves a great game and
there are so many games on the App Store
and we had with a lot of time looking
through
are the best games and try to figure out
which one was was the one that needed to
be a winner and there are many
that needed to be a winner on 42 we can
only award so many tonight
but one other types of gaming want to
take the games on the App Store this
super popular there really loves
that originated in the eighties is the
platformer
and I am and in the platformer game
us genre what you're doing is you're
you're basically you know running and
jumping moving in jumping
I to avoid obstacles and get coins and
say people and get money and you know
whatever you're getting
I am the whole point is to not fall off
the platform
right and i'd the way you fall off the
platform is you get
you know spear to you some of the ball
hits you were
something falls on you or whatever but
the point is that the platform is a
pretty loose term but you're moving
across this thing
and it just goes on and on and on in our
next winter
has created I think one of the most
incredible platformer games today on the
App Store their recent arrival
and and we're thrilled to wear them with
something today
to Leo's fortune from $13.37
memory
and
run
going
correctly rather well I'm ratliff
naturally in Leo fortune you hunt down a
cunning and the Furious ball
the when you found your phone am for a
yeah i coming in the theory is Bobby
traveling through lush
environment such as mark the fourth air
desert snow-capped mountains
and pirate fiddy uncover the truth
behind Leo stolen fortune
great well I'm not gonna go
to the snow-capped peaks sir I'm
underwater anything like that I'm gonna
show you the basic gameplay
us did you get a sense for for what's
going on
I get the following brought down a
little bit that be great
alright so we'll support him I'll you've
got about twenty five levels are more
that you can just
swipe through in a very familiar user a
user interface
I'm a star level one because I wanna
point out something
that is such a great example of their
attention to detail
and the way that they've done things in
this game so I'm gonna start the
tutorial
and this is really for the on-boarding
experience for the app in there are so
many APs nowadays that are needing to do
this they want to get you
up up on you know into the app and the
help you understand how to use the app
and you don't need something that's very
high
you know that super intense but to do
this well
takes a lot of design and I think a lot
of thinking and
its owner she is so the game starts off
like this and the first thing you're
told is where to place your thumbs
in order to do that you're immediately
learning how to hold the iPad to play
the game
sign up on my left them here right I'm
here and now the game starts the work
and it's got these coach marks so I'm
gonna move the left thumb
we're gonna start the clock points with
with Leo here
okay so here's the platformer experience
right
you're driving along on this so-called
platform
and boom I'm stock I can't get over this
thing but this on morning experience has
these goes thing images
and they tell me that if I move my right
thumb up I can inflate Leo
and move him up and down on and now I'm
dealing with an obstacle in this case
but keep going thanks
hope some down there no problem I can go
back up
I can play no sorry all come on
I what's the problem with these demos
right okay here we go we land on their
room that our here we are we drive
around
enormous the just be a factor in the
background is this
there's this perspective going on you
got petals
flying through the air on other levels
there's rain falling there's
all kinda stuff happening in this this
is a in the distance
and here you're dealing with this
obstacle in the game with
all these kinds of obstacles were we all
have to solve is to do something in one
spot
to open a door are some kind of a bridge
in this case I landed on top I would I
and some just getting played him put
this around and then
move along and keep jumping and
this is just the real quick view of
what's going on in this game
we just thought they did such a good job
for example with this kind of a NASCAR
which is really hard to get you know to
do well
I'll you going down for mines your hand
in a rainstorms all kinda stuff and then
here
again this on boarding experience but
I'm actually playing at and you see that
i'm suppose the jump this guy
right film and then now I'm
long this is just the first level but
the game goes on and we just
really love this game for that attention
to detail across all the levels
for the great integration with touch for
the leveraging a by West technologies in
graphics
for the sound system there's so much
that these guided right
and before I say congratulations this is
an awesome app
taken from
and right we all have busy lives
and one other things that that I've
learned over time and other people have
learned is that if you can capture
some other things that are going on and
take a moment to record
an idea a thought
a memory were something happens and it
triggers a thought you want to capture
that that that exercise
writing things down for a moment to just
capturing these little bit something
bits have above information throughout
the day
is actually a great way to relieve
stress it's actually a great way to
build memories and in kind of
catalog your day it can also be you know
I
idea incubator and so this is something
it's a good discipline for us all to get
into
in this developer the developer the next
up the next winter
totally understand this idea and they
are
Bloomville who've made day one
hamlet way
hamlet play
happily them
grappling day one lets you record your
life
as you live it from every day moment for
once in a lifetime event
the elegant interface a gay one makes
journal in your life
a simple pleasure rights with the backup
it's also available i OS up as well
are but we thought we would awarded for
the Mac can show it off on the Mac
because so many of us are so busy and
developers
our max everyday write code we're
spending time
and in Xcode or we're doing using
various tools he could be a spreadsheet
you could be writing some serve a
document up but along the way
something what happened you like your
phone call I thought pops into mind
an email arrives and you might wanna
record an idea or put something quickly
down which is a big part of journaling
not sitting down to write something huge
it's just capturing these little nuggets
and so day one test builds a little
menu extra you can type in and put some
sort of entry an indictable straight in
the log in then
into the into the Journal and then
you're back to your
are or we could just go up here and
we'll just launch the app
and I'll we can a
inside the app immediately create
journal entries so I can say
you know here I am at a couple
sign words sorry
the trophies or
great want one
things so right
there's my entry I can take turns out
attacks took a trophy
picture earlier so I can take this
picture dropping into here and a once
get it either take the date for the
picture just say
leave it unchanged based on the daytime
entering this journal entry and
and I think I'm done I can tag it with
various tags that are in the system
I can add a location that got Maps
integration like it to use current
location about like
and I'm done and there's the entry in
there and I can look at my journal
overtime using the the overall view up
all the journal entries and so here's
just a sample Journal
thats that we've got in the in the app
here
where you can take a look at all these
entries um and go back in time and
and see what's going on and really that
is the whole point of journaling is
capturing these moments
in time as they occur at the pop in your
mind and we felt that they won
did such a great job at this as well
they've got built in notifications you
can set up reminders to
to put things into your journal they've
got inspirational quotes that will pop
up when you're gonna create a journal
entry
they can be inspiring and get your
writing and really that's the essence of
a great tool right is that it it gets
the job done
it doesn't get in the way and it's
perfectly balanced and we selected this
tool for being super well design an OS
and in being exactly what it needs to be
and nothing more so congratulations on a
job well done
here
alright
our next winter is a
it's just such a great example love the
above the principal
%uh minimalist design you know design is
all about
of it and finish it's all about the
marriage between form and function
it's about are you know communicating
clearly
and and I West really
helps you to do this right by helping
you focus on content
arm I getting out of the way
giving you a a system that allows you to
draw
you know the the you like my with seven
that is
that is minimalist in nature and and you
know it takes a lot of attention
and a lot of focus and refinements to
actually end up with something that is
that is in its purest form that is
something that's that is exactly what
you wanted to be in nothing more there's
no extra dormant
and our next winner did that with their
game and they are
black by cannot be brother them
home Bradley
the goal in this game
to shape a line for all the colored
circle for while avoiding black hole
a long and proud from delightfully
simple to exceptionally deep and complex
it's a stroke of genius John you have
this app is
a is awesome and I wanna just to give
you not believe this game you need to
see it from the start
so the basic point the game is you know
I Sean said you
you gesture and you draw the line I
to knock out the colored dots and when
you get to a level where they're black
dots you want to avoid those
but you know it the first level you're
just the starting of here with this
gesture
and you know notices I'm playing here
that there is no
there's nothing extra on-screen it's
just the dots it's just my gesture
and the gesture the rendering of the
gesture is is almost like calligraphy a
minute just
the it it has a flair to it it's got
its representative at the speed up my
stroke the exact timing
the the link that everything so eager to
these three
so those are easy levels let me jump up
to
up to level eight here for a moment
which is kinda fun
so here I got an instance where I've got
to avoid the black dots but get the
white ones
are get the colored ones and and to do
that I've gotta figure out what gesture
to do that we'll repeat
across the screen through these colored
up no
the other thing that's super cool what
this app is that it leverages audio
other for for great feedback and so this
a very fun
lightweight a you know sounds that come
through as you screw up basically
so from with yep
you know so you're messing up when he
tried by right
knock-knock way not quite
Jill not quite anything about this
it's like that you like I'll black in
the sound is
with great feedback well after I all
now mind john all
naw I'm left but it would give up
but would be this a thoroughly the
Devils
yeah we love it game for the minimalist
design the great integration with the
touch
a you know system %uh ViaWest just that
expression
I'll I'll such as the great engagement
it's great expression at the game in a
very simplistic way
with no extra dormant and it so
congratulations on actual job
very much what the
may
play there right the hope
you know we were all
you know at the conference this weekend
we're crazy busy you've got a hundred
and what is it 10 fashions to attend and
so this is just a great example love how
busy we are
I for not a conference you guys are
writing code
you go to school you're doing you're
doing light and
and if you're anything like me you know
that it's hard to keep on top I love
all the things that are going on in the
world around us whether it's in our
industry
whether it's a not enter through enters
in our industry but something that
interests of whether it's sports or
world news or what have you
and so we've got News you know it's not
look for lack of news sources it's just
that there's so much news coming out
and it's often hard to pick
a quality sources news it's hard to
to find one that is you know curated
and that's gonna give you what you are
really interested in
in the link that you wanted to be in and
more importantly it's even hard to find
time to read it all
and the developer over next stop the
next stop the winner is
set out to solve this dilemma up getting
information to people
in a timely manner in a way that they
can consume it easily
and our winner is Yahoo news digest by
Yahoo
rightfully unfair
now out I'm got playing
up this apt-get
you in the know in no time it delivers
definitive summaries up all the
important to me to known you for the day
into beautiful dodger story for both
hand curated as well algorithmically
generated to ensure high-quality
and keep you informed of all the key
headline for the day reload
think a quick look at the got the news I
just so I
what you get is these two digested news
with a buddy
stories in them in the morning at 8 a.m.
and
at 6 p.m. in the evening and that's it
and so this is what time I go to New
zaps all the time
I wait for these I just arrived and once
they arrive
you can just scroll through on
this really simple you why that lists
the stories the top stories in the day
and what they've done really well as
they've
you know done this automatic collection
of information and aggregation and
all the work that they do behind the
scenes with some Lee but then they're
doing human curation at the content
in addition with the editors and so the
car could be you get
the news stories are extremely a
extremely high quality so here we are
we're moving through
%uh this list in CC Paul political story
there's a US news story technology world
below into the story headlined you've
got um
you've got these little Adams is all
circles
and you can tap them to get the legend
of what you to these mean
basically they're telling you how much
information there is available for one
other stories
the so let's go into the story but I'll
a wanna
and you the first time you use it it
says how to use the app and see you can
swipe
just right to left around the stories
or go back into a story and redid up
read it in more detail and I find that
these are you know if I just take about
10 minutes to plow through this I guess
I've got of some great information about
the latest headlines
and so you get these great call outs you
moving through the story that's pretty
much it
it's well laid-out at the bottom you're
getting extra information like
up photos that may be associated with
the story they're coming from really
good sources
there might be a topic breakdown there
might be a video that loads very very
quickly that
it's a a quick summary of up the story
others maps
integration if it if it's appropriate
and then you can go through
some top tweets I'll or other social
networking posts that
that apply to this story and and so
that's how we to the stories is laid out
and he just looked through them one by
one and read them
some really great visual effects in a
kind of a plea for you why
in the app another example playful you I
is the share button these guys kinda pop
up from the bottom they kinda
down some go away um so
really great experience and then when
you're done I love the
the what they've done Spears have a good
time I love would be done at the very
end because
you read through this in the news is
really great but its they've done a
great job with Kenny just came up buying
that's a little bit
by giving you feedback on how many the
story they just saying that you read
and so while we dislike through them now
it doesn't mean we read them but
impure you've read them in and at the
end you just get old hey we're at 7.9
and that its I just find it kinda cool
the feedback now the this digest that
we're looking at right here the black
background because it's the
the other day digest but working top the
top right corner
see that the next hour next I just as
coming in 11 hours by top the center the
screen it says
up patience is a virtue love that the
first time I saw that
and I can go back across the last week
and pick one
a maybe a died just that I haven't read
saw a pic a morning digest:
and here the news comes in and it's the
white background
so little bit of attention to detail
little attention to detail
on things like white background for Dane
is
black background for night time that
news I just very playful interface
really well I can agree with touch and
our
you know beautiful typography and layout
and excellent quality news
so really really well done
congratulations company
we talk about great
aP's a lot a on the evangelism team we
work with many have you
a on Sean's team she works with many
many developers
are always talking with an opportunity
but the need to create something that is
that is really great it's that is truly
impactful in people's lives and what are
the ways to create
a really great game is a porous to use
technology have a great game loop have a
great you know
game mechanic et cetera but more
important than any of that
is to add personality to a game that's
what makes an engaging
thats would makes a connection with
people and some other
you know some of the biggest names that
that we all know you know plants versus
zombies
cut the rope a a Angry Birds
a where's my water by Disney all those
games
had a great game experience but more
importantly
had really great personality very unique
to their game
and this next game does everything right
in addition to also adding personality
to the game and so
we're pleased to award a nata to 3
by servo the
you
him
deadly
them
probably addicted to that game
congratulations I personally am addicted
to this game
greeted the tiny puzzle that will grow
on you it's an engaging number matching
puzzle but you learn in a minute but
play and awfully
with an endearing have two characters in
an enchanting found track
it's been broadly imitated but never
equaled John
yet so true so I'll
you know most you probably play this way
more than I have
on and by the result to be a
by your response will be awarded them
but you know
hug her personality you know this game
is good attitude
rights over longer I talked the more
annoyed they're gonna get
because these piles our individual
characters
and weekend find out who they are this
is Tran
we can tap on number right knee
these guys got character I love to raise
the
a paying rate and
you can see on the part of the files
that there you know these two eyes and
nose or mouth the
the tiles or constantly in their blink
being there
there they're doing things with their
faith their connecting
up with each other so the game is your
you know you're doing one's and two's
connect greatly
then you can combine three together so
let's start to move here
forget they're playing here a so we can
combine 12
with three hello three years combining
the sick who is
right threes here he saw
absolute right and as you play
you get this really great experience me
who link you know hun title talking to
you
and I love this and this is i think what
with this team over the top and helps it
stand out from the crowd
I mean it's not just that I'll sorting
game the personality
is this extra layer huh you know
brilliant layer
on top of the technology so this is why
we picked this game is a winner it's
just great gameplay very engaging great
technology means an excellent personnel
I big very much thank Martin Luther
democrat okay
I okay
rights ok your creative professional
%uh the Mac has you know the chances are
the Mac has been your tool of choice
and in you know across all credit
markets whether professional or consumer
a you know in the creative space it's
pretty much always been the case
that the best stops are first on the Mac
or their Mac only and our winner in this
our next winter %uh stays in this
tradition
and and we'd like to award an ATA
tonight to
in a graft probe i click for photo
cinema craft bro
broccoli
correctly than a graph pro is a
professional tool that allows you to
create living photos
with its unique live mapping technology
allows artists to preview their images
in real time
and it creates ultra high-definition
output if you're hyper
photo right so
first thing is you know we all know how
compelling video is
and we see video on the web up for
advertisements or for
you know merchandising or in catalogs or
whatever I
for things that we might be interested
in we wanna know about
and videos really great the problem
video is it hard to make
and it you know that a big footprint
it's got to be brought down
it takes band with and so arm
you know there's a better way to do this
as far as these guys are concerned they
built this tool that optimize to create
something
they're calling portals for cinema
graphs which are basically living images
there a combination of a photo in a
video and
they benefit from being a whole lot more
lightweight then
video and a lot more interesting and
compelling
then photos to still photos so
arm but i wanna do here is show you
first the mall
just an animated a gear gyps re:
Amager that I'm gonna create in a moment
and
now this is sort of an old file format
on the web but it still prevalent
and that to create one these is is
difficult
up to do we're going to do a minute and
so here's an imager
and we're gonna end up with that in that
started with this
this raw video:
so this is just video taken at Subway in
New York
and we're gonna start with that in
quickly in a cup in like three steps
create
a be an Egyptian create a flex also
a me switch over to sell a graph pro
now what you do is you open up the the
raw
video that you've got and a in this case
we got somebody walking by on the left
that we've got the train coming in
are here if you just look to the left to
the escalator you'll see as the sloops
the train's pulling in and that there's
the light and it stops right so it's a
very short clip
but we don't want any that noise in the
side we don't want any the reflection
from the lights and in different things
that are in the station on the walls
and so we start in the topic or we
choose tram
we pull in the tram and we figure out
exactly
you notice the lady on the left we
decide where we want her to freeze
in the image that we're gonna create or
in the in the cinema grab the run a
great we stop it there with the left
side of the tram
the right to the tram I'm just gonna
pull in here
and adjust just slightly so I get the
light from the train coming into the
left to the escalator their EC that
their in there so I just pulling in for
the right side
and the next is where the magic happens
I'm gonna go to the masked all
a lil bit too big hear someone who just
its size go down
and I'm gonna mask up the portion
love the image that the video that I
want to keep everything else now becomes
up up basically mapped out and then I'm
gonna go to
loop decide what kind of a looper good
several types the loop so they can do
I'll just stick with repeat a I'm in it
you know
leave the speed the way it is a leave
the lay the wait isn't just increase
CrossFit CrossFit is what happens when
the video
and and then it looks back to the
beginning soldiers make that smooth
looks like a continuous movement of the
escalator and lastly will go to
I look a quick lead adjustments I can
adjust all kinds a
the the attributes on this video but
I'll just go to the can defects that are
here
and you can see that you can apply these
super quickly up to this
to this image and so let's grab a
black and white called Sun and then
we'll do
a render and we can save note is h264
or progress up 42 so we'll do that
save it to the desktop let's call it
demo and what's creating now is it's
creating this flexible file this
us in my graph that the folks at the
murder a pro
are three portal can host on their
servers for you
and it's super lightweight comes down
works with every browser
and is I gives you that exact experience
and so the end result is on is basically
this
we did you know you can see in the woman
on the left is frozen everything about
the scene is frozen
except the one piece that we want we did
this in three simple steps
this app is brand new on the Mac App
Store
its super gorgeous its really
streamlined it does one thing extremely
well
saving in 30 steps and other tools and I
they have a really great
up a model for hosting these things and
serving them out your site
and we just love this app it makes a Mac
Pro think so
really well done work thank you
alright we
talk about a moment ago about how great
app her personality
I and earlier on I talked about how we
judge the app's
up for the ADA talk about design we talk
about technology doppler we evaluate our
technology
adoption we evaluate on innovation and
we all know that
grade up sir also innovative and you
know innovation is hard to define
but it's for that that spark a
brilliance it's that
I that ingredient that if an app has it
it just makes your job drop
right it's a its it's the kind of thing
that makes
a category you know appear out of
nowhere greater category defining aP's
that are innovative
there they do something clever arm and
you know you really know when you see it
and we've all run across innovative aP's
and we've we've run across one for the
ADA this year that we thought was
that was just over the top in terms of
about just approaching
this game situation in a very clever way
our next winner if the by pic by Fino go
use time make a tie device sick
play for the convention obtain and
literature a captivating thriller which
the written word
if both your map as well as your
narrator and trying
story with puzzle and I blending pub
with no Bella
it draws the players into an intriguing
mystery governor of science and
technology
right
when I'm in landscape mode
I just bear with me here for landscape
mode
you're holding the iPad this is a
narrative that you're reading through to
book the you read through
and we're starting to have happily three
the first chapter
but as you move here you can see this
parallax effect behind these images
yeah and that is pervasive through the
app
I but not only is are the words on
screen
things that you really need to tell you
the story um
but you're also going to get clues about
the puzzle you up
call because fundamentally this is a
game but it's a combination of whole
game
and that's the you're reading along
you're looking at these photos
they do really interesting interactions
and are they have a great sound system
built in so sometimes
new approach sounds in your your um know
they become louder and software is your
near them
here we've run into an interactive a you
know an interactive piece
which at the moment doesn't do anything
but we're gonna need it at some point to
solve the puzzle
and we move on here and you'll see that
you know while I'm reading this text
the text is actually doing all kinds of
interesting things are moving along
don't worry about the fact that sport
right up there because
we're gonna go in different directions
here in a moment and you see that
under strong left but the text is
actually moving things
here I get to the third floor study I
keep going
and here I got a device that I can
interact with you know
Piper combo in or something I keep going
here
and now I've got a choice I could go up
or down I'm gonna keep going here a
little bit and now we're certainly get
to a point where we have to rotate the
device or
and now for you guys will be able to
read it no problem
now I'm approaching a sore throat sound
key
frames number in the room where a great
media no enough room well
I will leave that behind we go here
at the turn the device this way to read
gotta turn the device this way
person throwing up our projection I am
of there we passed that now we're going
here we're going this way we're reading
the text
now we're going to put this way and in
essentially the entire game
is you're moving into a dining hall
I
not gonna get authorization
on in what is
so innovative what this game is just
this combination up no
novel with game with puzzle interest the
you're constantly wrote in your device
tapping pinching zooming moving around
reading this story trying to figure it
out
and we've never seen anything like this
really and out so
great job congratulations have brought
about by
here
talk a little bit before about how we're
so busy that
getting news in a in a adjustable format
was at the Lima and the folks from Yahoo
News I just solve that problem
but you know there's also something else
that we're all doing
every day and that is sharing these
tidbits from our
from our lives with family with friends
with the world
if you hear WC in tell the world about
what's going on
but as interesting invaluable as these
tidbits are
they don't I don't think the replace
the need for sometimes telling a much
longer story
much more visual story that captures
arm an emotion and something much deeper
than
any tweet or any you know Facebook post
or any other social media posts could
could do and our next winner is an app
that allows
for that paper rich storytelling and it
is storehouse
visual storytelling by for her media
gradually wrestling
instantly travel the world
learn a new skill or discover
interesting people argued for the story
created by the store have community
or you can simply put together photos
videos and text to build your own story
and you don't have to be a designer to
put together something stunning alright
like a
like all over winners tonight this app
was designed no optimally designed for
the device it's running on for iPad for
iPhone for
for West Ham I and didn't nap
is the storytelling up it's built
exclusively for iPad
and the stories are told using photos
and video
and so what you do is in in their
contributed by
the community of story a storehouse arm
users
so you know you create account with them
and then you can just use this to
push out your stories to the world or
two a set of people that you want
up to view them and so you know it's to
some really gorgeous animations here we
can flip through
these books are the stories that have
been pushed out into the app
i think im gettin video and audio I'm so
what's going here and take a look at
this one Chicago I love this 13 just top
to go into the story that someone
published
and we gesture through any good to see
this you know the great effect on text
it happening here you can follow this as
publisher
look at these photos you can apply
affect the images
um you know this is this is pretty
gorgeous
a photography and it's just laid out in
such a good
really compelling way um that makes it
really they just a bowl and and easy to
to
to consume and then laying out text on
it is super easy
you ain't so when you're done with the
with the story could just pinch to get
outta bed
other using you know you I packed sand
you I dynamics and
stop for the transitions I'm let me go
into one that's got
some videos so it's going to this story
by photojournalist
who went to rwanda um and so
this one's got in a much larger photos a
lot more tact
is individual portrait is and quickly
here really get to
video the embedded radio and you don't
have to tap to start playing the video
it just does as the polls are the
majority vote on screen
rape you keep reading again it's a much
more significant
deeper more emotional story that's being
told here rain
and so these are being created by Sheps
pie fashion
fashion designers by photojournalists
around the world
and in families are creating them a
individuals are creating them so
one other want things about this app is
on it it lets you create ones books
through the story sorry
super easily so just tap the Create
button we were at
from the photo library let's say we went
to up
the lake we import these the is 14
images
and immediately they're laid out in in
the format
up that the upper right so what's a
you know trip to
Lake on great memories
and
we sit down on that okay so now we're
down in
these in the basic you which is
thumbnail view but
it's like I wanna do more than that I
wanna make something compelling like the
chicago won I saw a moment ago
so that they won't you know what that
this this image hereof the but the
cyclists is pretty cool so we just
happen drag
make that larger this one of her on the
on the
tree stump is pretty cool so we can just
happened right that we can double top
and and you know and property in the way
we want
go around make something really big like
this everything else moves are the way
great feedback through animation up and
you can just go on and on and you can
add the text you can create the brakes
you want to
and then you can publish this out to the
store oath a community
and people are following you they're
gonna see I your story
up in this case I'm just gonna save it
as a draft but
is just such a compelling up just to
browse through the stories
and and see what people are posting a
in there for more significant and more
meaningful and more emotionally
a charge then just something small that
we would put out to the world which is
equally valuable but very different so
great adopted by was technologies thanks
for making something exclusive right had
that is so compelling
guide
now
a people have been captivated for you
know
all-time pretty much by the night sky
I mean who hasn't sat out you know
are on a campground with friends the
back of a truck
on a country road somewhere looking up
at the night sky watching
you know airplane lights watching
satellite passover
identifying are you know constellations
we're trying to
arm you're pointing out things that are
better-known like the Big Dipper the
North Star something like that
we've all done that we've all been
captivated by that
and it's certainly a very humbling and
in powerful experience the see the night
sky
and the developer for next winter eyes
created an app that takes that to a
whole new level
and it is guy guide by fifty star lab
you
in preparation discovering what's in the
night sky
effort life with guy guide you can
search for 1000 the celestial objects
and simply follow the arrow in the sky
above you to feed them
and sky god works offline you can take
it with you anywhere
I'll take a look at the
a look at the lease is up you know first
and foremost the app
a just as everything right technically
it is optimized you know to the nth
degree
they're using OpenGL ES 3 they're using
knock or audio
their up you know leveraging all
technologies that are appropriate
relevant for this up and and
the performances to stunning one of the
first things you notice in the apt to
and you're hearing it now is this
justice this ambient music that's
playing in the background
other composer the music was on the same
think I have composed the sounds for
inet a winner of a couple years ago
called osmose great game um
in this this soundtrack here this for
this game is just so compelling
so as you're in this you can just you
know top around and look at the night
sky
it automatically is showing you the
various constellations
I can top on
stars and I'm not stop talking for men
is it up on the start small stars
produce a small
sound larger stars produce a large down
but just
you tap around you can almost make your
own music is your as you're just
experiencing this
I'm you can you can lift it up because
the short as the court would like to do
that
in top lift up missing is that the tax
you're looking at the sky it turns
it activates the compass in gyroscope
and snaking pan around
the sky above us in around us um in this
case I'm just gonna
go search for something that we all are
familiar with which is the
space station and
it you know you thought pointing to
we're going in now you can see the
trajectory the space station
a which is pretty cool I can zoom in on
stuff
I won't be able to see it in great
detail Americans
you know pretty small on let's go back
out here
and look at different for the
the night sky when things you can do is
you can just because the
the noise that the light pollution that
surround us when we're outside
you can actually just top two fingers on
screen
and drag upper down to adjust
the amount of stars on screen on the on
in style guide
relative to what you're seeing you know
when you're out when you're outside
so that's kinda cool so it's it's it's a
good match it also
learn a lot about the night sky by
leveraging at all
inside the app and this is the loop so
this lets you see
a difference spectra up beyond what's
visible to the human eye
and so you just bring up the slope you
can drag it around this guy
but he did take this and move through
you know microwave infrared HL up
and you can leave it there and simply
move around
the night sky and look at different
things that are going on that
you wouldn't know about but might be
behind one of your most being you know
most-favored constellations or something
um
if I tap on an individual item I get
this blog I am the side here you'll see
it on the right side there
its its blinking to say you know look at
me
and I can read three information about
the object serious in this case that I
selected
I can top something like anna's minor it
will go to that
a I can tap the name over another
all-star and it'll go there
untapped the Sun and it will rotate to
the Sun so
you know this is just scratching the
surface in this %ah it think rental
the attention to detail these guys put
into it the optimization fry Wes
on the soundtrack it's just a pleasure
to use this app
and I think it's at the standard that
that all over should aspire to
in our particular individual categories
so thank you for great work
place
I'm now speaking a great work
we all aspire to do great things in our
lives I we've all got these great ideas
olive you have got undoubtedly ideas
already
coming to mine for things are going to
do with I was a and with those 1070
I am n you know when we got these great
ideas
it I it we also have these very high
standard for ourselves in many cases
and when you've got these high standards
it's often difficult though to actually
realize them for a variety of reasons
beyond our own control
right wife is away and up taking charge
but and that's why some of these great
ideas and such a big challenge
but when you can pull them off its
its amazing I and it's definitely
something that's worth
noting definitely notable moment and so
arm our next winner is is just an
incredible ap
that are was definitely a big idea
I think for them and they set out to do
something
fantastic and I think the achieve that
and our final award the FAF ternoon goes
to
Monument Valley by a computer
the Tom rattling
at Lincoln the whole 20 a
Monument Valley is the
your real exploration through
fantastical architecture an impossible
geometry
guide the filing princess ida three
mysterious monument uncovering hidden
powers unfolding optical Aleutian
to outsmart the enigmatic crow people
this is such an awesome game and
I don't know where the idea came from I
love to hear the story someday
but it is need to set out to do
something so big
and the it the result is amazing so what
you're doing is you're taking this
little princess Ida
you've got to get her to the top these
you know to the top of the themes in
this case the top of the tower there
we're looking at this very Asher ask I
3d model
and a lot of things don't line up and
anyway
so we'll figure it out as we go number
one you know you can interact with
object on screen so this is pretty
straightforward with just happened
teller where to go he's gonna go up here
gonna put her up here but now now what
do we do %uh but you can
you get these hands on screen that term
so you can turn this
and so Walker on here a we're gonna walk
her around
but the surrounding now she's she's
gonna go and step on this special
platform
which is now gonna deconstructing but
you know when you look at this is like
okay now where she gonna go she can't
climb the
that center pole she can't you know what
we do but
was just so cool about this up is that
2030 interact with these objects
you realize like look what's going on
here
you didn't think that that top bar was
the same height as the other walkway
right
but as you start to rotate around
they've just done this great job
have going what you doin
you know it's like it like that
you know those there that has never and
written exactly the experience
so they're here turn around now she's
going to get to the final destination
rate answer she gets there we get this
power
that appears and now we get on to the
next level
and so she's gonna walk around here in
this
this just goes on and on and on and it's
just so
awesome because in this level here she
suddenly learns to walk sideways
and walk on different surfaces and
doesn't hear she's going up here
gonna walk around here and just go
through the
now on track that's going on behind the
scene a like what is gonna go what is
happening here
right by me but if we turn I don't think
I've ever had to do this
a was then the demo there can all I know
what to do I do it again i three
yeah I want to get to the back side
isn't no I can't do that a camera for
its okay you gotta play the game of a
missile technology
a great user experience fabulous art
that's optimized for retina display
and just such an intriguing experience a
and you should just be super proud of
your work we really appreciate what
you've done for iPad
thank you and regulation
thank you Iraq
so that yet over our 12 winners
for the Apple Design Award in 2014 12
incredible
up built on and for Iowa
7 no's' 10 maverick either 12 incredible
developers
we'd love to invite back on stage now
but come on up to you guys
you know these folks
are have done such great work you've
just seen
you seen a little a few seconds to be to
the wraps but already you get a glimpse
the why the zaps a really great
these these guys have set a new
benchmark with the zaps
for excellence for creativity for
technology adoption
for innovation for so many things and
and really these ops are set a standard
that
we're really saying to you is a
community you know you your work needs
to be
just like these guys it needs to be up
this quality or higher they accept new
bar
and I think just for a moment I
it be great to just give these people
and they've worked so hard so created
the thank you for all your hard work
he's doing it and we can't wait to see
what the developers in you do with I
with me and with Kenya family
thank you very much