alright good morning everyone good to
see you all here
we're here today to talk to you about
internationalization now
if you've been following along with our
previous years talks on international
support then you know that the App Store
is available in many many countries
worldwide more than 150 by last count
so I'm sure evolve major aP's localize
ball
so you concerned about to localize urs
and make them available in multiple
languages
is that sufficient of well
not necessarily you need to take some
care with regard to
internationalization otherwise you might
end up with
complaints like say half contact names
truck show up backwards in Europe or the
dayton is application unreadable
or my text is all messed up working in
this area we've
seen problems like this occur many many
times and
we're here today to tell you how to fix
them what we're gonna do
is first ball will run through
what we have its new international
support and your sanity and I was 8
then we'll go into detail about language
locale when you use what
and they were gonna run through a number
of case studies problems that we've seen
and internationalization had how to fix
up
so start off with what's new in
internationalization
and the latest releases are operating
systems we have a number of nice man
features
both at the user level and an 80 Iza to
develop a lot so the usual level
we have for Iowa's a number of new
localizations
as a new keyboards I we've agreed on I
was
language region sightings and we have
some
a new prevents tumor calendar support
then
and I API's developer level we have one
API for string encoding detection
we have some interesting new for matters
and something
new called formatting context which are
going to attempt a few minutes
so let's start with a new localization
two keyboards we have for Iowa us we
have new localizations for Hindi
for Indian English Canadian French and
Hong Kong Chinese
add some new keyboards for small
I for three and a claim which has been
ghali party in order to
to go along with our existing Indian
Tomo keyboards
ami also have keyboards for Indian
English Filipino and Slovenia
and there are a number of other new
things
I like new fonts for various crops
worldwide
second so
you may recall that the Mavericks we
redid the language region settings for
last 10 well this time around
it's the turn by OS and I was aid we've
read on the language in region settings
and they look something like this now
so you can still as always specify the
primary language localization
but now in addition on iowa's you can
also specify
users can specify the whole list their
preferred language isn't
order so one thing this allows you to do
is to localize your app's into
localizations for which Apple does not
provide
primary I'm OS localization so because
users can specify those ahead of
I wanna localization top-fives and your
Apple run in those languages for the
users who need that
I nuclear also is an advanced setting
that allows specifying
the language or the region format
independently of the localization
I we we make them the same by default
but users can change them if they like
and we'll go into that and more detail
later on
we have some improvement store support
from their calendars
so and our calendar applications we now
have the support for turning on I as an
overlay
and on account dates in addition to
Gregorian dates we also have a couple of
new calendar options either variants on
the Islamic calendar
but let's take a closer look at what
their so
this years counter app with up
Chinese calendar other counter dates
turn on you see
shoppers and overlay underneath the
Gregorian dates here it's very useful
for our Chinese customers and here's
what this looks like
in Ostend and see here the Gregorian
dates on the right and other candidates
on the left at the API level
these are API's available to foundation
level on both I'll ass and Austan
I so you may recall from some producers
tax sessions we talked about the
unfortunate situation that can occur
when you have a text file or some other
time Cup external taxed
any don't happen to know what the
coating it in
well in that case York may have no other
option but to try to
ghastly encoding from the text we now
have a specific API to do that
automatically for you based on all the
evidence that's available from the taxed
I and it's very handy in the water
options
you can I have a do the whole conversion
for you at once or just tell you what it
thinks
encoding tells here you can be have
lost your Namas a conversion and if you
happen to think you know
one coatings fly could be and you can
specify those or you can
require to be one of certain list and
coatings
we also have a number of nice new for
matters
so estate for matters great if the thing
you try to format
here's a date a particular moment in
time
but what if what you're trying to format
is more like an amount of time next
steps for an Interpol
we have and a state components for
matter for displaying
durations are amounts of time I a number
of hours or minutes or weeks or what
have you
you can specify the amount of time
either as a start and an end date
or a time interval or you can specify
all the components individually if you
like
then you can specify outs post reform
added with
wonderful this stuff date and time
styles
and you can also get to specify exactly
which
the components you want displayed
and there's some interesting things to
ya you can turn on
and look how sensitive way you can add
language to it that says
about a certain amount of time it is an
approximate time or
the locale I sensitive way of saying
remaining
for example if this is a sort of
countdown of some sort
so here are some examples of this in
various languages
you can as as per se choose various
styles either a
lengthy spell out kind of style
something shorter something very short
Marco me
and the last line shows the about option
now one thing I'm watchin to notice here
is that
some other news have their first word
capitalized
well that's appropriate sensor showing
up in the table here
but there are other contacts where you
might want to use
not to have the first word couple I say
if they were showing up the middle of
the Suns
and all talk about that more and just a
minute
I another new former estate interval for
matter
if what you're trying to display is a
range of times
from some beginning timer day to some
anti mcdade
I you might want in this case
to say not to show only once
the pieces that are common to the start
and a and as stated for matter what do
that for you
you provide the start date in the end
date: you can specify
up again and the above list a date or
time styles
or a template for full control over
which pieces get displayed
so here are some examples of this and
again in various languages
so you can see it can show arrange
updates arranger times or Ranger
dates and times and appropriately
the the pieces that are common to the
start and are only shown
once
we also have on some specific for
matters for particular kinds quantities
energy electron mass thats and as energy
for matter as long form at Rs mass for
matter
this is very usefull for example if
you're working with healthcare
and you're trying to displace a the
number collars purse has consumed or how
tall they are how far their honor
how much they weigh and it will show the
news
and America part plus a localized unit
you can specify the exact minute what
or you can request a look how
appropriate unit whatever standard
that particular locale there's a number
formatter attached to it
so you can use all the number formatter
options for from an american part
and there's a special option you can
check if that mass is particularly for
person's weight of the energies
particular for food cuz there maybe
particular standards first display knows
so here are some examples that and
various I live just
yeah you can see that the units very
and up the numbers you can choose an
appropriate format for those
finally the form and context now
remember as I mentioned before
you may need to have abusive text thats
format it Piemonte might want to
capitalize differently depending on
where it's showing up
and for some language is there are other
transformations a may need to apply
depending on where
it shows up in your view what I so we
have a new properties format in context
available for pay
number formatter into components for
matter by Cup format are currently
it's the form and context property
helped one oven
enumerated data values specify where
this format i think is supposed to end
up
at so that it can be capitalized or
otherwise appropriately
I changed for its context you can choose
a stand-alone context for example it has
gone appear by itself
and a field so I might be capitalized
the list item contact save it's going to
be in a menu or something like that
the beginning a sentence context again
usually capitalized
and the Middle ascends contacts probably
will not be capitalized
but it may happen that your
from an address all is going to show up
I was gonna be inserted into a localized
string
and you don't know our priority without
having a localized string at
whether it's gonna be at the start or
somewhere in the middle so we have
another bout you
the dynamic value you to specify that
and then
want it inserted into that format
straying
it gets automatically at automatically
detects whether it is the stark
middle animal capitalize it or otherwise
change inappropriately
automatically so that's what's new
and now I'm gonna bring up my colleague
deborah Goldsmith to
go into detail about languages and
locales
think attack hi everybody
today we're going to talk about
languages in Lok house
the differences between them and how to
use them
so dentures showed us the new language
in region settings in Iowa State
I hear you can see an example on the
left there's
the language settings and you can see
there's a list to three languages
English Simplified Chinese and
traditional Chinese
on the right you see the region or
locale setting and that showing the
region of the United States
which together with English makes a
locality US English
so why are there two preferences where
they used for
well the language setting keeps track of
which languages the user prefers to use
the region's or locale setting keeps
track of which regional conventions they
want to follow
it's worth pointing out that neither of
these indicates the language that users
using documents
that might be the same language but it
might be something completely different
and we'll talk more about that a little
later on
so let's look a little more closely at
the preferred language last
what uses it well probably the most
important thing that uses the preferred
language list is an ass bundle
it uses that information to pick the
localization
that your app by uses when it runs
but it's also used by in a string and a
string has sat several
language sensitive operations such as
localized string comparison
or breaking text into words or sentences
and in a string uses the preferred
language was to determine which language
to use for that
it's also used by web can't everytime
WebKit sends a request to a web server
includes in the HTTP header a field
called accept-language:
which is essentially the preferred
language last the web server looks at
that information and uses it to decide
which language to use for the page it
sends back
the list is in preference order from the
user's most preferred language to the
one-day wanna see blast
any language is that the user is not in
interested in
don't appear in the list at all cell
affectively
it a little more complicated than this
but effectively when tapped in web sites
do
is step through the list in order and
they look for the first language that
they support
and then they used as their localization
if they don't find a language that they
support
then they'll use the default that
depends on the particular application or
website
by contrast in a string will use the
very first language in less
always as the language for language
sensitive operations
it's worth pointing out that when the
user changes the language preference
capstone pick it up until the next time
they restart so
they'll keep using the old setting until
that happens
so now let's talk about the a
low-calorie chin setting
in a little bit more detail and see what
it's used for
well most importantly its use for the
locale in particular the current locale
it determines the properties have that
locale are many different properties
that
I determine the regional conventions
internet controls the behavior for
matters
both the familiar daytime a number for
they've been around for a while and also
all the new for matters the duck just
talked about
it controls the behavior calendars are
both the calendar that you're using
for example you might use to cook to
recover Korean calendar in one country
or the Thai Buddhist calendar but it
also controls
other calendar aspects such as what's
the first day of the week
is it Monday Sunday or something else
now in contrast to the language
preference
when the user changes full the locale
are aP's don't need to restart their
supposed to pick up that new setting
right away and we'll talk a little bit
more later on how to do that
so what is a locale anyway earlier we
saw one example the US English look how
there was a language and there was a
region but look house can have
many more attributes are there can be an
optional script
for example you might need to indicate
whether you want to use
Arabic cursory like script with a
particular language
are there can also be key words added
which fine-tune the behavior of the
locale
so let's look at one hypothetical
example let's look at a particular
user's current locale
and print out its identify our
there it is cell let's pick it apart
and see what each part means so the
first part is the language
that's occurred in this case are
the region is India so what the user is
saying is they want to see
their dates times and so forth in the
urging language in following the
regional conventions
at the India but the user also has some
keywords to do some overrides the
default for that
that particular locale for example the
default
fault calendar in India is ther
Gregorian calendar
but the you this user wants to use the
Islamic calendar
perhaps they do a lot of business with
people in the Middle East
in addition the default currency for
India is the rupee
but this user says they want to use the
US dollars thirty fault currency
again perhaps because they do a lot of
international business
selleck house have a lot of information
in them but you shouldn't get
all the information that you need out of
the locale
there's something she should get from
elsewhere cell
you might think that because there's a
region in the locale
that that's where the user is located
but the region just indicates their
preference for certain things
it doesn't mean that's where they
actually are I can have my region
setting
as India that doesn't mean I'm in India
so if you don't need to know where the
user is located
or more precisely where their devices
located you score location
again the locale has a language says he
did with it
but that's not necessarily the language
that your application is running in
so if you need to ask localization
questions
use an s-band all not an ass locale
as I mentioned earlier the language the
user uses in their documents
may not be the same language is either
the locale or
the localization language on typically
you don't need to know what language is
any user document but if you do
you can use and its linguistic Thacker
again the region in the locale is just a
preference
it's not something you should use for
regulatory or legal purposes
for determining which shock kinda credit
card to use or whatever for that you
have to use other means
probably talking to a server
again if you doing financial or
commercial transactions
Ardell be in some particular currency
but that's not necessarily the currency
that's
indicated by the current locale you
should use some other means probably
having your server tell you which
currency to use
now if you know the currency are if you
know the three-letter I so code
you can set that on a number formatter
and it will then format amounts in their
currency
using the user's preferences it 12
conversion between currency's value have
to handle that yourself
now we've discussed some of the
differences between mine which is
embark house so happy returns
preferences
will typically you don't have to the
system handles this for you
I'm all the formatter objects including
the new ones calendars locale objects
fill all views that users locale
preference by default
you don't have to do anything I appeared
doing localization use NS Bundela now
will use the user's preferences for you
you don't need to read them directly
and again if you doing language
sensitive operations using in a string
like a localized comparisons for sorting
are searching
in a string will do the right thing by
default
but you say I am some application in
mind I have some
are kind of decision I need to make
about behavior
my application or I need to get
localized resources feder elsewhere
so I really need to read these
preferences
well even in that case you don't need to
quite often
sell for example you might think you
need the language that your application
is running in
in order to control behavior say you
wanted to do
something when it's raining in English
but you don't want to do that when it's
running in Japanese
well you don't need to read the
preference for that you can use in its
battle to make this decision for you if
you wanted to do something
when it's raining in English but not
Japanese put a localized resource in
your band all
which has the value yes for English but
no for Japanese
and your application will pick up the
right behavior automatically
now if you are getting localized
information
from outside your application then you
might need to know the language you're
running in
and we'll talk about that in a little
bit
similarly if you have a setup language
resources
from elsewhere say they're stored on a
server and you need to pick the right
one
you might think you'd need to read the
user's preferred languages
but en espanol can handle this for you
there's a class method
preferred localizations from a reggae
you handled
handed an array which is a list of
language identifiers
are which represent your localized
resources and it will match that against
the user's preferences
and pick the right one for you to use he
don't need to read the Preferences
directly
and this will use the same logic tennis
bundle uses when picking localize
resources
have a bundle
and again if you need to know the
language content to the document
which is unusual but sometimes necessary
you can use any of linguistic tagger one
thing to keep in mind
is that a single document can have more
than one language
and in fact you can have different
languages appearing even in the same
paragraph
or send
so suppose you do need to get some
localized information from
outside your applications bundle how do
you go about doing that
well the first thing you need to know is
what language
your application is running in right now
that actually pretty straightforward
you just get your main band all you ask
it for its preferred localizations
and the first object in that array will
be the language code
for the language your application is
using right now
so what's an example of something you
might use that for
say your application displays the names
of currencies
you could ask your local icers to
localize the names of all the currencies
for you
and put in your application battle but
that's unnecessary NS locale have fed
information
so you can ask a locale for the
localized name of a currency
but if he'd do that with the current
locale you'll get it
in the language of the current locale
which may not be the same language that
your application is running in and then
you have a mismatch
where the UI if your app is in one
language
but the currency names are showing up in
another said to avoid that
what we do is we make a locale using
the language ID that we computed in the
previous slide
so we take the language I Dr app is
running in we make a locale from it
and then we asked that locale what the
local ice name for currency yes
so here's an example of what you get for
three different localizations
for the ice a currency code si NY
English French and Chinese
similarly NS locale can give you
localize beginning in and quotes
com in if you want those quotes to match
the language that your application is
running in again
you make a locale using that language
and then query it for the beginning in
quotes
if you wanted the quotes to match a
different language
say you've retrieved a web page in you
want to insert quote marks in it
then you with used at mine which to
create the look up Cal
inquiry it for the quote marks so here
again is an example of what you get for
three different localizations
English French and Japanese
site I mentioned a few slides back
that the user can change their locale
preference their region setting
and aP's don't need to restart for that
to take effect
APs are supposed to react to it sell let
me show you when a lot of gaps do
when the user changes to look how
well unfortunately they don't react to
it and the user is forced to quit the
app
and restarted in order for the change to
take effect
say let's talk about how are supposed to
handle this
so the first thing you need to do is
listen for the notification which is NS
current locale to change notification
if you have objects around that use the
locale like
for matters or locale object you'll need
to update
their locale property but there's a
workaround for this
if you set up the object in the first
place to use the auto updating variant
at the current locale you don't need to
do anything
they'll be updated automatically but
there's still some work that needs to be
done
if you have a date formatter for example
that
is using template formats you'll need to
regenerate those based on the new locale
and of course any strings that you
format it using your for matters
need to be created again to reflect the
new locale
arm and finally if if you want the
a change in the lookout to be reflected
on the display
you need to invalidate any views that
are showing that kind of information
so here's a very simple example I am
first we set up a listener for the
nf-kappa current locale to change
notification
and when the user changes their
preference here's what we do
so soon there's a date formatter the
first thing I'm going to do
is update the locale property with the
new value of the current locale
now again if I'd set that locale
property with the auto updating current
locale
I could skip this step this particular
date formatter
is using a day for Mac generated from a
template
and sent that generation depends on the
lookout I have to do it over again
so I call the class method on an estate
formatter
pass at the new locale if the formatter
in regenerate the date format
finally by Mark Knight view 30+ said
that
everything gets three displayed and in
this case I'm assuming that the draw
method of the few
will call the for matters to regenerate
all the strings
for dates times and so on and now I'd
like to ask around me shredded cannot
to talk about some case studies
current
hello I'm cut in the shower and I'd like
to talk you a little bit about
making a rap worked for international
customers
now this is a
very normal looking time string and this
is a time thats appropriately format it
for
US English what you might not have seen
before
is that I was in a listen actually
support dates and times in many
different languages
and you're just a few of them to show
you the variety so some other
differences are of course
you might not even have &amp marker
because he's trying for our time
but of course even if that markers there
it can take many different shapes and
sizes and go in different places
so what you need to keep in mind about
this well let's take
two examples am on left you have
US English on the right you have
Simplified Chinese
has spoken in mainland China
this is a common problem that we see in
many APs which is that
a format for US English is applied to
Chinese
to Chinese user this looks very wrong
similarly here's a perfectly format a
date for US English
this is not a perfectly formatted date
in Chinese in fact it looks like
nonsense
the date on the right is what a Chinese
either would expect to see in step
just to turn the tables around here's a
date that's well format it for Chinese
with
the day month and year of course in
Chinese its year month day
and here's what happens if you take that
order and apply it to an English day
as you can see what you would expect to
see is something on the right hand side
and when you see something on the left
it doesn't just look wrong it looks
blatantly wrong
like it it's broken so how to me
avoid making these faux pas well
the first thing is don't use FX format
fixed formats will work for a fix
language and not work for all the
languages
so now you might look at the English UK
example
in the second row and say well I look
fine its English in it
make sense but what you might not
imagine is
even if you just cross the Atlantic the
format change pretty drastically
so in UK English for example its three
june thru June 3
and these 24-hour time by default so
you don't have champion marker so what's
the right way to do this at the API
level
well localized string from date
is going to get you a date that is
property format it for the current
locale
and you pass in the date style at times
style and that
determines how of succinct over both you
want your dates and times to be
and if format the data property for all
you look house
now you might come back to me and say
while past not working for me
I need something more custom so the
first step on your
attorney to custom dates should be
looking at date format from template
now this allows you to specify a
template and within the template
the template contains information about
exactly what
elements at the date and time you wanna
show and then you passing a lookout
so that the temple it gets it gives you
a format
back from template and then that format
is appropriately
is appropriate for the locale that you
passed in and that final you set that
format under
on the formatter to get your data types
of course you might still come back to
me and say well
none of the preset styles work for me
and not have the template formats
I they work for me so what should I do
well
it becomes a little more complicated as
you can see me but the basic idea is
you might have a custom format but you
probably have not considered
every possible look at the world so
don't apply or custom format every
possible how in the world
if you have a custom format for US
English check for
English US and apply just English US
and of course if your custom formats for
other locales check for the specific
locales
and make sure to fall back to the
default in your health case
and that's all there is to dates and
times next letting want names
a very similar to dates and times names
come in many different languages and
scripts
and formats here's what happens
if you apply a name format candidate for
Chinese
to an English name doesn't look very
good
and believe me that this Chinese name
looks just as awkward
to a Chinese you there because if using
English informant
so what's wrong here well
most commonly what we see is that a
fixed format has been hard coded
and when you use a fixed format it's
only going to work for some names
so clearly this is not the right
approach
now what might not be super intuitive is
that even using
a format obtained from the current
localization
will not give you the right formatting
every time
why now if you're living in the US most
for contacts might be in English
but a lot of customers especially those
in Asia
most often have hun tax in at least two
languages
if not more say Chinese and English or
Japanese English
so with the fixed format obtained from
the current localization
you might formats a all Chinese names
right
but you might get on the English names
wrong so that just not good experience
so what should you do well there's a
great API called
a view record copy composite name you
pass a
a record from address book it will give
you back the name to display
just that simple there's no code
underneath and this API
of course it in cap sleeve a lot of
logic that we have
designed that takes into account the
language of the contact the user
settings
and of course it has a lot of
language-specific logic to then find the
right format to show the contact in
but you need to worry about that just
use this API of course you might say
my head contact don't come from the
address book to come from somewhere else
that's fine you can take the name
information that you get from another
source
create a temporary AB record assign
these values
and then ask for the display name again
and of course if you're using boys 10
then
there the display name you can't there
too and that's really all there is two
names
just use these APIs and I'll be alright
next would like to talk to you about
right to left text so
first of all don't think that just
because you don't have a right to left
localization like Arabic or Hebrew that
you can stop listening
this is important even if you localize
just in English
so what's different about these
languages well
their own right to left that's what's
different and had actually cause a lot
of issues
so there are two main topics here one is
alignment
and the others directionality let me
talk about alignment first
this looks like a perfectly innocuous
line of code
said alignment left I mean what's the
alignment for it not for setting
well it works fine for englishtext
but if you set Arabic text in left
alignment
it's kind of like setting englishtext in
Rydal in right alignment
you might do it for a the heading or for
some special cases but you don't
format entire paragraphs of text it
right alignment for English
so that texan operate easy to read
what's the answer well the answer is we
should using natural alignment
now this lets the underlying frameworks
to determine what the appropriate
alignment is left to right
depending on the language in use can
defuse this
you get a nice left alignment for
English and other left to right:
languages
and you get nice right alignment for
Arabic and other try to attract
so that sexy let's move on to something
less easy
directionality now tax now at:
in contrast alignment determines what
the
logical order and the and Vishal order
of the word
is within a given runoff text like
within a single sentence
so would be /c most commonly and going
wrong
is that and someone is trying actually
to be helpful
and the attacked the fact that the app
is running Arabic or Hebrew
and the hard code the base writing
correction to right to left
why is this wrong well this is wrong
because User Content
can be in any language as tell you
mentioned before and you cannot assume
the language if User Content
now this is a sentence that supposed to
be an English with one
would the word in the middle so it's
supposed to said that the DC
is a fun conference it's not really
saying that right now because it's using
right to left a texan directionality and
that doesn't make sense
so what should you do well for any
text view or text field in which you
expect the user to type content
set the writing correction to natural
now again that lets the
underlying frameworks determine what
good best guess for the writing texan
its
in this case it will take a look at the
first few letters
the string which is WWDC and since those
are left to right
characters it will take a guess that
this string should go left to right
and in this case that produces the
expected sentence we did
type DC is a must conference
so of course as I mentioned
it's a best guess and so you might have
a sentence like this now since you saw
it animate in
you can't see the order see see can see
it once more time
so Safari first then mosier data in
Arabic and then Mac
so you might be able to tell
if you side being typed that the user
wants to say Safari on Mac
but because it started with Latin
letters would go on left to right
the directionality was assumed as left
to right
and so you have the opposite sentence
Mac on Safari
so how do you fix this well
this is the sentence you want to get and
in order to get dis order of the words
what you need to do is you need to
insert a right to left a mark
at the beginning of the sentence this is
an invisible character that you insert
to
control the technology the string
and of course you might have a case
that is the opposite in fact in in which
you start with
say in Arabic word which is right to
left and OS will guess that
the whole sentence is supposed to flow
from right to left but what you intended
was a for the sentence TUF to flow from
left to right and if you have a
translation app you might actually have
already encountered a case like this
and in this case be solution is to
insert a left to right mark
so what you're probably thinking as well
that's great but who was supposed to
insert these marks interprets strings
because you might not have heard about
them so the answer is
well it is you but
and probably not exactly you would you
need to do
is to talk to your local actors your
local eyes ears
I and not just earned right to left
language localize there's like a look
let us for Arabic and Hebrew
all your localize there's need to
understand how these marks work
because they need to insert these in for
example if there's
/url localize upholstering that starts
with a format argument
now when the user a
content comes in that format argument
could be replaced by
an English word are an Arabic word or
Hebrew word our French word
so you don't know at compile-time what
it's going to be
so you need to insert if you're in a
left-right localization like English or
French or German
you need to have left to right mark
their to tell it that even if an Arabic
word comes in I want the sentence to
flow left to right
and the same and the opposite for right
left localizations
of course this is just a brief
introduction
to a handling right to left text
are actually makes text I should say and
you should
check out our internationalization and
localization guy for
more details about handing more bass
cases
lastly for right to left I should
mention that
Xcode 6 has a great new feature which
lets you simulate
a right to left localization so you can
run in English
but in right to left to see how your
layout flows in the right level
localization
and of course I highly encourage you to
attend the localizing
exposition which is later today to learn
more about exco six and what it brings
for localization
let's let me talk about the keyboard now
this is the US English keyboard
and as you probably know from yesterday
we now have predictive typing
so what does this mean for you at the
developer
well even more than it for
you need to keep track of the height and
size at the keyboard
so I have first of all hope that none of
you have hard coded the size of the
keyboard and you were in your apt
on and now of course if you do that
you're going to get a lot a one-star
ratings
up so first default notice that
even when predictive typing as of
likened left there's still a thin bar on
top the keepers at the height of the
keyboard still different from what it
used to be
but not all the keywords and I was are
predictive typing enabled so you still
might have a keyboard like the Bengali
keyboard which is new and I was take
which does not have even that sand bar
on top so already you had three
different sizes
then we also have keyboards like
Japanese
and Chinese in which before these are
starts typing
if the short height and once the start
typing there's a bar on top because the
top I'd
so your happiness to accommodate the
site changes on the fly
and of course users will switch back and
forth between these keyboards
not only that but this is something
you're probably aware of
for sure is that when the keyboard comes
up your UI needs to move
away if you don't want to get hidden
behind the keyboard
so how do we do all of this well
helpfully
the keyboard lets you know all when it's
coming in going out or change in size
so all you need to do is watch for those
notifications
now what can you do with these well
here's an example of
Safari when the keyboard comes in as you
can see
the the search field tricks
and I'll play it again so you can see
that
these two animations are actually
happening in tandem
so how do you make this happen in your
apt
well the keyboard will show
a notification actually contains a lot
of information first of all
it contains information about the frame
where the people will start and where
the key word will
ended animation it also contains
information
about the animation duration curve
sexually you can use
these two piece of information together
and make sure that your UI
moves away from the keyboard and also
moves in tandem with the keyboard that
gives a very smooth experience to the
user
we also have hardware keyboards so I O S
any IRS device can attach to a hundred
people via bluetooth
and of course the joint assimilated
there's an option the simulator
to do that as well so what does this
mean for your caps
well if you have an app like this which
has a toolbar
above the keyboard the important thing
to keep in mind is that there's
functionality like
choose font in this case which you don't
want the user to lose when the
attach a hardware keyboard so
this is not what you want when hardware
keyboard attached
what you want is this in which the
toolbar at the bottom remains
even door hardware keyboard attached so
how do you make this happen
well if you do have a view that just
goes on on top of the keyboard
if the one line it's a one line that Co
change which is
to use input excess review into texas
review
allows you to specify a view and that
view is stuck on top the keyboard
in the keyboard takes care animating it
in and making it out and
making sure it docks at the bottom when
the hardware keyboard attached
moving onto another keyboard topic
keyboard type
now keep your types basically allow you
to
specify within the same keyboard
different
specific optimize keyboard type so for
example here we have
email type which is meant for email
addresses usernames et cetera and as you
can see
has the at and full stop keys on the
first plane
to let you use the type those
of course the punctuation planes are
also optimize for email type for email
address typing
and so you have more frequent use
symbols there
what you might not know is that in the
keyboards for many languages like
Simplified Chinese Arabic et cetera
many of the commonly use punctuation
symbols for other languages
are not the same symbols that I use for
email address or URL
and so the problem is that if
if you expect a certain kind of input in
your text field and you don't specify
the right type
if the user might actually be forced to
switch keyboards just a typing email
address or username
and that's not a very good experience so
make sure to specify that I keep your
type
and of course we have more than just
email we have URL Twitter
number pad in fact we have a whole host
of different keyboard types
and another one that I'd like to call
your attention to is ASCII capable
now if you have a text field a TextView
in richer expecting content
that is only an ASCII go ahead and
specify the asked capable type that'll
make sure that the users keyboard
is fished for example from Chinese to an
ASCII
keyboard automatically and they don't
have to manually switch keyboards to do
that
you should also know about the auto
correction type suffer some of your text
using text fields
auto correction may not be useful in
fact that might actually hamper user
input
so make sure to turn our oppression of
where appropriate
similarly auto capitalization is if has
for our four options which are very
useful for different context and these
are all
also language where say should use these
appropriately
had depending on what kind input you
expecting a certain text me or text
field
and lastly I wanna talk about mark text
now you might never have seen this if
you never used the Chinese or Japanese
keyboard
but for these languages when the user
types
they do not directly type the output
characters like to do in English
but the first type usually a frenetic or
other kind
input string and then
they choose candidate from the bar below
par its about the keyboard
so what does this mean for you as a
developer
the important thing to know here is when
a text you or text feel has marked X
in it because when it does have marked X
in it
the number one thing you wanna make sure
is to not added to the content of that
text your text field
why because if you do that their mark
text
will get committed to the document
pretty much no user wants that to happen
because that is not the text they were
trying to type and you're going to have
some are some very frustrated users if
you do that
and of course while the markets as their
you can use it for other things like
auto-completion
are are showing some predictions to the
user
but would you should remember is that
this is not their final text
and often the marked X is not going to
contain
meaningful linguistic content because
it's just the input codes for that
in but so use it for life searching for
if you like but
note that it might not be at the user's
file contact
and that is really all
the well that's not all but I would say
that those are the most common think
they should keep in mind
and let me just reiterate some of the
items that we talked about earlier
that will help prevent you getting a
one-star rating
from someone in Asia or the Middle East
so first to fall local as your apt
into tender languages on
of course I wasn't always 10 both
support a lot of languages
and we added new ones for both platforms
and starting in IRS 8 you can localize
into many languages that Apple doesn't
localizing do so don't let that stop you
secondly understand the differences
between language and locale
and when to use them and only to use
them
of course format dates times and named
correctly
as you saw it's really easy to do
and note that there are a lot of
right to left users on both IRS analysts
and in fact it's one of the most popular
languages for
input on IRS can I was 10 so
regardless of whether you localize into
Arabic or Hebrew are not the right to
left language or not
make sure that you're not breaking text
input for these users
keyboards of course come in many
different shapes and sizes
and well actually one shape many thanks
on
and of course becoming new science with
IRS
eight so make sure you keep that in mind
of course to the right keyboard type for
the context so that you make
the input experience smooth and easy
and don't touch the mark text if
a don't ask the document while there's
mark text in the document
how for more information of course I'll
you can contact Jake who's our apt remix
evangelist
and we also have the
internationalization localization guide
that I mentioned previously
up on their website that you should
really check out
we also have tooth two sessions that you
should definitely check out
one is localizing with Xcode six which
is later this morning
and actually we covered a lot of new
material this year
an act we didn't actually repeat a lot
of the material from previous years
internationalization talks which are
actually still relevant
for your apt today so definitely go
ahead and check out
making a rap world ready which is last
year's internationalization session
thank you very much