thanks so much for coming to what's new
in Cocoa Touch
it's really great to see a packed house
here today
I know that we have a lot of new
attendees in the house this week
and so for those of you who have never
been to a dub dub DC
have never been to a what's new in Cocoa
Touch talk
this is really a great opportunity for
you to get a taste for
all the new things that we're releasing
in the FTK this year
and as you know this is actually the
biggest
STK Relief simply FTK self for this BBC
is going to be absolutely huge
and recession is your opportunity to
gonna take
both technologies and I'll be pointing
throughout the session
and again at the end of the session to
all the other related
sessions to the technology so i'm
talking about. you can get an idea
have one other talk but you wanna see
this week not allowed
you're gonna wanna go to and that for a
fact so
to begin i wanna talk about this core
idea
what we've set up love what I West
aid is really all about from the after K
perspective and that this idea
at activity activity is going to pervade
everything that we do in Cocoa Touch
and Iowa State and adaptivity mean
several
think on one hand activity is a design
philosophy
it's a wave architecting your ass and
we're going to
give you an idea of how we want perhaps
to be built from now on using are a
design philosophy that encourages code
reuse
generic code that adapts from contact
to contact and is I able to go from
devices like iPhone and iPad
FEMA way additionally
activity income through the whole that
have
things that we are providing directly
from you like it
to you things like adaptive
view controllers adaptive you
controllers are something that
we have written with the design
philosophy of activity
that when you use in your app can allow
you to do things like
take a simple primary/secondary view
controller pattern
have it on iphone have the same code
that puts out on iphone
put an interface that you text back to
on iPad
and do that without any device check
now all be the same code running on both
devices will show you how to do that
them only we've taken the philosophy
ever activity to view controller
presentation
and we'll show you how to build code
that prevent something like a full
screen mode a view controller on iphone
and something more appropriate like a
popover
on iPad again without any device
specific tax because we're focusing on
reusable
adoptive code bad as the theme
a are Cocoa Touch on Iowa a additionally
we're gonna be pressuring
a new user interface icon fact that we
won all
application to adopt and that dynamic
erred
dynamic packed and adapting to dynamic
tax
this was actually a feature is
introduced in Iraq 7
users can change their preferred text
size
and I with 8 we've extended the idea
such that
all haps built in the Iraq respond to
dynamic type and are adapted to that
and we want to show you how you can do
that we recognize
that won the common places that uses
iraq attacks is actually
I inlet in a former table views so we
art took it upon ourselves to make it
you here to take a simple table like
what you with the impending
respond to the user's dynamic texturing
make the tax bigger and make the Rose
bigger as well
finally an activity
refers to the ability to this
opportunity actually to extend to the
system to adapt the system to your users
need
and desires by bringing your
functionality
in 250 maps as well other third-party
app suit on the keynote that we can do
things
like add a photo filter right within the
Photos app
without ever having to go to your
application so these are the kind of
things
that we're going to be talking about
throughout the talk the first part
is particularly about the design
philosophy
and then we'll move into lifting of a
lot of the things that are
especially knew about the API to me
again we'll talk about this design
philosophy
adaptive playout so
I said it before but of eight again make
the Kiev what we mean by adaptive layout
is
something that is reusable believe code
that is generic
that transcend device foundry and
orientation boundaries for the first
thing we want to talk about
is a simple idea a interface orientation
this has been a a stalwart concept
through the API since the s2k was
introduced
I'm actually want to move now to a place
where
when we're writing our apt our layout
code doesn't have to care what the
interface
orientation and that can be the FEMA
we're talking about now
so we can imagine that I designer gave
us a design for a photos out
and they say okay this Photos app
on portrait in an iPad looks like a grid
rectangular thumbnail photos and there's
five column from Agra
them only they give it back and say if
the iPad and landscape
show if the motor similar thumbnail but
seven columns up
now the nine-year way to approach this
would be
okay but hard code in five columns have
things
I for a portrait and seven columns and
things for landscape
but to become adaptive
we want to take a deeper understanding
I've why we have five columns in
portrait and why we have seven call and
and landscape it's pretty easy to
understand with the
this example but the reason is the
portrait view
if 768 points wide
and based on the thumbnail size that we
want to achieve it just so happens that
we can fit 5 across so we have five
columns
some only when we go to landscape we now
have 1024 point
in the west to mention and based on the
thumbnail 5 size that we wanted to
achieve we can outfit
seven columns the difference here is
that when we take that logic
that we say okay we can bit this many
columns in this space
as opposed to there are seven columns
and landscape
man the actual interface for annotation
is not irrelevant being in determining
what your layout look like anymore
all that matters is what the canvas 5
looks like
so there's also another decision being
made under the hood here if we decide to
focus in on this view
and that we've made these rectangular
not spread out from now but the Photos
app on the iPhone has actually much more
compacted
thumbnail other square in shape and the
reason about way on the iPhone
it's very similar vein reason it's
because the five the iPhone is different
and so we come packed the layout when we
are in a compacted
5 and so we can actually think about bad
decision that the the compacted iPhone
style layout which is what you see up
here the more spread out
rectangular from their way out as also
being determined by the five
and not actually based on a device
iPhone person iPad
tour now going to begin to think this
interface is determined by
the idea that it has regular size
to mention the height is regular the
whip his regular
and we're thinking about this
semantic-based fighting idea
as a new thing that we call five class
side coffins are a very simple a
numeration
that gets us thinking about canvas size
when we do layout
rather than interface orientation
I we have independent horizontal and
vertical 5 Proctor's and either wannabes
acted
can be either compaq or regular
am NOT simple choice can allow us to
choose between what we may now think
about an iPhone style interface
and iPad style interface really isn't
about the device
it's about the canvas 5 that we have and
will continue to talk about this idea
not throughout the fashion but part of
what makes back key
is that you may end up in a situation
where
you are showing something displaying
your view on them
iPad where the five the back canvas
actually compatible about just being on
an iPhone
and if you've written adaptive code that
simply uses the size rather than the
device to do it layout
you get and iPhone style layout when
appropriate in smaller spaces
on an iPad so the situation but we
cannot ban
are on the iPad having regular five and
regular with this is true in either
orientation
on the iPhone which becomes compacted
and Matt you think that bit of
information the photos that can choose
to shrink to it more compacted square
thumbnail based layout them only when
the iPhone
goes to landscape it still has a compact
with but often takes on
a compact hype you can use both those
people information
25 what happened in your layout in your
app
so we've wrapped up this concept side
pockets
and are exposing it to you via nuclei in
your eye care
call you a tree collection you write
recollection
is a handy bringing together a few
pieces of information including the
horizontal 55
the vertical 5 choir the display scale
and user interface ATM now what makes
track collections convenient is there
Hong right
as a property on you a view controller
you can access them from your view
controller you can also get them from
the current screen
and then using that information you have
your side class
you can make that determination what is
the right thing to do for you
so the simple example we can think of
what we did with photos
and and implement i5 quad
did change map it and for photos
I it just means to consider what the new
psychoactive
an based on whether the horizontal five
clock
is compact or not the
the photos way out choose to use either
at compaq
squares based layout if it is a comeback
of course all five prop
or otherwise it uses it rectangle
rectangular from now more spread out
layout and then this is this particular
snippet model to be on a collection view
controller
so it just takes that layout object and
apply that to it
collection view as a new way out object
now thelma view maybe I'm not a thing
with I'm unfamiliar scribe to you on the
screen
I if this is your first time seeing
swept congratulations I
here is here your intro and you can feed
just how easy it is to understand
and this will give you 90 an idea of how
easy it is
to start adopting swept immediately with
all cocoa and Cocoa Touch
API's to it that I
all talk about quickly another new API
that we've
added to support your layout and I with
a
which is I margins so margin
coincide with an API release in Iraq
seven witches male pride
layout guide help you know about hard
lines on the screen in this case
the top and the bottom of the screen
where the top is a noting that the
navigation bar there
the layout guide tells you about that
navigation bar in case you like to avoid
a
if they were to a bar at the bottom the
screen your layout I would often turn
out
the top about to a bar in this case it
just a note the hard-line
that is the bottom of the screen but
there's another concept
in this year I that isn't covered by the
Arcade
that is the white space that is I in
cutting the content from the edge in the
screen
so and I with eight we're introducing an
API and Uribe you
which is male guide which tells you
about
that white space and allows you to that
whatever white space
you want for your lap that the property
annual review
also come native with native support for
auto layout
the map in the former knew an FBI
attributes including
lap right leading trailing
et cetera there's a bunch to the if
you've been using are allowed in your
code you'll find this
natural and familiar
so to learn more tricks about building I
adoptive where after there's going to be
a great talk tomorrow
on the mission call about building
adaptive ap with you I kept
summary moving onto talking about some
other
ways that we have adopted the philosophy
have adaptive five clock based design
to build things that you can use out of
the box
that are adaptive without you having to
do any work
and so we'll start by talking about
adaptive you control it is a great new
feature
and could begin to dive into the I'm
actually gonna go back and talk a little
bit more
about this idea fornication which
our rotation which we touched on with
the orientation segment of the talk so
now I'm gonna have a have after some
this question
what is rotation really because asking
ourselves that question
yield a result but helpless right
adaptive code
and that result is
it's just and animated change in for
five
view so if we consider a view
that on screen we might have been
thinking out
when the device rotate that view
rotates with it and this is a rotating
bill
that perspective actually complicate
the idea of what we have to do in our
way out
and so beginning I would say we're
encouraging you to take
a different perspective towards how
rotation works
which is just think a bit as a view that
happens to have
on this case a regular height in a
compact where
and when the device rotates something
happens to that view
and the thing that happens that view is
it undergoes an animated
5 change and perhaps it goes to a
compact high
and a regular wept I don't want to
confuse you
in that standard on an iPhone I
in landscape the weapons actually
compact but this is an illustrative
example
what might happen to reviewers review I
changes 5
Xing go to any new siphoning side cross
and that's really all that
happening when you're undergoing a
rotation
and part of the advantage over thinking
about rotations this way is merely a
5 change is that once you handle
rotations as size changes any other
situation that you might end up in
where your size change in you will have
handled
because you will have written your code
in a way that it can handle
size and especially the their animated
so in order to move in this new
direction we're taking a lot of API
that used to exist and iraq 710 still
exist and I was a
but we're deprecating this is just a
subset
the rotation API that is deprecated in
Iowa effect
and when I really like
is what we're replacing that's where
thinking about things as size changes
you can just implement one method will
transition 25
inference that pic to transition
coordinator
if this interesting things you want to
do if you wanna animate along with that
size change whether it be rotation or
anything else that changes the five
have your view controller you can use
that
transition coordinator to do an
animation and you defend in a block
with that transition coordinator and
those changes
will be animated along with besides
change which may be
a rotation have you can't or so in this
case I've used the side chains
to simply change the number of columns
in my photo layout
based on the new size so
beyond just view controllers themselves
I
with rotation we've built from view
controllers that
allow you to adapt the hierarchy from
device to device
in a way that makes it so that you write
Lasko
and for many viewers probably written
something like you see on the screen
area primary/secondary view controller
patterning you do that
using a split view controller and then
you in bed and navigation controller
as the master view controller that about
but you controller and then when you
would go and take the same design
pattern a primary/secondary view
controller
you end up on the iPhone with a
navigation controller
as you review controller and that meant
you would have
a device any Amtrak seeing am i on an
iPad
if so build this new controller
hierarchy if not
filled with other you can view
controller hierarchy with a navigation
controller
at the ritz I found while iPad
just as we want to make it for you no
longer need to care
what year interface orientation is we
also want to make it for you no longer
need to care what your interface
intimate anna & to do that we're making
so you can book this interface on iphone
with the split view controller as the
root view controller
and it will still contain a navigation
controller
as its master view controller then
when you want to you know push another
view onto the stack
you can just call show you can't rely on
this it will do exactly what you would
expect from a navigation
experience pushing everyone to the back
and
when you would I execute something that
would be there
requirement to showing a detail on iPad
you can just call show detail view
controller
and on the phone it will do exactly what
you expect a phone interface to do
which is pressure onto the navigation
controller because
that are not available on the phone but
that
same that have a PI that same call
sequence
calling show view controller or and show
detail view controller
iPad were will yield what the user would
expect
on iPad which is a detail view
controller
over on the right its but you so
US but you can sure is really a
workhorse to be used an IRS
8 the the key to is that it now
available on all devices
allowing you to build view controller
hierarchies that don't depend on what
device you're on it's the same hierarchy
and
iPad and iPhone and view controller will
adapt
for you so without it handles the
primary secondary controller
Palin transparently for you an offer to
go along with this
but you controller has a whole host
have new updates to it API and its
relief I can't even begin to talk about
what they are if you'd like to learn
more about them be a great talk
out tomorrow morning view controller
Hampton and I with 8
so moving on
to adaptive presentation this is another
way that the view controller system
is helping you have code that is simple
and device eggnog Dec but that does the
right thing
on each device we want to help you build
something like a full screen mode of
presentation
on iPhone and get something more
appropriate
like a form she on iPad or even a
popover
and do the with out Kodak shacks with
device Iran only the same code on every
device
so in particular for one thing that is
that is really
not changing the paradigm is poppers
Part II with a popovers were only
available on iPad
and we would use them in the form a view
i pop over controller
well that paradigm is changing
significantly because we're now no
longer requiring the use if you are pop
over control to present a popover
instead popovers are presented via API
as a presentation style
for view controller
so that means if you present a pop over
with her a view controller with the
popover presentation style
and the presenting view controller 5
we're gonna fuck off
is regular it appears you expect a
popover
to appear with that same code using a
popover presentation style
if the presenting view controllers
compaq in the horizontal mention my QPR
iPhone
it would just appear as as in over
as an overshoot so that you get what you
would expect
on iPhone for taking their
these concepts and we're bringing an
activity to some another view controller
that we've and
like search results which may be
thinking of how to view controller while
perfecting that because US church
control display controller
is replaced by US troops controller
and US church controller is crucially
view controller some cry
and that means that it can take
advantage all of the power adapter
hierarchies
and presentations we've just talked
about that all at your fingertips with
the new
you I search controller as new USB
controllers also
able to be fully customized in the way
that it's you I appears and how it's
presented so that
you can adapt research controller into
your application here if you're a fully
customized you I
like that and FaceTime it will look the
way that you want to look
we doing something similar with alert
and I was a
now we're taking you I learnt view new
action sheet
and replacing them with you i alert
controller
kinda thought you guys might like that
one I
you and your controllers also will do I
view controller subclass
but we can internally use all of the
power adapter presentation
to our advantage and to your advantage
things look great
of course you I alert controller adapted
styling
to the contact so that when you
presented on an iPhone
are in anything that has a compact
horizontal 55
you get an action she appearance you can
learn parents often the action suit
style
you get something that looks like what
you expect an action sheet look like
and the same code the present that
action she on an iPhone
in a regular horizontal 5 profligate
I've had will appear in a popover
without you having to write any device
checking code
to you can learn more about how all this
adapter presentation missionary work
by checking out a look inside view
controllers Thursday morning in the
mission
I've been a stalker couple time it's
really great if you want to understand
the nitty-gritty behind how all these
presentation controllers work
and especially if you're thinking hey
this built-in you like it stock the
fantastic
I want to build my own presentation
controllers
that are also adaptive this talk will
teach you how to do that
so what we've been talking about for a
while as tools that were giving you
via the API to write adaptive code
but there's another steps to writing
great code
and that testing so we're giving you
another great to all that we're excited
about
in the Iowa simulator and that if the
ability to
re 5 the physical simulated
hardware and so I don't know if you can
feel on the screen at a little small
but you'll find in your FBK p.m. found
it yet
Numancia the Iowa simulator their two
new devices
but you can flack wanted a resizable
iPad
and wanted the resizable iPhone you can
use the
to actually punchan custom values for
the hardware side
I've the iPad or the iPhone and pack the
ad activity
I've your code on the fly
really excited for how this kinda thing
can
make you can change the way we architect
perhaps because we can architect things
the way that we intend and then tapping
our intentions are doing
what we thought they were going to do so
I actually stole the top you see on
screen
from the a look inside presentation
controllers talk but I just mentioned
and it have a custom presentation
controller
which is the view that find out from the
right and designed to take up to 30 the
screen
I went after that in the resizable iPad
to make sure that if it was in a compact
wet we do the right thing
and sure enough the guys who wrote this
are really great and it doesn't do the
right thing
presenter than over full screen
presentation in the compact with so
let's talk about some other new things
and I Iowa
aid for you I kept for customizing user
interface revenue clock
called you i'd visual look back view the
right view
some clock an interview that takes you I
visual effect
i'm Jack that parameterized custom
rendering mode for the view itself in
the contact and find it sewer shipping a
couple a different back
that you can use with the visual effect
view to get
the fact that you want and first one is
the UI blur a fact
believe me i've been waiting for you
guys to get view this
to for you I were facts will give you a
live blur over the content
where you use it the second the fact
that we're shipping
a review I fiber in fear back now
vibrancy a fact if you are
if you don't know what that is that
refers to the separators in
notification fenner a maybe a little bit
hard to see on the screen but you can
pull out your phone called on occasion
Turner
take a look at those beautiful color
changing color dodging separators
and that biven thing nothing
I heard a pop over there thanks and I
think that we're introducing
is image after image after to something
that encapsulate the one actor to act
the iPhone the iPad representation
view image in the home a trip there are
many comes with some API that makes it
really easy
to get the right images out of the image
catalog because we can you something
like image named
and add a parameter to it that take the
trick collection and sensed
recollections are hung right on your
view controllers
you can take that recollection from
South been viewed it appears something
and apply it directly to an ImageView in
your view controller and you have the
right
image the if statement that implied
in figuring out one-act to act iPhone
iPad Federer
is all encoded within the track
collection which you don't have to do
any work for comes directly
with your view controller another
thank you another
you I feature as condensing bars you may
be familiar with the
if you've used Safari on Iowa 7
have similar concept when you scroll for
30 bargain this rink
well we've extended back contact
throughout the
IRS a fukn given you access to that sort
of behavior in your app
so if you have a navigation bar you can
make it that when the user scrolls
the navigation bar get a little bit
smaller or
if you have a view that has a navigation
bar and a toolbar
you can make up for it when you to
schools navigation by shrinking to buy
disappears
altogether third to learn all about some
great things you can do
with innovative customization I we have
a talk that is tomorrow
called creating custom Iowa user
interface so
I alluded to earlier to a feature that
is that we're pushing an Iowa
8 which is dynamic type everywhere all
about Paul
ap have adapted or have adopted ben-ami
type in our adapting to the changes that
are required for that
when I think that we realize is that
table views
are a very common place where cactus
displayed in something that we would
want to respond
to user tax I'd changes and so
we have maybe you here in Iowa 8
for you to respond to these types of
changes by allowing you to have dynamic
type rose
without actually implementing a delegate
method Table View High for our index
I know that a lot of you have been
asking for this over the years and so on
our solution about it
self coming caps like their sizing logic
inside themselves
they'd get better actually
because this fellow natively support
are only now so yeah have got to get
better
prep and serve you have constraints in
yourselves
you like it can derive the appropriate
height for those cells from the content
and I'm in a constrained to be placed on
you can do something like this where I'm
not implementing the delegate method
high protein extract and dad and myself
initializer
I felt from constraining and this
particular so I have attacked you know I
hope some content I said a vertical
constraint that this ad from padding
around that text you using the visual
format language I do the same thing
on the horizontal axis adding padding on
the right and left
about TextView and then when it I was
created to be populated with an attack
the table you will know how wide it is
will be able to take the content that in
that text view
and the margins that I've setup without
a way out and determine what the
appropriate height for that fell should
be based on that contact and the weapon
the table if you
really I would like to learn more about
that or if you just like to hear me talk
come back to the same room two days from
now where I'll be presenting on with my
very him calling the beloved doctor
Libya good nest
and we'll be talking about what's new in
table and collection views
to moving onto my favorite feature
a bio s FBK was actually kinda hard to
wait till this part of the presentation
but ap extension after extension
are just spent after goofiness in Aquino
after extension are just gonna change
the way that we write I'm
in the way that users enjoy we produce
for them
we can do things like in photos taking
taking a photo bringing up a sheet that
shows the extensions that we have
selecting York
pension right there in photos applying
something like a filter to that photo
and ending up in photos where we always
were
we never had to leave the apt and your
content is right there
for the user at their fingertips you we
can also have sharing extensions which
allow
users to share to your sharing service
right from what ever after and they can
share photos videos
tax and other content without having to
do it or if you go over to your apt
has to be a better experience for the
user and it means more people
can share to your apt because it will be
left work for them to do so
we're we also have notification center
widget
you can write a fantastic notification
center widget I recommend up on my phone
and I can fear
every day I can be extremely grateful
for you
to you for doing that so I extension
opened a lot of doors some %uh the big
things and I are 8 that you can use
after sentence for
course photos sharing notification
fenner
it's also possible to build extension
for don't actually have you know
user interface and a great example of
this is the being translated
action without you I that we saw on the
key now additionally
you can build custom file providers this
is something that will allow the user
to use documents from your cloud storage
solution
EFI mostly as if those documents were
and I Cloud Drive
just by your extension providing them to
absent in the system
additionally I what they make that
possible to write custom keyboard
be shared throughout the fifth time
front row like
back yeah a to learn more about building
after Fenton
we have two great talk today and
tomorrow the when you everything you
need to know
about building upon this just absolutely
tremendous technology that it's just
gonna
I i think is the fine posted different
from here on out some updates to
notification
notification changed a bit in particular
in the way that we model
I how users approve notification that
appear on screen
has always been true that users have to
approve push notification and
it one untrue previously that users
would have to approve
local notification to control local
notification I without the user
giving approval to not so when I was aid
any notification that shows your eye on
the screen is
going to require one time approval from
the user
the flip side to that as you can send
push notifications that
don't show you I to the user that simply
shuttle David here ap
and those will not by default require
user approval to you can just send
notifications the route from you don't
have to
the referee about
notifications can now also have actions
associated with them
that is if you want to display something
I have the reply button or other actions
those can be tacked onto your
notifications and whatever action the
user solak
that will be shuffled over to your apt
for your custom logic to be invoked
based on action notifications can also
be location-based
in Iowa State so you can pop up a
notification when a user
enters or exits a significant area that
you wanna
show them in addition about
finally we've increased increased the
payload per side
from 250 hey 5 one
four-time from my love for everyone I
if you wanna learn more about this
there's a great talk with new highway
notification
tomorrow afternoon in help so we're
introducing a doc picker
and I would say and it looks beautiful
looks like that I as questionable on
iPad and iPhone
and what's great about this is we now
have 50 me why
for selecting document you no longer
have to write come
completely custom code starting from
scratch to give the user a document
picking experience
if you want to be able to interact with
document in your application
you can use the UI document pick your
view controller as being exposed in a
course in to view controller
a good to take advantage of all the
adaptive presentation hierarchy
machinery
that we talked about earlier this
document picture has access to documents
in the local scope
and FEMA we also in the i five drives go
and finally
anybody who is supplying a document
right extension to the system
those documents were also appear in the
document picker
at all family completely seaman finney
for the user and your application just
get to you are all back
for the document any means to open to
learn more about
document picker support we've got a
great cock and building a doctrine based
app in the marina on Thursday
a quick word about STK modernization
we made a few changes throughout the
headers I in the cocoa and Cocoa Touch
if you i've as want to give you a a
quick rundown of what that's all about
we've annotated all the designated
initializer have class with an A
designated initializer annotation C you
know which ones are the designated
initializer
which of course you need to know if
you're going to be a good for crop
improvement
additionally I love the return types
furnish litres have changed from ID to
instance tight
kinda makes over auto complete better I
and we've introduced additional
properties I in place a classic ok a
method
in particular like the NFL object
protocol where hash used to be a method
ash is now a property for Anna object
and these changes enhance the experience
for use with the cocoa and Cocoa Touch
API token object if the and in
particularly
with swept so hand-off
is an opportunity for your out to
participate in a feature that we talked
about in the Keno
which is continuity
continuity is the thing that allows
users to do something like start a email
on their phone
go to their computer finish that email
and it all seems experience well
with hand of we're giving you the
opportunity to
have user active you have your own so
that they can do that
not just with male or with other
built-in
activity but with your activities as
well
so hand-off has built-in support for
activities
in apk it and do I care both natively
support activities in their document
factors
and I you'll be able to use that
out of the box to learn more about
hand-off a check out the adopting
handoff and Iowa
talk tomorrow in the mission so
there's a whole lot of stuff has changed
here
I lots of new things we also have
several brand new frameworks an Iowa
8 and I don't really have time to talk
in any kinda depth about these things
but I want to give you an idea hey
avoided out there
so you can see what other sessions that
you'd like to attend because
this framework allow you to build after
you simply could not build
before iraq 8 and that's fantastic
of course first one we've already
touched on Notification Center
will support you building extension to
add widgets to
the notifications on iraq's that
notification ended up from work
and you can learn about that by I
checking out
the building up its pensions talk
of a brand-new photos framework this
will give you
complete read/write access to the photos
library
this means you can do whenever your
application needs to do
to provide the best user experience
possible taken to leave for
I can do non-destructive at do whatever
it needs to do
so that the user gets what they need
while mister actually in the photos talk
her in in the photos framework I do want
to take this opportunity to play now
II with a also brings custom core image
filters
and so you'll be able to use these on
your photos as well as videos and Iowa
State
for brand new framework called cloud
kept and this framework
is absolutely spectacular I really can't
say enough good things about it
I'm it gives you more control than you
ever had over the data that you put
in the cloud and more really makes this
spectacular is you can use cloud care to
build
a client-server application with a
building a server side
you can to find that on the client side
and what Apple take care
for you so I and II can even wait to see
what startups come
out a bit will be fantastic and we love
cloud kit
so much that we build I hard drive and
photos in the cloud on top of it
it's a fantastic technology and you love
building your up some top
not a new framework if health care
health kit
brings all of the biometric information
from the various devices the user has
all into one place this information is
shared across
aP's rather than filo dough into one app
has
one biometric device information another
Apple has another biometric devices
information
at 4shared so you can I use that to
create
a perfect experience for user based on
all in the biometric data available
from all of their customers family
we are introducing a home-care which
does the same thing for connected home
devices
put all about information in one play
to rate you can build an app for that
everything the user needs
for their connected home accessing all
of those things
in one place of have a new local
authentication
framework this allows you to leverage
the power
biometric authentication in your own apt
and as you probably know from having
watched the keynote this means that you
get to use patch id:
right inside your application that's
great and we have a talk that you can go
check out
I to learn more about how to do that
Russia bringing
been kept to iraq 8 think editor
great framework for building 3d
rendering and we've had it on the Mac
for a year
when i bringing it to Iraq now we have a
great cross-platform solution
for doing 3d rendering view have our do
you think a
you're gonna love this so there you have
it your offer gonna love it
everybody's gonna love it threat that
all the brand new frameworks that not
all the changes though
a point out one other framework that is
made some significant changes which is
core location
crew location now make that possible to
get
the user's location details indoors and
by that I mean
you can get what Florida users on not
just
where they are
regrettable after you have never never
built before
I'm for I we also have new EP I think
rotation that will make it
easier to save power when getting
significant location updates how to be a
better for everyone I'm a big power
magnet myself
for using me is on hand everyone's
experience that were also changing
the user approval model around
provocation
so that users can now are choose to
prove your app
either all the time for a location near
or only give a
you can you can this request to be
approved only when you're in you
so the user can rest assured that your
app is not using
location not draining the battery not
feeling any secret
when your apt if not in use for to
change provocation
so to finish up here want to reiterate
some ideas about the design philosophy
because really I O FA
is a is a mark in the fan for how we
think about
building apt in addition to all a bit
new API
so we're going to be centered around
building reusable code that device
taking off stick
that is air face orientation agnostic
that is
adaptive so we can use the tools that
are presented in you like it and I with
a
to them for fire layout by using things
like five profits or not
worrying about what the specific 5
things are
we use the five clock to make a
determination whether it's compact
a regular and we can't ask for things
out using the resizable familiar
we can use I the iPhone and iPad code in
a unified way
but we only have one bit of code that
does the right thing
on all devices and we're bringing a
doctor view controller technology to you
that will allow you to do that you can
integrate into the system now using
after extension
so that the user can do more things in
more places than ever before
and your ass can be more useful for and
that ever done
am finally have we just covered since
we've introduced
several brand new framework for things
that you just could never do before that
now you can do
you can expand your tool set using all
of these
brand new thing so if you want more
information about anything in this
talk you can always talk to are
innumerable
frameworks evangelist Jack Barron check
out our documentation on developer Apple
com or head up the dough forms for
people like me can answer your questions
I have a whole bunch related fashion you
can check out or get out of the way
I don't wanna right any block anyone
from running the down is actually
another screen
after this for anyone who wants a check
out more
related fashion something too many
people using pencil
is that a national related fashion
and we also have a water lab course time
that the city is packed with my
all week I more than I could ever
even bother to call out but Cocoa Touch
labs are the next three days you'll be
able to find me and a couple dozen have
my colleague to answer all your
questions
related to building you like it
application
and I really hope you're able to get an
idea
all that we have to offer in the BBC and
I hope you have a fantastic week thanks
for coming