everyone welcome tent reducing health
care
my name's Justin i mean i OS
engineer and i'll be joined appear in a
little while by my colleague CG
CGI got to work together on health care
and we're really excited to show to
today so
there are a ton have health and fitness
aP's
on the App Store today they do all sorts
of awesome things
the lead our users get healthy and stay
healthy
problem is not a lot of the zaps
can share data between each other this
makes it really hard for our users to
get a cohesive you
their current health the few aP's
they can share data had to write all
sorts of custom code to do so
which means you spend your time an
energy
working on features that aren't court to
the experience
if your applications now
we recognize the different applications
have different needs
the way we see it they can be grouped
into three
main categories first their applications
that perform statistical analysis
using graphs trans next their
applications to let users
enter information last
their applications put out by health
providers to let users sync data
with their personal medical record these
are three very different scenarios
but we don't health kit so that it can
handle all of them
we're gonna show you how does that today
throughout the stalk
we're going to refer to the health ap
this is talking about the new health
application
that we're introducing with IOSA to use
our agenda for today
we're gonna start off by walking you
through the health care API
so you can learn how to create data how
to save data
and how to ask for data as well 10 CDs
gonna come up here and give you a demo
so you can see how to incorporate health
kit and your own applications
will finish things off with some help
get best practices
health kit
is a framework that lets you store and
retrieve health and fitness information
so data is really important we're gonna
start off by talking about what data is
and health care storing health
information
in a way that can scale to work all
across the world has presented some
challenging problems every time you step
on your scale
your weight maybe pounds in the United
States stones in England
her kilograms and many other areas we
didn't want you to have to do unit
conversion yourself
so we handle unit conversion for you
writing health kit
units are handled
by HK unit in HK unit
represents a particular unit in the
metric or imperial units system
these can be simple such as grams
but they can be complex like milligrams
per deciliter
base units are classified
in two types: types defined which units
are compatible with each other
for example a mass units value can be
converted
to any other mass unit here you can see
the milligrams per deciliter is an
example amass
per volume unit we give you a couple
have different ways to create units
first you can specify them explicitly
incurred here we're creating a gram unit
and then we're creating a de salir unit
and we're combining the two
to make a grams protest leader unit this
works really well for sample units
but as you can see it gets pretty
unwieldy as we expand to more complex
want
to make things easier on you we let you
specify units using unit strings
like so so this line will create an
identical
unit to the three lines above it
once you have your unit the next thing
you're going to want to do
is create in HK quantity in HK quantity
is a double value relative to a
particular unit
what's really cool about quantities
though is that they can be used to do
unit conversion for you
let's take a look at how they do that
here
we start off by making a quantity have
twenty grams
next we can ask for its double value in
kilograms
this will give us back point 02
unfortunately not all units play nicely
together
if you ask a quantity for its value and
a unit it's not compatible with
we're going to throw an exception you
can always gorgeous often code
by asking a quantity if it's compatible
with the particular unit
to return a ball so
now that you have your quantity the
question should be asking yourself
is what is this a quantity of to answer
that question
we're going to take a look at object
types
object types represent all the different
kinds data
that we can store in health care there
are over 60 different types
major groups have types for organized
into their own classes
all these classes and hair from HK
object-type
characteristic types are characteristics
the user
or trade that don't change overtime
these are things such as their blood
type or date of birth
sample types on the other hand are
treated the user that
do change over time as such they can be
sampled
at a particular point in time
one kind of sample type its K quantity
type
these are the kind today didn't they can
be represented fine HK quantity
they're by far the most common kinds of
data and health care
and represent everything from blood
pressure to potassium
to the number of steps you taken
last we have is K category type
category types described the kind of
data they can be categorized
into an enumeration values an example if
category type
is sleeping Alice which is how we store
sleep
and health kit let's talk about how you
create in instance
I'm in HK object-type every type has its
own
type identify you cannot create your own
types
or type identifiers but it's important
to understand how their structured
so that you can use auto complete tear
drainage
here we have are identifiers for heart
rate
the first part of the identifiers is
which object-type subclass
it represents as you can see heart rate
is a quantity type
the second part did identifiers is the
type
name or what you would call the type
once you have your type identifiers you
can pass it to one of these three
constructors
on HK object-type it's important to note
that your identifiers
and your constructor need to match up
so if you were to pass a category type
identifiers
to quantity type for identifiers you're
going to get back
nell
so now we have a quantity
and we have an object type it sounds
like you're ready
to create some data all data are stored
and health care
is a subclass its K object
here we have a diagram other its K
object class hierarchy
you I noticed that this is pretty
similar to the hierarchy we just saw
for HK object-type this is by design
as object types and objects are very
closely tied together
let's take a look at some of these
different classes
will start off with its K quantity
sample
this is by far the most common kind of
HK object and health kit
there how we store quantities in the
database
every quality sample has a quantity type
this is what kind of data the sample
represents
they also have a quantity which is the
value
at the sample it's important to note
that your quantities unit and your
quantity type need to match up
every quantity type expects a certain
kind of the unit
and if there's a mismatch here then
we'll throw an exception
next we have its K category sample
category samples
are very similar to quality samples they
have a category type
which again describes what kind of data
the sample represent
and they have a valued now
remember the category types for the
kinds of data they can be categorized
into an and numeration values
as such every category type is paired
with the corresponding Keenum this value
property
must be one of the members that the num
if an invalid value is provided we throw
an exception
just like we do for quantity samples
both these inherit from HK sample
remembered that samples are the kind to
data they can be sampled
at a particular point in time to support
this
every sample has both a start date and
and a
why but the start date mandate might ask
well
for some kind today to such as your way
the reading is pretty instantaneous so
your start date and end date
should probably be the same for other
kinds a dated oh
you're reading My take place over a
period of time
you might wanna say that your heart rate
wasn't averages 80 beats per minute
over the course have 30 seconds
every sample also has a sample type
this is going to be the same as your
category type or quantity type
depending on which subclass you choose
to implement
all these inherit from HK object
every object has a UUID which is a
unique identifiers that has persisted
for the lifetime of the object
so you can count on this always being
the same
they also have a source because health
information
is so sensitive we wanted to make sure
that every object could identify
where it came from each application
represents
its own source but sources can also be
pieces of hardware
such is a Bluetooth heart rate monitor
or the step tracker near fun
meta data is an important part the
extensibility
up an object you can create an object
with whatever method eighty like
note that meta data is a regular annis
dictionary
except it can only store strings as keys
and strings numbers and dates is values
we give you a few predefined meta-data
keys which we think you might be used
which we think might be useful we
encourage you to create your own
meta-data keys
as well
now you may have noticed that all of the
properties you saw here are read-only
this is because all data and health kit
is immutable
as great as it would be to go back and
change my high need really doesn't make
any sense
so you can create objects using
constructors on HK quantity sample
NHK category sample
this is an example how you might create
object to represent someone's body
temperature
first we create our quantity type which
in this case is the quantity type
for body temperature
next week create are quantity let's say
this person feeling pretty healthy today
so their temperature is ninety eight
points6 degrees Fahrenheit
last recreates a medida this piece a
meta data says that the person probably
took
their body temperature using your
thermometer
we can then pass all this to HK quantity
samples
quanti sample with type: and given a
start date and end date
right now
now that you have your data what do you
actually do with it
well to really do anything with health
kit the first thing you need
is in HK help store you can think if
your health store
is your link to the database
it lets you save objects and as we'll
find out a little bit
it lets you ask for data as well
remember though that you really only
need one health store
they should be long-lived and you don't
really get anything out of having
multiple ones floating around
so create one hold on to it and you're
done
here's an example a bus saving some data
to health kit
first we create our health store
next we create a quantity sample
we can then pass our sample to our
health store using safe object
with completion and wala we have
officially saved data
and health kit
so saving date is great but it's not
really any fine
unless we can ask for it back right
health kit gives you lots of ways
task for data the easiest information to
get
are characteristics at the user because
these don't change over time
we really only care about the current
value so you can just
ask your health store directly
here's an example a bus asking our
health store for the users
date of birth this doesn't work for
everything though
so to ask for the book about data we're
gonna need something
a little more heavy duty this
is work where he's come in queries
provide a structured mechanism
for you to look at health data in a
variety of ways
all queries inherit from HK query
in HK query has a sample type which is
what kind of data
is being queried for they also
have a predicate predicate isn't NS
predicate
that filters which objects are to be
returned by the query
you can create predicates and a couple
different ways
first you can use regular and its
predicate constructors what you may
already be used to
we give you a constant for every key
path that you can use
with predicates this is a really
powerful tool
we wanted to make it easy on you to
create the predicates that are most
commonly used
so we provide some convenience
constructors right punished a query
note that these two methods are going to
create identical predicates
so you can use whichever method you feel
more comfortable with
now let's say that you're working on a
brand new application
this app is for a fancy new health
tracker they can measure the user's
blood sugar
and sink it to their fun your app
already saves all that state and health
kit now you want to create a screen
that will show the user their most
recent blood sugar reading
you can do this with HK sample query
every sample query has a limit this
defines how many
objects were going to be returned by the
query
if you don't wanna limit your results
you can specify HK object query
no limit they also have a sort order
this is an array event assert
descriptors that dictates the order for
which you'll receive your result
here's an example thus creating a sample
query to get our most recent blood sugar
reading
first we create our quality type which
in this case his blood sugar
next we create our sort descriptor
because we want the most recent
we want to order a result and end date:
by just
in descending order when we create our
sample query
we ended it with a sample type blood
sugar
until predicate because we don't want to
filter results
a limit love one because we want the one
most recent
and an array containing the sort
descriptor
we just created
in a result handler because we know
there's only going to be at most one
result we can just ask are ask a result
for the last
object soured pretty well
but you realize that every time a new
reading comes over from your health
tracker
nothing happened will be really great if
every time you received a new reading
the display would just update
all by itself you could create some kind
of pull mechanism to do this
where every 30 seconds or so you checked
with the most recent has
but will be a lot nicer if you could
just be alerted
when things actually change this is the
job
a HK observer query observer queries are
very simple
all they do is watch for changes in the
database
their little bit different than sample
queries in the sense that their
long-running
so you're up to a hand there's going to
be called every time a new object is
saved
or removed from the database
you might notice that in Europe they
hand there there's a completion handler
this is for a future that we won't have
time to go into today
called background livery if you have any
questions about back on delivery
please come by whenever laps
hears us creating an observer query
all we do is tell it that we want all
blood sugar readings
and our up to a hand there will be
called every time a new blood sugar
reading
is saved or removed from the database
now let's say that you're health up the
your out
is partnering with the health provider
what it's supposed to do is take all the
blood sugar readings
that it's created and think im to the
cloud
you could do this using sample query
where every time you query for all the
objects in the database
and figure out which ones you haven't
sent yet probably using the UUID
but this is a lot of work
and it would be a lot nicer if and would
be a waste to pull all the objects from
the database
just to find out that nothing has
actually changed
this is the perfect job for HK anchored
object query
and anchored objects larry has a limit
which again defines how many
results are to be returned by the query
it also
has an anchor the
Watson anchor well behind-the-scenes
every object stored in health care has
its own anchor
in the database your query anchor says
that you want everything after
a certain point so if you're to provide
a query anchor 0 you get back
everything if you're to provide a query
anchor at three
you'd only get back objects for 5 and
sex
so in creating and anchored object query
your anchor should represent the last
piece of data
that you've seen if you haven't seen any
day D at
then you can specify 0 which means you
don't have an anchor
in your call back you'll receive a new
anchor
which you can then use and subsequent
queries
here's an example a bus creating and
anchored objects query
at some point I'm probably during our
initializer
we set our last anchor to be 0
when we create a query we talked we want
all blood sugar readings
that have occurred since our last anchor
and we don't want to limit our results
and in our completion handler we'll get
our results as well as a new anchor
which we can then use your next query
let's see how this would look with some
actual data
let's say our database has three objects
in it since I haven't seen anything yet
will say that my current anchor 0
when I run my query I'll get back
objects one two and three
and my current anchor will now be three
next two objects were added to the
database
when I run another query I'll get back
objects for in five
and my current anchor will now be five
so I've shown you a few different
queries and some situations that are
useful in
but we haven't talked about how to
actually run your queries
this is done using two methods on a
scale health store
execute query and stop query execute
query tells a query to begin running
at any point I'm you can call stop query
which will kill your query and prevent
any call backs that haven't happened yet
you can call stop query is many times as
you want
it doesn't matter but you can only
execute a query
once this is because once a query is
stopped
its call back are invalidated to prevent
retain cycles
remember though that you only need to
stop long-running queries
such is the observer query other queries
no to stop themselves
once they received their national data
now all the queries we've talked about
so far
let you get actual objects from the
database
but oftentimes we don't care about the
individual objects
themselves what we really care about
our statistics on our data
you could use a sample query and iterate
over all your results
summing the quantities together but this
would be
a lot of work and a lot of objects in
memory considering all we really care
about
is the sum to support operations like
this
statistics are first-class citizen and
health kit
statistics are handled by HK statistics
and HK statistics object is an
aggregation
have multiple kinds of statistics such
as some
men max an average
you can ask for statistics across all
data
or only for statistics that came from a
particular source
because we're talking about numerical
analysis statistics are
only valid for quantity types
remember though did not all types are
the same
we care about different statistics
depending on what kind of data
we're looking at we classify types
is either discrete or cumulative
discrete types by things like your
height wat
her blood pressure the kinds of data
where an individual sample
has although the context you need to
make sense if its quantity
the only statistics we care about for
discrete types Armin
max an average if I were to take all of
my way
readings and add them together I
wouldn't get any useful information
whatsoever
cumulative types Arctic are things like
your step count or the number of
calories the print
in contrast to discrete types I really
don't care about an individual sample
when i care about. is an aggregation of
samples over a period of time
for example that I took seven thousand
steps today
so the only statistic we care about on
cumulative types
is some
so every quantity type is classified is
either discrete
or cumulative
in our type identifiers header every
type identifiers
is listed with its aggregation style
if you wanna check incurred though HK
quantity type has an aggregation style
property
that we return either cumulative or
discrete
now back to statistics as you may or may
not know
generating statistics on large amounts
of data and
can be rather expensive because if this
we had you tell us what you want
ahead of time using a bitmask HK
statistics options
average man max and some each have their
own statistics option
these are marked is either discrete
accumulative if you ask a cumulative
type
for discrete statistic we're going to
throw an exception
a little bit less straightforward is
separate by source
this lets you askin its K statistics
object for the statistics that came from
a particular source
the why is this important let's say that
we have two sources
source a and source be
both the sources a writing step data to
health care at the same time
now the say that I want to sum up my
steps
I could take all the samples in the
database and adn together
which would give me 41 which is also
wrong because these sources were saving
data at the same time
in many cases I was actually double
counting
to handle this we let the user-specified
in the health up which sources are most
important to them
for a particular quantity type we then
use this information
to try to figure out what actually
happened
if you don't like armor strategy then
you can always perform your own
by separating by source
now back to your application let's say
that your health tracker just gone
awesome new feature now can count the
user steps
to support this you want to have a new
screen that shows the user
their total steps for the day this is a
some
so you know you want to use statistics
but how do you actually generate
statistics
this is done through its K statistics
query
statistics queries take a bitmask have
statistics options
and return statistics object
so here's an example of us creating
statistics query
first we get are quietly type which in
this case
step count
next we perform some day calculations to
only return objects that happened today
we create our statistics options which
in this case is some
and then when we create our query we
tell we want all steps that happened
today
and we want to take their some and in
our completion handler
will be given in HK statistics object
the week and then asked for it some
quantity
well you feel like a rock star right now
using your UI code from your blood sugar
screening you're able to bust this out
in like five minutes with all that extra
time
you decide it would be really cool if
you could show the user
their daily step count throughout the
week
how do you do this you could execute 7
statistics queries
one for each day and once they all
return
use the results to drive your truck
the sound like a lot of effort though
this is actually the perfect job for HK
statistics collection
from high-level statistics collection is
just a collection
after test subjects it splits timeout
into a series of time intervals and
generate statistics
on each other's time intervals
let's take a look at how this actually
works
miss diagram each have our gray boxes
represents its own HK statistic subject
we call our delta T are interval
components and this isn't an acidic
components object
the reason why we chose to use an estate
components is because when we talk about
health information
and historical way we tend to talk about
it
in days weeks months in years
to do this properly you need to use day
components
if you're curious about day calculations
please see last year's
video solutions to common date and time
challenges
so now let's say that we have an
internal components
have one day the problem is we don't
know if you want your day to be midnight
to midnight
noon to noon are something completely
different
to handle this we have you give us an
anchor date
all the anchored it does is tell you
what the edge up wanna be your time
intervals is
and that's all we need to create a
collection have statistics for you
let's see how this would look with some
actual data
want to get your anchor date and your
interval components we split up
all time in this series time intervals
week and then grouped data into these
different time intervals
and collect statistics on such as ask
for it some
so this is what the statistics
collection is
but how do you actually interact with
the subject
because we don't force you to give us a
start date porn and eight
there's potential and infinite numbers
statistics
the first thing you can do is asked for
an array evolve the populated statistics
populated statistics are the ones where
their time interval
actually had data and
you can ask for the statistics that
occurred on a particular date
what this will do is find out which time
period your date falls into
and give you back the statistics from
that time period
whether or not there is any data
last you can enumerate across all this
test statistics
between two dates this will return both
populated
and non populated statistics objects
sup this seems like it's gonna work
pretty well
all you need to do s best find anchored
80 Sunday at midnight
an internal components have one day
and that's about it so how do you
actually create
statistics collection this is done with
an HK statistics collection query
the steak a bit mask if statistics
options
an anchor day and an internal components
object
and give you back and HK statistics
collection
that easy
now I'm gonna hang things over to CG so
that she can show you how to incorporate
health kit
and your own applications thank you
Justin he everybody good morning
I'm the delay to Tom and I'm one of the
engineers and help get really excited to
be here today to give you this quick
demo for the three things that you will
see in this demo
first you see how you can leverage help
get to retrieve existing information
about the user from head start
not this information might have been
inserted into head start by some other
app
Sechin you'll see how you can read and
write cute own data objects into heads
to Rick
into you see some examples are the
greedy for Justin spoke about
now for the purpose this demo I'm going
to walk you through making a fitness
check it out
the goal this app would be to track in
net energy burnt but a given day
and beer going to define the net energy
burned as the total energy burn my
activity
subjected by the total energy consumed
now with that in mind let's go take a
quick look at the demo
so we know that we're going to be using
health get ready to suit its needs
but before we can do that many the
user's permission and this is the code
that you will try to get the user's
permission
the first you check with your health kit
is supported and the current I was still
life
and this is because some devices such as
the iPad does not support
can't get next you create an instant
offense to it
and then use testers are today the shin
ABA's
to request leave shared access to these
different set
updated I now I have already set up my
device to be on today's but the first
time you done this piece of code
you're going to get this dialogue she
pop up that request permissions from you
now let's look at the app
now since you're dealing with
user-specific energy bring calculations
let's assume that we need some you there
specific statistics if it
for instance the user's each height we
now I fed up day at such that the user
can endure these details
maybe feel much cooler if you can look
at health store thief the values already
exist in
if so does it leave it in this play for
the use of information
so let's go tonight the court but I'd go
to do just that
I'm a quick note before that and not
doing much anything good in this demo
but that a sample code for this absolute
it online and there'll be a much better
day
now to get that uses age we debated
breakbeat is a characteristic phenotype
and help get
and head start has this convenient
synchronous method to directly access
users pretty
let's go ahead and use that method here
and once we have to beat the heat it
simple beat Matt to get the user's
age notice here
that I am passing each back and
completion block
let's run this code in C
dunno eat it does show up and how this
happened because earlier today I use
happened pent up to insert my birthday
up into history now let's look at user
height
in beat next who height read a quantity
be today
in health kit and to get quality samples
out a pen Stewart me today to sample
query
let's go ahead and radar for some pic
reading this convenient method
between give us like the most recent one
in December any given day today
so this is our first sample grading
now I want single moved to the thing
quantity sample
of a given day today and so for that I'm
first going to start
my existing samples in descending order
and then a specified limit of want to
get just the first one out of it
I don't want to filter the does my
predicate is nil
and the be to God that I am interested
in is fastened into this method
now Mendes greeleyville it turns I get
in at the back
and this is a natty of quantity samples
in nike's if they're is invalid quantity
sample existing in history
the new gonna get just one quantities
and the back so what we are going to do
is get the quantity objects associated
with that wanna be found the back
and about that in the completion doc
political and I'd go to do that
to look at the first subject and passes
it on the completion DUP
emitting Barton 20 video clearly please
don't forget to execute the query
ok now let's use this convenient method
to actually get the user's height fill
its first going by that method
just wrote now you think height
is a quite a debate Mitt identify and
height and fly past that in
now integrated don't I get the most
recent quantity
object and has just released talking
about earlier
a quantity object is nothing but a
double value associated with the
particular unit
now I wanna sure my height inches
and so I am gonna specify
its key in it each unit
and months at half height we need to
pass it back to the view controller who
wants it
mcnaught that creatiefste uninstall
wizard on on on on a month
anonymous background cute 3 need to make
sure we switch back to the mean queue
and if that should give us the height
now I have already set up
good to do the exact same for getting
the user three the only difference is
that the identify it here is that for
body mass
and the unit that I'm interested in is
bound
Nolan stern that's good
name it makes the knife okay
okay only 41
so be are interested in getting the net
energy going to be defined as the
daughter energy but make DVD subjected
by the total energy consumed
let's give the user a chance to enter
details about the energy consumed
now I'm already set up this app too sure
a possible if the food items consumed
but really this app doesn't do much is
right now what I wanted to be able to do
is then I select an item I wanna see
that item details and to help Stewart
and then I come back to this means clean
I wanted achieve those details and
display it
let's go in like the court date code to
do that now
I get a quick note so food item is a lot
more damage than just calories
but for the purpose of this to move into
focus on saving just the gallery
information
so I'm going to treat each food item as
a quantity sample and i wanna see the
food items need and calorie information
a theme as MIDI da and calorie
information as the quantity object
associated with that
twenty-something let's cook leader first
quality sample
now the be denied that I'm going to see
if the food sample as
is that updated d-calif and solid
specify that
now the quantity object as we just
mentioned will be the calorie count
and fu
will be key locality unit
and the double value is passed into this
method
and that are going to be object now I'm
just gonna see this food sample with a
good indeed and I'm
and as I mentioned earlier the medical
you down they had the food name
associated with it
noted here that helped get actually
provide
the thin mean strings to be used as key
is in medicaid and
so you just gonna use the food AP and
that's it we have officially created our
first sample
now let's go and see this into the day
to be into head start
and their done of another bf
see these items let's take good effects
these items are then displayed
now we already know what we are going to
use to get quality samples out offense
to it
yep let's try to some degree
the sample type that I'm interested in
is that have time to look at least
because that's what I saved it in a
now in this key if I wanna filtered
samples out and get only both samples
that were inserted infertility
so I have a predicate but the start date
and then indeed
and start be done and it will be start
of 2d and enough to be
now I don't really care about the number
of samples as long as they get all of
them back
and I don't wanna fight them some
ministers find it here
know again been discredited don't
I'm going to get on the quantity samples
back and what I want to do is it really
relevant information from each
wanna b sample mitchen I Keith will be
the food items name
and calorie information and I'm gonna
package that into an anti
so that's what this code does here
notice here that I get back
the calorie information and the calorie
meal
and I put that into the Atty and once I
happy early I'm gonna switch back to the
mean queue and send it back in the
completion
up
as always let's not forget to execute
the query once we have written a grating
let's see whether this works
so I had oatmeal
me that break and banana
so now that we have in dade these
details we can actually go ahead in
computer
a net energy way so didn't define and
energy burn
as the total energy burn subjected by
the total energy consumed
so ideally the daughter here good
would be this duty energy consumed but
what about the total energy burn
Philip as you now that I'm adding this
imaginary fitness tracker device
feared and every time I think my iPhone
with the fitness tracker device
in third active energy bone samples and
different story
so that state court actually get the
total of all these quality samples
now I goodnight a sample grading get all
the quantity samples that I am
interested in and then
iteratively leg over you can compute the
value but
really what I want to do we get is you
the statistically because that's what
this is meant to do
so as always let's have a convenience
method
and then in that a trader for statistics
creating
the quantity type and I'm interested in
will be passed into this method
now again the predicate will be
filtering based on studied nd
because I'm interested only in samples
that are relevant for 2d
and studied in ended up going to be
start have to be an entity
now this is interesting but you know I'm
going to specify cumulated
some because that's the quantity that
I'm interested in
and then discreetly take turns note that
been going to get in each key statistics
object back
and what I want to do is get the
quantity object associated with the
statistics
object back and pass it along
so I do that and let's not forget to
execute the query
not actually get the total energy
consumed with this greedy
silicon dipping means method that we
just chillin
the energy type that I am interested in
is that have died legalities because
that's what I saved it in
and finally when I get the quantity back
I know that i won the unit ask you look
at the unit
as always let's switch back to the main
cue and returned it
now I've already setup go to do the
exact same but active energy bone
samples that were inserted by
my fitness tracker device
the only difference here is that if they
don't teach will now be active energy
buying
let's even it this week
and keep know I should see 255 kennedy
feared
and that Bernanke and now let's see what
they're thinking reaction to actually
get mine and energy when
ended I'm on track with my net energy
burned
and that was a quick demo so we thought
in less than 10 minutes how he managed
to integrate
help get but %uh ap I hope you guys
enjoyed it
for the time being good for this up demo
is already uploaded online
he's come to allowed to do you have any
more questions own already Justin
thanks so much CG as you can see
it's really easy to incorporate health
care in your own applications
next we're gonna talk through some
health kit best practices
so before you can use health care the
first thing you need to do
is let us know that you intend to use it
to support this we've got health kit
right and the capabilities pain
the tax code so that you can manage it
in the same way you use to managing
things
like Game Center or passbook
want you given your apt to health kit
capability
the last thing you need his permission
from the user to access their health
data
but remember health data is really
sensitive
too many of our users we want to
encourage our users to only give out
access to the information that they feel
comfortable sharing
to support this we let users give your
app permission
on a per object type basis
that way if the only thing your
application needs
is step data they don't need to give it
access to what may be more sensitive
kind data we also let them
give your app separate read and write
permissions per object type
and a user might be totally fine with
your application saving data
to health care but might not wanna
reading data that came from other
sources
to request access for set of types you
can use
HK health stores request authorization
status:
request authorization to share types
re types completion this should be
called before you start interacting with
your health store
so the you can ensure that the users
been given a chance to grant your app
access
want to ask for authorization to a new
type
the user's going to be presented with
this authorization sheet
this is a little bit different then the
authorization alert you may be used to
seeing
from other frameworks this a specially
designed so that the user can manage
multiple permissions
for your application at the same time
to give your user the best experience
possible you should request
authorization for all types you intend
to use
at the same time
once you've requested authorization the
next thing you're probably going to want
to do
its check if you've been granted access
in health care we let you see whether
you've been granted sharing
or right access to particular type
but you can't see if you've been granted
read access
this is because for some kind of
information knowing that the user
blocked your app
can be just as private as what the as
knowing the data itself
for example if you a user to block your
out from reading
their blood sugar in my indicate that
their diabetic
and we don't want to leak this
information
you can check your authorization status:
for particular type
using a scale health stores
authorization status: for type
our users are spread all around the
world
to be able to reach all these people
it's really important that your app
supports localization
foundation already has a set event is
for matters
that let you localize things such as
numbers dates
and even by Coun you could use a number
formatter
to localize the quantities value but you
have to localize the unit yourself
to help you localize some kinda the data
that we keep in health care
we've added three brand new for matters
to foundation
and this mass formatter and a slang for
matter and anise anergy formatter
these let you display thing such as
weight energy and distant
in a way that's pertinent to the user's
current locale
let's take a look at how you might use
annis mass for matter
first we create our formatter
and we tell it that is to be used per
person mass
this is pretty important because
depending on your region
you might use a different unit to
measure the weight of a person
then you would to measure the way object
next week creator quantity and gets
double value
in kilograms we then passed this weight
in kilograms
to our formatter and it gives us a
localized string
including the unit string note that our
formatter
explicitly takes its value in kilograms
behind the scenes will convert this
value to the proper unit
this works great if all you're doing is
putting
a value in a label but oftentimes you
need to know what the unit
which unit was actually used to support
this
you can pass and NS mass formatter unit
pointer
to your formatter and it will be filled
with wood every unit was used by the
formatter
so we talked about a lot of stuff today
what I really want you to take away from
this is that health kit
makes it easy for you to store and share
health data
which means you can spend your time
doing what you do best
keeping our users happy and healthy
before you go there's one thing that I
would love for all of you to do
after the session tryout health kit for
yourself
through you can make with it check out
our sample code so you can see some
examples of how to properly use
health care for more information you can
reach out to one of our
awesome evangelists data long David
Harrington
our sample code is already available on
developer
that Apple dot com and we encourage you
to ask questions
honor Apple developer forums
we have one related session which
unfortunately
has already passed you should totally
check it out online
and it on it has some great information
on how Bluetooth devices are integrated
right now health kit thank you and
everybody have a fantastic
WWDC