good morning welcome to what's new in
Cocoa my name with all the other I'm the
director
frameworks at Apple so I gotta pack
agenda today we're going to give you a
high level coverage of the changes
in cocoa and North in Yosemite I'm gonna
get pointers to related sessions and
relevant labs
as well and the topics recovering are
new look
extensions on hand of which are big user
features you saw yesterday
and I we don't talk about them API such
a storyboard a new controllers
API modernization effort we've been
doing of course we don't talk about
swept
and implications on cocoa and Cocoa
Touch API and a number of other topics
as well
and to fight I wanna put this badge on
everything applied
pretty much everything we're talking
about today is new and I or scan your
seventy or in some cases I was 8 as well
okay so with that let's get started with
new look there's very a
components to new look you saw them
yesterday and you probably seen if you
installed your so many on your
machines there's an updated look for
controls there's translucent skin
vibrancy there's new window styles
and there's also a new font in yosemite
let's take a look at updated look for
controls
here is the %ah good old found prep
preferences panel
in a maverick and here's the same panel
in Yosemite so one thing to notice is
that I'm
you know there's a lighter there's
lighter brighter colors
there is a queen and simpler look I'm
not gonna go into the details here we're
gonna do
more of that in some other talks but it
is sort of a wider
pressure look of course another thing to
note of that controls are pretty much
metrics compatible
that's important important thing to note
here's another a comparison this is the
add a new mail account
panel one thing you'll notice of course
is there the default button in maverick
this poll thing
continuously poll thing while the one in
Yosemite is not whole thing
another thing to notice is the focus
ring the one in Yosemite is
a lot cleaner while the one in maverick
is a bit by the they both a rapid
control but your 71 have a cleaner look
that's of course in line with the
overall
overlook of yes seventy now
we have gotten rid of these long-running
animations like that the default button
but we have some subtle animations in in
its place
you noticed the radio button in the
opera operate them
they sorta gently respond York like are
your pictures
just like that you think it's another
some other cases as well such as I check
boxes and search fields
now the good thing about all this
all these updated look for controls
they're all
automatic in your applications I when
your application runs on your seventy
it will pretty much inherit all these
looks and behaviors
up I mean unless you're doing something
very custom using custom artwork once on
your caps will get the assembly look in
fact we do not even sport the Mavericks
look
for applications on your sanity okay let
me talk now about translucent skin
vibrancy
the translucent see as you saw yesterday
castles and see the combination of
transparency and blur
and enable the purse now P of the
desktop or the content that you're
looking at
to come through in your Windows and
very aesthetically pleasing way so let's
look at
places where use I translucent be here
is your
people to stop picture keeping up with
the party window with and desist are the
favorites view
you see that the whole window has a
translucent background here
this is usually not the case in most
cases know once you start looking at
content
the translucency is usually limited to
the sidebar for instance
here in your I'm Nimes sure what's your
favorite app
Xcode mail also had the same for the
treatment in five are you get the
transport translucency in the sidebar
area another use of caps associate
something like
up preview application here I have an
image and I am in school that yet but
once I start to scroll
you'll see that to images gonna start
coming through the toolbar title bar
area
of the window now note that this case is
what we call
in window translucency while the other
cases were behind a window or through
the window translucent see their you're
seeing to the desktop
here we're just seeing through the title
bar the content
of the window to my document you other
case a path to see include
the menu bar I'm sorry to menus
and sheets as well and pop overs as well
have destroyed a treatment so traffic
through Cincy is automatic
in many cases she menus popovers except
rap
source list these are the table view
than outlined views which are configured
to
look like those sidebars will also get a
translucent the automatically in most
cases
and also title bars and toolbars will
get a chance to Cincy
in a number of cases let me talk about
that
whenever you have a window and you have
a ScrollView next to the title bar
like in the case a preview you'll get
Rasmussen C treatment
four-dot title bar area the psych review
does
this is the case first an app like text
that as well
now in other cases where you wanna you
more sophisticated things are not
getting translucent the automatically
for your title bar
you can use this new I window style
mouth called NS
full-size content you window mask
in addition we have I'd property such as
title visibility entitled appears
transparent and this window
and I will have other talks were going
to depth about these
but these new out features allow you to
do
highly customized windows with
translucent see an example
is the messages window burns's the
messages window
has the circus but look with the
commentary on the right
and that the five are on that left for
your for the messages
and if you %uh put this on top of art
desktop here you'll see that there is
through window translucent see on the
left side in window travel some fee for
the Mets just content
on your right side the good news is we
have API
for you to do this sort of thing in your
own applications as well where
appropriate
so you can do substantive design like
this
know byron see goes very much hand in
hand with translucency
now translucent in general is of course
averaging
the foreground and background but as it
blurs the background
and sometimes this could result in
reduce contrast
and it could even result reduce overall
impact of
what you're trying to show the user I'm
now Byron C
what privacy does that help all the
elements out
by a blending in fancy ways for instance
by using colored Dodge color burn or
variants of such blending modes
let me show you an example hear what I
mean here is
a I'm no love you by Brent you which
include some tech
and image and there now being treated
vibrancy
not plywood to remove vibrancy from this
you get this through slightly a know
what punch
to that it's more more gray ash it's not
as impactful 11 at the vibrancy back in
it's really adding not punch that allows
the users content to come through and
separated from the background and be
presented to the user
so this is vibrancy now vibrancy is
automatic in context
in most cases are applying translucency
and it's for controls and other and this
abuse where appropriate but not
appropriate for all cases now
example of that in a few seconds
now to enable vibrancy and also
translucency explicitly in your
applications
we have a new view called an official
affect you
you created you I have you specify what
kind of translucent
you want either in window or behind
window and you specify what kinda
vibrant appearance you want you have
choice of dark or light
and then you populate it with by been
capable controls
and you can recognize such controls
because they return yes from this new
property called allows vibrancy
and if I mentioned earlier some controls
offer
vibrancy they I'll Bay up into vibrancy
at appropriate times let me give an
example of that
here's a window with two image use in it
on the left we have an ImageView with a
template image
and on the right we have an ImageView
with just the regular image
now this is on the regular no
translucent the window I'm gonna put
this on Doc vibrancy
and as you saw the the viewed imagery on
the left is applying the vibrancy
and out treating the template image to
give it the appropriate look on papa doc
byron back Ron
wild elephant image remains put not
affected at all
similarly fights which like vibrancy
again you're getting that
by twenty applied to the template image
wild elephant image against a spot that
a No ImageView
is dynamically deciding between being by
but not depending on its content
we made some changes mouth color we've
updated existing system colors
to be a consistent with of course the
overall look of your seventy
and we also made it so that some and the
scholars have appearance
specific very so what that means is
I below you an example here is some text
use
drawing a drawn with the system color
and hear the same text drawn
on a dark fiber surface these are both
using a new system color we've added
called secondary
label color and you'll know that note
that in the dark fiber in case the Texas
actually appearing
white so to fairly different color so
you need to you know if you
ever assuming I'm the color stay put
through the
through like I'm a nap or in different
contexts notes good
stop the sumptin and just use and that
scholars as is without taking them apart
we have a new pop and you think that
that
the new park as hell but Cano yeah it's
been optimized for almost ten
with metrics similar to loose the
grounding
now you should obtain the spot with
methods such as a system pop-up size
which is of course what happened by
default when you drive elements out and
Xcode Interface Builder
and um now would for compatibility
if you're up for existing binary
applications are already out there that
applications which are linked against
the 10 not nine SPK
or and earlier we do two things one
if we see explicit references to lose
the ground they know you I element
we assume that you really meant have a
deacon or your
and we don't the replacement in addition
if we find out
the text clips or wraps because it's too
wide for the area it has
will compress it so it its debts so that
of course
insurers compatible p for existing
applications
now note that we do not do this once
your application is reeling
3 built against the 10 not 10 STK there
we want you to take a look at your apt
and correct any places where there may
be problems
I'm now for secure funding up help your
controls are too tight and not fitting
night like to recommend you actually
look at or layout as a way to
not only fix this problem but also make
your application
a more forward-looking and more local
either we look like
and so on laughing on the talk about
here in the section this in a segmented
control we have a new style of segmented
control
segment style separated it allows you to
do things like the backboard but then
you see here in Safari
it's also visible in a few other apt as
well I just a new style but did not
represent the back forward buttons and
other similar kind abuses that
you can switch to we have to relate to
sessions for the new-look
one this afternoon that up in your
adapting your apt to the new book
a of yosemite and another
another one tomorrow which is a more
advanced talk where you can learn about
how to
used by been seeing more subs it ways
and create Windows
like that messages ap you saw okay so
now let me talk a bit about extensions
again extension to the future I you saw
yesterday
extensions provide accessed your app's
functionality and content
in other APs for those of you familiar
with the Services menu from
earlier or Stanley says so it's all
about the Services menu
start over spiritual precursor to the
speaker it's a much more limited scope
version up two extensions feature
extensions run in a separate process
from the app in which there been invoked
which of course means there's
security performance and stability
benefits
and extensions are delivered with ap as
this think bundles within
the application so as you ship a nap on
the App Store or
wherever you may ship it you may bundled
extensions inside of it end the users
can enable those extensions if they
find them useful not an extension
through application
in Xcode you would go ahead and specify
that you want a new target within your
application project
and then on North can you have choice of
four extensions
action extensions are like extensions
you saw yesterday
the markup extension they work with and
this excuse and web use
a and a the translate
extension use on afternoon is out or
maybe the morning after which
was also another example of that finder
think extensions let you customize
finders drawing in a safe manner
share extensions allow you to extend the
share menu
and today extensions August augment to
today view
in the Notification Center point since
like reminders and you saw examples of
this
yesterday not to use extension their
three new API three new classes
let me just show you how you would use
these in your extension
inside after extension you have a
principal class
with something you typically specify and
tell us
for you I base extension it would be a
subclass of in SU controller are you I
view controller
the principal class has appointed
extension contact
which is basically the central point for
that extensions data
and an extension context has an array of
another extension
items where he cannot extension item
represent
8 data that the user one operate on
points in the case of the markup
extension the image that the user wants
to edit
would be represented by hand extension
item
internet each and its extension item
points array of item providers
item providers are basically what makes
the data
for that extension item available there
might be one
there might be more and extension can
choose which provided
once use it's pretty straightforward you
these API
inside after extension to get the
derailed items
you would just say extension context
that input items
and then you know you work on them are
you like to use our work on them as in
the case of
mark-up when you're done you want to
return to results
you put them in an array or maybe that's
an array of one of course if there's
only one result
may call this a PI complete requests
returning items completion handler
now but turns out the user canceled the
operation
or there was an error you can call the
other API cancel request
with are so it's pretty straightforward
yep two sessions for extensions
want this afternoon creating extensions
part 1
and another one tomorrow morning both
talk about hand-off
again feature you saw yesterday at the
keynote
hand-off enables users to seamlessly
transition activities between their
devices
and there is a simple bass API here
called and that
user activity and their related API than
enough application in this document and
thats responder
and also in there you like it
counterparts as well that you know the
cross-platform
feature in the future activity
encapsulate
hand of information about a single user
activity
so you create one I would in it with it
activity type
you specify is sir I don't fire with for
the activity user might be doing whether
it's browsing the web page playing a
game
editing a document whatever and then you
go ahead and use at various information
a that would enable recreating a
activity another device
as you can see here maybe the level the
location the score that you're in the
game
and even going in for a title which is
usable title for that activity
and then at appropriate times you make
that current
or you tell it's no longer current in
the system apparently
system looks at what activities current
and make available to other nearby
devices as appropriate we just need to
worry about telling us
whence current in months not current
look pretty straightforward
enough application we have several API's
the first one here
indicates few that the user has
indicated an interest in moving activity
to your device
and you can return yet if you out are
handling it or you can read
return 0 and let the system handle it
the next API application continues her
activity
actually gives you then this user
activity which has the data from which
you can recreate the activity
not you're using and this document
there's easy hand of sport bike lock
documents you
really just have to do one thing and
that is at the ski
here in for that P left for your
document type: indicating that you are
sporting hand-off for this document
you specify a unique type i dont fire as
you can see her calm but Apple not
accept that
editing not gonna do something more
sophisticated
for instance specified selection or a
some other
viewing parameters with that hand of I'm
information
you have a handle to the user activity
of a fan of document that you can
that the parameters in next time to talk
about storyboards and U controller
switches
set up new API for adding two of us 10
now if you
done I with development you're very
likely familiar with
concept of storyboard storyboard the
visual representation of the user
interface
of your application so it's giving you a
higher level
you of your user interface with higher
level than
creating individual names and may be
sending party connections together
I'm and if you wanna just create a
storyboard applications fairly
straightforward in Xcode as you're
creating your new app you just go check
the checkbox
couldn't be simpler at and will give you
a default template that you can
modify from there now storyboard specify
different parts of your UI
as different scenes and then you would
use segways to connect or transition
between
these storyboards between the thin
their two classes and a storyboard and
storyboard segue these are
very are parallel to their UI kit
counterparts
we also have a new protocol segue
performing
just collect the Segway performing
methods because on our
can we have two classes that respond to
these methods view controller
and window controller as well so they
both respond to these I think what
performing that that's
in addition these two classes also
provide access to the storyboard be a
a property so you can get find out the
storyboard that they came from that they
were created from
now we have two new view controllers as
well that of course
help you create better storyboards have
your controller and
with your controller and day they
no in spirit there similar to ours
counterpart there's a few differences
let me tell you how these work
so you have a cab your controller the
tablet controller has an array of
an effort have you items now you might
be familiar with Anna have you item
the class we had for a long time we
augment just a bit
to work with you controllers each tab
you I don't
intern has a new property view
controller and that might
point to a view controller in the case
of a cab view controller setup like this
that's pretty straightforward let me
show you how you create one of these are
structures
there are two ways to do it to add a
trial controller to a tabbed view
controller
one where you could do it is you just
first create item
enough have you I don't have you I then
the few controller
you go through that and that creates so
that creates that
a relationship there you can go ahead
and set their
properties on the item
point since its label and whatever else
you want and then you go ahead and add
the item
to the view controller with at have the
item so this is one way to do it
another way to do it it simply take the
trial view controller
this guy here and added to the tablet
controller directly without the child
new controller which is the generic API
we expose an issue controller
this will automatically create the tab
you item for you and inserted in there
so this is the
it through the approach you on the use
if you want to deal with the item at all
but if you do wanna said properties on
the item later
you can still get the item corresponding
to that child view controller
and then you can set the properties just
like he did in the other case
now let's look at with your controller
and no surprise that
turns out to be very parallel ass but
the controller has an area
but you items which point to their view
controllers to create it you do the item
you're added are you create
at the child you controller got it ok
mary Fallin now we have some methods
from you control a presentation
if you wanna do your own manual
presentation rather than going through
segways
I you can present two controllers sheep
you can Controller
you can present it as a model window or
the popover you can also of course
dismiss you controllers
you can transitions between your
controllers with this method here
options give you the trend to how you
wanna transition
a one-goal tip their options let you go
I'm
flied left or right you can also choose
to slide
forward or backward which is a much more
international Saudi way of doing it
because an art
at the right to left language it will go
the a
go the other way which is appropriate
for that for the users
you why we also have methods which will
be familiar
to you from my OS method that let you
see i
for
thank I got to talk about this first I
gotta say
2008 Buell appear and then the like and
also met to find out when my outlook
you're so pretty straightforward stuff
and a good addition to the class
I one more thing about you controller is
that it's now automatically added
into the responder chaim car there you
go
I have and again let me just show a
picture and then trying to read those
two bollocks here's your view
here's a responder chain you have your
parent use all the way up to the windows
you control are you up child abuse
pointing
at the view and view controller with
sorta hang around in the side
you know not part of that whole group
there on out part of that group
not that we tried doing this for all out
and we ran into responder chain cycle
not a good idea so this happens that
this changes affect the only perhaps
building if the 1010 SPK
let me now talk a about
something a little different API
modernization
now they're been many a bath in
objective-c or in recent years
a for instance at property that's been
around for a while now
instance type enough to text with
underlying types
NS require super and a new one because
added and after the gate and a slider
that lets you identified as need
initializer
and then 1010 and I was a testy case we
made a concerted
effort to adopt these and a lot more are
PPI
and why are we doing this well-being
allow
up to state the API's more precisely
more correctly
and that of course has many benefits
API's are now more self documenting you
don't have to go to the documentation
that much it's much clearer right there
in the other file one API does
it allowed API to be more consistent you
don't ever ask the question now why is
this a property in this other thing that
looks very much like it
not a property it allow pics go to be
more helpful
you now get much better context since
the completion from some cases
it allows the composite enable the
compiler to
our Warren and a it did detect and
warned about potential bugs and this is
really a big win I mean it will really
find some errors
and out last but not least that allows
better exposure or API
and swept a script for instance has a
stricter definition
for the up property is and by declaring
the properties experts will be in
objective-c we allowed them to be
exposed
properly and sweat as well
now one a consequence of all this is
that as you build your applications
against the new st. case you may see new
warnings and errors in your bill
please pay attention to them because
some of them might actually be potential
a real bugs lurking around in your code
K I wanna just talk a bit about one of
these areas here and that's the at
property change:
now we converted many accessors many
getter setter pairs and getters not if
the ice to at property
and obvious ones for instance if you
look at as control the target property
in object Valley property are now
real property you must at the target
property is weak I'm gonna talk about
that in a second
but we also conducted what are computed
properties or possibly Computer
Properties
at property fourth integer value in
string value enough
control might be computed of object
value property but we don't want to
expose that
implementation detail in our API so we
make them all into poverty
no you don't care as the API consumer
another thing we commend the property is
something like this corruption which is
obvious the computer
every kind called it's going to generate
the description but that's also a good
property we believe and we made it into
a proper
so use property for anything up about
the value our state on object or its
relationship to other objects
so then you might be wondering what is
not a property
well okay not every method which can be
expressed as a property should be
not every method but looks like a
property should be not sometimes but
looks like a duck
it's not a doc the canonical example is
the retain method you know the good ol
became method for those of you still
remember what that is
I'll it returns a value it takes no
arguments looks like a getter
but it's not a doc neither on a property
either so what are our some example
of bad can it with her back and it's for
a property
so methods which do things such as load
part and particle
these might return like apart state they
might turn a result they might turn a
bully and
and they might pick no arguments but
they're not properties you can usually
recognize these car they have a burr
prefix
on the name generators like in it not
that cocky about that some of these also
at the first rule of course or object
enumerator these guys
are returning your result every time
they're not returning
values that I results that are I'd
important meaning the same every time so
they're not good candidates for
properties
another category is method which change
state such as next object
not a good another attended for part B
as well
we have to make sure the methods also
swim like a duck and quacks like a duck
before you make up the property
not earlier you saw week property on
enough on the target
probably be I'm we use the rowing week
for target now
that the cleared with the week actually
on the target now to see what effect the
only an application to link against the
1010 STK
up preview for other applications that
thing binaries
targets still have the a fine behavior
now we're also using week for delegates
and data sources
moving forward new API's front of your
the new API we add
this relief however we're not changing
the existing delegate and datasource
methods
to use we properties there's too many
compatible considerations for that one
now as I said we've done these in our
API's but you can also modernize your
code as well
if you'd like into good idea because it
might help you find bugs in your code
and you get the benefit type shown
the convert the modern objective-c them
pack mod a
refactoring tool which is actually next
go today has been augmented
to do so the to do thought these changes
as well
ICANN fee outcome of them in the a panel
you get
and you can choose which ones you and do
and go ahead and do them now one word of
warning though
I'm this tool doesn't do all the changes
it also
may not get everything right point that
might not get the exact
type of property right so you really
need to review the
the changes offered up by the school and
I
accept them or tweet them as needed
the next I'm not talk about swept now
they're lot of questions about swept
so I'm not gonna go into any language
details or anything else about try to
teach you certain
anything like that so I'm I hope you'll
be able to go to go sessions and enjoy
does
I'm said I'm just gonna talk to
basically about the API attractions
within the context of cocoa and Cocoa
Touch
Swift is the new language for cocoa and
provide seamless interoperability with
the cocoa API's and of course a
objective-c code
now as you know API is a API design is
a near and dear to our hearts I
given a few AP I'd find talking about so
we think deeply about
API consideration
and existing API guidelines we have in
cocoa for objective-c
pretty much applied uswest as well and
with just one exception but I'll talk
about later dinette methods
there's really no changes in API as
their exposed
in swept now this doesn't mean of course
as we
out start adopting more apps which
features in our API
more API's forward not be taking
advantage of something new and exciting
features apps with objective-c does not
offer
so we're gonna be doing up over time of
course
so just let me just show you how some
cocoa AP I've come across in sweat
first properties there's a pretty
obvious one
at the and that's wrecked a at the frame
propagandist you typed as an abstract
be straightforward here's how it looks
like in sweat
now as I'm showing the fight if you have
a comp is a lot which lines objective-c
which line the swift just look for the
lack of semicolon
that identified the sweat line there's
another one
storyboard property of of an issue
controller
here's what looks like in swept note the
exclamation mark there on the storyboard
which indicates that the property of
this could be no
and to get which indicate that this is a
read-only property
and here's one more case the sub use
property of %uh
an SRA which is of course declared as an
SRA in objective-c
which implicitly means an SRA of ID
it comes across the swift as an array of
any object for any object is the
counterpart I D not just want to refine
what I'm talking about as we move
forward
you wanna declared API better because we
this is really an area and this
use of course right now this is not
coming through the API
here but its refinement but we'd like to
do here and other places and more
importantly
as you define your own API since work
within your programs you take advantage
of sweat
unique features to express your program
better
now let me show you some mapping of
methods point method with no arguments
there's a simple case display if needed
here's what looks like an
swept and here's what the call looks
like in swept
display need it with open poster and at
the end to indicate that this is a
method called pretty straightforward
there's a method with one argument
and at some you method
here's what it looks like in sweat now
nope this a view here
and one thing to note is that this a
view colon is not a label
the name of this method does add sup you
this a view is simply that name of the
variable
the name of the local variable for that
argument existing objective-c Heather
making its way into the swift interface
here so really there method signature of
this method is at sub you and it takes
an in-depth
you calling something like this is
again also pretty straightforward at sup
you and and your arguments right there
now let's look at the are case with
multiple arguments
there's a new method performs take what
identifiers that take a Segway ID and a
Fender
the first part name goes outside the car
and and then any
labels for second and further arguments
go inside the parent like this
not that the Segway ID is again the
variable name for the local argument
that up goes there and the fender goes
right there with the fender sis
that label and argument name are the
same a swift collapse
them for you into one it doesn't repeat
the word sender so note that in this
case the Segway ideas not
part of than it's on the label it's not
part of the name of the method but the
fender is
so really the method signature for this
is performed segment I don't fire
extreme argument and then senator Colin
twitches and in the object argument
an indication of this is pretty
straightforward as you can see here
so Coco API so many experts that label
on the first argument
we saw that with the I'm with their
example from the previous slide
here's another example points this is
how you call a delegate methods but you
can collapse up to you
it works very well the first part of the
name includes the
the type of the first argument and other
labels described other arguments
here's another example with three
argument that resource value values the
first argument and four key and error
explicit labels
on the subsequent arguments this results
in natural method mean for their easy to
read
easy to speak and easy to really crap as
redeveloping API
now you might be thinking when to use
when should you consider labels on the
first time in because swift will
RR you to put labels on the first
argument methodName it's just not the
default behavior
up one cases where argument technique we
weighed
subpart so the whole funds but the other
method called moved to XY
in swept it would come across like this
and may be worth a look so good
wide extruded what somewhat differently
than why
you might consider method names like
this
and is actually the kind of structure
you will see increased and free-form
functions in sweat
where you have the ability to put labels
on argument
but it's better in these cases the store
to think about if these are all
equally weights apart for the whole is
there some combo type that represents
them
force in this case the CG point on and
this point there are many other benefits
to using a combo type you're not
shopping all the arguments all over the
place
also a using a comp combined single type
is a more promising approach the API
guidance pathfinder arguments one by one
you're specifying this one
whole thing to represent them and you
know we have many other types to
represent combine types an estate in a
state components
I'm you I collar and a scholar and a
strange CD rack we have a new FB and
vector three types represent
points and 3d space and so on so now you
such types where appropriate and the
you get rid of this problem now earlier
I mentioned it methods
it methods I are an exception to the
label thing it's another case
that the to the rule with the about the
first argument here than it with frame
in objective-c here's how it comes
across
in threat again frame here
is a label and the way you call this
is in a few throw the constructor syntax
initializer syntax with the frame
argument at the label
in this case save now we see in the
sense of the code you read and
and flight yesterday
and there's the fear the frame label now
communis constructors
I'm as you know in objective-c we've had
initializer Zenit methods
we also have what we call these
constructor method like this one and a
scholar
color but pattern image and these were
just another way to say that method
except you don't have to call
out lock and the communion affect
stripped
recognize these patterns it in fact it
I'm it reflects that as an initializer
method just like this so swift
recognizes that this method is really in
it
with a pattern image argument so this
actually comes across in sweat
just like initializer does will actually
great because it simplifies
that dichotomy between companies
constructors and magnet methods
I let me talk about one more thing about
API I'm
induct in MI two types because this one
is really really pretty cool
here's a new I you know we've added
recently a few releases ago
might come format account style note
that it's got four values but it's so
hard to figure out
what's different about those for now
they are these not long words which are
night in this trip there but
it sorta like what's going on there
here's what this looks like and sweat
it's really like breath of fresh air
like while you know if I'll
memory death more by Andrea really cool
and you think is really pretty neat to
hear that
you know I am up to call it you might
say and its by come from other counts
style
not file however in context where the
argument type is known
you really just after you stop file and
you know I can fit that
bulletin to one line and Val improve our
slides moving forward
its people that
thanks
so let's talk about gesture recognizers
which is a known you a prob added
in and again a few gesture recognizers
on IRC this is Artus will feel familiar
to you
gesture recognizers allow you to
eliminate large chunks of code
by doing there mouse tracking for you
and just generating an action at the end
for the appropriate texture
it also i helped disintegrate between
various types of quicksand drags it
might sometimes be hard to figure out
there's a new class gesture recognizer
it's got five apartment and you can also
create your own subclasses because we
provide API that specifically
designed for supply thing that gesture
recognizer
there's gonna be more about gesture
recognizers at the storyboards and
controllers talk which is
this afternoon at 4:30 now if you want
to deal with events yourself
ordeal with other kinds of events other
than mouse events there's a block-based
event tracking API this also helps
eliminate a lot of code by taking over
that
new that you might are often have to
ride this a
whips let me show you that I think there
you go so this
I'm to lobby the path the math
governmental interest in a time out and
there's a block up
called ended the tracking will continue
until your
Telep stop or the timeout timeout with
the key
in
we have some new accessibility API the
new API's are
simpler their express tax bill p-values
exploit the values for various Rylance
and you I i'm
properties are expressed directly as
property there's no need to subclass
in bogus umbria some review the old API
and I bear bear a compile-time warnings
as well because they're now
actual property is being used here let
me give you an example
before you had this acceptable catchment
value method which you had to override
any other theories if statements to deal
with it
now you can either just going to
override acceptable P label method
fairly straightforward I can actually
affect the property as well if you're
not supply from there
apart from that class for other reasons
so know much cleaner
much cleaner approach let me talk a bit
about power and
count on my power the kind of power that
comes out of a wall clock it but
even that kinda even with that kind of
power comes great responsibility
because you need to use it wisely new
API we've added across the system
in a number of class and cocoa is this
concept of quality of service
it finance operation at operation Q&A
thread and so on
this allows indicating the nature and
importance of the work
you're doing in lets us to manage
resources
between your processing across processes
are possible
let me talk about what the values of
this quality of service property
are I'll just go through use cases for
it the first one user interactive is an
interactive session with the user
such as a drawing program or maybe
scrolling and human email message you
really want 60 frames per second there
for the user and up that represents that
kinda work the next hour later here
user initiated is like when the user
clicks email message they want to appear
there very quickly but maybe don't have
the same 60 pips continuous behavior
all these wanna get no whatever is
possible to get that to happen as
quickly as possible
you to a PR quality of services
something like periodic male patch these
are expected to happen expected to
happen fast on a regular basis
but you know can be off by a few seconds
if the system is busy with other things
we have a background quality of service
which is like indexing
which needs to happen but could be
delayed if they're more important things
happening
and then the default which allows the
quality of service
be inferred from other operations are
going on sometimes you might have a
dependent operation that will dictate
what the resulting what the resulting
quality of service here
is we also have a new API nuke what's
called a nice background activity
scheduler this is basically a coke a
little interface XPC activity API
mythological schedule maintenance or
background
kinda path for instance periodic picking
up mail or maybe I
indexing and so on you can provide again
quality of service that you want on this
this operation we have a number of talks
about power
here's pointers to to a bomb ones
tomorrow morning riding energy efficient
code part 1
there's also a part 2 as well that can
go to after this one if you want
and powerful from for diagnostics what's
new in GCB annex PC and thats Thursday
afternoon at cue
I'll let me talk a
to you a bit about in a string we have a
new API
in a string encoding detector this is to
allow
detecting encodings of random back to
bite
which come from who knows where
who knows where they've been but you
need to show it to the user and
typically we r encodings up there some
bad characters in there are other bad be
generated or corrupt along the way it
becomes pretty hard to make heads or
tails out and that's what the PPI tries
to do
you have number options a among the
options are debited specify which in
coatings to include
consider for sure which including to
exclude taking give hand
to make the operation more focused you
can
tell us whether you want lofty
conversion or not if
including conversion is not possible
without loss
well just do it anyway and maybe some
characters are lost and finally
not finally this is just another option
can provide a language came to which
allows day including conversion
to again focus more that knows what
language that encoding is intended to be
in
we have to you small new API's contained
in string in Lok life cases contain
string
might be thinking you mean though these
right there well they were you know you
could use range of string
but after some years we decided you know
even though these are just one
whiners even
thank you even though these are
one-liners and you know that's right to
append the API
sensibility of why create a one-line
communion they're really good
for discover bill T you know campaign
string at the lawn or this Carlton
range of strings up here we have them
okay
the one other thing on the talking about
that this might impact your abscess
tagged pointer strings
what we do here is we take a hole in a
string object and we
stop it into the base pointer and
something roller dealing with some
objects like enough numbers and the
state and now we're doing a banana
strings as well
let me give you a visual guide of how
this works here you're creating a utf8
string
typically you have your object pointer
base pointer which is
the a pointer and that in turn points to
an object which contains the is up plus
some bookkeeping information and then
the bites of the string
so just a call that and we shove it just
like that
into the base pointer and you saw how
that works and
no we don't need for the pointer anymore
so being a real point you're so now in
that 64 bits we have
the bolstering up with along with some
it but keeping information
now turns out we can do this for about
25 to 40 40 percent of your strings in
some applications
there are some things to watch for
there's no is a pointer
now you aren't supposed to be acting as
a pointer but if you were you will
really crash right now
in their different performance
characteristics some operations get much
faster and some get
low-floor and they're better out of
bounds checking
we've make sure that these can do much
better outta bounds checking we try to
get outta bounds checking but there are
some cases where the math and actually
does a better job
since all of these three are potential
compatibility concerns
we actually make it so that this changes
enabled for 1010 link
ap or later but not earlier aP's and of
course only 46 for the haps
cuz trying to shovel them to a 3-pointer
it was not fun
let me talk a bit about for matters and
here we have I
but when you format your classes in this
format a classis
the first three are fairly
straightforward mas por matter
energy for matter and length for matter
we also have a date in trouble for
matter that we should take two dates and
show you that a
thank you and a date components for
matter which Walden
show you a duration for three hours 25
an Arby's have some various
customization options for slot
last one could be customized say know
about 10 minutes remaining
and now note that these are for
formatting only not for parsing
so it's for output of beta
in we have a form and context
property on all are and as for matters
and here's what looks like and I'll DEF
explain to you what some of these are
for what form and context does that tell
the formatter where the result of the
formatting
is intended to be used and that allows
it to give a different result
where possible went with if your arm
formatting date in French
beginning of a sentence would look like
this June with a capital J
while the middle of a sentence would use
a Little J now this dynamic here one is
pretty cool
because what it does is depending on
about the result is used
in the context of in a string formatting
depending on whether to use at the
beginning of a sentence middle of a
sentence or
found along it will use one of the other
three options to do the right thing
such downs usually the one you want to
use on the you definitely know whatever
the result is going
there the internationalization talked
this morning if you missed it
you can't action on video of course let
me talk a bit about
I cloud and you heard about I card
yesterday of course
we have new API the clock at API with
the new framework for managing structure
they don't i cloud
in for sharing such data between users
as well
and clout it was also as an
implementation detail the back
and the for I clarke document storage as
well
I'm not gonna talk about pocket anymore
other than just telling you there too
great sessions you can go to this
afternoon and Thursday afternoon
now iPod document storage as you know i
ka documents or just something we've had
for a while and this document and you I
document provides support for it
so having you back and in the form of
cloud kid
and we also another feature a document
versions are now available
on I clout in addition you heard about I
call drive yesterday where
all applications can now read and write
files from
I clout thanks to die Cloud Drive as
well
now in the moving to the new back and
and taking advantages up some of these
other changes some of the
way we work but I car documents has
changed
now course abusing us document in you I
document
perhaps you don't have to worry about
these perhaps you do
handling of noun downloaded files has
changed previously there'd be a file
with the same name as the Nano the
document
and we just fell in overtime now such
files are tracked with invisible filed
with different names
if you're using AP of such as Medicare
Quarrymen today the item pile
coordinator you're probably in good
shape and you probably won't have to
worry about this
but you're a new meeting I called
contain yourself
you need to I'm ignore hidden or
unrecognized files
but better yet just switch to one of
these other API if you can
higher level the better we'll talk some
APIs URL
that allow you to get meta data for
possibly
undone loud and downloaded element and
this is like get promised item resource
value for thier
there are few other method like this as
well
I just a quick job update on core data
we have a number of new API's in core
data and that's backed up data quest
a lousy new batch updates and at
actually pretty cool and on
you know small memory striations that's
what you can do a lot of updates
efficiently
and efficient inspector crest is a new
class for doing a few
inspecting it provides a nice progress
support which allows you to
I'm monitor progress and also in fact
cancelled operation as well
and finally of course it's worth
mentioning that the new back and fry
clout
is I is also up underneath core data as
well
so there's infrastructure improvements
we do have a related session what's new
in court it up Thursday morning
I'll or layout you have some we've been
improving our way out all along are
allowed in
remains a very important I'm a that's
all pnr frameworks both
I'm on Iowa and North Penn we have some
you APIC I'm just can't talk about it
poom these arm allow you to activate and
a flat-out constraints directly as you
might know a way out constrain has
pointed to the views that its
um the defining a relationship or
surrounded and talking to their
views you cannot talk layout constraints
directly to activate and deactivate them
which is a much Queen our model so what
this means is that these three methods
here at
the two methods put the property replace
these for existing methods effectively
NFL is on its way to form a deprecation
I think we've been saying this for a few
years now
a I'm it Phillips
I so some enough LAPI have been promoted
to their corresponding control for
classes
and so you should use the controls where
possible
no don't use self control now have the
API's hopefully and you can refer to
them
and i felt basic cable you has been
deprecated use the view-based
table view that also allows you to get
to my new the new features will be in
showing you with new look and so on much
more
you going enough metric space and this
browser is deprecated use the item based
on this browser API's
and its major convulsants way out since
its so Anna cell-based
I'm 1 one of the most common uses
brightness matrixes was of course that
radio button behavior very quick one in
all the others turned off
now sibling radio buttons with the same
action will now operate as a group
so this is a way to get at matrix
functionality without using make
okay I'm gonna go quickly threw out some
other news
stall you can slowed us down when you
watch the video Q&A catch more about it
I am sign up table %um out my music and
creepy statically now if you have a pic
stable you would like five rows and
don't do anything else you don't wanna
provide data source you can do that now
there's a way to do it
and if the mitchell out in space by
passing Reseda reciting behaviors you
can specify cap insert
you can I'm also specify resizing out
and you can also
you such enough images as math for
additional affect you fun
forget and as bitmap image wrapped
allied
specify I'm Indian this and other bitmap
format so you can actually sport
BGR a data friends and
if you're into that sort of thing and
after catalogs
have in Xcode now sport more of formats
like JPG images
and up yeltsin also are you could just
fly thing and the use of course the
estimates captain said API to expose
that flight information
you can do later prospects affect the
tributes ring
popovers now how much is your way to
detach you don't have to worry about
paying the rent or whatever
just responses delegate method combo box
datepicker pop up button search your
pants but you know all too
right to left properly and will let and
you might as the user might expect
and so you don't have to worry about
no bloating have a new API to do custom
set up in your view subclass
for live use sport and Interface Builder
to just
to use in context Interface Builder if
you wanna do something custom
while for debugging purposes OpenGL
context you can now carry some property
so you don't have to go down to the CDL
context
file coordinator has a methods for a
sickness waiting
so rather than having to all these
methods on your own background cues you
let the file coordinator create and
manage the queues for you
so much better way to do this and its
workspace have methods
as your opening your alls you can now
specify exactly which
ap you want to be used
NS Euro also have a lot of new API's one
for instance while I it's result Ilyas
file
with this you I'll buy you something
else alias file
if you are okay and we have our last few
and this process info has methods to get
the operating system version and can be
operating system
version comparisons a few months and and
a fix PC Connection of sport enough
progress part
across processes which actually is a
pretty cool feature as well
okay so no more pictures of food cuz
we're done
a here are the things we talked about
many exciting features some of these are
free from not
now as you go down to lunch I expect you
to try to adopt these in your
application see how it's working and
come find us at the lab doesn't work
I'm and heroes information what with the
contact Jake barons
is sitting right there is a pretty great
guy and OneNote our release notes
for yosemite are not yet available we
hope to make available very soon
and the related sessions are shown you
most of these what you meant race
builder and show you that before thats
my afternoon
and with that thank you very much