hello
I'm Ian Baird I was frameworks engineer
and today I'm here to tell you about
creating extensions
for Iowa's and OS 10 gonna lay out a
quick agenda for today's stock
first we're going to talk about
extensions an extension points
then I'm going to invite my colleague
Matt Campbell
from the Notification Center team to the
stage to tell you more
and show you more about creating one of
the hottest new tickets at BBC 14
today extensions
and then following on from that we're
going to invite
our colleague I forton onto the stage
to tell you more about how to create
share extensions
like the one you saw in the keynote with
Pinterest
moving on
water extensions well extensions
are almost like it's a way for you
to extend the system and other
applications
it's almost like more surface area for
you to be able to apply
bits and pieces have your app as you can
see here
we have a screenshot at the Apple
homepage on an iPad
showing the new activity view controller
you'll notice a lot of familiar faces a
lot of familiar icons
in that activity view controller you can
see messages male
and we have a new one the butterfly
and butterflies sharing extension you
can see it at home
right there with its brother in right in
the midst
at the sharing extensions and we also
support sharing extensions on LSN
in see we have the butterfly sherry
extension on Yosemite
we support Notification Center
extensions
also known as today extensions and as
you can see
notification extensions are really good
forgiving you
at a glance information something where
you just wanna pull your phone
out your pocket take a quick look checks
in sports scores
may be traffic conditions the weather
and put it back in your pocket
gives you at a glance quick access to
information you want
and of course we support this on your
seventy
and you can see it looks gorgeous
blended right over that new background
is just beautiful stunningly beautiful
team did a great job
next
I want to show you the custom action
extensions you can see here
we have our new annotate image extension
which I'm gonna show you how to build
tomorrow
right in that role with actions actions
can be
you I in nine you I actions as you saw
with the Bing translate extension
and we support custom actions on the
west end as well as a matter fact this
is
the infrastructure for the markup
extension
on a west and you'll notice is a very
common theme
we're sharing infrastructure we're
making it easy for you to build things
for both platforms
next on Iowa s only
we have the I the photo extensions now
if there's a photo filter that you've
been missing
I don't know maybe arm or an annotation
extension you would like to make for
photos you can build it now
right into the photos you why this is
really cool we also support
document providers document providers
bring
storage and things like that from the
cloud writing and applications
incited by a last this is our first it
really breaks down a lot of barriers
that we've all been living with for
a I believe 7 releases and next I want
to tell you about a finder extensions
finder extensions are really cool in the
past if you wanted to be able to bad
sure
annotate items and folders inside the
Finder
you may have to resort to super sketchy
behavior
like mocking jay act or or some sort of
hackery
and now you don't have to do that now
you actually have a supported way
to daj items in the Finder and we think
this is really cool
and then
the last but not least third-party
keyboards
were supporting third-party keyboards in
I'll ask now
using extensions so I told you about
extensions and some the extension point
so we're offering
NIOS and a West and next I'd like to
tell you about delivering extensions
extensions are delivered as part of your
up known as
the extension container an extension
container
petain many different types extensions
for example it could contain today view
which it
it contain sharing extension and it
could also contain
maybe multiple custom action extensions
they're all bound up with in your
applications bundle
and delivered via the App Store
extension points wife talked a little
bit but dow extension points earlier
well tell tell you what they are
extension points again are the new
bits and pieces have surface area that
we've exposed on the system
for your extensions to bind to you for
example
a today view widget binds to the
Notification Center
via the Notification Center extension 30
today view
extension point this means you're never
going to see
it. debut extension any activity view
controller for example
and one thing to remember about all
extensions is that their purpose
build binaries see these are not aP's
these are not even
at apiece if your app it's not a special
mode that we launcher app and
it's a special purpose binary it has its
own
code signature has its own set of
entitlements
and it has own container Damien's going
to speak to this further in tomorrow's
session
so as I said they're not outs and
they're always
accessed via Apple frameworks code you
never really direct we launched an apple
frameworks code
is in charge of discovering them for you
and providing usually the user
interaction by which their launch in all
talk about that later
and as I was talking with the developer
at lunch about this right before we came
here these are not facilitating
app to app my PC you don't get like
a pipe back to the containing out for
your extension be able to talk to it
if you want to build workflows that
incorporate apk app by PC you can still
use things like
UI application open /url but
what I would ask you to do is reconsider
some these workflows that you had before
that involved
sort of contextually switching from one
application to another on a user's phone
and reconsider casting this may be in
terms of custom actions which are really
the spiritual successors to you services
so next what our extension points a very
high level they mark extensible parts in
the system
they're always packaged in system
frameworks we don't support
third-party extension points and they
combine
API and policies you can imagine again
with the to debut aged
the today be widget its it's very simple
it's largely is Matt's going to tell you
a view controller but this view
controller also comes with its own
policy
policy which incorporates things like
launch characteristics
an important thing to remember about
extensions most extensions on the system
are bound 121 with our hosting ap
so let me give you an example of this
what say you write a sharing extension
and the sharing extension is invoked in
Safari
instanceof your extension a new process
is going to be spun up
to serve Safari now to use our homes out
goes over to mail and large is your
extension again
but say maybe to share an attachment a
brand new process is going to be spun up
four-year extension those processes are
not going to share address spaces
this protects you from mistakes your
code if you're still using Objective C
in you have a while pointer or something
like that
you're not going to be able to bring
down all the instances have your
extension
that are running on the system it's
really cool
the extension point also governs the
presentation have your extension
important thing to remember is that you
extensions are you I view controllers
you can hear this multiple times today
but you are you controllers can be
expose the user in multiple ways
and usually since extensions live inside
the applique inside the user interface
another application
its up to that application up to the
system as to how it decides present you
you can either be contained or presented
Notification Center widgets to debut
extensions
are contained while sharing extensions
are presented
and many extension points support for a
few extension point support
view controller and non view controller
variance at the extension point
for instance custom actions as you'll
see tomorrow
support a view controller variant which
allows the user to interact with the
content before it's transformed and sent
back to the host
as you saw during the keynote when Craig
capped the Bing translate extension
there was no UI and that was in non-fuel
extension and we'll tell you more about
that later
cell how extensions and felt this is
again
going back to our example the show you
what happens
when user decides to tap on the
butterfly sharing extension
user taps and the extension host which
is safari at this time
goes and talks to the Notification
Center framework
the notification sorry not notification
the social framework
and the social framework goes and
discovers and loads and presents the
extension
you'll notice that Safari is not
directly
watching the extension at any point its
balancing through Apple frameworks to do
this
so in summary extensions are small
pieces the functionality
their purpose built to do one thing and
get out the way
they stand the system in New an
interesting ways
we can't wait to see what you guys do
with these things
and a mark extendable parse the system
as I said new surface area for you to
attach the functionality of your app
interesting and meaningful ways for our
users
and now to tell you more about
Notification Center extensions
I'd like to invite my colleague not
gamble to the stage
hello I'm at Campbell Newman engineer in
the I US notifications team
and today I'm a tell you about
Notification Center extensions
widgets as we call them now we've had
widgets in some fashion on the
system for a while now but for the first
time
you know I was 8 we're giving developers
the power to add their own content to
the notification centers today view
now perhaps most fundamentally widgets
are view controllers
so that means everything you know about
you controllers including the life cycle
in containment behavior in API
will serve you well when you're
constructing your widget
for example the appearance calls these
I'll tell you when
your widget is coming and going in the
Notification Center
in a particular interest is you will
appear as you want to be sure that your
view is
up and ready to be used by the user by
the time you're returning from you will
appear
so speedy have getting ready it's
important to get ready fast performance
the very big consideration with
notification center widgets
so couple tips are be sure to load cache
data so you're bringing up your view
quickly and ready to go
and if you have some new data comes in
you can do your own custom transition
also kick off your expensive operations
as early as possible
and definitely in the background and
when those expensive operations return
be sure to cash this data
so layout is another concern are of
course your widgets in your
your widget has control over its sub the
hierarchy in laying all your content out
but just as with any other parent child
you control your relationship
the Notification Center will be laying
out your views
frame so that means that the
notification center is setting
the frames you don't set your own widget
views frame
but of course not all content is created
equal so
if you might have need some more room
for your content
you can indicate your preferred height
you do this in two ways the for sister
on a layup
if you can are described your Widgets
height with constraints then those to be
honored automatically in Notification
Center
otherwise if you're using more manual
layout you can use the view controller
method Sep referred content size
and both the systems work across both I
O S and OS 10
so while you will definitely want to set
your size as early as possible to ensure
that you're showing your content
are him the right way in Notification
Center that's not the only time
that you can call it if for some reason
you are showing different content or
changes you can call this later
for instance let's say that we had a
button that would show a little bit more
content
are a little bit more detail about some
content that we have in our widget
you could tie this up to this action
calculate the new height for this new
content
and then just call Sep referred content
size the Notification Center
will take care of this it'll
automatically resize your widget
but that's only half the story which you
probably want to do is ensure
that your content animates along with
this transition
and you can do that on I Wes with the
new method
view will transition to size with
transition coordinator
to if you're would implement this method
it'll get called
and passed in a transition coordinator
and with this corner you can call
animate alongside transition passing in
your
a block with your animations and easily
run in parallel with the system's
resize animation and again and then a
completion to know when everything's
finished up
now there's a similar story on OS 10 in
this case its view will transition to
size
again this will be called and you can
take advantage love
and as animation contact to run your own
animation group
and again pass in a completion handler
see you know when everything's finished
up
now new IRS 8 is a protocol
NC which it providing and one of the a
optional map is this protocol is with
you perform update
with completion handler and some porn
implement this one
as it'll insurer that your which is
content stays up-to-date
so if this is implemented you'll be
passing completion hanlon
you want to perform your own update and
then determine what is the appropriate
result to pass back in that block
so if you have some new data go ahead
and use NC update result
new data if there's nothing new
go ahead news no data and if something
went horribly wrong
pass failed in will try to leave well
enough alone
and then finally be sure to call the
completion handler with the result
I that you have
alright let's take a look at this
so so you may remember from last year I
we had a presentation we showed off
and awesome I O S application for
staying in touch with all the clowns
that are in your clown network call that
clown town
what we're gonna take this application a
little bit further by adding widgets
for the Notification Center
now adding a widget is as simple as
opening up an existing application
project
and adding any target for both iowa's
and OS 10 you'll see there's an
application extension section
and you can just select the today
extension
but I've actually already started work
on one sarin ago
right into our view controller here
switch its our view controllers and the
first thing I'm gonna do
is ensure that my which it has the right
height
so I'm using an interface builder
storyboard for my interface
so awake from nearby is a pretty handy
place to take care of this
so after calling super and then setting
up a little state
I'm gonna go ahead and get the most
recent Posts
once I've gotten those update my table
view
I'm this doesn't need to be animated
were just initializing here
an important step is making sure to set
my preferred content sized
to this case just the content size at my
table view
so this'll make sure that were
initialized in the state were showing
a single post in our widget which is
nice
but perhaps you want to see a little bit
more of what's going on in your clown
network
while how bout we add a button
an action for Ubuntu show a little bit
more
so the first thing will do is update our
state
and then calculate our preferred height
which sits reusing a table view on
account the number
rose and also make sure to account for
our full review
what we have our preferred hi we want to
set are preferred content size
and then make sure we tell ourselves
that we had to do an update
in the future that'll come in handy
later
so again we've set our preferred content
size so this will be sure to animate the
widget to the appropriate Hyatt
but we want to make sure that our
content comes in a really nice animated
fashion
and to do that will implement you will
transition to size
with transition coordinator and so if we
have a coordinator
then we know that this is an animated
transition and so will call animate
alongside transition completion
to make sure to update our table view an
animated fashion
and in the completion be sure I
to update the title of our button up
if for some reason we didn't get a
coordinator then we'll just
up dinner table without animation and
then update the button
so this will make sure that our I art
adding a bar rose comes in a nice
animated way
alongside the system animation that's
resizing are widget
now one more thing I want to do before
we give this a try
that is making sure that our content
stays up-to-date so I'm and implement
the method
widget perform update with completion
handler
so I'll start by getting the recent most
recent Posts make sure it get any
updates
and then calculate the result so if we
already know that we needed to do an
update
or if we actually did get some new
content they want to use NC update
result new data
otherwise we can just go ahead and use
no data
so if we actually did get to new data
wanna do a couple things will def want
to update our table view to ensure that
it's reflecting our most recent content
and then up their preferred size to
ensure there which is the right height
and in either case we certainly don't
need any more updates
and will call our completion handler
with our result
alright I think we can go ahead and give
this a shot
so I'm gonna go ahead and build and run
for the simulator
I'll switch over to the simulator now
ok and here we have our client an
application
on a home out of this and present the
Notification Center
go to the Edit menu and our which it is
not there
the I excellent
to give that one more shot
well yes there we go
there's our application
bring down this one new widget available
there it is
alright so hit done and here's our
widget
out we can see that Corbin icon has a
multi-colored suspenders is giving away
gonna make sure to picture alright his
arm or bun
we tap that get a new rose animate in
nicely
y la to weddings happening
less class is everything back down and
nice animated fashion
looking pretty good well i def wanna
know more about these multi-colored
suspender somebody go ahead and
how ok I what we've definitely seen
if you look at the the system widgets
that's a pretty common pattern to
tap something in the widget and then
transition to the application and maybe
I see some more details or get some more
contact are well that's definitely
something that we're interested in doing
so let's return excursion a stop to the
burger
and since I'm using a table view I want
to implement able to you
dislike throw it in XPath so after we
make sure we have a valid post
ability to manage an object called
extension context
now the extension contest is an object
it you have access to you in your widget
are in any extension that's running in
host and it has a
tell you some interesting things about
what's happening in your current host
I'd also has a couple really interesting
methods in our case really take
advantage of open URL
completion handler now I have to find a
custom URL scheme that share between my
which in my application
so i cant construct the URL with this
scheme
and then add some identifying
information for my post
and then one final thing I want to do
just make sure to disliked this row so
it's not selected the next time the user
pose down notification center
alright sort build and run this again
here's our application present here
at this back
and here's Corbin again so let's see if
I tap this hopefully I'll be able to get
some more information about the
suspenders there we go
brings us right to the application gets
more detail make sure we don't miss out
on the suspenders
so few things to remember we deserve you
controllers
everything you know about view
controllers in the API and behaviors to
serve you really well
when you're constructing a rigid
also be sure your Widgets resume
immediately you don't want users bring
down notification center in tapping in
not having anything happen
now while the notification center
handles layout not all widgets are
created equal you want different heights
you can do this with the preferred
height within the constraints in auto
layout
works closely through preferred content
size missus across both platforms
also you want to be sure to you if you
enemy your content along with the resize
animation
this again we have API's on both I O S
and OS 10
help you do this
and then be sure to handle update
request to make sure that all the
content what's up today
now I'd like to invite guy up on stage
to tell us about share extensions
hi so my name is guy Fullerton and I am
an engineer on the IRS
social an account teams and I'm gonna
give you everything you need to know to
implement share extensions
so sure extensions our way to take
sharing and upload functionality
in your app and package it up and get
that presented in the sharing mood
standard activity and sharing
affordances in the operating system
shirts go back so like the US activity
view and share menu
in Mac OS 10 so this is particularly
useful
for Social Network aP's or perhaps that
like to do video
or photo hosting for example a month and
other stuff
so able to come a concrete example let's
have got a photo blogging application
that normally allows major to launch the
app
pick a photo from the photos library
i'ma take that a little bit maybe make
a choose an audience to present it to
you and then upload it to a photoblog
but wouldn't it be great if I could do
that upload directly from within Photos
app
well that's what share extension would
let you do so let's I am I mean photos
I select the photo that I like tap the
share button
pops the activity view and you can see
my phone about to look
photo blog application icon there any
activity view
tap that and up slides a compose cheaper
for a blog
let your user type some text to
annotated choose an audience whether
they want to limit the
exposure that for and what not and
posted
some going to hammer this home a lot the
next couple days but a lot of extensions
are basically just view controllers
that's where most of the workers and you
probably aren't familiar with how to do
that
but share extensions have a couple other
concerns having to do with their
packaging
specifically the extensions in populist
so let's talk about that
so normally when a share extension shows
up in one of these
sharing affordances you generally want
that extension to have
be absent name that's going to be the
thing the musician was for mayor
from with looking for when they want to
select that extension
but some applications may have multiple
share affordances
I the photo blog for example might want
a basic posting share functionality
and maybe once a way to specifically set
the blogs header photo for example
so it's important to be able to
customize your share extensions name
and the way you do that is with CF
mantel display name
injury in populist just set that to the
name you want your share extension to
show up with
and sharing you I will display the name
appropriately for your extension
so the next thing to talk about or
activation rules
and this is probably best explain to an
example
what's a year in photos and you have a
senate real things
selected you get two photos and a video
and user wants to share that so they tap
the share button
a pops the are you actively view where
the share menu 10 X 10
and behind-the-scenes we've created an
extension context
net extension context is the conduit
that your extension we used the poll
data
from the host application into itself so
this extension context for this
particular scenario
has three things I'm it's got a
reference to two of those images
and of course a reference to the video
as well now the user might have a bunch
of share extensions on their system
and each them wants to get involved in
different kinda situations
and so the activation rules are with
that lets the system make the right
decision about which extensions to put
in the activity beware the share menu
based on the kind of data that any
extension context
there are two ways for your extension to
supply its activation
horse the first as a predicate now every
extensions in populist
has an NS extension dictionary and
within that and its extension dictionary
is the NS extension attributes
the system uses those attributes as part
of its decision-making process about
which extensions to show
but importantly for sharing stanchions
the Ennis activation rule
I with in the NS extension at Reese's
what you need to set
if you set that to a string that the
predicate we will run that predicate in
the host app and figure out if your
extension his appropriate and that
predicate can be as detailed as you need
it to be
were can be simple if you want to be
whatever you need to get the job done
and this will serve the needs a lot of
extensions
other extensions however I may have a
little more fine-grained
what we found internally is that a lot
of our extensions just wanted to know
basically just wanted to say
that they support a basic setup images
more videos for some URL's attacked
so we offer these condensed rules that
allow extensions to specify just those
particular things without having to
write a complex predicates
now ultimately these condensed rules
boil down to a predicate and behind the
scenes but you don't need it worry about
that
so to specify condense rules you still
put me in in NS activation rule insider
and its extension attributes
but this time it's a dictionary and
there are a number of keys you can put
in a dictionary that indicate the amount
of that type of data
your extension is interested in
now the bottom those two activation
rules both had to do with web content
and they're slightly different we have a
web URL support and a webpage support
and i wanna go into the details about
these so some
share extensions are all about taking
the link you're currently looking at in
Safari
and posting it someplace else to some
vetoes somebody else can click on that
link and go see the web page
for those kinds of sharing extensions
you want to specify that you support the
web URL
with Max camp now another class
insurance tensions are all about looking
at the page that Safari is currently got
displayed
and polling data out on that page and
for those cheering extensions
we have the web page with Max count
power activation will
now in order to support the web page
with Max count your extension also needs
to supply a javascript that's run
to determine what part the web content
actually stick on the extension context
I'm not gonna go into detail on that
here but in tomorrow session we dive
into the
take detail on that so please check that
session a
hammering at home get again extensions
are basically just view controllers
so it's a lot of familiar territory
share extensions can be implemented with
two kinds view controllers
on we support among both I O S and OS 10
and you can subclass %um you control or
an issue control as you wish
you probably already have you control
the code in your apt today that you can
repurpose per share extension
sure maybe you wanna make some tweaks to
it too to conform better to make it a
limited
on another space you have on the screen
or what not but you take that existing
code
massage it a little bit and deployed an
extension and you can get to look
exactly how you want using your own
branding
existing you are whatever
some extensions however want to conform
to the standard system share should look
and for them we offer the SL compose
service you controller
that you can subclass to get among other
things the standard
book standard animations text editing
a indication the remaining characters
based on the characters type so far
I the post and Cancel buttons built in
previewing
and other limited matter customization
so once you've implemented your view
controller the next thing you need to be
concerned about
is actually doing the upload or post to
wherever you're sharing stated
the key here is that you need to use an
issue /url session
with a background session configuration
reason being
your extension does not live beyond its
presentation
at least not very long and we'll talk
more about that tomorrow
so you need to make sure that by using a
background in this URL session
you're allowing the system to handle the
upload for you
secret a background in this world
session configuration build an issue
I'll session around that
build an issue are URL request that I
encompasses the items that are being
shared and create and upload task
wrapped around
an issue or a crest and then start that
up a task
once you've done that the system is
gonna handle the upload for you
at that point your extension needs to
tell the host ap
that it's done and you can tell down the
presentation a view controller
and you do that by calling a method on
the extension contact called complete
request returning items completion
handler
if the user chooses to cancel your sheet
or whatever your presentation happens to
be
there's another extension context meant
that you need call has called cancel
request
with your so mad already talked about
performance with request
with respect to the today which is and i
wanna talk about that a little bit
different way
in terms of share tensions I'm sure
extensions often have to grab a bunch of
data from the host at
they might be dealing with 10 photos for
an enormous video
and it can be expensive to be pulling
out from the host ap
while the presentation is happening so
if you notice
that I your your presentation mission is
staggering
you may need for someone that heavy
lifting until after the presentation is
completed
if you some question would you
controller an issue controller do
whatever makes sense for the rest if
your code
just two for that task so it's not
impacting the animation
if you subclass SL compose service be
controller however
we will call your subclasses
presentation animation did finish method
giving your I'm you control a good hook
with which to start that heavy lifting
so let's take a look at the photo blog
app and a photoblog share extension
quick
before going into the code I'm gonna
show you the
sure extension running so some legal
make a little bit more sense
so we're gonna go into for us just like
that for the screenshots I showed speak
a different one
puppies a.m.
and I will do just one so no it's not
true that
there we go click on the Forgot your
extension and up comes the composer you
so this is clearly using
the standard system composed she looked
arrive from so compose service few
controller
and you can do a couple different things
a you can take some taxed
and as I'm typing text kinda hard to see
but is a little indicator the remaining
characters and once I type too much text
it goes negative
and the post button disables this is all
happening more or less for for you'll
see some details when we look at the
code
the image preview their it happens for
free
the base class will be there for you we
also
this particular subclass adds an
audience picker
so this photo blog supports the notion
of posting publicly I
or only to my friends were completely
primarily in you can choose a different
audience
treats text here so we're within
the allowed range and we can post so
let's go back in Xcode
and see how we implement that
so the first thing I did it's hard to
see sorry but this is skills they can do
with the hippie with the first thing I
did was set the panel display name for
my extension
2400 block and I set up an activation
rule
I this particular activation will says
my share extension
only once one image that's all you need
to give me I don't care about anything
else this is one time relevant
and now my view controller so mine
you controller subclasses from so
compose service we control our
now take a look at the implementation
before Easter & Co to this
I want to talk about a couple artificial
constraints for this demo app so for
purposes
up showing off the remaining characters
count and I generally updating the
postman
I'm gonna say that my photoblog has two
constraints associated with it
the first is that no photo can be posted
with more than 20 characters
a alongside the photo because it's meant
to just let you see the photo and not
get distracted by the text
and also it's supposed to be a
lightweight for a blog doesn't wanna
spend it on a storage space on the
photos
so no photo that you post can be bigger
than one megabyte
and this class constraint is
particularly important because when you
pull data from the host application
you're not in control of the day decide
if you've got a photo coming from Photos
app it might be quite large
and therefore its your extensions
responsibility down sample that image
data to fit within your size constraint
so let's start implementing view
controller
so I'm gonna add an image data property
to my subclass this is going to be the
fully down sampled image data
that i'm gonna ultimately upload to the
photoblog
I'm going to keep track of the audience
that be user wants to post it to you
and I'm gonna keep configuration item
that i'm gonna talk about a little bit
later on
basically this represents that audience
bigger table cell down in the bottom
have the compose p
all right sir you did load we're going
to
initialize the audience we already have
a utility routine in our apt that knows
how to fetch the right default audience
based on a number of factors so we're
just gonna be used that quote from the
app
now a those constraints I was talking
about the twenty character limit
and the down sampling both need to
affect whether the post button
is enabled so if the user is tight more
than 20 characters
we don't want them to be able to post if
the down samples not finished
likewise we don't want them to be able
to post so we need to make sure the post
button is disabled in those cases
also since we're using the remaining
character count indicator
we need to make sure that up to date at
all times the right place to do that
is the is content valid method SL
compose service view controller calls
your
subclasses is content valid method
whenever it needs to update the status
on the post button to give your chance
to do those things
for temperament some other the first
thing I want to do is look at the
are number of characters that the users
type so far
SL compose service to controller has a
content text property
which is the text that these are state
so far so we grab a drink
next week actually the number of
characters remaining based on our photo
blogs constraint
then we set eso composers Wii
controllers characters remaining
property
this is an NS number by setting that too
and in this number
the base class automatically updates the
text
on the composure she trefor start to
reflect the number of characters you
still have worked
to stand here so next we're going to
same
that the post but should be enabled if
the user is not types too much text
and if we already have a fully down
sampled image data otherwise
don't enable the post but now we've got
to get a fully down temple image data
and like I said this can be a
potentially expensive operations we
don't know how much data is gonna be
coming over from the house
so we wanted to for that to presentation
animation did finish
this method is called by sub called on
subclasses a vessel compose service few
controller
after decompose she has slid up on
screen so the first thing we're gonna do
is look at the extension context again
and in particular look at the input
items
now I'm gonna go off from the weed a
little bit here but bear with me
the extension context can have multiple
input items
on it each input item represents a
separate upload
block for most share extensions
you only care about doing one uploaded
the time but you might imagine a
particular sharing extension that
allowed to do
5 posts 21 social network at one go so
for that kinda
hypothetical chair extension you're
gonna need to look at all the input
items
but since this photo blog extension only
cares about posting one photo at a time
with one post at a time
we just look at the first input on next
we're going to iterate over all the
attachments
on that extension I'm I each extension
eat each post request could come with
multiple pieces a day to
like you could go into photos and select
two photos can choose to share that
you would have a extension contacts with
one item
with two attachments so we're going in
to rate over the attachments and find
the photo that we care about
so what we do is we
we iterate over all the other providers
in the extension item and we call has I
don't conform to type it in a fire
passing K U T take image this is hey I
don't provider do you have an image
in you and if we find out but the answer
is yes
we're going to do some work we're gonna
need a poll that particular item
fighters data and we're gonna wanna do
that on a background cue so as to not
hi disrupt the main thread and since we
found the one image that we support
we can stop generating now silly
actual work pulling the data happens
with the
load item for type identifiers options
completion had limited again saying
gimme some UT type
image please and the completion heavily
handle the past actually has a flexible
first parameter
indicates the way you would like the
item provider to supply your data
in this case my share extension is
interested in NSA a
so that's what my completion has
protected and
when hi get the school
for me civic breakthrough wider rap so
much
I'm it's important to note
that no doubt have happened in a fire
completes on an arbitrary cue
and since we're going to view controller
work I'm gonna need to dispatch a sink
under the main she'd actually do that
work
and I'm gonna call a method on my psych
class called image data loaded finish in
passive
idea let's go implement that
so my application already has down
sampling code right that's what it would
need
in the normal case in normal application
case I'm just going to repurpose that
and ask it to down sample the image data
passing mapsize
and that's going to complete on an
arbitrary cue so again
once it completes I'm gonna give you
control it works I dispatch a sink onto
the main cue
and then I remember the down sample
image data
now that I've got that image data I need
a post button to get updated
and the way I do that is call a method
on SL compose you control a commonality
content validate content calls your
subclasses
is content validated and gives it
another chance to determine whether or
not
that enable the post button
okay so when the user taps the post
button
on SL compose new controller subclass I
we call that subclasses
did select post method so let's react to
that
the first thing we're gonna do is
perform the upload
and after that we need to tell the host
that
are extensions done you can dismiss our
view controller and again we do that by
calling
and that on extension contest called
complete request returning items
completion handler so it's at look at
the Apple again
so the upload is going to be very
similar to what I already showed on the
slides but let's go through it again
because it's
very important for extensions because
they have a short life span first thing
we're gonna do you
is create K background in a swirl
session configuration
create an issue or a session from that
configuration
and create a request representing the
upload
now again this is code we stole much
told called we borrowed from the main
application
that building an issuer local request
from the photo data
I from the context that the user is
typing the audience
building upload task around that request
and then start to happen now in this
particular case
I well as he lets her back for a second
so we implemented it's like post method
eso composers you controller will also
call aidid select Cancel method
on your subclass but in this particular
case
we don't need to implement the default
implementation and it's like cancer will
go ahead and cancel the attention
context for you automatically
but if your extension needs to do some
cleanup work in response to a cancel
you can override it select Cancel so
that a No
to handle the basic uploading and
interaction with the sheet
but at the bottom of the sheet Murray
there is that little audience pick your
cell
I'll show you how to implement that the
base class will call your subclasses
configuration items method
as a way to give your subclass a chance
to supply
that set up table cells to put on the a
bottom-up share she
so we can implement the configuration
Adams method its are subclasses
responsibility
to return an array es el cumple she
configuration items
one for each configuration item in the
table now the example here
only has one configuration item but you
might imagine a
share extension that means multiples in
fact some the built-in system
extensions have multiples configuration
and on the bottom
so we instantiate 1 and we said
title the title is what's displayed on
the left side of the table cell
and we said its value which is the
audience displayed on the right side of
the table cell
and then we need to react to when that
table sellers tapped
and when we do that is by setting a tap
handle on the configuration
now I'm gonna avoid to retain cycle
between my view controller
any configuration item but capturing a
weak reference to myself
inside the tap handler and then what we
do is we got a strong reference to do
that week strong dance
and if our view controller is still
around on
at that point we know the table cells
been tapped we want to show that
audience paper you why
so we've already implemented in audience
pick your view controller
it's just a basic table view controller
that happens to be in. specific for this
particular use
so we instantiate a we set ourselves to
be its delegate
our custom audience bigger view
controller class has a delegate method
it's called
when the user taps an audience so that
we get to react to the specific audience
chosen
we're gonna tell it what the currently
selected audiences so I can check
the right thing and then we're gonna
call a method on its ok oppose service
you control a telling it to please enemy
this other be control or on screen and
the method is
push configuration new controller so
this slides your
new view controller in a navigation
controller like style and resizes the
computer she
to fit your view controllers past
desired size and then finally
now that we've implemented that we can
return are single configuration item
from configurations
alright so here is our daily a method
that is called when the audience pick
your view controller
sees beer tap a cell we need to react to
that we're gonna remember the selected
audience
we're gonna tell our configuration item
hey it's got a new value and by doing at
the table cell is updated automatically
showing the new audience
and finally what ought to dismiss that
audience bigger view controller
I'm you don't have to lose it really
depends on what your configuration items
needs are
but generally for this kind of simple
audience picker want to tap a cell you
wanted to swipe away
revealing the main compose she so this
is just a boilerplate code for executing
code after a short delay
and then we call pop configuration new
controller
so in a navigation controller like way
this says remove the Thomas B controller
from the stack
and since we only had one there it
restores the
the fall churches appearance
so that is it let's go ahead and rerun
this guy and take a look at it one more
time
for a blog at its hometowns
go back to photos as our photo
weekend bring up the photo by extension
and there it is
we can choose an audience make a comment
and pursuant so that's how you make a
shared vision for Iowa's
but if you are looking at the expo
project closely you can see that there's
a couple
West End targets and their and now it
turns out that shared
yeah tights more stuff that's your
extensions
are very portable now it was pretty easy
for me to take my eyelash extension
and massage the coat a little bit for OS
10 hand so that
is working here I can go to some photos
select a full preview it bring up the
share menu
painters my photo blog item and there's
my OS 10
4 o'clock your country he so that demo
was all about a subclass a vessel
compose service view controller
but we know a lot of Extension
developers are gonna wanna just subclass
from UAB
view controller and SQ controller and
we'd love you to do that cuz you can go
to town and customize the wine for your
branding and whatnot
but the basic work that you need to do
beyond implementing the new controller
is pretty much what are you changing the
demo
you get those info pls concerns you need
is still set your
on your display name are you need still
provide your activation rules
and you still need to do you upload
within an issue or a background section
see just learned
all about ap extensions you learned a
little bit about to have a packaged
about the different extension points
have a communication works between the
host
and the extension itself you learn how
to make
a two-day widget and a share extension
on both I O S
and OS 10 so go take a look at your
applications
figure out what pieces if you're sharing
functionality or other functionality
you can package up into an act extension
and deploy so we think this is really
cool technology and we're really looking
forward to all the good features and
functionality you're able to supply
users
with your extensions here
take barings is our Super Avenger with
we have really comprehensive ap
extensions programming guide
goes into tons in detail on all the
SharePoint in all the mechanics in all
this
tomorrow we have another great extension
session where we go into detail on more
more SharePoint
I we also talk about more the underlying
infrastructure
we also go into great detail on the
JavaScript support for web content
and importantly more detail on the
extension context in an aside a provider
so there's tons a good information I
refer to check those out
we have two labs where you can talk to a
sapling in years we'd love to get you
started implementing your share
extensions
one of those labs immediately after this
so previous downstairs would love to
chat
thank you