good afternoon everyone my name is
honors I'm an engineer on the Safari and
what
a team and i'll be joined later by my
colleague bath and the session has
session till sex
introducing the modern web can API we've
got a lot a really cool things to show
you
self let's go started for first fighting
I want to give you a brief overview of
what can actually yes
one way you can think about it
yes that white kid is the layout and
rendering engine
behind Safari on Mac and I'll
Sol
what kept parsers and render Saget him
how
it loads into space images it runs
JavaScript and so forth
another way to look at it
yes that WebKit starts where the so far
user interface than
but what good is also used by a lot of
other APs
such as male for displaying rich HTML
email
and iBooks for rendering gorgeous
e-books and even applications you
wouldn't normally think per
for use in but can't like messages for
its conversation you
and of course most important of all
your apt you done some really amazing
things with WebKit
so
if you're using WebKit in Europe today
on I O S
you're using you I webview so let's have
a quick show of hands
how many view are using you I webview in
a nap today
while on our span
you would be using a WebView an how many
are you are using a WebView
call now
over the years we've receive a lotta
requests from you especially on iowa's
for something a bit more powerful and we
really think
we have something that you're gonna like
and that is the modern web today
guy so what do you wanna learn today
you'll see how to adopt
the modern working in PI and to you said
in your apt we'll take a look at a few
new coffee church an
how to integrate those in your app an
them will I'm a bit deeper and you can
see how you can customize the way WebKit
votes web pages
and even customize the web content
itself for the modern web committee i
class for class
this API is exactly the same on iowa's
analyst yeah
from of course there are some
minor changes due to the way we hook
into ap kitten you like it
but its pretty much the same
are also taking advantage
the latest and greatest language and
cocoa futures
so you can spend less time writing group
called
and more time focusing on making your
apt way and we tried
really hard to reduce the surface
area while still giving you access to a
ton of cool features
and we're using
the multiprocessor architecture that
we're also using Safari on POF
our stand since I N and now on I'll ass
when when I am a in fact
one of the goals we had with this modern
API wise
to take a bottle features that were
previously only available to Safari
and give you access to them for example
super smooth 60 frames-per-second
scrolling
using harburg Federation coronation the
full power
other JavaScript nitro engine on both
Western
and I'll and this includes
the fourth tier LVM base compiler that
greg was telling you about yesterday
we've taken the back forwards swipes
and abused assume gestures and
from Safari and built them right into
web
and we have a really cool way for your
have
to talk to web pages and vice versa
now I mention that work at s
multi-process
and what what does this really mean
it means the web content runs
in a separate process completely
isolated from your
like this now why is this a good idea
while it's great for responsiveness
what's but so you uploaded a web page
and the web page is running a lot of
scraps and
I'm doing a lot of layouts your Apple
Store for Responsive
even if it happens and if you vote on
the web page that is
creating a lot of JavaScript object and
using our memory
well make sure to handle that gracefully
instead of having your app
jetsam
it's also a really good for battery life
and power usage
says each webpage runs separately in
Assam process
we can put individual web pages into our
low power mode
for things like back on tabs a fully
uprooted Windows
now this is all completely transparent
to you
when you create a wk webview that is our
new
webview class in the morning PI
what's been up about condom process
when you create another wk webview will
spring up another web content prop
now we do this up to eliminate and then
when used create more public a wave use
they'll share the web.com process
an when you TLK two KK where views
we tear down the process is for you and
you don't have to worry about a thing
let's talk about hard adopt the modern
went to the PI
so Beth and I are both huge Wikipedia
fans
we love we compete reading Wikipedia we
read it all the time
and so we figured a it will be a kinda
cool idea
to write a dedicated work computer
browser app using the modern API
this is what it looks like it's called
KK pedia now if you think this is just
the topic a WebView
inside an honest window your absolutely
right
by don't worry we're we're gonna add
some more features to it
but 100 recreate this topic a WebView
and 100
to reload the web page while creating a
public a WebView is really easy
just as with any any other view you call
our and then call in for frame
and that's it and how do you want a web
page
you get there I'll
you get the URL request and the new Call
KK webview
load request and that although the
webpage
saw what's all good if you have a nap
with a single webview but for wk PDR
we really wanna have support multiple
windows
you can have on the one article showing
up one's
an when you do this jurors always some
states that you wanna share between your
web use
such as preference the setup process is
to you
to you to create your your web pages in
and
visited links and the way to do this
yes to create a single configuration
object
and then when you create your KK web
views
you pass upon the configuration and
government sure that all the state
strictly share between
swept this is what it looks like in cone
first you create your wk webview
configuration
and then use incredibly clear whether
you buy used network frame
configuration and you given
configuration
and that's all you have to do
or head back to the Wikipedia now even
though this is not gonna be a
full-fledged
rouser there are still some brosser like
futures that we wanna had
such as: a back forward button
title and a progress indicator
so let's take a look at how we would do
this
and let's cover much to write and star
with the back forward
for the Earth's we have a bunch action
methods
and a week a WebView here are some other
you can totally sup in Interface Builder
your UI elements
without having to write any code and so
for TTP Dr the ones were interested in
our go back go former
and these are also auto validating which
means that
I'm when you have hope these up to your
UI it'll automatically update the
enable/disable state
based on whether you can go back
performers you don't have to worry about
that
so what about the title and the progress
in
for that we have a bunch of properties
KK web
herself them these are CoCo Key value
observing compliant
which means that you can use the normal
Coco kevo methods listen for any changes
to the property values
an if you're in a western you can use
cocoa bindings
to hook them up to your UI without
having to write a single line of code
so for WP Dr we're interested in the
page title
just the prime property an whether the
page is loading or not
and that's from owning property
okay the WPS really starting to come
along here
but it's still not a dedicated
Wikipedia
now what do I mean by that well
what so you go to the web article in
Wikipedia
and you click this
link to the website homepage
that open the link inside that we keep
your browser
but we want this to be a dedicated
Wikipedia have
and we don't avoid any external links
so what we wanna do you is customized
the way
pages are loaded but before I can tell
you about that
I A need to explain how page loading
actually works
Mike
so first something happens
that triggers a paged this can be one
too many things
for example the user signaling
are using back forward buttons could be
JavaScript setting the windows of
occasion property
are could be a subframe bushing because
subframes
and frames are just documents inside
each other
hand as we saw earlier it could be you
calling KK web you more
then we send a request after the server
and we get back a response
this could be a positive response or
the server could give back them back for
a for which means
sorry I know don't know what this
resources from
and then service and back some data
and we're done now
what you can do with WebKit yes to have
your
ap sorta inject itself
after the action and response phase
and to decide whether
to continue to load or whether to cancel
and the way you do this yes by
implementing methods
on the topic your web use navigation
dock
there are two methods that corresponds
to the very to the two different phases
first one is decide party for navigation
action
for the action the second one
is the fight party for navigation
response for response
and with both of these target methods
you get
data objects that contain enough
information
for you to be able to make an informed
decision about whether you want to
continue
the low turn so
fortify pasta for navigation action that
object yes
wk navigation action
it has properties for example the
navigation pipe let you find out which
type of navigation
actually started the loan like everyone
said
playing Inc like to refer was a go back
come forward
request so request
is the request we're gonna send to the
server
and with the modifier flags property you
can even tell if the user hell down
Schefter commander option
I kindling
for decide party for navigation response
you get a wk navigation response
checked there's also house properties
response s the age to be response that
we get back from the server
and in addition to these data objects
you also get a decision handler
in the form of a block
this is how your app can decide whether
you want to go through the log
our council you do this
by calling the block with one of two
value
so for decide party for navigation
action your past
wk navigation action Policy Council or
allow
and for decide policy for navigation
response
you pass either KK navigation response
Policy Council
or allow now you can either call these
blocks
right away more you can call them
sometimes later which can be really
useful if you wanna put up some UI
and that the user decide whether the
large you continue on
now I'd like to ask my colleague bath up
on stage
to show week npr how to add some these
features
hi everyone and that takin understand I
work together on safari in WebKit but
lately we've been working
on our pet projects wk pedia so I have a
super bare-bones version of the app to
show you
and together we'll use all the
information under just gave us to build
it up and turn it into
a dedicated breast so I'll show you what
we have
and then lower on improving
its gonna build in
here we go wKP as it stands it's really
just a
wk webview and a window yet I love the
great wk
features super fast scrolling we get the
super-fast
JavaScript engine with fourth-year him
just in time compiler
can click on links navigate new pages
so that's great but I'm clearly missing
some basic browsing features
if I look at the same website in Safari
for example
if I click on a new link then
I get some progress indication at the
top indicating how the loads going
URL bar gives me some indication web
page
on I can go back these are things that
we clearly want in our effort to feel
like a web browser
cell them I give you a quick tour
the code furs this is our main class
it's a browser window controller
and that Nintendo controller if we look
at the implementation file
this is where we have a property for the
WK webview
and down here in windowed this is where
we allocate a review
and it's a reload our initial request
okay but we want
them so let's go interface their
to get to here
you know first make the toolbar visible
lunch and double click it start
adding some items so first we wanted
back and forward buttons
wild red those in
and if we go over panel here lemme
highlight on here
up for you you can see I've already
heard these buttons
up to the appropriate method the back
button sorry hooked up to the
go back action for but already hooked up
to go forward for those should work
then we want some indication have the
page that runs we don't wanna URL field
here cuz we want the
dedicated browser app we don't want
people to type in
random URL will use the search field and
Wikipedia to get two different pages
we just want taxed but we wanted to
reflect
the title I love the Wikipedia page
they're actually on
so that's very easy
over here can
so for this text you just want to bind
it to you
the file's owner which is that browser
window controller class
show you a minute ago and then leon is
that the monarchy path
to with you title
and so that's one of those KVL compliant
properties on Wed the
wk webview that under telling us about
this should be all that we have to do
this should automatically
update whenever the title value changes
just get all that Kb oh good
right and finally we just want some
progress indication dragon
ok looks about right let see
how that works building ran
okay so we have some progress here I'll
up a little
we have back four buttons great we'll
see if they work in a second
we have title reflects the page that
were on
San Francisco are spinner doesn't seem
to be doing quite the right thing it's
just kind of always
there and it's not indicating any load
progress yet
fine I've navigate to any page great the
title updated right away
like San Diego cook my back button
and we went back awesome forward great
okay so we've made a lot of improvements
we need to fix that
spinner I'll feel like this titles is
really long
they all seem to have this suffix
wikipedia the free encyclopedia
I think you'll be more useful in our app
if we truncated the title down just to
be the beginning
we can handle that very easily and
Interface Builder as well
let make those to fix
first let's fix that been
to fix that we want you
go over here again
the animation section and we want to
bind
the file's owner again and again that
their browser window controller class
and hear the monarchy path the webview
not loading and again that's one of
those Kb a complaint properties
that should be all we have to do to get
this enemy whenever
whether you don't loading through is one
other thing I wanna do
though she's over here I want you
on check display when then
should go away when it's not him
okay and now I wanna tranki that title
also so I did already write some code
that would do that
on down year looking here
so this is just a simple code that I
wrote that were taken and its training
and see if it had
this is suffix at the end and then
return a string that doesn't have that
part
so I already wrote some code that and I
can invoke it
from within Interface Builder
right over year using the value
transformer
option the early Wikipedia title that
value transformer
that will take the title and invoke this
method
with the title and then the result will
be what's reflected
to a bar
building run again
okay so progress has been made let's try
cooking another link we get spinner
animating goes away when are gone our
title is now
much smaller more useful thing for our
apt
we still have our back four buttons this
is looking great this is really
feeling like a browser but I haven't
done anything yet
to make it a dedicated Wikipedia rather
sides just now writing URL field
but if I go to a link like this and
click on its going to still open
right in my app which is not the
behavior that i'm looking for that
sort of defeats the purpose being a
dedicated Wikipedia
so we can easily fix this by
implementing
the navigation delegate just like under
products
do that right now go back to the code
okay self first
I want add one line of code
here to set the navigation delegate
here in setting the navigation delegate
to self
so this way WebKit will know to look
here in my class
to see if there's any implementation
these delicate
delegate method and everyone
implement to delegate
implement decide policy for navigation
action so let's quickly stepped through
this
so first I wanna get the URL that the ap
navigate you and then I if host URL
did not have a Wikipedia .org suffix
then on Wikipedia link
then in that case I want to pass
navigation off to the default browser
system that's what will happen with this
line of code Safari should open that
link instead
but we still need to tell are wk webview
that it shouldn't go ahead with the
navigation also
will invoke the decision handler block
with the WK navigation action policy
camp value and while you're here I
thought it would be cool just add a
feature
to command click a link in open it in a
new window and my own app so that's what
I added down here
the first day I'm finding out navigation
is happening
with the command down is
then I'm going to create a brand new
browser window controller
and I'm giving that this navigation
request
and then again it since I don't want
this wk with you too also
navigate new page I am the decision
handler block
with the camp value and other as if we
didn't fall into any of those
situations then well invoked the
decision handler block
with allow let save and built in
okay great so regular page loading still
work so that's good
let see click on think an awesome
successfully handled that navigation
after the default browser
and if I command click a link
I get it and new window in my own apt to
these are in its own process
monument API pretty cool
cell this is awesome in just a few
minutes with bill up a dedicated
browser app using the modern WebKit API
but I still feel like there are a few
modern features
that I am lacking here for example again
if we look
back in Safari really uses the back
button anymore I mean I
typically slide back Chester to go back
and I also want to be able to double tap
to zoom in 10 check out
I try to do those things in my ap
nothing
happen double tap no
nothing's happening but it's really
really easy to add these features I'm
going to really quickly even on
should have had to do it quite yet but
just need to add to
lines code back up here in window
deadline
okay so this for sign a code allows back
for navigation jesters at that yes
they can see the backboard swiping and
allows magnification I'll get double tap
unhinged
them that built in
okay now by go forward should be able to
use
right back awesome can double tap
pinch right out of them so there you
have it with bill
a modern would use the modern yeah I to
build a dedicated
Wikipedia browser app with modern
feeling features in just a few minutes
so many headed back to under is gonna
teach you a lot the
more advanced features that you can do
with this API and I'll be back up later
to show you how you can integrate
features into our iPad version at wk
pedia
back to you under
thanks for I was really cool I
especially like the extra touch
at the end where are you the gesture
support let's recap
how bed so for the navigation jesters
thats swipe to go back and forward just
said
the other aspect forward navigation
jesters property
yes on your KK what for June gestures
on a western you said
a while magnification property yes
on iowa's this is handled by the
underlying UIScrollView
and it's already on by default you don't
have to do anything
so what's talk about the Wikipedia for
iPad
this is what it looks like its really
great I use it all the time for reading
Wikipedia articles on my way to work
but I've noticed something bad
bothers me a little see I like to read
certain sections
an article and that means that
I have to go find the table conference I
have to scroll down to it
I find a section I wanna read hi up on
that
playing and then when I read it
I need to scroll all the way back up
source flight back
and look for another section read so
I told Matt about this and she said well
why don't you some other more advanced
features on the modern work API
to take care Mike
why don't we just got red a few more
condoms from the web page
an while we're at it we can also get rid
of this
sidebar to the left to make more room
for the article
and them we can put the table of
contents
natively in the UI we have this little
button in the top left corner
and when you tap it you get the table
contents in a native UI tableview
and burn your landscape mode you can
always admissible because
the extra space so what we really want
to do here
yes customize web page content from from
Wikipedia and we want to use two
features to do this
one is called user scripts
the other one is called script message
these are both handled by an object
called KK User Conference controller
public a user content controller is part
of the configuration
so it's a property on the topic a
WebView configuration
called User Content controller
talk about users Users Group our way
for you app developers
to take some javascript an injected into
the web page
and I have to do something this will
happen automatically for every web page
see you don't have to manually call it
every time the page
when you add a user scripts you need to
consider two things
the first one s when you want to use a
script to write
you can either run you use a script that
document start
this yes right after the document
element has been created
by before any the document has been
parsed
or you can run them a document and which
is
after the document is finished parsing
by
before any server resources such as
images necessarily
changed this corresponds to the DOM
content loading
voted you also want to consider where
the scripture
run you can run them either for of
frames
both the mainframe and the subframes or
just for the mainframe
so how do you create a user
first you get the script string from
somewhere
in my case I'm just have it as a string
literal in my co
then you create KK user script object
and passes the source code and here I've
highlighted the when and where
so we want this user scripts run had
document start I'm
but only for the main
and then you tell the user content
controller to go ahead at the user's
and that's it
now what user scripts to you
Users group can do anything that scripts
running on the web page
into so that includes using the DOM API
to change the document structures
adding event listeners for on-loan
events are
kleczka answer key for events or any
other
you can buy an external resources like
images and even acknowledged if you
request
hand you can also communicate back
to the application and this is for a
script messages come in
script passengers are messengers user
scripts and
cue the application
they consist J Sunday so
objects arranged strings et cetera
when you something from your web page we
automatically convert them to the
corresponding objective-c types
so Anna dictionaries and as a raise and
a string
when you wanna listen for scrip
messengers in your you wanna read
register script message
this involves creating an object that
conforms to wk script message hambre
protocol
this protocol has one method that you
have to implement that receives script
message
and then you tell the user content
roller at the script message handler
and you give it a name
and his name is really important because
it is how
your web page communicate back to you
so when you've had a script message
handler we expose a window dot web get
that message
numbers dot your name that post message:
function
yours how are you use this post function
you get your
your message and Jason form from
somewhere
and the new car parts message and you
pass on the message
so on the receiving side webcam will
call
that receives grit message on the
correct use a script message handler
and the body property other KK script
message
object along here well have your message
automatically convert
there are also some other properties
publicly script message
you can find out which web page posted a
message
and the name that was used post them
one interesting thing about script
messages yes
that it's just not use a script the
concern script messages
your web page can also send messages
this is really cool if you have a
website an
happen you want a Web site to you to be
able to communicate
when you're out fired it also means if
you have a generic browser
can vote any website you don't wanna
blindly
trust messages that are posted by
so make sure you do the right message
allegation and check that the object is
the expected type
now I'd like to ask have to come up on
stage again
and show off Wikipedia for I
think Sunday
so I'll show you wk PDF for iPad and
then we'll add them user scripts and
script messaging
to add these features okay so back into
Xcode
so I'm using the same Xcode project for
both versions the wKP actually
so I'm just gonna close up the OS 10
version
open I'll could and switch my scheme to
the IRS
team that now and I building run I'll be
building and running
for the iPad simulator alright let me
show you what we have
i right here wk pedia for the iPad
so again idea that we want to use user
scripts for
as you want to hide some this content
but I had this side by
so that we can maximize the screen space
on the smaller screen
and we also want to hide this table of
contents section
and then we want to extract all the data
from the table of contents section
and put it into are you a table view
that we already have in place
so we can do this with two user scripts
first
we will you it at a user script to hide
the things on the page the one hit in
and then we'll go back in filler in are
you a table with another one
alright so first im gonna add a
javascript file to my project
have one here
called high debt JS so this is a really
simple
JavaScript file first I'm creating a
style
element and I'm attending into the
document
and the style man I'm giving it just
three styles so we used
this if I web inspector to look at what
the Wikipedia code
looks like right now and we saw that the
table of contents wanna hide
as the class name a to.see so on adding
another style to that class I'm setting
it to display none
and making that being important so that
it will override any other just
any other displaced felt they had set on
it and the side panel
has earned idea MW panel some setting
that to display known as well
and finally I just wanna just imagine on
the content to make sure it fills an
extra area now that the side panels gone
okay so this is the JavaScript that I
want my apt in books and now it isn't it
add some code to invoke it
so web view controller this is my main
class in my iPad version you'll see this
is where again we have a
property for a wk web you should like
awfully familiar
0 here I have
a currently empty method called add user
scripts to content controller
so you can see this is and vote from
load view
so in its passing in the WK zircon 10
controller which is the party the
configuration so
honors mention the configuration earlier
on in the tax owed
user's group for example is something
that's party the configuration so that's
an example
why you want your different wk levees to
share a configuration so they all get
these
scripts i right
let's invoke this script just 39 zip
code so first we're creating an a string
with the contents above URL hideout JS
they're gonna take that file that I just
added to the project
and turn it into an stream then I am
creating
wk user script object with
that string and getting an injection
time a
wk script injection time a document
stacked
so this means the script will be
injected and it will run right after the
document element is created before
anything else happens that's good that's
what I want to happen
for this script because I wanna make
sure those styles are there right away I
don't want the chance for the
table of contents inside by to appear
and only then does my script incident
disappear
Abby terrible so documents that that's
what I want and
yeah for the mainframe mommy okay then
find that it needs
add the user scripts to the User Content
controller
and that should be all I have to do so
let's build in
and success
the side panel is gone no longer there
is Heather
article taking up the full with have the
page and
we also have hidden table of contents
section ago right into the history
section
awesome so now let's add a second user
script
to get the data from that table of
contents section put into your table
view
so first add
second JavaScript file to our project so
this goes through
set table of contents section at bundles
up all the data we want puts it into an
array
and then it sends it this is the
important part and as a message
back tonight ap so let's make sure this
could get invoked
and then I'll show you the code that
runs when the JavaScript send a message
back
cell back here in my ad user scripts to
content control method
add a little bit more cologne
okay I'm creating another NS string with
the content
URL this case this time it's with my
fetched at JS
class saw putting a javascript internet
streaming
then creating a wk user script with that
string
and this 1i want to be injected at the
document and
time so this time I want to make sure
that the don has been built up
that it has all those elements
representing a table of contents in it
before my script around
otherwise it's not gonna find anything
and again for the mainframe only add
that as a user script and then
this is important line according to call
this so that
javaScript can call back into my app ads
script message handler
set itself and give it a name did
vegetable content
so in the JavaScript goes back into my
app
make a wider this is the method that
will be
call did receive script message so what
I'm doing and that
method is I'm making sure that this is
scripts that I am expecting to be
calling needed fetch
table of contents and if so I i'm
calling into my
you a table view class with a method
that I have written their
so shit to you so here in my
you a table view could I am just
gonna make sure that this message body:
this is the
data that was sent to me straight from
the JavaScript making sure it's an array
because that's it
I'm expecting that I call make entries
which is
implement read it here I go through that
array
they make sure it's all the data that I
am expecting it to be that I have
written my script
send over its string representing the
title
if the URL representing the URL that
that title
navigate to so that we can have our
after navigate to that
URL when the user taps on it
and if I have all that data like I'm
expecting it
I create a table of contents entry an
attitude ray
and then finally back here this is
rainbow that
method I'm gonna tell the table view to
reload did at this point and then that
edition all be in there okay show
set this all up let's see if it worked
filled in
he reacted pedia everything's hidden
still great
content did not quite work alright
so I suspect that I have a bug in my
JavaScript and what one thing that's
really cool is that I can actually
inspect
all other web content in my wk webview
using the Safari web inspector
an even inspect the user's group that I
have injected which is pretty cool
but oh really you can do this it here at
the other people won't be able to
inspect your app
sell any open the inspector
see if it make sure this happens on
pages to new page still no table of
contents okay
here five
for into my resources panel helen is in
actually you can see that I have my
user scripts over here under the extra
script section
so under user script you this is a
script I want to
look at so I can add a break point there
and just reload right in the inspector
i right that
okay let's step through here's the links
all right do we get into the Luke we do
great
get the tax tax break I'll okay
well there's a bug we had two breaks in
a row so we never got to the code added
any other state to enter a
so this should be an easy ride to fix
now that I spotted it
so let's go back into Xcode
there she is
all right let's build in
we have a table of contents so now
I have a table of contents if I could
around here
I'll navigate to the right section in
the document because I was sure to
include that data when I passed it
back from the script and there you have
it
sell it today with bill a
dedicated Wikipedia browser app for Mac
and for IRS with added some advanced
features
maker at interact with our web content
and we've done it all with a
modern market API that's all I have for
your hand and act on it now
thanks well this is real economy
my we keep your browsing so much more
efficient on my way to work
so the modern working API
available for I was a and honest I'm so
many
same API on both platforms you get to
fall JavaScript nitro engine
including the fourth your compiler its
multi-process
which is right for Responsive
and also for barry
and with users crap
and scrip messages web pages can talk to
your
up by Spurs now
we've only showed a handful classes here
but the modern weaponry PI has much more
to offer
so here's what I want you to do
adopt the modern web API
if you think writing a new app ice
would strongly consider using the new
API
if you already have an app that is using
either you I wuv you
or what have you don't worry those
replies are still there
but we are committed to this new API the
modern world
API and some features by
faster JavaScript her only gonna be
available
new API am
this is america i would really love to
hear what you think about it
so I radars come to the lab
bring your call I'm post and the
developer for
if you wanna contact
are frameworks evangelism
there's more information on webcam
answer for you freedom summer
and a modern working API is part of the
weapon open source projects you can go
to work
dorgan check it out I'm you can also go
to the developer forums
and post your questions and more mature
related sessions
if you haven't up on a Web site you
wanna make sure they work together
there's a great session this afternoon
call your up your website and Safari
on Thursday there's a session about the
web inspector
on Friday morning there's a really
interesting session we're engineers
on the a work team talk about best
practices for sharing called between
analyst and thank you very much for
coming