well come o come for session till seven
accessibility and North
10 my name is patty Hou I'm souter
engineer on the last 10
accessibility team today
my colleague Chris Dillon I and II are
extremely excited to tell you
about this brand new API we have to
install for you
that's designed to make your life
simpler but before I talk about that I
want to just touch up
on the importance of accessibility
and what it means for your application
to be accessible to everyone
then out show you some examples of how
to use this new API
to make some UI accessible
and then also show you some tools they
can use to verify a changes
then then latter half of the session
Chris will come up and give you like
them all
of making a game accessible so Apple
would really care about providing
the best platform for all users to have
that great and wonderful experience
when using your application how I feel
our users
I me users with various range abilities
dang close those who may be visually
challenged
and me arm excuse me
those who may be visually challenged and
have trouble seeing
the collars and the graphics on that
cation those
who are deaf and hard-of-hearing who may
not be
real to hear the south the back in
application
those who may have mobility limitation
and then I people use the physical mouse
or keyboard
what a cheap the goal of making sure
that everyone could have equal access
Apple workroom lonely heart provide
hud's up accessibility solutions
built right into OS 10 and now includes
products such as
voice-over design for the visually
impaired user
switch control designed for model
compare users who may only people to use
a single swish
to operate the computer close captioning
for the deaf and hard-of-hearing and
tons and tons of
other great accessibility features don't
want a left n
but all of these features are simply
tolls for the user to use your
application
after all years
your application that they're looking at
whether not as to
re an article or two watch a movie
use your application that their
interacting with
what whether it's to play a game or to
write a term paper
is your application at the Emerald Bay
that they're looking forward to use
every day so how do you make sure that
your application
a successful to everyone well with
build the foundation for T for you to
build your application
and we have this Walcott accessibility
API
take it implement make sure your
applications accessible to everyone
so I want to spend the rest of the
session
telling you about this API but the first
thing I wanna tell you
s give you are the big picture a hall
this accessibility API work and system
saw first there's your application
and then we have what we call a sister
suffer such as voice-over in such
control help users
to perceive understand interact with
your application
and that happens through a channel well
are what we call
a accessibility API
and so that's why i wanna talk to you
about today
estas accessibility API which for all
last 10
yosemite I'll we create a funk roundup
this brand new API I am excited to tell
you about this
sort with well worth were first Zionist
a PI we have few things in mind
actually just one goal
and that is to simplify to make it easy
for you to use
and to show you just how easy is to use
this API
al walk you through a few examples
so what you see on the screen for sale
is a window that contains
like a media player controller so what
we're gonna do is focus on
the UI's in the middle why CEOs
airs everyone play and follow a button
well how do I come to that conclusion
because
visually you could see three distinct
icons and each of those i Carl represent
something
well if you're not sided eat the Pegasus
to suffer like voice-over
to help you perceive what's on the
screen
what this is what a voice-over user
we'll probably see
just a bunch of buttons they will know
what to do with them
even worse if you implement them
as custom views dorsey
nothing not terribly accessible is it
while today I'm gonna show you how to
make the issue lies accessible
so what do first we'll focus on just one
button in the middle
the play button
if you say you're using app to control
you're in luck
because you get most of that
accessibility for free
by default ako already fill in all the
accessibility information
for that he's a view I knowing that it's
a button I ever afters not psychic
it's not gonna be with the No what the
funk showed that Biden what do
that's something only you the developer
well now
and so that's where you come in to help
label
this button so this too late to do it
you going to exclude Co %uh identity
inspector
under the accessibility I didn't ease
section
you could just added description play
so this is you could do that and as a
file or if you'd like to do this
programmatically
you can simply going to your
initialization Co
and in your button cells simply set the
accessibility label property to beat the
localized string that you wanted to be
and with just that low now a voice-over
user could be
be able to perceive this as a play
button
what makes it so easy well
with the new API which is a method based
API with Cumbernauld
attributes into properties sold just
like
any some object to see property
you could now yet and set the property
directly armed object itself see no
longer have to subclass
cell whenever possible your staff to
control
before any reason you can use apt-get
after controlling have to do your own
stuff like creating custom view for each
of the UI
when this case obviously was over a long
nap yet to see anything on the screen
scenario wondering great is a lot more
have to do
well the good thing is
s just as easy if used to spread your
API
you cunt any use to accessibility
property I just mention
I gave you an example Dr tweaking one
that the property the label property
there's tons a property CPU's but won a
talent for developers
knowing exactly which property you have
to implement
so now we've introduce accessibility
park all
that's designed to take that guesswork
out of the equation
ilk how the park also guide you through
the whole implementation process so you
know exactly which property you have to
implement
now we have forecast that should cover
most of the commonly
used type love you ice out there
so how do you go about implementing this
while farce you have to pick up or call
so we have a look at the park all seeker
choose from so you should pick one
that RESPA that corresponds to doesn't
look and
feel love you I the way Dr the function
love that you I
us so in our case we have example while
showing earlier with the play button
in looks and behaves like a button so
we're gonna pick the button protocol
sawyer interface filed simply say I here
to diana's
accessibility button
so now he at that you compile
the good thing is now exculpate compiler
will tell you
give you some warning and tell you what
you need to implement so in this case
are you have to implement the
accessibility perform Press
and accessibility label methods so it's
gonna do that
selling your implementation file simply
for the accessibility label
method just return a localized string
the were play
for the accessibility perform Press you
simply need to
perform the action a pressing a button
so what's next there's no next step
that's all that's just how easy is too
important an
accessibility even for custom view
so what makes it so easy what's because
packets doing a lot of work on your
behalf
by simply using this protocol ako what
inferred that
East elements are accessibility elements
and depending on which protocol you use
have Caleb on a popularly information
like what the role it
so if for example if I use the MS
accessibility
fun Procol ako wala macklin for Dad the
role for this
this button
size the to see how easy is to use I
also have her give you a little bit more
detail by these protocol
I am so the first mother's to Bass Pro
call
was what we call the MS accessibility
alman protocol
has a few require method like the
fraying and accessibility parent
dust-up basic information that all
accessibility Alysha half
and the bill on top of that we have all
the other protocols
like the button Procol I just talked
about which has
to require method accessibility label
inaccessibility perform Press
can St Salt earlier ex-cop compiler
already won its about
those methods
so that's just how easy a simple man a a
custom view
on by the way the Protocols of snow so
you don't have to implement
if you don't want to but it's relief
really can be
so let's go through another example
that's a little bit more complicated
on the screen you see are six different
in the shapes
the way to developer may have
implemented is simply a custom view
what they're doing their own drawing
safety have something like this
someone like a voice-over user was still
need to be able to know that there's six
this think you I sitting on a screen
so you have two rappers again and
accessibility representation
foot each other image that's been purse
play on the screen
so how do you do that for you I stagger
rendering yourself
and you don't have a in as few backing
well for the interview who are from the
lowest I'll all simple call we have
something call for you our men
and now with the new API we have a
formalized version
that car and this accessibility helmet
you can use this class to support all
the issue I've that do not have a back
in s few
so let's see how you go about
implementing thats
sell for the example earlier with the
image
the six shape images foot each of those
in a you want to create an NS
accessibility
Alama instance for that
sell you create one of the sisters and
then he set up some of the accessibility
properties for that such as:
with the parent s what their role is
well in this case which is gonna say
these are
initial and then give it a unique label
and then set up with a friend this
so when that custom view containing
custom view is being asked for the
accessibility children
then this is where year returned your
array up NS accessibility
alumax
and one thing I do wanna know is you
should keep geese
I accessibility Alma alive as long as
they are
on-screen that's because assistive
suffer like voice-over
could be asking information about these
objects at anytime through I PC costs
so as long as there are screaming a
cash in a row
pic sub that was pretty simple even for
something like that where you
are rendering own UI so there might be a
few viewing audience who
may have already implemented
accessibility with it all API
your application you're wondering why
how does this apply to me
what he already at accessibility into
your application
there is no actual work for you you all
API ko will continue to work just fine
because the new API as binary and source
compatible
so you don't have to worry up but if you
do you like to try out the new
API and we do encourage you to do so
you could continue to do so the whole
Cole will continue to work alongside
the new code
so I just told you why should make your
application accessible
and a run through a few examples houten
use this brainy API to make some UI
successful
you saw how quickly and easily wheeling
we were able to
a meets all the threes
examples that show you
and it really is fast anoche sometime
for you to develop and making sure your
act as accessible
cell with some eckstein you may have my
hand I really hope you could take some
of that time too
do some testing because after all
no the co you act you wanna make sure
you will be
usable by everyone so how do you go Bell
and making sure that your app is
accessible
after you make those changes what we
have to toss it to use
the first test accessibility inspector
this is a tool that display all the
accessibility information for
any piece %uh view i'd is currently on
that the mouse
and with the new OS for share after
inspector
will now displayed their accessibility
properties
love that you I so this is really
helpful so you know exactly which
properties he may need to treat
the second for we have
is called voice-over voice-over as a
screen reader
artist design for the visually
challenged users to be able to
explore and interact with the content
have the screen can get the use else
will get feedback throws speech or
terrell
said how do you go about using less well
first you gotta turn are
if you just remembered the shortcut
command f5
now we turn our or it going to the
accessibility Prof paying
there's a enable voice over checkbox
simply check that and yucatan voice-over
are
so the very first time he turned voice
over our its gonna prompt you
to see if you wanna go tho tutorial cell
if you just click on the
learn click the Learn More button then a
run through a tutorial with you
so I really encourage you to try that
man through the tutorial
now voice-over SF very powerful tool
so has hundreds of commands but today
I'm gonna show you just five simple
commands he could use
to be proficient in testing with
voice-over
so the first that yes how you navigate
found one piece %uh view I to another
and thats control optional by errol for
just remember that once he have was
overturned on
any time you press Control and option
any other key pressed at the same time
what on a manic later
into voice over command
sup where contraption buyout got
annexing if you want to reverse
you do control option left arrow
if you wanna press a button are actively
something simply do control options
space
this is very similar to pressing space
be spacebar are something that has a
keyboard focus
and then we have to what commands wires
as intergroup which is contraption shift
on a roll
a relief group contraption shift apparel
so what is group well voice-over have
this concept
up group and it goes like this: if you
have on the screen
I am what I have on the screen is just
someone
when does not have you I while to two
people navigate quickly to
certain piece %uh view I nm Momin was
over have this concept
grouping so honest greasy three
different groups one is a toolbar
the other one is the tabla folders
Hassall a the collection
the love indigenous sought to be able to
interact or just no enter and exit these
group
like I said earlier he said he could
just press to enter group
or leave group command so was just the
five
voice-over commands along you should be
pretty good and testing with voice-over
so not that show you the tools and
run you through some example do a using
API dimple
simple man you are I am some the UI
example such young
earlier i would like to bring up presto
one to come up
to give you a like them all love making
the tic tac toe game
accessible
thanks patty hi my name is Chris and I'm
a software engineer on the OS 10
accessibility team
and I'm really excited to show you just
how simple and just how easy it is to
accessibility to your app
with our brand new API to do this
I've written a little to stop here and
it's it's a very simple game of
tic-tac-toe
so in this case the board is full the
game is over and says
the O player has won I can come in and
restart the game
out play some pieces on the board I can
even turn on the AI opponents in
and play against a taken flap this is
very simple application and I i want to
use this covers are launching point to
show you
how you wouldn't mind all the different
techniques the padded just told you
in this application but before I do that
I want to give you an idea of what this
application look like to someone who's
using voice over so they may have just
heard from social media that
this is the great new apt to have or
that you wrote in the wanna check it out
and this is our first experience with it
and want to keep that in mind
so I'm going to use the keyboard command
to turn on voice-over
so here two things have happened when I
turn voice over on you are currently on
attack element
the first is that the caption panel has
shown up in the bottom
are bottom corner and all this does is a
house all of the tax that's currently
being spoken
so this is really really helpful if I'm
collaborating
with someone who's using voice over and
they often have their speech kinda
really really fast
so here I can read all of the tax that
being spoken
helps me on collaborating the second
thing you'll see
is that there's a black box stronger
around the axe wins
label and we call this the voiceover
cursor you can kind of thing for doesn't
alternate keyboard focus
so just like I can produce space on a
keyboard focused on women to do
something with that element
when I press one of the many voice-over
commands keeper commands
that normally act on currently
voice-over focused element
so now what I'd like to do is turn on a
unload
in voiceover contract had commander and
all it allows me to do is just
explore the UI with my finger just like
voice over on iowa's
I can I move around the interface and
voice-over will speak
the descriptions all the items
underneath my finger
internet on what trackpad commander on
and down this going to explore around
the interface and you'll see a blue
circle where mime
wherever my fingers close button
minimize button damned zoom button great
so the tow bars looking good
but you'll notice anywhere where there's
no elements there's the sounding play it
says this is an empty space
tic-tac-toe kind titles gun
empty space here axe whens cat the label
shows up fine
more empty spaces are we've had our
first problem
there's nothing being reported here for
accessibility for this truck box
so this is one of the problems will have
to fix difficulty
difficulties 52 social level button
button
him to button button not delete 1.41
percent
so we saw there's a problem with the
bonds are just as bun
so far not decided you so I don't
understand what's going on with the fam
what to do when I click a
more empty space
and again the restart game month the
same way there's there's absolutely no
information for tough people do that
what about the grid while I had the same
problem here
the grid isn't even being reported
turquoise over of
so as you can see the user experience
for this application is quite poor
when using voice over a lot in the major
fun challenge for the top
just doesn't show up I can't play a
piece i cant restart the game account
I a cam played NCAA are you can I can
click the checkbox
and so what I'd like to do it take you
through each of these individual amounts
and show you how out to make them
accessible
so here's my Xcode project and before
even talk about the code
I just want to orient you to the Canada
layout at this project
so over here to the classic NBC style
apso have all my models and these are
the files
that encapsulated you know those tic tac
toe board in the game rules and
how what it means to win the game record
a touch any other model files here this
is the games that we don't need that
the next folder is all the views so we
have a lot to custom UI in this
application
and we need to use to backed them and
these are all the files are used to do
that
this is where we're gonna be spending a
majority over time in the code
now said the controller section the app
delegate is currently empty
and the tic tac to view controller is
the thing that hooks up all the UI
interactions with the model objects
the last thing and I want to point out
as the main menu Neb
this is the one and only need for this
entire project
and this is actually where we're gonna
start
to the first elements were gonna work on
are the plus and minus buttons here for
the difficulty
if you remember this is one of the items
that we could land on but there's no
contextual information about
what these buttons dan so I'd like to
show you how to add accessibility to
time two different with
the first is actually quite simple I I'm
just going to select
that element and Interface Builder and
end up in the top right
I can open up the panel and the third
icon from the locked is the identity
inspector
and in here as the accessible the
identity information:
this is we're going to add the
description for the spine
so what does this button do well when I
click it it decreases the difficulty
some gather I'm just contact on here
great not allowed to do very simple
so what about if I decided I want to do
the same thing
but in code well turns out that's really
simple to
taking over to my view controller
and my week from near here I can play
out the button cell
and I have an outlet
2.1 and then I can use one of the new
accessibility property is to just sad
the accessibility label
and remember you always want to %uh
localize the strings
and this is the increase difficulty
button
I'm just glad that in
okay just like that that's all I need to
do and
our without now in a voiceover user
lands on his plus-minus puns
will be writers the increased difficulty
or the decrease difficulty button
so why do we get that accessibility for
free why did they even show up in the
first place
won't this custom classes actually
subclasses and thats button
so we've done a lot to work behind the
scenes to be fixable the in
to all the standard up controls so
whenever possible try to use those cuz
we done as much work as possible for you
the one thing you need to do is just add
a description which is which is quite
simple
so now we've worked on the plus or minus
buttons let's move on to the restart
game button
now you might recall that this was one
other item side by nothing was reported
there for accessibility
let's take a look at why
so have a class with button and the
first thing I immediately notice
isn't it in and ask you some class son
doing a lot of actual work behind the
scenes
to make this view act and look like a
bum this includes all my own keyboard
and
now so than handling as walls hold my
own drying
handing out on an extra work here while
how do I am accessibility to the so on
turns out it's also quite simple all I
need to do his pic
the accessibility protocol that best
represents the subject
and the protocol for this as the an ass
accessibility
button protocol none other from conform
to that protocol
I can move into my infant Asian file
and the first thing I see if I get to
new warnings
so this is really really helpful for me
because now I know exactly what I need
to implement
to at accessibility to the south custom
control
to the two methods here are accessible
the label and accessibility perform
props
sought to take those one at a time
have a section here for accessibility
and the first one
is accessible the label
tree now what do I want to be returned
here
I happen to know that this bun is only
ever used to
draw the restart game 1 so the label for
this is just going to be restarted
at the
to now I can go back up to the top in my
file a nurse at warning has gone away
so only have one more matter to
implement and that accessibility perform
Press
for to do that warm prompt:
so what should happen here well when I
use the mouse to interact with the
spartan
when I click it something happens right
that seem something should happen
when an accessible declined so pay I
want to activate this item
so in my case I happen to have
in method compress down or perform press
rather
and perform crosses what gets called
when the mouse hand in large excels
yes this button has been pressed so I
want to call that same exact method
now you notice accessible to perform
price return
returns a boolean and this is a yes or
no did I handle this
a band and and always handle in so yes I
return
yes and with that I can go back up to
the top in my file
and I C all of my mornings have gone
away Sutter
the protocol has got me through what I
need to do that accessibility
implemented our and I'm from another
are the slower rate sections finished I
want to work on the artificial
intelligence
checkbox if you recall again this was
another element that was invisible to
accessibility at all
so I have my header file here for the
check box
and again I see the same situation I
haven't the button
it's an an issue some cock so do a lot
of work
to make it look and act like a checkbox
some this case
and you to pick a protocol in the
protocol for this
the Anna success ability checkbox
protocol
and now
when I go into my implementation file I
get a few new warnings
to this tells me what I need to do to
make the check box accessible to the
three warnings I have here
accessible the value accessible the
label
and accessibility perform price semantic
those
I one at a time to the first one
and we've seen this one before the
excitable the label something to that
first
so what should be the label for the
strike box
well this is a control diet designed I
follow my reuse
I in other places factually haven't I've
are around that keeps the check box
taxed
and this is the string actually gets
rendered an and Ron are in the dryer act
math and
so I can just return
the check box text here great
for my morning has gone away the next 1i
want to work on
is accessibility perform Press so just
like the bond money
interact with us control using the mouse
something happens
it and changes the checked state I need
that same something to happen
when the trouble to clients say hey I
want to interact with the filament
so that's the accessibility perform
price
and I have
a method called title track stain and
this is what it's called
from the mass handling logic and just
like with the bun
return yes I didn't fact handle birth
thus action not to go back up to the top
issue that I still have one
more methane you to implement and this
is acceptable devalue
at this point I ask myself all what is
the value for a check box where my
supposed to return
refer to really really hard to try to
answer all these questions in one place
we tried to make and a successful the
protocol file
the one stop shop for this missus were
all the protocols are implementing
are defined so in another tower how the
spur close file
and there's the and a successful the
check box protocol right here
and I see under the required methods the
excitable the value
returns an annus number okay so the
answer is my first question
and says I return yeah subtract or know
if I'm track
great it's not have this information
can come down here and implement an
actor
so here I have another
I I've are around which is and I checked
or not and I can use that to return
yeah or no
return
okay snacking a back up to the top in my
file I see all the warnings have gone
away
so this is all I need to do to him from
and accessible checkbox
to now the entire right hand side over
application
has added the Sun basic a class ability
to it so let's work on the next part
which is the grid and this is perhaps
the most difficult part
again I'm gonna go back into my project
and I have a a view representing the
board
means the board for you and here I
notice it again
nanosphere some doing all of my own
drawing here and in fact this class
draws the board and all the pieces so
and it made a successful and I need to
pick a protocol now to what protocol
do I need well the way that I like to
think about the tic tac toe board
it's really a collection up squares rain
every time I interact with the border
it's not so much a bored I wanna play
the square I want to put my piece there
I want to get three no
bro to win I want to block my opponent
from getting three in a row and so this
the sport is really a collection to me
and the way that that's
the protocol that you can use to
represent that the CNS accessibility
group
protocol it's a collection of things
great
to now go to my implementation file and
i notice I have
no warning showing up
and no one's so does this mean while
I have no required methods that they
need to implement for the acceptable
degree protocol
by just like with Reese what we saw the
other elements
I can still and accessibility to and I
so what's the first thing I want to do
while the board you when I land on its a
group
and i won some label to describe it to
just like with all the other controls
I'm going to add I'll a label here
inaccessible the labels very simple so
what am I gonna return here
while just it's the tic tac toe board
some the voiceover
actress for land on the third south this
at the tic tac toe board group
okay so have a group had contains things
fall
what are these things the individual
squares
but you to the squares doesn't have a
backing view to them
so I need to create some object to
represent 22 accessibility
and the way that we've done this is with
the anna's accessibility
element patty should win the slides how
you treat instanceof this in line
and what I've chosen to do here's
discrete a subclass a bit in another
file
so I have a subclass here
called the tic-tac-toe square
accessibility element
and the subclass I love and a successful
the element
has one initializer which takes a row or
column in the delegate
and has three properties a row or column
in a delegate
the delegate method are the delegate
is just a class that can answer
questions about hey what pieces
are at this location on the board is the
game over is that still in progress
to cancel all the questions that this
piece is going to need
had to ask so have the element
representing an
mall I'm gonna pick a protocol now to
use to implement it
so what bast encapsulates what a squared
us
but when I click on it something happens
like
place my piece there I put my piece area
player great
Allah and elements where you click them
to interact with them and they do
something about month
I can conform to the accessibility
button protocol here
and now when I move into my
implementation file
again a buncha warnings for the items
that I need to implement
to the fore warnings I get here are
accessible the parent
label reform process and frame need to
be and
important in semitic is one at a time
for or the frame
and for the parent Anderson return
whatever my super classes implementation
of
some point is we need to be sad so keep
that in mind defensible the labels a
little bit more interesting
and this is the description for
particular square
so I'm going to do ask my delegated
for hey what's the square at my row and
column and this is actually an instant
for the model
object representing a square on the
board and then
I can ask the board using one of its
class methods
was the description for the square so
this is going to return something like
this is and axe square at the top ride
turn
00 square in the centre or an empty
square at the bottom left
and a so when a land on the Salman
that's what I want to be spoken
up and in the last night the menu to
implement as accessibility perform price
so when this item is priced what should
I do while I wanna play my piece there I
wanna play that's
where I wanna make my mark their and my
delegate knows how to play a square in a
row and column some just gonna ask it to
do that and again
return yes I handled the salon so I can
go back up to the top of my file
and I see that all the warnings have
gone away such great
have now a class that represents an
individual square
for accessibility that doesn't have a
backing view so now I need to go back to
my group
I need to create instances up this class
to represent each square some back in my
board view
I want to say this a group house
children
views elements and the way to do that
with
rupi is to override the accessibility
children Mattoon
some gonna walk through
it looks like a lot occurred I promise
it's not gonna walk through it line by
line with the Stars
so the first thing is I'm
overriding accessible to children right
so I'm
the accessible to children gather and
returning an array from
and I have this I've are around so if
I've already created my children don't
need to create them again
if i havent I create an array to hold
all of Rd Trussville the children
and I set up two variables are many
using under my competitions
now wanting to do is create an instance
about accessibility element
for every square on the board some kinda
I'm
iterate over all the rows and all the
columns
and then instantiate 10 those accessible
the elements for the square
now remember that the parent in the
frame we're just returned as whatever
super classes implementation once
so I need to make sure that they're such
somewhere and that's why I'm gonna do it
here
so I can certainly try to build the
parent using a property and I just said
to myself because the parent
have a square is the board
and they need to set the frame typically
the accessibility frames
always been given in screen coordinates
and important for us because that's what
we use to draw a voice-over cursor
around a particular element I'm we were
thinking about this
with the new API in saying no be really
cool if we could just say here's my
friend
relative to my parent and they don't
have to do any work when the window
moves her my parent was around to
recalculate my frame
and screen space so we've added the
snakes convenience property to
and a successful the element as colic
sensibility freemen parent space and it
does exactly that
I can calculate the actual are tracked
that I'm using during the
for drawing and thats a given in my
parents pace
and I can suck that as the accessible
the freemen parents face and now
whenever something moves we have enough
information are on hour and
to recalculate where the frame its you
don't have to do any of that bookkeeping
so now we've created the successful the
element for each square
you want to make sure that we at the
mall to the array in the study said
you want to make sure that you cash
these elements so
at any point I'll in your applications
lifetime where this
I am has been drawn on screen the
accessible the
element representing it has to be there
for trust building to be able to query
and then lastly remember we overrode the
gather here
so need to make sure re actually return
these children
so it and I can go back up to the top in
my file and I down just made this really
complicated you I
accessible must not not much extra work
I see that all my warnings have gone
away we didn't have any warnings here
for example
but this is now added a basic level
accessibility to my app
and so let's take a look at power what
that looks like now
in the way I'm gonna verify that my
changes worked
is by using one which was pretty much in
italics us a building inspector
you can launch it from the Xcode menu
under open developer tool
an excess a building inspector
and again what this does is it shows you
the accessibility information
for the item under the mouse so here
there there's
three sections that are showing up the
very top
is the accessibility hierarchy so if
this is analogous to scan like the view
hierarchy
if you're such a bill the omens are
inaccessible the hierarchy they're not
can be available to accessibility
clients
much like a view to find the view
hierarchy won't be shown
the next sections the attributes for
these are all the properties that we've
now added
onto accessible the elements and you can
see each other values
Khan and there's also some some more a
complicated ones like prime tries
attributes
so the very first thing that we worked
on was the plus or minus one
remember this was to increase and
decrease the difficulty we need to
decide to label their
has a standard app to control I'm
and I can see is that dick sucked you
down here is showing up as decreased
difficulties this has got me know that
this
elements now labeled it's going to be
spoken when it's not gay but voice-over
same thing with the increased difficulty
bun
the label as as there which is gone
what about the restart game button I
remember this wasn't even available to
accessibility
and now we see that in the hierarchy is
inaccessible the button
and also has a label a restart game
disagree it's gonna be read on as a
restart game button
similarly with the check box it's now in
the view hierarchy which is
which is awesome so I'll show up to
acceptable the client's
it says that the check box it has a
label love AI opponent
and now the grid so the grid shows up as
a group
and I wanna be acceptable the proper
uses the accessible to children
and we see that has nine items and
they're all bonds
so if you take a look at just one button
it says it has i
it's in the hierarchy as well as it has
a label for its the empty top
of next one South MT top
and to top right you'll notice here also
there's a an action section on the bond
same perform Prasanth
this is what this almond supports for
actions Sosa
that actually really great okay so now
that I've
audited my app with excess a building
inspector I'm fairly certain that the
personally I've implemented
is correct so now I'm gonna turn on
voice over I'm gonna order that using
voice over
voice over on tic-tac-toe tic-tac-toe
window
a high pollen uncheck checkbox has
keyboard focus
great so we can now land on the element
check an opponent checkbox
I can activate it difficult decrease
difficulty
button Press Press Press decrease
button the buns are labeled them they
support the ACF increased effect
restart game button Press restart game
button you can press to reset the game
if I have a game in progress
big tax tic tac toe board group I also
land on the board group
interact with tic tac toe board group
nine items
empty top left button and I can move
into the script to see the different
power
peace and the top button now by place
apiece they're using activate options
Press ext top button MD top left button
Press X top left button I'm so over of
I can play a full game of tic-tac-toe
now this is really exciting and I hope
you seen that
was just a few lines of code which
really walk you through what you need to
do that
add accessibility to something something
like this
and I hope you really see that the level
the castle is quite drastic
before there's hardly any in and now
there's on us for support
so there's a couple more things that you
can do here
to make this app even more excitable
Minister point out one
suppose for example that I'm playing
this game with
a a user who is using voice over and
they're on the check box
focuses on the check box they can
activity I am using
Command Option space but I can also go
in and click the checkbox with my maps
so how does a voice-over user know if
I've change the state of something
out from underneath them while we solve
this problem using accessibility
notifications
and this has been some questions about
which ones do I use wonder I use than
and we really tried to answer that with
the new protocols file
so again this is your one-stop shop and
you can really go back there
and here in the check box protocol
declaration there's a comment which
tells me about the notifications on you
to post
son this case it sells the accessibility
value change notification
needs to be posted whenever the
accessibility value changes
recall that search act or unchecked
state
so for any point changes for any reason
I need her
are some this notification as really
easy to do
min go back to my check box you if you
recall we had the title track stay and
missus
work on activated when used the
accessibility activate action
and here's where need to push the
notification I can be there with
and its accessibility post notification
the element this notification should be
associated with us the check box itself
and the notification type as an annus
accessibility
value change notification at a
so again from the more advanced
accessible via items now
done actually take that much more code
you there
and so now if you were to run the shop
again and your clobbering with the
voiceover use on you click to bun
there now be announced the new state
will now be announced to them
so that's the end that the demo now and
I hope what you've seen is that we've
tried to make it
as easy as possible for you
out accessibility with our new API
I should also mention dad we have
a sample app you may have seen from
Patna college you accessible DUI
examples
and what it is is a collection are all
different types of elements
so here there's a button taxed images
we also have more complicated you I like
layout areas
collapsible outline views people views
and what we've done
is implemented you should use using
different methods so for example
subclassing from a standard app controls
making and
a subclass a tentative you but also Open
GL CA layers we have examples for all
those
and for this release we've gone through
ripped out the excess ability that we
had
and additive right back in with the new
API and what we found was a drastic
code savings many many fewer lines of
code
and we hope to do is have this available
as a reference for you say hey I want
learn how to use this protocol
you have an example on a concrete
implementation I we've done
this is available along with the
tic-tac-toe app on developer dot dot dot
dot com
today please go check it out download it
we also have
in this particular example a nice read
me file the house
have a developer quick start on how to
use our API
so with an and summary really took this
release to think about
how can we make it easier to
accessibility to your application
and what we came away with was a
brand-new really easy to use API
and is really easy to use because all
the accessible the attributes
are now property is on the object for
the really easy to set up
house at the trouble the protocols which
guide you through
the items that you need to implement in
order to meet your custom
you I a trustable and then lastly we
formalize the four you own a cloth
into an a successful the element and
there for you
to be accessible the backin object when
there's no UI view 4 and her an issue
back in
would like to encourage you to test with
voice over it ships with every Mac
and its a great way for you to see what
our customers are going to experience
using assistive technology with your
application
if you'd like to just an empty bag a
little bit more
we have accessible inspector there to
really getting at what exactly is going
on with your
accessibility element and lastly
we want to support you in this
transition to the new API
we really want to contribute encourage
you to use it and so we built is really
great developer examples that we've been
that we've now released and we hope you
can use as a reference
cash for your implementation
if you'd like more information about our
team works of the building
our framework in general please feel
free to reach out to our
ap frameworks a band or strict parents
his emails barron's on
Apple to come if you have more technical
questions
can take a look at the documentation and
developer Apple dot com
as well as ask questions on the dub
forums
if you like this session and your
interest in finding out how accessible
the works
on our other platforms there's a new
accessibility and IR suction
in this room right after this
presentation and then our web
accessibility
presentation on Friday at 9am
thank you so much for coming to our
session really appreciate you being here
and from all the sample we hope you have
a fantastic rest at WWDC
thank you very much