I my name is really been a I'm the entry
matter
on the client side
so up until today
Apple had me i cud technologies and a
loop like
this to you we had i car driver i cud
Chordata iPod the library
and how they interacted with the iPod
the
Apple icon server was kinda miss through
said today were
lifting sum up the mystery
in increasing pocket so let's look at
this
what we're going to cover here in the
session so first we're going to start
with
what is cloud kids we're going to walk
are you through the couple of steps you
need to enable market in Europe cation
and start using it
we're going you walk through with the
different
API's we're going to talk about
how pocket and tracked with the Apple
the iPad user accounts
and last but not least we'll cover
when to use cloud kid as opposed to
other existing
iPod API's we already have on the pipe
bombs
so let's start with his pockets
I you'll notice the new batch but the
whole session is new so it's your only
on that slide
and clock is the way to give you access
to our cloud servers
and we really mean it's at
clock is the foundation for both I Club
Drive
an iPod for library both teachers were
written from scratch
on top of pocket cock is supported on
those
Western and I O S it's a new public
frame or pocket that free markets
check it out yes UK clock its uses
yeah I clarke ounce infrastructure debt
means that
if there's a logged in I clout counts
on the device will use that to attend
fide
the user if there's non will provide
read only unanimous access
clock it supports both
a concept of public and private
databases you can see public databases
as a superb day dad that's all you user
can access
to private databases are meant to stored
the the actual data just don t have a
specific user
clark et support both structured and all
data
you can use it to store large falls on
the on
I cloud servers and we'll take care of
the transmitting them efficiently
happen from the icon servers importantly
clout kids is a transport technology it
does in providing local persistence
its enables you to send and receive data
from the servers
so let's start
how do you enable more clout kids in
your application
so first you're launching a gate Europe
cations capabilities pain in Xcode
see that big I cloud off switch you want
to turn on
and you on issued checked the car kit
check box here
at that point already there's no
four-step
your app is reach you read and write
data to
Apple's iPod server and to walk you
through the PRI on how to do this
I'm going to hand over to Paul to chat
about it
thank you Maria so as Libby said my
name's Paul
I work on the clout to climb from work
and I'm very excited to talk you guys
today
about cloud cap we're gonna start of
organist are talking about the
fundamental clark et objects
these are going to be the set of objects
that your initially exposed to you
when you open up and start playing with
the craft kit framework jus running for
a quick list to them
we're going to talk about containers and
we're going to talk about databases
we're going to talk about records we're
going to talk about
record zones and record identifiers
we're going to talk about references and
we're going to talk about assets
it's quite a list this is gonna be a
really fun and really jam-packed session
so let's get started let's get started
and we're gonna talk about containers
this is sort of the idealized model up
your application talking I clout
arm know you guys are application
developers you gotta climb developers
and you know what that your application
running on the client
whether that client is a iPhone
wetherbee a mac book
yours is not the only process running on
the client rather yours is one of many
now on your client your process is going
to be
silence the Inbox in some ways I in some
cases it to you
literal sandbox certainly in others
running your own memory space
this concept of taking your client
actually running it separated from other
clients
is pretty powerful it is not a couple
damages
it helps with security it also stability
and it helps the privacy
so as we're figuring out how we want to
Bill Clark it we thought to ourselves
how can you take the
you three advantages and replicate them
up in the server
and so here's what we did just as your
client is one of many
I'm sorry your application is one of
many running on the client
so too depart if I call that you're
talking to is one of many up on I clout
arm week all these different silos
containers
so containers containers are exposing
the coated free-market
as the CK container class CK's are
prefixed you can see this all over the
place
by default one application talk to one
container
containers afford us the ability to
segregate data
means that your application can read and
write data type cloud
another application can read and write
it i cloud and the two data sets up on
the server will not be intermingled
in addition to desegregation this
containers asiana I cloud storage allows
us to encapsulate user information
now as we mentioned Clark it involves
using the I card account infrastructure
and we want to give you some limited
access to that i cud account
and we want to make sure that we're
doing so in a problem privacy
conscientious manner
so in order to do that we encapsulate
user information
user information available to your
application is going to be container
scoped
and therefore different and the the
viewer user information seen by another
application
containers are managed by you the
developer you can be managing them
view the WWD our portal it's important
to note
that the namespace the love containers
is global to all developers
so when you choose a name for your
container make sure that you're using it
University in
you're using a reverse DNS name
now a right up there just like a little
while ago I said that
by default there is one container to one
application the one to one mapping
we think that this is going to be
successful for 99 percent abuse cases
and certainly as you go start using
cloud it's going to be great as you
start exploring the framework
but we recognize there are some
scenarios were you need a more complex
mapping
so we support many many model we mean is
that multiple applications can
coordinate
on the same II clout container also
a single application can talk to
multiple like our containers
on the databases what are the chief
purpose is a cloudy is the ability to
take your object model in your
application
and replicate that up to the server and
so when we start thinking about how we
want to present is modeling to you
we thought to ourselves how can we
divide up application objects
obviously all objects in my application
are not treated equally
and one of the first things that we
noticed was that is a fundamental
difference
in the the audience of data
some data is intended to be used by the
user that created it
if you imagine an application where I'm
writing up notes and i wanna see my
notes everywhere else that's my data
I created I consume it on the other hand
there are others use for what we call
public data this is data that can be
a created by the user for the benefit of
the community
think perhaps a review on a restaurant
or could be information that you the
developer has uploaded I cloud because
it's useful to your application
in either case the audience is not a
single user but a community of people
so how do we solve the fact that we've
got these different types of data
with break open container and have a
look inside
inside a container you gonna notice
first and foremost the public database
this is the soup this is where all the
public and community to
cool Lipscomb Ingles additional you're
gonna notice that there's private
databases
and you're going to find there's
individual private database for each
user
your application now this is where the
fifty thousand foot overview of what the
I cloud infrastructure looks like but
you know how much you guys care about
that would you guys are interested in is
what is this infrastructure look like to
me the client running on a phone are
running on a Mac
obviously you're only going to have
access to the currently logged in I
cloud user
the rather than seeing a public database
in a good deal in private databases
your views gonna look a little more like
this you can have a choice between a
public database
or the private database that is
correlated to the currently logged a
nightclub user
so databases databases are exposing our
EP I
as a CK database class every application
is access to them
the public and the proper with have a
look at a little bit of code
the container is the initial entry point
into clout kept
here we see that I'm talking to my
default container and getting its public
database
I can also talk to the default container
get a private database
which have a look at the differences
between these two databases
as we mentioned the desired audience is
going to be different
between the public address on the
privateers the public BB is per share
data
the private TV is for the users own data
as such we have different requirements
for whether or not and i cud account
needs to exist
on the client in the private database
since I'm
reading and writing a user's data if we
have no notion of the user
that is if you don't have a login i cud
account there's really no utility in
moving this information to and from
there
the server so we require and i cud
account to be logged in if you want to
use the private database
in the public database since the
audience is more communal we'll are you
read only anonymous access to the public
database
you'll recall from yesterday's talk that
Clark it is free with minutes so we've
got some
pretty aggressive quotas that being said
we still need to account
for weird it is being used so that we
can talk to you when we start
approaching those limits
a data stored in a public database is
accounted for on the developer's corner
data stored in the private databases
accounted for on the user's korda
by default data written to the public
databases world readable
detour into the private database is use
a readable again it's the users own data
so
they're really the only ones to have
access to it in the private database
we recognize that editing that world
readable is not an appropriate
permission for a lot of data in the
public database
so we give you the ability to edit these
permissions on a record class
level the mechanism by which edit these
permissions is something that we call
the I cloud dashboard roles
i cud dashboard is the administrative
interface into clapped
I but you got to come back on Thursday
for the advanced talking go into a lot
of detail about the the dashboard
suffice it to say there's an ability to
set the seals so that a user is a member
verbal
and the role can have a certain enlarged
access to a class of records
in the private database things start out
lockdown there's no need at them
the users who we want to create a to end
users going to be worried that data
and when I see that the user is going to
be able to read that data I really mean
it
you is the developer do not have access
into somebody else's private database
their data is their own right to those
databases
let's talk about records
I'm so here's our model that we have so
far we've got a container within
containers are databases
let's keep going down the rabbit hole
crack open a database inside the
database we see that it's for records
records are exposing our framework is
the CK record class
there the mechanism by which you move
structured data
to and from clark et CK records rap
key/value pairs lest you think that a CK
record is just a glorified dictionary
there are some additional attributes
that make it worthwhile is being its own
class
to start off with records have a record
type: if Clark it is a mechanism by
which you take your object graph from
your application
and moving into Clark Kent and would
continue that analogy
instance of an object in your
application is equivalent to tourists
instanceof a CK record similarly the
class of the object
in your application is equivalent to the
record type:
the CK record
records have a just in time schema you
do not need to talk about it about what
your day looks like before you headed
before you hand crafted your data and
issue date it will figure it out
clark et season seek a record also
supports a raft a
meta-data for example ABC a record
understands when it was created
who created it it understands when a
record was last modified
who last modified and lastly a record
contains the notion
to change tack a change tag is a virgin
a record in dade represent a specific
revision of this record
an issue so that we can have a
lightweight way determining whether or
not the client to server have the same
version of a record
let's talk a bit about little bit about
record values CK records rap key/value
pairs
what are the acceptable value type C
important to seek a record
well we've got your usual suspects your
Youkilis types
strings your numbers your date is in
your dates we think
that especially the public database
domain location is an interesting
scenario
so see location is a native type you can
set on a CK record
you can set CK references and CK assets
were gonna go over what those are just a
moment
and Leslie me tell you can be a single
instance I could have a string
or dates were can be a homogeneous
terrain I can have an array of numbers
or in a rave CK assets
which have a look at a lil bit of code
here with you seek a record seek a
record initializer takes a record high
because at the
invaluable necessary piece of a record
you can
for said objects and get our checks from
a record using a dictionary syntax
were a key that subscribing syntax we
also give you the ability to enumerate
ok he's on a record so you can dump the
entire key/value pair
with have a look at a specific example
now throughout the stalk my example is
going to be an application that created
for me my friends
this application allows us to create
pardons and we're gonna stick party
records in the public database
it's gone a party might be a structured
data it's gonna have a summary a start
date and end date
I am I also have additional metadata
that we associate with it
pictures at the party et cetera so
how do I create a party record well a
great one just as you might imagine with
the party record
with the party record time I can now set
values on it
and I can reveal use from it using
either dictionary or keep subscribing
syntax
the records let's talk about records
owns
some this is the model that we've just
presented and it was kind of a lie but
was a useful lifetime
arm so a records
had don't exist by themselves just has
objects in your application don't just
by themselves is gonna be a natural
grouping objects within your application
similar we similarly we won a way to
express this grouping
in cloud cap fundamentally we're trying
to be a clerk at to take as much if
you're
knowledge about your object graph and
reflect that up to the server
so the way that we group records is
really something that we call a record
zone
there can be multiple records within a
record zone and there can be multiple
records zones within a database
every database has the default records
on
some databases support additional
customer exams
record zones are the default granularity
which are going to do atomic
commits and change tracking its other
there's an interesting to you and put
you back on Thursday for the offense
talk we're gonna go over hold on to that
so those were records arms what's on my
record identifiers
record identifiers get caught up there
are a tubal
the represented both the client provided
record name
and also the zone in which that record
name exists
so what are their characteristics number
one they're created by the client
um you get to specify the the idea
the record name up the record but
because we are
coupling this record name which is
scoped her records own
along with the reference to the owning
records on
they become a fully normalize
representation on the record
its before path to it
we think that it's going to be fairly
common for you try and bridge in
external data set
into clout if you're doing so and if
your external data set has a unique key
on using the unique E as the CK record
id:
allows you to have a foreign key back
into your external data set
totaling approved usage let's have a
look at some code
here we are you know creating a record
if you're not already
and we got multiple initializes for CK
record you can either choose to provide
as a record id: where you can choose not
to
if you choose not to provide a record
id: we're going to assign arena
UUID to the record also note here that
when I created my record id: I chose not
to give it to the ozone
throughout corporate API if you choose
not to give us a record zone
we're going to assume that you meant the
default zone so here
I am creating a record id: with the name
a well-known party
that exists within the default zone so
does a record ID's
now let's talk about references just as
there's a natural groupings
records that we want to expose be a
record zone is also gonna be a natural
relationship between objects
for example let's say that in addition
to being able to read %uh parties I can
find different clones
parties because what is the point to the
party if you don't have a few claims
so I heard one some way above
representing this
a the object relationship that I have
between parties and clowns up to the
server
and we we do that is you something that
we call references
now you note here that in this contrived
example
parties own clowns that is we've got a
parent-child relationship
with the party is apparent in the clown
as a child and that the reference goes
from the the child object from the clown
up to its parent object
we call that a back reference
references are exposing our EP I as the
CK reference class
they are away when the server understand
the relationship between records
when the server understands the
relationship between records they can do
very interesting things
such as cascade elites if the REC if the
server notices that you've deleted
the record and that record is the parent
in a parent-child relationship
the server will automatically go ahead
and cascade delete all the children of
that I'd
with any database this scope and scale
of clout cat
dangling pointers are going to become
unnecessary an inconvenient truth about
your use a cracka
arm by the time you such a record and
you read a reference
when you go and fetch the target of that
reference that target may not exist
so it's important that your code is
resuming into this
again as I mentioned you up for back
references it's not a requirement but
it's more efficient
if references go from child objects to
parent objects:
this is the tip of the iceberg in a very
large topic called data modeling
on and if you come back on Thursday were
gonna tell you a whole bunch about data
modeling and Clark a
with have a look at some code here we
see my creating a reference between
to seek a record instances that I have
in memory
but it's not necessary that I have the
target a reference in memory
I can make a reference that point at a
record id:
this allows me to refer to a record that
I got you know reason to believe exists
up on the server
if I were to say this record and the
target didn't exist that actually be
creating
dangling pointer and that's okay because
the code you're going to write is going
to support
and be resilient in the face sitting
with pointers
so those references now let's talk about
assets
here we have a model again just a
refresher container database record
and now let's take the the idea that I
want to write a
record I wanna read a party record up to
the server let's say that I want to
associate a large file with that record
would say for example that we're going
to have a get together after
presentation
and I'm gonna redo a screenplay that
I've been working on
now I know I understand that there's
different characteristics between these
different leaders
I understand that the record about the
party's is structured
you know it's got a summer you've got a
start date and end date
and you just innately I believe that I
want the server to understand does
those bits about the record if you
contrast that
to the screenplay well the screenplay is
just essentially a back up its
right I don't feel any real need to tell
the server how much can play breaks down
into amazing acts and you know dashing
scenes
but I do know that I want to treat them
as just an opaque bag
so how do we solve this Lawrence all
this and we're going to
we're gonna solve the fact that it has
different characteristics like this
in two different ways upon the server
we're going to introduce a notion that
we call book
storage as you might expect bookstore
just great for storing
book data similarly on the client
you're going to tell clark et about the
different characteristics if your data
by treating some a bit as a CK record
and other bits of it as a CK asset
ICP Asset is the representation of his
bag of dicks
now when you ask like to save this
record the profits are going to go on
the appropriate database
structure data in the public database
book data in bookstore
so assets assets are exposing our
framework
as the CK asset class they represent
large
unstructured data because you don't
necessarily want large unstructured data
in memory
the way you communicate assets 21 from
Clark it is your files on disk
assets are owned by records this gives
us a nice tight coupling between a
record in an asset
with this allows the server to do is
garbage collector assets
even though that we're storing the state
into separate areas
when the server to Texas the lead for
record you can go ahead and let me clean
up any assets that were owned by that
record
lastly because we expect seek asset to
be large a pic data
we go through some great things to try
and move that data to and from the
server as efficiently as possible
this is also the inside a cloud get
we're gonna send only the pics that
the minimal amount of bets that we can
let's have a look at some code here in
creating a asi que asset based on file
URL to my screenplay on desk
and just like any other seek a record
value support in class
I'm setting in on seek a record
so these are the fundamental objects in
cloud cap the first thing you talked to
was a container
within a container to different
databases databases contains records
records are wrapped in group within
record zones you identify record via a
record identify your I records are
related to one another via
references and large book data is
transmitted to and from Clark it be a
Sikh assets
alright because me through the nouns now
it's getting to the burbs for
clerk it we offer two different API's
for using cloud get
we call them the operationally PI and
convenience API the operational EPI
has every single bill was for you might
while care about
arm and in some cases the you're gonna
want to tweak
every single don't whistle to fit your
applications model
but not every application really wants
to do all this tweaking
and not every application has enough
knowledge to set these bets correctly
sometimes you want to let the framework
make some of these decisions on your
behalf
and so on we offer the convenience API
it's convenient it's gonna be what you
do I want to start of playing with when
you start looking at Club ca
for many uses a crowd its although
you're going to need touch
so quickly we're gonna go over how you
save a record in the community API
pay fetcher record from the server via
the community PI and how you can take
even saved fetched a record modify it
and save it back up to the server
let's start of a saving a record
here in creating a record you guys are
now very well familiar with this
when I wanna see the record I have to
choose which database I want to save it
into here I'm going to save the date
into the public database
and how do I do that well I call the
same record with completion handler
method now I want you guys to note three
separate things about this
this code right here first ball it's
very simple
right you guys are providing a lot of
options your delegating a lot of the
bells and whistles like
how important is this what interview
should I send this data over
you delegating the choices of the clock
second its a synchronous as Libyan
mention the car kit does not have
local persistence we r transport
technology we're gonna transported up to
the server
stored on the server and transported
back down other clients
so when you see the record via clark et
we're going to attend to say that record
directly to the server
if it fails we're going to tell you
about that immediately for you know as
quickly as we can
now we don't want to block fred's and we
don't want you to block the user
so we don't wanna make this a sickness
call so here we can a synchronous call
now the third thing I want you to know
is that even though this is a very
simple method
we do provide an error as part of the
call back now
if you've been to WWC in the past or if
you watch any presentations using
something that looks like this
get Apple Developer appear and the Apple
developer says
you need to hit 0 errors their return
from our framework
no I'm not going liars it's true you do
need to handle where is returned from
frameworks
in many applications it's the difference
between you know a good and functioning
application and a great application
Clark it is a little bit different Clark
it by its very nature is gonna be
talking over the network
networks are inherently lossy phones
like the fall of a network of time
so in Cloquet the difference between
handling a reverse is not a millionaire
is really the difference between a
functional in a nonfunctional ap
their handling has got to be one of the
first things that you look at when you
start using Kaka I'm gonna be a little
too glib throughout the slides here but
every time she comment imagine what
you're seeing just some really nice
a rambling
so let's talk about never received a
record up to the server how do we set a
record back down from the server
I'm gonna start by deciding which
database I want to touch a record from
and then going to construct a record id:
the identifiers the record I can affect
down here I've gotten this name
either be some side channel or something
it's built in my application
I then can ask the database to fetch a
record with ID with completion handler
again a synchronous simple amazing a
rambling
once I fetched a record get the car back
up here
I want you to know to that the
successful return value is an actual
seek a record instance
and this is alive honest to god seek a
record what's am having so much fun at
his party I pulled
that I want to last a little bit longer
I can take a record of it
I can pump out the end it by half an
hour and I can set that record
that value back on the record once I've
done that I can take my CK record
instance in just like one that created
locally
I can turn around and save it back up to
the database
again with amazing your headline
arts that's the convenience API the
initial typical flow the you're gonna go
through when talking with clout get
gonna be saving record setting records
and taking those
records are you fetched modifying them
and bring them back up the
to the server so now let's say my party
application starts becoming really
popular
and it's grown my user base is no longer
me my friends but it's it's all love you
you know everyone's really excited about
joining into the party's
what are some other problems I'm gonna
run into well
let's assume that when I started out I
was a relatively naive developer
and because the developer on stage that
Clark it's all about taking your
autograph and we'll get to and from the
cloud
that's exactly what I did I had a 1:1
mapping my objects went up to the cloud
and every client I would fetch the
entire cloud state and I would become i
object graph were some problems are
gonna run into him
well at that point we've got big data
and a very tiny phone
the more popular my %uh becomes the more
data on the database
the less reasonable it is to have a cash
for that entire data
locally on my device so how we gonna
solve this
know what thing but what we want to do
we want to keep a
the large data in the cloud the cloud is
very good storing large datasets
my client wants to view a slice of that
data
because I'm reading application for my
users and my users have their own
preferences
I want each client to be able to view a
difference by so that data
and each individual client might want to
change its view that data
we saw this is be something that we call
queries
clients his queries to focus their
viewpoint so that they can see a small
section
a large dataset that exists up on the
cloud
so what is a clearing well as you might
imagine it it's exposing our EP I
as the CK query class a query combines
three different things it combines a
record type: a predicate
and optionally a sort descriptor if
you've used and it's pretty good in the
past you know that as predicate is very
expressive
cock it supports most urbanised Kritika
we document the parts that we do
and if you had a predicate that we don't
understand we're gonna throw an
exception
so you're gonna learn pretty quickly
which ones are not supported
let's have a look at some that are
supported
here we see a predicate that would match
records we're name is equal to a value
that I had in memory
predicates allow you to use dynamic keys
so they don't have to know the key name
at compile-time we can do relative
ordering comparisons as opposed to strip
the qualities
we mention that location is an
interesting aspect in the public
database
you can query with location as a filter
this is every location within 100 meters
up we're standing here in moscow
crockett support to organization search
so what this
predicate is going to do is it going to
talk in eyes that
string after session and it's going to
come up with two different organs
after in session this predicate will
match
any record that has those two tokens as
values
these two tokens don't need to exist
side by side they don't even need to
exist in the same key value pair
but so long as the record has the token
after and the record has the talk in
session
the record will be a match and lastly
corporate support compound predicates
join using the and operator
he was the predicate that does that
here we see the creation of a query I
and as we mentioned its
combining both the record tied and a
predicate how do I perform queries after
have created them
well just like setting records
performing a query is going to be a
database
specific operation some going to choose
the data base on which I want to perform
a query
even in the simply PI in the cabinets
API
we give me the ability to restrict these
queries by record zones
you see here that when not using the
passing records on filter
so this query is going to search across
the entire public database
let's have a look at what happens in the
area completion hamper
first course amazing air handling second
if we don't have errors which have a
look at the results
and you'll see here that the results are
actually seek a record instances
he's alive objects if I wanted to I
could pulled it off with them
I could set it up on them I could even
choose to see them back to the server
so we to think about queries is that
queries are polls
and polls are great in some scenarios
the great for slicing through large
datasets
if your application once the startup in
for example show all the parties at the
top 10 parties at or near me
a query is absolutely the way to go but
there's other things he might be tempted
to use a query for thats
are not perfect if you find yourself
issuing the same query
over and over and over again and you're
getting bout a statically mostly seem
data result set well then you've got a
large mostly static data set
inquiries are bad for that use case for
a few reasons
the bad for battery life get the car for
the week the device up
poll run the same query go back more or
less the same results
the bad for network traffic all those
questions but to the server
if they're not going down new and
interesting data why do we bother
and also bad for the user experience on
by definition you're only gonna learn
about new results
are on the period love how often your
polling
uses nowadays have come to expect push
through supposed to using a client
generated query in the scenario
which you really want is you want the
server to be running the query on your
behalf
you on the server to be running the
query on your behalf in the background
you want that to happen after every
single record say weather was you or
somebody else that save the record
and Leslie of course you want pushes
when the the results that changes
well we've given you this and we call
that subscriptions
yeah
so subscriptions are exposing our API
as seek a subscription class they
combine the record type:
a predicate and push pushes delivered
via the Apple Push service
if you've used a BS in the past year
largely familiar with this but note
Clark it pushes are slightly augmented
they contain crockett specific
information
about what caused the push to happen
let's have a look at and sample
here we have a phone and that phone is
interested in parties that are going to
be happening in the future
this phone when it sees that happening
wants to be alerted with the push that
says party time
the phones gonna go ahead and say that
after I cloud
and i cud gonna you know shuffled away
with all the other subscriptions
now along comes the Mac the Mac creates
a new record
itself record Thai Party and its
happening tonight and because the Mac
didn't choose to give us a record id: we
we created that
random UUID you see the Mac goes ahead
and save that to the eye
2i cloud i cud is in a loop through all
those descriptions that it had knows
about
eventually it's going to come across
this one its gonna check and say
yeah okay this is a new party and yet
happening in the future
so that point is going to create a push
and it's going to take some information
from the subscription here to open the
the alert string party time
it's going to take other information
from the record itself
here were pulling in the record id:
another constructed
augmented payload I can send that
augment the payload done all clients
that are registered an interest in it
should look at some code
how do I create a subscription well a
subscription
combines a record type: and a predator
because
a subscription is also in charge telling
the server how you want to be alerted
we introduce the notion called seek a
notification in for here we're
requesting
that the server badges are icon that it
plays a particular sound pulled out my
resources
and that it shows an alert string bass
on a string in my localized strings file
I can associate the notification for
with the subscription
and I've created everything I need my
subscription let's go ahead and save it
to the server
as you might imagine view the community
PRI
its simple it's a sickness and it's got
great error handling
with what about how you gonna be
handling subscriptions how you can help
pushes as they come in
if you used a PS in the past you're
probably familiar with this code snippet
this is your application delegate
implementing the application
did receive remote notification method
now
in most scenarios if you know the format
of the push peeler that's coming in
you just then iterate through the
dictionary pulling up the key/value
pairs that you care about
however because Clark it was when the
generated this push
we ask that you look like a kid do that
parsing so we are the way you do that is
BS EQ notification
than that really long when I'm not gonna
name once we've actually
parts down to seek a notification you
can pull off BPS level information from
it and you can also pull off clark et
level information from it here we're
taking the record id:
over the saved record the cause the push
to happen
so between queries in subscriptions we
have an answer to the Big Data tiny
phone problem
you can leave a large data up in the
cloud and you can use these two
capabilities to give your users a quick
view
into that market now I wanna talk about
cloud kid user accounts
as a Libyan mentioned
club kid is built on top of the icon
account infrastructure
so what does that mean I want to focus a
little bit on how
how accounts are exposed to you
explicitly throughout the API
when you think about an account system
the first thing you think about as
authentication
and Clark it supports authentication via
the log and i cud user
but that's not you know that sort of
behind the scenes you guys don't care
about that that's implicit
let's talk about the explicit things
what do we give you
on because we don't have my card
accounts we give you identity
wave identifying the user we give you a
meditator
the ability to save and retrieve
information about users
we do all this and privacy country and
just manner
we don't disclose anything if the user
has an agreed to it and lastly we give
users the ability to discover their
friends
they're using your application let's
dive in the twenties
first we're going to talk about identity
so
here's our model we've got a client or
application running on the client and
all these different users in the private
databases
up in the container your specific client
is going to be. linked to one and only
one of those users
with this is related to the
User's that log in BI cloud locally on
your device
because this is i cloud we've got a rich
backing store
user information and because I club is
the one
that is hosting your container we can
correlate users
for example here we see that the user
whose email addresses
C&I klout.com is linked to your current
client
so given the setup how are we going to
present and identity
how we're going to let you know your
client your application
no what users logged in well naively you
might think
there was given email address we're not
going to do that obviously
on that spot private user identifiable
information
we don't want to give that out so
instead what we do
is on a container by container basis we
gonna come up with the random I D
this is a ride in a fire that is stable
so that is
your application no matter what client
it's running on
talking to this container will get the
same identify your
but it's not identifying the user via
any personal information
so we feel confident giving you this a
identify your
you can take this identify and do with
it what you will
note that different applications running
on your phone
because they're talking two different
contacts using because we're talking to
different containers
are going to get back different
containers coat record identifiers
for the same user this goes back to what
we talked about in the beginning that
we've got user in caps elation
so user identity we expose user identity
VR API
as a user record id: it is a stable
identifiers for this user
it will be the same for your application
no matter where your application is
running
its coat to the container so two
different applications are going to come
up with different identifiers
for the same user is a feature
and lastly this is an independent API
this is a section of the car kit
framework
you can use as in collaboration with the
database API or
you can use is completely separately
we've given you enough support
that if you wanted to you could
implement a login VI clout flow
in your application using the car kit
framework
let's have a look at the code up
I'll have a look at the code because
identity is a container scoped
notion and not a database scope notion
we go to our container to learn about
our user
here we're asking our container to fetch
the use a record id:
now because we have we may have to talk
to the server to figure this out
for example the first time you access
and try and learn about a record id:
we have to go to the server to do their
translation I come up with the container
scope and fell
so a synchronous and we have to do a
rambling thats user identity
let's talk about use a meditator and
quickly to recap the problem
we have here is we have a stable
identify your
and we've got a desire to set key/value
pairs
based on that identify your I don't know
about you but to me that sounds very
much like it was a record was built to
do
so we expose users as user records
looking inside a container with a lid
database we see that there is one
use a record in the private database
that use a record represents your user
there are many user records inside the
public database
represent which one the uses of your
application one of them will have a
record id:
that matches you are currently logged in
I cloud users record id:
so user meta-data
exposed to be our framework as a user
record there's one per database that you
that represents your current user use a
record in the public database like any
other
default record our world readable the
treated mostly
like a ordinary record with the record
type that we expose in the free market
seek a record type: use a record but
there are couple caveats
first of these records are reserved by
the system
you do not create the use a record
rather you fetch an existing one from
the server
what that means is that you can be
assured that when you fetch
the record for your current user but it
has not been scooped
it was indeed I cloud that created the
record in the first place
secondly we think that it doesn't make
sense for you to be able to query the
entire setup use a record in public
database
doesn't really make sense to be able to
say I want to look at all users
whose first name begins with Kay too
little bit too coarse grained
for something that's so up that we want
to protect privacy around
so we don't allow you to query use a
records
but we're gonna gonna fix and couple
slides
are so what's it look like here
we have the same code that we saw
earlier were fetching use a record id:
want to have that seek a record id: I
can go ahead and I can fetch that record
from either database that I choose here
I'm choosing to fetch
a record with that identify your from
the public database assuming that I
don't get an error
I now have a live seek a record that
represents
this user and I can treat it like I
would any other city record
I can poll records aren't using I can
pull key/value pairs of a bit
I can secular repairs on it me if I
wanted to I could go ahead and save it
back to the server
now I'll talk to privacy
we care very much about our users
privacy therefore we disclose
no information no personally identifying
user information
about the current user by default now we
recognize
that in some cases you replication is
going to want to have limited access
to meditate about the user so if I
you want that data you can request that
from Clark
when you do we're gonna go to the user
to make sure they're okay with that you
see an example of the party application
requesting the ability for my user
account to be discoverable within the
application
the user can either accused to a lower
than either assuming that the user has
a acquiesced to this privacy request we
can go on to the next phase which is
discovery
let's talk a little bit about user
discovery user image we've got our
clients talking to a container in the
container is backed by I cloud
and I cloud has all this rich user
information if you look a little bit
more
on the client side we see that there's
actually two different processes
involved here
there's your client process and then
there's the clark et process
and it's the cloud kit process that's
the one that actually talking
over the wire so let's examine what user
discovery would look like
if you want to discover information
about user given a record id:
you take that record id: and you can
send it off to clark et
Clark it is going to interns ended up to
the container
once it hits the container we're going
to ask the icon account info
to exchange it for different information
for information about that user
if that user has opted in to discover
ability
we're going to get information back that
information can traverse back to clark
et
and back be the process boundary over to
your client
but we're not restricted to just record
ID's if the user enters an email address
we can do the same sort of dance this
e-mail address is sent from your client
overclock it
Clark it wasn't gonna have shut up a
whole 12 times that we're not sending
personal info of
the of the client also that up to the
container
the container texting is it with I cloud
and if the targeted this discovery has
opted in to discover ability
we're gonna get a result setback those
results can go back to Clark at
and concurs back up to your client
now I'd like to think that we're pretty
good about naming things and Clark it
but this one we sorta
can really do well I'm so we offer
different leave
doing use a discovery that we call the
whole address book into if you discover
the whole ladders ok
arm and the way this works is that your
client is going to say
I would like to discover the user record
ID's and more information
about every user that his friends with
by currently locked and i cud user you
send the request over to the clerk at
process
the Cloquet process is then gonna pull
in the user's address book
we're going to take over you know the
address in the address book we're gonna
have some up
organs and you know it the
non-personally identifying version about
address book up to the car container the
containers gonna send it after I cloud
and for those members of my address book
that have adopted into discoverability
I'm gonna learn information about them
that information going to come back to
Clark it
as gonna be sent over the process
boundary to your client
now if you'll note at no point did your
client in this
with the flow have access to the user's
address book
what this means is that we can give you
the support without you requiring that
your user allows
your application to the address book
mean that you don't have to have the
blue alert which is now the white alert
giving your application access to the
address book you can leverage it
without access to it
so use a discovery he's in the three
different kinds of inputs that we can
have for you to discovery
in sort of a user record id: email
address or request
to view the entire address book what do
you get back from user discovery
well you get back to use a record id: in
the latter two cases that new
information
you also get back first and last name
this user
now of course it bears repeating first
and last name
is personally identifying information so
you're only going to get discovery
results
for users that have opted in to discover
ability
let's have a look at some code here here
we are asking our default container
to discover all of my users that are
part of my address book
in the response again a synchronous
error handling arm
in be successful response case what we
see is that we get backing CK discovered
userinfo object and the user info from
that I can pull
use a record id: and a first and last
name
so these are really the the four temples
love how we
do user accounts we give you a stable
identify your
we give you the ability to store and
retrieve metadata about
users we protect users privacy
and we give your users the ability to
discover their friends in your
application
now to tell you when it's appropriate to
use Clark it for so many other I cloud
technologies that we already have
exposed
I'd like to buy back up to Libya burning
thank you Paul so pocket
is the new framework but it doesn't
obsolete or deprecate
any of the existing tools its really
just a new toy in your toolbox
I am let's look at all the
for tools you now have and look at were
different use cases were we think they
make sense
and their appropriate to use so first
I clarke you go to store I clarke you go
to store
keeps small pillow /div data up to date
between europe and jackpot servers this
is done asynchronously
Europe doesn't really need to care about
when and how this is dawn
we think this is great for small amount
of data like
application preferences game States
conflict resolution is free sample last
writer wins
so thats I caught you value store
I Club Drive built on top of the
existing I called documents EPI
I am it that doing so would provide 24
of Lancashire North then
all the files on the icon try but the
user are downloading on North
then it's completely unstructured and
and truly title file system
used to follow coordination API's shoes
read and write data
in your application i cud container on
the filesystem
Jack hard drive human takes care of
applauding
and downloading those changes happened
to happened from
on the icon servers I am
we think it's great for document center
caps or abstain need to deal with an
existing file formats
I told Chordata built on top of
I hard drive replicates of again
specific user data between all the users
devices
it's great for keeping private richter
day don't think
but because its downloads all the data
to all devices your
also constrain to the size of a small
device in that case
and tourist club kid the new kid on the
block and we think there are a number of
interesting use cases were cock it makes
sense
and I am compliments pre-world
the existing technologies so first any
public the dow
if your app if you need to give access
to all the users of your apt to
large data sets and pocket public
databases
are pretty good a compelling I'm
tool clock it supports both structured
and bought the dow
so you can use it to store law large
files an iPod
and we take care of downloading and
uploading them
of to the I taught servers
ask Paul describe talk it supports has
good support for large data sets were
your app will want to give
a specific slice specific view I am
after wards tested to the user at a
given point I'm
club kid lets you I
youth league thing I cry the up
account infrastructure whether you need
to identify the user
or to led the user discover his
friends using your app Clark it is the
Naples you to do that last but not least
compared to the other three technologies
we think rockets is closer to the mail
in some way
in this case if when you're using pocket
Europe is really in control of
when the app is uploading or downloading
from the server
your your app is killing the operations
Union and that's also why you need to do
this all summer and Ling done for all
that you will do
so in summary what have we covered today
clock it gives you access to our cloud
servers
it supports both public and private data
it supports both structured and all data
you can use it for large falls
and it leverage the existing Akribos
account infrastructure which means that
you over 400 million I clarke
accounts out there or sure for you to
take advantage of
Apple is building on it in a big way
have both
I called drive and I thought for library
were built from scratch on top of clout
kids
we're super excited to see what you're
going to build
on top of this new framework arm
so for more information Davis or
evangelists we have
some awesome framework reference on the
OPORD Apple dot com website
as well developer forums we have an
Advent sprocket session
on Thursday and Jacob is going to tell
you everything you want to know about
that I'm mulling
and advanced record manipulations thank
you very much for being here and thank
you for attention