good afternoon
welcome
son Patrick einen am a manager in the
air cocoa frameworks group
and welcome to adapting to the new UI
voz tenuous amity
let's get started so I
your family your house so it brings a
pretty fresh look to the Mac be astute
observers among you might have noticed
there's been some changes in the visual
department
well were here to help you understand
what has changed NY so to break it all
down for you
walked through it and to get a better
understanding a bit and then most most
importantly
I how to get the most out over this new
you why in your cocoa applications
so how are we gonna do this well
first we're going to talk about some
phenomenal design principles that went
into the choices
that resulted in the current design that
you see in Austin yosemite
I then we're gonna take it into the tour
bus
and I just take a tour love of your
family in all the key pieces
that have changed but our relevance for
Coco app developers from developers
point of view
then we're gonna talk about vibrancy
which is one of these important elements
I am just deconstruct that you can get a
conceptual basis for understanding how
what role it plays and how it works and
what it does for you
then talk about some elements that you
might bring to your applications fonts
colors are working how they should how
they know what their role is now some
things we've done to make working with
them
easier I in in your Sammy and last but
definitely not least we'll talk about
app compatibility in how to mitigate
are the risk introducing this big design
change in having a nap work
across different scenarios okay so with
that i'm gonna hand it over to my
colleague morning get right into
the design portion stock Mike
thank you Patrick hi everyone saw Mike
Stern I'm
user experience evangelist without Paul
and
I I'm not an engineer I'm a designer
so what am I doing here at this
engineering session well we're talking
about the new design
voters 10 and I thought I would just
come here for a few minutes to talk
about some other high-level principles
are design teams that
guided and inspired the design OS 10
yosemite
now yesterday we announced I was 10 your
sanity
and the most innocent is the 10th
police 2000 s10 and in that time span
there's been a few really major you I
releases for OS 10
and as with every one of those releases
elements like the menu bar Windows
the doc have been refined
to be friendlier easier to use
more approachable but they've also been
redesigned to have greater utility power
and support more sophisticated
and advanced workflows you send it is
just another step in a continuous
process
evolving OS 10 let's dive in and talk
about some the principles that
really core to this particular redefine
the first one
its simplicity let's take a look at
these app icons
in particular
let's look at the calendar icon as
before
calendar was redesigned but it still
very much looks like a realistic
three-dimensional object
with realistic highlights realistic
shadows
and even the texture have the paper but
some other element to the previous icon
were removed
like the many calendars you where the
metal rings
those elements work really necessary
to depict a daily death counter and by
removing those elements the new icon
is more simple it's less cluttered more
straightforward
simplicity also influence the decision
to go away from using lucid Agron day as
the system font
and towards using how Vatican Noida
American Lawyer
is a simpler typeface with Sid Agron day
is designed to evoke hand-written letter
forms
American oil on the other hand is
designed to clearly and simply
the pics the letterforms and numbers
without any ornamentation so the more
appropriate
typeface to use for the new design
language
what does that mean well here's a
comparison
you can see that the ass is a little bit
more geometric
full simpler there's less variation
between the thickness
the stroke weight between then and there
thick part so the letter
the shoulder here for the N has a
smoother form to it
less have an abrupt transition and fonts
have a more consistent with
to them and the next
theme is about consistency
again let's go back to the app icons now
from the beginning ago with 10 app icons
were rendered to look like
they were three-dimensional object to
that was sitting on a table in front
view
and they were rotated a bit so they
could be easily distinguished from
documents or folders plugins and
utilities
but over time there was a little bit
oven divergence going on with every
absolute doing its own thing
that led to some variation like icons
that have a really strong perspective
and Keystone effect
or instead of looking like they're lying
flat on a table they look to be
sitting upright
OS 10 brings a a harmonization
but the style all the icons so here the
realistic looking icons you can see they
all the same perspective
same light source same rendering
and the graphical icons these round
icons are also
internally consistent with each other
the symbols at the centre them had the
same and boss affect
the shape the convex shape the the form
is consistent across all im
let's go back to type again how America
know is the new system fun
and one of the things that the salt for
us was an inconsistency that existed
before
overtime some maps like notes had
started to use Helvetica Neue as a
content fun
and outs like iTunes iPhoto iMovie Final
Cut Pro and logic
were using help Eric annoying as a
content fine as well as a UI font
this led to serve unfortunate mismatch
between the system
and those individual aP's
so by changing to have Erica know it now
we have this consistency across the
entire
Mac experience and another side benefit
to that
there's more consistency between Mac and
I O S
the third major principal at FEMA this
redesign
is about death we believe that software
interfaces should feel
physically the two have physical
dimensionality and that should be
really plausible that dimensionality
helps you to focus on the things that
are in the foreground
and pay less attention to those things
which are in the background
now on I O S death is conveyed through
using translucency
for example the Notification Center for
the control center
and the elements that are within those
you eyes
also have translucency meaning similar
background colors allowed to
come through now o.o s10 pickup on S and
uses the same kinda translucent affect
for the Notification Center and other
parts the UI
now on Isleworth course we use motion a
fax to show deaths as well
so when you move the device running your
hand things have a sense a parallax
that's great for something that weighs
as late as the iPhone or iPad
but we're not about to encourage people
to pick up the iMac and start moving it
around to get the same effect
so it's still really important to use
things like gradients
drop shadows to convey that sense space
and correctly order things
and easy access
the last major principle for this
redesign is around designing your own
content to be content focused
content is what's most important not the
user interface
so for example one way to to be content
focuses to disallow there to be more
space for content so now there's this
unified toolbar
that does whether title bar
and the toolbar had done before
by unifying those elements there's now
more physical space
for the thing that you really care about
which is the webpage
itself and
deferring to content /url on content to
be the focus is also
about having a user interface that's
less heavy less strong so we've stripped
away love the textures and highlights in
the shadows
to have a simpler appearance that in
combination with the translucent window
chrome
toolbar in this case allows the content
to really come through in effect the
appearance
have the entire screen again it lowers
your content to be the center your focus
so that all I really have you today and
now I like to
handed off to our tour bus driver Rachel
Gordon
thank you very much take
thanks Mike good afternoon thanks for
being here as
they mention I'm gonna give you a little
developers tour the new UI
in I OS in Yosemite
I let's start off here by taking a look
at finder
and I'm gonna give you actually eighty
mini tour before the tour
the things that I'll cover we'll take a
look at
the toolbars again window control button
in New kind of segmented control
the sidebar which is translucent now
and then will move over to Safari to
take a look
at what might just mention the combine
to a bar in title bar
and then we'll take a look at System
Preferences to show with an example
love are animated controls search field
radio buttons pop-up menus
and checkboxes now after that
we will go over to Notification Center
and look at our new vibrant dark
appearance
that's used here and then the context
menu
which uses the vibrant light appearance
as do popovers
alright back to the top translucent
toolbars
for anyone who's gone and installed
yosemite already I'm sure you played
around this unseen as he's cool things
up you can just see them coming through
the toolbar and give you a sense
love your content flying under the
toolbar
how do you get it well all you have to
have
is an Anna school view that is adjacent
to the toolbar
and then it happens automatically for
you
but if you don't have that you can still
get it by using this new window style
masked
NS full-size content view window mask
simply ordered in with your existing
Windows style mask
and you get the transparent translucent
to a bar style
this can be useful for things such as
toolbars our title buyers that show and
hide
over content that is not in a ScrollView
or the school he is not right at the top
lots more details about this in
tomorrow's advance session adopting
advanced features
the new UI OS 10 yosemite
alright tinted slater's hiding away in
the bottom right corner
this window these are little
new thing on yosemite and
to get those you just need to have a
non-directional fighter
which is a slider that has Eurotech max
alright now let's take a look at the new
window control button as well as being
flatter
you also notice that the full screen
button has moved into the green
button if you're sad about that
and you'd like zoom behavior back hold
the Option key
and you'll get them behavior I'd also
like to point out that
any window that can't go fullscreen
reverts to the old
in behavior
and then next the new kind of separated
segmented control
these are useful for things like
navigation like this
went backwards and forwards button here
or other kind incremental step
operations such as zooming
and this is easy to get by sending the
segment style n/a
segment style separated and it's nice to
know that
the style will automatically adjust
whether in a toolbar
were in a window
now I'm gonna bring another window onto
fighter here
and we'll take a look at some the subtle
differences that happen between
active and inactive Windows
when the window comes forward and
becomes active the sidebars translucent
but when it goes to the background and
inactive Sabres opaque
so it's nice to know that the
translucency is only in the active
window
let's take a closer look here at the
toolbar
couple things to know a good chance to
stay
that the metrics we tried to keep them
as much the same as possible so that
all year old control center
automatically move to the new look
even without recompiling should all fit
in the same state
and there's also some subtle things that
happen when you use
template images these are great way take
take advantage of our automatic
adjustment for state changes
and so I'm gonna send this window to the
back and you can see the state changes
in the template images particularly that
selected
part that segment to control look at
image
you see it completely change color so
you can take advantage of that
by using template images
and let's take a look again at the
translucent sidebar
once again opaque here translucent here
and how do you get translucent sidebars
guess what
there for free if if used in an
outline viewer and a stable view
and use that the highlights style to
source list
which you can do in Interface Builder or
incurred
alright and to just show how easy it was
a downloaded
a sidebar demo which was put together
for OS 10 lie in 10 points 7
an out-of-the-box it had translucent
fibers
now moving over to Safari to take a look
at the new kind of to a bar that has a
hidden title bar
hidden under Title Search Eve using this
new
win NS window property title visibility
and you can set the title disability and
this window title hidden
in order to get the effect that safari
hat and I'd like to point out to you
that Safari has some special things that
make this work
one of which is that they have put the
window title
into the combined URL and search field
and so you can still see the window
title even though there's no title bar
also as andrea pointed out yesterday
they've left room for
users to click in the toolbar in order
to move the window around
you wanna make sure you have room for
that if you're going to use this new
style
moving on to animated controls
search field now enemy very much like
they do on i OS
with that magnifying glass and the
placeholder text moving to the left when
you click
radio buttons have an animation and when
a nice things about them is as you
flecked a radio button
the other one deflecting enemy out
simultaneously
nice little touch
Xboxes as well are now animated and this
is a good time for me to point out that
that first preference their double-click
Windows title bar to minimize if you
even
unchecked which is the default
double-clicking a window's title bar
will do the little hidden feature for
your and last
pop up button when you select a Papa
button I and
choose an item from the menu you know
and make back into place in the pop
alright
moving on to Notification Center
and the vibrant dark parents let's take
a little bit of a closer look
as what happens when the background
changes I want you to pay particular
attention to those
tabs at the top say today and
notifications and see how they change
as the background changes it looks very
close
to standard transparency but we're
actually using special blend modes pull
the color in
a little more than just plain ol
transparency how did they get it
they use this new and a few subclass and
its visual effect for you
as well as the new vibrant dark parents
which is in an effort parents see you
can create
and an official affect you get the Anna
appearance name vibrant dark apparent
and set that
on the effect you in order to achieve
this look similarly
here's an example the vibrant might
appearance same deal
an official affect you but this time
using the vibrant light appearance you
set that on your fact few
and you get this new vibrant I apparent
lots more
about an official affect you and
vibrancy in tomorrow's talk
and now I will hand back to Patrick
who will talk to you in more depth about
vibrancy
thank you very much accurate or thank
you
okay so vibrancy
size ritual mentioned it's not just
plain ol transversely what is this for
everything well
its a pretty important visual building
block for lost time as you
in its makes its way into many different
applications many different areas
are both in light and dark I'm most
prominently in Notification Center but
also other
other places in in the US so what is it
what is this vibrant thing well or I'm
gonna try
and bear with me here but when I try to
be constructing breakdowns
explain conceptually what it is and was
trying to do what its goal is
to help give you a framework for
understanding what happens technically
with with your application
so vibrancy is advance planning
on dynamic or adaptive backgrounds so
what's advanced about it well
why I'm about in the world's world's
were to be
Cummings I I think we I'm gonna try to
make the case for
with vibrancy to pose to can not only
before but we can actually make it equal
25 in fact it's all about making
vibrancy can actually make the whole
greater than the sum of the parts things
that you put into it
Mexican end up with something more
interesting than the two things you put
into it so what two things my talking
about well
it's really all about combining
foreground and background elements most
%uh view our graphics
is all about combining some for gramm
content onto a back on whether it's a
button
onto a window background whether to Pisa
text onto
a button or window content background
sober combining those individual pixels
in interesting ways
well so let's do that we have this
beautiful puppy background
and let's do in traditionally let's we
have here a gray
amid tone grey circle that we put on top
at this background
and we can just put it on and now it's
okay but it kinda simply blend well
it'll come sticks out in fact
in this image now traditionally the tool
we would have at our disposal
to calm combiner ball ended in some
interesting we would be
transparency or using al for opacity so
here I faded
this gray circle by about 25 percent
maybe a little less
I'm not a design I so
I but you'll notice there's a problem
with this time
is it leaves a little bit I'm on the
table in terms of
that the resulting in stocks because
what happens with transparent is all you
doing to taking that form in the back
room just
taking a fraction fractional midpoint
between
in combining those what it really ends
up being like is like as if you're
taking up for going on in punching a
scream
like punch him doing the loopholes and
letting the backgrounds through
with the and the fact that the
background that the show through the
foreign element
into can can amor quién mardian he's in
as you make it
more to opaque it has to come get darker
and moodier
really doesn't that the back room
doesn't get the combined in an
interesting way
well what if we did this different what
if we and the other thing I want to
point out is that
we're not really doing anything with the
collar information
form in the background weep when we
combine in this way well what if we
to approach the problem differently what
it look but if we actually took
the color information the foreground
pixel in the background element
and combining an interesting way where
we actually trying to preserve the color
turnout in the background
I am just using the actual for bank or
as as a hint as to how much
a black color to preserving the generals
intensity level
so that's want that's what I'm Water
Mill Street in here in this slide
is actually a sort of a burn burn effect
I a burn bland
I a four-round same circle same actual
gray value here I have changed nothing
about the program elements still that
same
gray circle it's just not now I've
combined with the background in a more
interesting where I'm using
the gray value to actually direct how
much of the color information to keep
from the background
I'm as walls general I'm to melody
I what's nice about this is you really
preserve the character the background as
you can see
and what also very nice about this is it
kind of works really well
as things change network changing the
lightness a a quite a bit
as we go between the end to the popping
in the center but
get the sort of general contrast ratio
and engine of book
that about composite is actually pretty
preserve pretty well by that planned
and in fact this design is very
resilient
to completely changing back on offer
something different
so once again I from change nothing
about the foreground element here I just
changed
now we have this lotus flower background
I'm endure
you'll see that the actual are
combinations roughly the same overall
character
as a result well so case that this this
is a good illustration of the basic
setup
foreground and background blending using
sorta for more advanced bland
but now how do we build this up into
what we see you know its 10-year Sammy
today to get these are these transfers
materials well now we need to combine
with a different kinda background so
what's build up this
this light material here will first we
just wanna put a nice
my flashlight employer August that's
transparent
over the over the background to give us
a nice or like substrate onto which the
drawer you I because we want it or you
are directly entered
a picture of course I'm and then
all we need to do to make it better is
just blurred as a little bit and
and to keep the overall cartoon out in
the rough shape up your
a your your background but still
preserve
but but gift giver a smoother rendering
up the overall result
now you know as I went through and
brought this up I've changed nothing
about the for colonel
all I've done is a change that
background and it's that it's been
planning on to
and the nice thing about this is is it
still preserves that same character as
as I'm going across in as the back room
is changing
the overall composition really preserves
its character and still live give you
some other
be the important color information I
up the above the back from that
underneath and and let it shine through
so in fact are I'd like to argue
the whole can be greater than the sum
parts for when you doing
when you combine using the right my mods
himself some tricky design problems I am
so what are these for movement fiber
materials which we speak so
ritual enumerated some the area so we we
have
built up a couple different styles are
one of which can be seen in menus and
pop overs
then there's the general light
appearance which is what you see in the
sidebars and source list
I'm then there's the translucent title
bars at another fiber material
and of course the dark the dark
appearance but you saw
Notification Center there are a couple
of key
new provinces to be here is a bit what
I'm mean by this is areas where
your application even without taking any
steps you'll just automatically benefit
from this new compositions now
were using one of which of course a
source list
I then there's the transmission title
bar menus and popovers automatically get
this
as their as their background and of
course
menu bar am status items minibars
so I am how do you use vibrancy in your
app's
how to use it effectively well once
again
I it's all about combining for ground
with background
in an appropriate way improper an
interesting way well
and a special effect few is the view
that actually is performed the role of
this background the
thing that we've built up in the slide
before with that white gambler and
translucency this provides a subsidy
onto the canvas into which we're control
and it as and it's offered in light and
dark
basic material flavors stuff for you
bedtime ritual
bridge we demonstrated Birmingham
and the important thing about in
official affect you and what it does to
your applications that takes care
are all love the stuff all of the steps
needed to make sure that
as the content either underneath her
window or underneath view
inside the window as it changes as you
scroll things around as
you drag Windows run as your background
changes it can automatically update
as the company's changes you don't have
to worry about any that all that is
handled for you
so much movement and its appearance so
in this appearance is in this equation
is the one that's taking the role of the
foreground element
is gonna its gonna drive both the
selection for content as well as
drive some other blaming behavior so I
it's offered im to to appearance burns
and his passion environment light
animus appearance name vibrant dark
and what its role in life is is to
provide
a sort of a panoply of colors controls
and template image treatments that are
appropriate and suitable
provide for anyone to pull within Visual
Effects use and carbon surfaces
now this is important because as we have
as you saw in the
I'm in the earlier section %uh vibrancy
selecting the former No
now these the way things combined for
different in traditionally so selecting
something appropriate for 500 is very
critical
and so we need alternate sets up these
design values
alternate versions this for government
to get the right result
on these firemen services so
as I said its it's really the in this
appearance can really be fought over the
thing at that helps elect unidentified
your for content source makes it
appropriate in locked in for that
for for firing for the material
and once it's in effect then apk it can
automatically
pick up the appropriate colours pick up
the appropriate template remains
pick them all up and do with the and
pick up the right blend months
especially
I for appropriate for the for the view
and them to your rendering onto
okay so how do you do this well it's
with such a try to do a downer
exciting
one
okay so I am so what we're gonna do here
is I we have a very very very very
simple application
I that's basically just a an image
editor
I'm image editor with some adjustment
sliders here and what I'm gonna try to
show you is how simple it is to just
and some vibrancy into your UI
how little will ever take so all we all
we're gonna do is we're gonna but we're
going to try to do is win tried to give
visual effect few
and put it inside that little inspector
in rehearse the controls inside a bit
to give it a vibrant vibrant parents
so let me go ahead and do that so
the first thing I'm gonna do years I'm
going to
create a visual effect few an
initializer with the inspectors frame
and then I'm going to said its
appearance to be the vibrant dark pants
now next and then the only other thing I
really need to do is I need to re host
the
I am take out the existing content the
controls under the existing content view
and put them into I'm this new affects
you
and then place it has the content view
the window
so that's all I'm doing here this is a
really directly relevant to the demo but
I just for here for
for on steam for disclosure here
so I key thing to see here's the
parents being put on here and you see
presto Chango I have not only some nice
dark fiber material but I also have
I you know alternate slider Ultima
controls after automatically selected
different artwork that's appropriate for
rival rendering specifically for the
dark material
the text colors have inverted and
everything is is updating dynamically
now all it took was deploying that
visual affect you
okay so back to the home
okay and out that was a very very
cursory demonstration for a lot more
details
about all the ins and outs official
affect you
and some other a summer the more
advanced techniques abusing them to
build
somebody somebody bill you I someone to
some other things that we have in our
system
please go to the to the in-depth talk
our tomorrow adopting advanced features
the new why
you know is tenuous amity
okay so let's move on
to fonts colors an artwork these are the
elements that are
typically things that you you you you as
an app developer my to make some
specific design choices and provide
material for
so was talk of Arts first
so what's new and fun but swell
about the system fun that's not that big
it always
it's not a big change at all I actually
it is so
this is a here's an illustration of the
the Mavericks many borrowers Slusser
grounding
and here's what it looks like today with
homework anaya
I it's actually a pretty significant
difference
it can be seen even more dramatically if
you compare the two side by side
are you notice it's a it's quite the
sizing kirker six old different but in
general it is
a lot crisper typographical Ian cervical
a cleaner layout
so let's talk about this new system fun
so it's all american I am but is not
just plain old your mothers however can
I it is especially
optimized version have an economy that
has been optimized for lost time
and what do I mean by optimized well
anytime you put
a font for corrupting system I wanted a
pic to key two things to balance
are I aesthetics and layout
compatibility
now for first editor all we were
concerned with we would just be
render the font exactly how the type
designer originally envisioned it
try to do our best job in rendering
remembering the individual letter forms
and leave it at that what the problem is
a for sure switching system fight this
means we're updating the typography in
applications that haven't been modified
in an even be aware of it
so we have to think about things were
like the layout may change because
optimal response have different size
characteristics
so the version Republican know that
we've deployed has been specifically to
to balance a stray off to try to strike
a good balance there to make sure that
we still get the aesthetic
when they were really looking forward to
scream typography but not at the cost of
happy occasion compatibility
let me go into that with a little more
detail explaining
so here's here's the an emulation ever
find a ride home
ap bio menu item on the that you might
see on the menu bar
and this is happy to introduce the
ground
and you can see here sorta
approximations are the
the intercooler spacing here and now as
a switch this
to american know your there's some
interesting things going on here
because you must be over offering
shorter
but actually if you if you look
carefully
some other letters actually got bigger
summon them got shorter so it's not a
straightforward thing saying oh yeah how
america's everything's risking a truck
by Sir
finish not that much more subtle than
that can become too dependent some
things are getting wider
some things are getting shorter
something's getting more consistent
where they were inconsistent with the
ground between the king
capital letter sizes and in the lower
case letter sizes
so it's it's a complicated equation so
that's why it was important
to 22 optimizes metrics appropriately
so that they they've the so that they
solve this compatibility problem
you somewhere here you can see them to
on top of each other in consumer
dramatically
this difference is you bf in particular
is actually shorter
mister grimes wider I'm sorry its
finner in the serb-run in wider im
in Hoboken I but almost all the other
letter forms except maybe the d
are actually I considerably shorter
so solely are compatible that's a that's
a big big topic is an important topic
and what do we do about it
well for for for unmodified applications
one technique that we've applied use
to apply to wear compression if there's
a danger of the text ring
clipping given existing bouncer for
example if you have a text field
size just so to just fit just perfectly
I'm
on I'm maverick's you know there's a
chance that some that that same
same text field I've if no measures were
taking would
would would be would get clipped are
with the new fart
because some strange choice in there was
causing the the overall layout to be
longer
one those circumstances we're just gonna
imply a bit over interred with
compression
to try to make sure that it fits so you
with see all the information and there's
no information loss
and as I'm and this is active for for
abs built against Temple in an earlier
only so this is an important takeaway
here because
if this this compression medication that
we do
does not apply if your app is targeted
and built against the
1010 STK I'm
so this so what does this mean this
means that you can you don't have to
worry about your existing applications
having problems with your users but when
you going forward we encourage you to
really look carefully
at your at your text in your application
to make sure that you're using on ole
alter that your
really you sort of comparing testing
sure that that the with serve all your
text elements is is optimized according
and also want to mention that this I be
this compression technique that we apply
is not a silver bullet by any means I
in one shouldn't think of it as the
secure all and the reason is because
wear compression is not come without a
significant cost which is
that it can really effect legibility I
and that's especially true I'm 1x I'm on
retina displays where there's very few
pixels to work with
for every for every cliff in every
pixels doing a heckuva lot of work and
if you're compressing things together
really making suffering terms the
information much ability
so how do you use this new system font
you make sure your app
use using the appropriate type
well thankfully we have a whole bunch of
system fun selectors to choose from and
that's what we encourage you to use to
make sure that you're using the right
the right thing so if you're if you're
doing this in in first builder
rest assure that you know if you as long
as you stick with the standard font
elections in the
far pop-ups shopping for school you
should be okay
otherwise we encourage you to use the
system fonts workers are the ones that
aren't as font
an example there's many more but I'm
just picking a few to highlight here
I response system fantasize and it's fun
polled system fantasize
and a new one actually label fantasize
actually that's not
I don't think that's necessarily new I'm
is another label from coming out so
opener so all of the youth selectors
won't make sure that the appropriate UI
font on its optimized
has been selecting is going to be used
at the proper for you
important takeaway here if you remember
nothing else
about the fun sections talk is please do
not explicitly set your font
U-turn code or an IB hope Erica know
your
you know as a literal string cuz that
that's the actual document content fart
that's been not optimized version you'll
get very unexpected results
and it make your application less
compatible going forward as we continue
to improve
upon the typography a first time
okay so colors so colors are in often
underappreciated element
I'm a few why I which is a shame because
if you actually look at most windows on
most applications about 90 percent the
pixels
if that you know it are actually
composed of color feel so they're
actually pretty important part of
building your you why
and it's especially important on this
day of a
multiple appearances and different I'm
in different sections of your
applications
so we have system colors them a
I'm I'm Inc in cocoa and these are what
we urge you to gravitate towards
an by system cause I mean two things I
mean literally the concourse provided by
the system
in terms of their color selectors an ass
coloriage but I'm also
would like to emphasize that shouldn't
have colors as a system of colors not
just as a set of numbers that you might
pick up
you know from a designer like I'll RGB
128 142
136 no victim is a system as in like
what is the semantic color that would be
appropriate to use here
this is where system called can really
help
because many have the standard colors
like for example in his color control
text color
in a scholar I I'm secondary select to
control color and
you as a whole host of others have been
adapted have been optimized
are to make sure that they work in all
areas and under all appearances
in your eye and they may also change in
the future so it's just a good way to
bulletproof your
yourself I'm for textual elements
a in your you why we also I'm
would like to encourage you thinking of
lineout sure you I'm serving information
heart
hierarchy and by that I mean
view my have some sort of primary sort
of information elements are labels many
my some secondary supporting information
you'll see this pattern and in many in
many different applications
in Yosemite and we've introduced some
new
color selector specifically to help with
this
the two coach likes our label color and
secondary label color
and the nice thing about these is
they've been specifically designed to
work well in almost any context that you
might put them on with the menus which
have the like five min appearance
regular Windows
Notification Center in its stark
I you why no matter what you do
it'll look correct
so what about control text a button text
or other things like that
well the good news there is the control
text
koko's gonna make sure that control text
automatically adapts
to any particular control stay
that your your control me find itself
and so actually
I I would encourage you to if you must
you have a really compelling overriding
reason to do so
please let pic kit provide the coloring
for any textual elements on your buttons
and and an image look at images in the
second because there really are such a
wide range of
interaction in control States and our
designers over carefully selected colors
and styling for each one of these across
all the different appearances
and doing so well this will let the the
kid
provide optimal parents including
adapting
to the vibrance appearances he richard
nixon example of what
label color and secondary label color
look like across
the light and the dark 51 appearances
you can see the pics or preserve their
design intent there being priming
secondary
they're both vibrant the site but
secondary one is a little bit more so
that is
its leading a little more the background
through it a little more transistors
pick up a little more color the
background
I'm but it'll preserve it'll be afraid
design choices I
on any of these appearances including
the been on Bourbon appearance
regular our column
okay so last time here
in the section artwork so our workers is
only other important elements that you
might want to integrate
into your application and for this word
on the thing I wanna mainly highlight is
you template images
I template images can be an excellent
way to get maximum flexibility
out of your artwork and have it be
resilient across
wide range of you I scenarios in your
application
sorter template images a brief review
temple images are
image resources were the image content
itself
is per just providing the shape up
off-the-cuff the control of the element
that you want to depict
it's providing new color information
it's something you can put color in
there but it's going to get ignored
because it's basically just the shape
that it better than is critical
and then what happens is makes it
possible for after to transform it
with a context-specific apparently can
take that shape in a can render and
translucent gray one it's disabled or
commander
bright blue one selected and you can me
to make always interested in style it
in a way that's appropriate for specific
apparent am for specific interaction
state
okay app compatibility
so macros 10 yosemite
does bring some big changes to your
app's look and feel
and even perhaps that really haven't
made any changes %uh the visual
differences can be quite
quite significant this is dictionary
hearing even those is a pretty
straightforward application
you can see the I the differences are
are notable
both in terms of the generous tax as
well as the layout I some the elements
well so what does this mean for your for
your app
and how to think about having a wrap or
on Yosemite well
first and foremost we really like to
encourage you to
make your app is awesome as it can be on
your salmon in take advantage of as many
of these
new you why experiences that we've
provided the building blocks for
I including the including definitely me
too
visual effects %um vibrancy but what
about deploying a maverick's
you know it's quite legitimate to meet
him to want to have an application that
works both
on maverick's in and in on your family
are so that you can have
per support all other customers
well having it both ways can be quite
challenging
given the changes that we've made into
designer
a fourth time as a case study
I I'd like to show Xcode here now this
is my Xcode running on
I maverick's and noticed the up the tab
which was carefully designed to blend in
very well with the title bar mixer well
here we go
in yosemite and are changed the time or
material and suddenly everything doesn't
match
well this is Nick illustration of the
challenges that napkin face if they have
to support both
the old old you I language as well as
the new
well we all know this had a happy ending
because this is in fact what the excuse
that you're living with right now
I looks like on you so many because
Xcode actually did make an optimization
to make sure they look perfect for
I'm your semi release
so what techniques can you use to
set yourself up for success
I in the face have these big design
changes
well first and foremost we encourage you
to stick with the system what we mean by
that is
where possible I miss you have an
overriding and
reason to do so I stick with standard
control stick with
template images stick with the system
colors
I stick with system fonts all those
things will be automatically managed and
after appropriately by after across both
platforms
and will look reasonable like for
example the entire title bar all the
control
all the all the fun selectors all the
colors to automatically resolve
themselves to the proper thing
on each platform after there there are
many cases where that may not be
sufficient
and we actually do have to write
different code like for example
the selected PAP change in Xcode
well you can also to use one-time checks
to
to tailor your code in resources for
each design
so let's go through two techniques there
are more but these are two primary ones
I wanna to
to show you for what you might be able
to do well the first thing could be a
simple check
so let's say you have an application
it's actually go deployment target of
$10.9
and you wanna you wanna potential
introduce some pirate you are but you
know you can't just directly reference
that stuff
I'm you know I'm tonight because it
doesn't exist well
what you can do is you can do using that
with the
stanwyck when can be whoever are Susie
redeployment targets at the $10.9 you
can always check to see if
are an important symbol like in this
case and its appearance name vibrant
dark
is my MIL in only fits my mail then you
can go ahead in
and use that code and set up a visual
effects you for example
for a piece if your UI that can be very
remembers nice thing about this code is
that
it automatically brings in the vibrancy
when an application is running
on yosemite but does whatever
me to do before I'll I'm maverick's
another approach is to do a version
check
to serve check but Runtime Environment
my I'm I'm
as a little more straight forward Lamar
old school so one
this is the standard technique that we
recommend for doing that at least for
Coco applications trying to Kolkata
work I compare the in a second version
number
against the pre published Constance make
sure you get that to greater than sign
correct don't put it the other way you
end up with a rather surprising results
I am and then this would allow you to
for example select different image
resources are going to totally different
code our constructions I'm across one
version of the OS versus the other
up bill so
in general what we'd really like to
encourage you to do
is look for opportunities to freshen
your design
in as many places as possible and
freshen your design everywhere
we really think that a majority of your
customers are going to majority for
users i should say
are going to be on the US amity design
and your family
in the in in the very near future and
it's going to be
if you do have to make a choice
a about opinion is on your word about
about
about I'm changing things on I'm older
platforms
I I would also like to encourage you to
when in doubt favor the new visual style
what I mean by that an actual
Xcode is an example of this as a case
study
it's okay to go and bring some of the
elements that have been introduced
him and so I'm L matter to be
interesting to yosemite and bring them
back into your maverick's
app UI design language so for example
and I don't mean like obviously the
whole translucency think that that
doesn't work on all
on maverick's but I for in terms of
partnerships button cliffs
are your icon for example it is totally
OK and it actually works are reasonably
well
to take somebody simpler cleaner I
design styles that are
featured in Yosemite and to have them
show up on your buttons are in your
you win the title bar a in your
application maverick's
so I can help relieve some pressure
so I A we're getting close to wrapping
up here
so just want to recap what we talked
about today
so we have this there's a brand new user
first time first time
we walk through that we've talked a
little bit and trying to understand the
components a vibrancy in what role the
players and what it does for you
and we talked about adapting your
applications to these new
these new features please a primitive
another plugin for the advanced session
for more in depth exploration above
using a special affect you
using fiber materials and of some other
from the
tips and tricks of getting I getting
these you eyes together
with alacrity
so in summary a lot of excitement lots
of exciting design changes
coming to West Ham and I if there's one
message i'd like to leave with you
has stepped to the coca firms can help
guide you through all this change
and please avail yourselves their
services
for more information we have our
excellent developer evangelist right
over here with the fantasy makers to
experience
and handkerchief you know him if you
have any questions
and there are many related sessions I
including the what's new in Cocoa which
happened earlier today
are actually yeah earlier today today's
Tuesday
I the there's also the fans talk
tomorrow
I also wanna point out the creating
extensions for I listen or stem
which happen actually is concluding
happened just an hour ago
and the reason I mention as I think the
talk about Notification Center
extensions which is one of the places
where you use
dark fiber an appearance and there are
also some
some there's an Xcode sessions and
Interface Builder sessions and encourage
you to go to we're
I'm they're not gonna touch directly on
some other stuff is very important to
see some
some the new new features that have been
exposed in new wine in your preschooler
and if you haven't gotten enough my not
an engineer colleague Mike Stern he's
having a
talk right following this one called is
an intuitive user experiences
and you can get more neva more design
wisdom
and with that like to wrap up and thank
you