hi everyone I'm Claire and I'm on the
island successfully team
here at Apple today I'll be sharing with
you about accessibility I i OS
and how you can get all your app's to be
used by everyone
our talk today is going to be in two
parts
first are given introduction to
accessibility
I'll talk about some the features we
offer I was currently
as well as a new things coming in I was
in a second hardest talk
I'll be showing you how you can make
your app successful both by adding
visual accommodations
and by implementing magic accessibility
so first what is accessibility
accessibility is all about making things
usable
for everyone I O S we look at four broad
areas
have your needs we want users with
physical motor challenges users with
learning needs
users with hearing loss and uses a
different vision needs
to be able to experience I West fully
our goal is equal access
for everyone so let's look at some
examples
how e-commerce this some users may have
a physical impairment that prevents them
from using the touchscreen
in fact there only infer device maybe
a switch a switch could be something
like a button
mounted on a wheelchair had best so how
do we make
the rich touch interface I'll ask usual
by someone who can only use a switch
I answer is switch control
when special the naval a cursor appears
on the street and moves for item
to Adam with a specific time when the
user
activator switch that wasn't interact
with the highlighted on
so they can do things like top or scroll
necklace look at
learning I was devices have an
incredibly powerful
in the classroom because other easy to
use interface
and they're engaging aP's for the same
reasons they've been great for children
with autism for the theaters we faced
some
unique challenges that first for one
much I have a daughter then
is learning an app they might decide to
press the home button
and now the device is full distractions
so to address this issue
we create a guided access which the way
for our parents
for educators to keep the device in a
specific ap
when God actors at the naval
pressing the Home button where the lock
button have no effect
and so the child can have an
uninterrupted learning experience
free from distractions next let's look
at hearing
many users were hearing loss use hearing
aids
to help amplify the sound around them
but traditional hearing aids come with a
couple
issues first they require that you carry
are not with you
so that you can adjust the volume and
that can be cumbersome
and second call quality can be less than
after all
when using hearing it we have a phone
next to a hearing aid
you the hearing Fi's all the town
including
background noise or picks up the signal
from the phone electromagnetic field but
that signal can also be noisy
trading static so to address these two
issues
we partnered with hearing in
manufacturers around the globe
treat me for iPhone hearing aids these
hearing aid
connect directly to your iPhone and you
can do things like
adjust the following the hearing aids
without the need for a separate remote
in addition audio stream directly from
your iPhone
you're hearing aid so becomes
effectively a Bluetooth headset
and thats improves clock Ali
dramatically
finally let's look
at the broad area vision when the iPhone
was first introduced
many people were concerned that blind
users would not be able to take
advantage of its features
could do you think about it how do you
use a touch screen
if you don't see the screen it's going
to be difficult because
you wanna say really know what your
touching and you might accidentally tap
a button that you didn't mean to tap
so to address this we created Voice
number
when Voice number is unable you can
touch
anywhere on screen to hear what they
just touched before they take an action
like
tapping a button we also have
accommodations in our settings
for users with low vision who may not
necessarily need the full power
a voice-over for example some users
for for Boulder funds in which case they
can enable Bowl text
to get picture text some users may be
higher contrast
and if so we offer several options
including the ability to reduce
transparency on the system
and finally for users who are more
sensitive to motion
we offer reduced motion setting which
provides more subtle transitions
for example when you launch an app with
this notion enabled
crossfade interview
somewhat we offer I was currently to
support equal access
but we've been working hard and I'd like
to hide or some other new features were
offering an Iowa State
first guided access time limits
time limits are all about transitions
when a child is immersed
an app and then it's time to move on to
the next activity
that transition can cause some anxiety
with time limits a caretaker can assign
a specific amount
a time that a child should use an app
when the town is
almost reached the child receives a
warning helping them to prepare to move
on to the next
activity and when the time limit is over
the device locks next worrying Alex
Tyler s
summer you may have already met Alex but
for those who haven't
to let him introduce himself hi
everyone I'm Alex and I mean US English
voice
I've been living on Macs for years and
now
I'm excited to make myself at home on my
OS
to Alex will be available in all of our
assistive technologies that you speech
including voice-over speaks election
and a new feature introducing I was
eight called speak street
screen is great for anyone might have
trouble reading the screen
when it enabled you can do a simple
gesture or
ask Siri to speak the streams you and
advice will start reading whatever's
on street you also get options like the
ability to Paul's
rewind organ slow down the speech
and finally I'd like to highlight soon
someone you may have been using zoom for
years on I West
but we've reimagined I was 8 and add a
whole new way for you to interact with
but before I introduce at let's first
talk about what's the Indus currently
zoom magnifies the entire screen and
then use three fingers gestures
to navigate this approach comes
with a few issues first if you're using
three finger gestures
that means you're covering up a
significant part of the screen
especially on iPhones
also using free finger gestures mean
it's hard to use a phone
on the go you can't use the phone in a
single hand
you always need have one had to hold it
and the other hand to do three things:
gestures
finally typing can be tricky with you
enable
you have the choice between zooming in
on the content you're creating
or having access to the full keyboard
but you can't have both
at the same time
so to address all these issues for
introducing a new window
note for Zim and I like democrat to you
now
this is window too soon not only part
the screen
is magnified I can change what part
knife I
by dragging the edge at the window with
a single finger
I can also tap the edges the window to
get resize handles
so I can change how much the screen
night fight
if I tap on the a row at the edge in the
window
I get a menu with several options
including the ability to adjust my
Zimbio
now it's going to notes I would create a
new note and
watch what happens when the key or comes
up
Zuma no automatically got out of the way
the keyboard so I have full
access the keyboard but my constant
an ally tight
notice how the zoom into follows makers
are so I can always see what I just
typed
sadat some what we've been doing here at
Apple float
equal access for everyone but for the
second part of the story
we need your help I was is a great
platform could
all the app's you guys create and it's
up to you
to make sure that your abs can be used
by everyone
to that end I'll be showing you now how
you can do that with our API
utah real is going to be in two parts
first I'll show you how to add visual
accommodations
for users with different vision needs
and second I'll be showing you how to
implement some magic accessibility
sudden assistive technology like
voice-over can navigate your app
earlier in the stock showed some other
visual accommodations we offer i OS
for you to a different vision aids now
of writing API
see you can make those accommodations in
your app's as well
we have a way for you to detect whether
the user has all text
redo transparency starting colors or
reduce motion enabled
and that makes it really easy for you to
make specific adjustments
in your app for those users
suddenly show you how you can do that
now using a sample app we created for
this presentation
okay so first we're going to identify
some areas are ap
that need visual accommodations to do
that I've got my simulator
and I'm enabled several the
accessibility settings
in this case I got ball text reduce
motion
and underneath increase contrast I've
also got reduce transparency
and dark colors that way when the
billion dollar after Xcode
we'll see what the user with those
settings we'll see
not going to Xcode and when I click on
building run
so this is a simple dating app at the
top you have the title the app which is
hello goodbye notice how the title is
very bold
and the background is fully opaque that
because we're using a standard
navigation controller
so we get the ball text and reduce
transparency behaviors
for free but because we're doing some
custom UI in our apt
there's still some work we need to do
you probably already noticed
how we have transparent overlays over a
photo background
when reduced transparency is on you
should really be making those opaque
in addition the text in the buttons
should be thicker because we have all
text enable
now going to click on the profile but
so here's where the user I can adjust my
settings
again we have the transparent overlay
and the text that should be bolder
at the bottom issue we have a preview
tap which I can slide up
to see how other users on this app will
see my profile
knows how my info is in great text under
each beheadings
when the user has dark in color enabled
it would be better if that text for
darker
to provide higher contrast against the
white background
now going to click on back and I'm going
to go into the match is page
so here's where I can see matches that
the app is adjusting for me
and I can say hello or goodbye to each
one
I want this guy's elevator pitch so I
want to say hello
and watch what happens when I swipe up
noticed how the next match enemies
on-screen
as those coming from far away two dozen
example
an animation where we should provide an
alternate
for users who are more sensitive to
motion
and now let's do all this using the API
Xcode
to the first thing you're going to dress
in the text let's make sure that it's
thicker when bolt act is on
to do that I'm going to click on the
style utilities file on the left
which is where all our colors and fonts
are defined and then click on the drop
down to the top
to find our phat methods
years have both of these methods are
returning Avenir light
at the custom font now if we were using
the system
bond or the preferred font for textile
API
we would be getting Paul text for free
but because we expect
be picked a specific font two years we
also need to pick a fight to use when
Paul Texas enable
to do that I'd like to create
a helper method in the return the font
name
all we're doing here is first checking
your book butterball text is enabled
and it is we can return a thicker
version are fought
otherwise we can return the same but
we've been using
and now we just need to use our helper
you not to fun its
not take careful text now let's look at
those transparent overlays
I'm gonna click on the drop down at the
top and find where that transparent
overly color
is defined notice how right now
returning
eighty percent white when we do
transparency is enabled we should return
a 100 percent white
so we do that here
okay now let's make sure that the great
text in the profile preview
is doctor went dark in colors on to do
that
and when I click on the drop down again
and fined for that colors to find
so here we just returning gray let's
first check
whether the user has dark in color the
naval and if so
weakening trend black instead
finally look at that zooming animation
we saw on a Mac cheese page
where the new match appears as though
it's coming from far away
to to address that I'm going to click on
the matches you controller on the left
now but open the drop-down and find
worry enemy the cards
no talk here resuming the new card
interview
now for users who have reduced motion
enable a better experience
would be to fade the card interview
because that animation
does not utilize a motion effect so
I'm going to create helper method the
phage the card interview
all we're doing is setting the Alpha the
card with animation
and that the point we would normally
issued card let's first check
whether reduce motion the naval if it is
we use our famous but instead
we can use assuming method for other
uses
K now let's build a runner after these
changes
here's our app again notice have a
transparent overlays are done
and have been replaced by opaque white
because reduce transparent even able
in addition the text in about as much
thicker
when I click on profile
again the same issues have been resolved
here I can slide up on a few tab
and now notice how my information is
darker
and higher contrast against the white
background
now and click on back and click on the
matches but
again I'm going to say hello to my
favorite match and watch what happens
when I do that
the next match page on to view because
we have reduced motion enable
so that's how easy it is for you to make
visual accommodations in your app
for users were different vision needs
next let's look at implementing semantic
accessibility
that boys are are users and switch
control user's
can also use your app
somatic accessibility is what allows an
assistive technology like by seller
to get information from a nap and to
control the app
doing things like tapping buttons are
adjusting sliders
here's an example assume at the
accessibility at work
let's say I've got the calculator app
open and voice-overs enable
when i touch on top of the five button
voice-over
intersect that touch and then asks the
app
what it has at that point
the app respond with an element that
represents the firefighter
and that allows voice-over to draw
cursor around the five
and to speak five so that I know what I
just touched
if I then decide to tap the five adn I
can do a double tap
anymore on screen and that tells
voice-over activate
the selected item so that's how
voice-over users
can use a calculator app
so how do you make sure that your app
for Savoy server in this way
as well well the good news is that
most demanding accessibility is already
built anti OS
so you get a lot of stuff for free but
you should still
audit your app with voice over on the
device
and there are couple questions you
should ask yourself
first can voice-over speak everything
that needs to be seen
second can voice-over do everything that
a user would want to do
now I'm going to be referring a lot to
voice over in the stop but all the work
for going to do in our apt also applies
to switch control
just keep that in mind
to some an audit your app for semantic
accessibility
I recommend that you go to your
accessibility settings on the device
and set your accessibility shortcut to
voice our that will allow you
to crypt triple click the home button to
quickly enable or disable voice over
if you never use voice over before here
are some tips to get you started
when you tap something that selects and
speaks
so for example in this screen if I tap
on the accessibility table cell
the cursor moves there and the device
speaks accessibility
if I double tap anywhere on screen that
%uh boys over to
activate the selected item so in this
case if I did that
accessibility table cell would get
pressed and we were moved accessibility
page
when I swipe to the right that selects
and speaks
the next element right now the back
button is selected
so if I tried to the right the
navigation title become select
and finally when you have a ScrollView
you can use three finger swipes
to scroll so I want to see more the
accessibility settings
i cant three-finger swipe up just roll
down by page
for that all you need to know to do an
audit of your own apt with oyster
and now lets show you how he knew that
with our sample app
so here they're dating app running on
the device when I triple click the home
button
boys over on for sorry company
the first then we'll do with ask
ourselves that question can voice-over
speak everything that needs to be seen
to first I'm going to tap on the title
at the top
hello goodbye heading okay so voice-over
can see that
now let's touch on the logo
it's kinda quiet but that sound you just
heard means that voice-over doesn't
think there's anything under my finger
so it looks like most other users won't
be able to read this logo
now I'm gonna tap on the Profile button
profile
button and literacies that when I swiped
right
at select the next outlet so I do that
matches button
water finds a match but if I select the
right
one more time we hear that sound with me
there's nothing else
after the salomon which is correct in
this case so it looks like this view is
in pretty good shape except for the
missing logo
now what did happen profile profile
button and when a double tap activated
profile
profile back back button let's wipe the
right a few times
to see what boys overseas profile
heading your age nineteen percent
adjustable swipe up or down with one
finger to adjust the value
tonight a little strange we just heard
your age
followed by nineteen percent it would
make a lot more sense
if voice-over said the age here which is
actually 37
and the instruction set a swipe offer
down to adjust the night
so I swipe up watch what happens 28
percent
by a jumping up by 10 years
so it doesn't look like bush ever users
will be able to set their age
accurately right now in our apt
now I'm going to strike the right if you
are times to see what else was overseas
47 copies
music swing dance wine text field
double tap to edit let's make sure that
moisture users Canada two hotties
so I'm a double tap text field is
editing
music swing dance wine and people came
up
so that looks like whatever users will
be able to do that
let's just make sure that the Done
button which appeared in the top right
is also visible to voice-over salt app
on that
done button and it is I double tap
that it has added editing so it looks
like my hobbies are in good shape
and the elevator pitch field is very
similar hobbies so we'll skip that
for now now I'm gonna touch on the
Preview tab at the bottom
preview so it's just saying preview
and if I couldn't see the screen without
visual indication a cab
in Miami clear to me what this does I
mean I might try to double tap it
and so when I do that preview nothing
happens because
this tab doesn't respond to attack in
needs to have a slide gesture up
the right now bush ever users cannot
preview their profile
now I'm gonna touch on the back button
back back button
and double-tap hello goodbye heading
I'm a tap on matches now matches button
and double-tap matches matches back
back button okay again we're gonna swept
the right a few times
to see what voice overseas matches
heading
swipe up their own to say hello slide
down a road to say goodbye
Alexis okay that's also a little strange
on visually when you look at this logo
are thus label you see swipe up to say
hello
but voiceover saying swipe up a row to
say hello
not because voice-overs reading each
other's characters literally
so it would be better if voice-over
described as in a more natural way
now a swipe to the right to get to the
photo gauge
except we didn't get to the phone a now
to try touching it directly
and again I get that sound which means
whatever doesn't think there's a voter
there
now some are you might be wondering
whether that even import
you after all voice our User doesn't see
the photo right
but you're not is important so for a
couple reasons
first on a voice-over user using this
app I need to know
that other people in a sap can see my
photo
even if I don't take full advantage to
the photo it's important to know that
it's there
and second remember that semantic
accessibility is not just about
voice-over
so it's always a good idea to expose any
meaningful info
from your app okay now wanna touch I
age again age
and one swipe to the right a few times
parties 32 cooking bubble tea with
friends
travel you're paying close attention
you may have noticed how boys are went
from age
to hobbies and then back to 32
so when you're looking at the visual
layout at this profile card is clear
what this means but moisture users are
often
swiping to to the different elements
because that can be easier than
touching exactly where an element is and
so it's important
have a logical order for how the
talented
it's also important for switch control
user's switch control
the experts control cursor will move
from element alman
in the same order and it's important or
defeat predictable
so that a switch control user can
activate the switch at the right time
okay lasting remember that our second
question was
can voice-over do everything that needs
to be due done in asap
the prior to the match is pages so allow
users to say hello
or goodbye to the matches but more so
for years
won't be able to do this right now
because swipe gestures
get intercepted by voice sir and when
you provide a different way
for moisture years to do the same
actions not the kinda process you can
take
with your own apt to see whether it is
semantically accessible
now let's look at resolving those issues
beyond countered for someone to
introduce the most basic accessibility
API
there are only two properties here and
he remember nothing else from the stock
please remember these two just by using
these two property
you can solve a lot of accessibility
issues
the most important property you need no
is the is excess Billy Allen property
this is the boy in that determines
whether a view is visible
to voice-over by default returned yes
for standard UI controls and labels
which is why even though we haven't done
any semantic accessibility work
in our apt yet a lot of the text is
already visible to voice our
and a second most important property you
need to know in the accessibility label
property
this describes love you and by several
speak this
when a voice over your touches on a view
if you train your views and Interface
Builder you can set the property
directly from Xcode you I
on the right hand side Xcode you'll find
an identity inspector
and there's an accessibility section
there the accessibility
enable text box corresponds to is
excessively and
and the label field correspond to access
Billy label
if you creating your views in code it's
still really easy to set these
properties
as shown here
so now with look at using these two
properties
and see how much more accessible we can
make ap it's the first thing
we're going to do and make sure that
whatever users can read the logo on the
first page
to do that I'm going to go
click on the Start controller on the
left which is where
and we create that lip I'm gonna click
on the drop down
and find our view did learn math
to hear the lookout just image right now
and first we're going to set is
exceptionally Alan to yes
so that voice-over can see it then we
also need to make sure voice-over
describes it correctly
so we give it and accessibility label in
this case we're just going to give it
but expect inside the lookout notice
also that were local I'd in a string
because voice-over speak in many
languages
next let's make sure that the photo that
in the profile card can also be seen by
voice
do that I'm going to click on the car
review class on the left
and I would over the drop down to find
where we add our profile views:
so here's we're adding the fire again we
set it just really element PS
and we get inappropriate access Billy
label
in this case we're just gonna call it
profile photo
filing let's look at the instructions
for saying hello or goodbye
right now voice-over is saying swipe a
row to say hello
let's fix that so to you that I'm going
to click
on the matches you can chill are on the
left and organ open the dropped out of
the top
to find where we add those fighting
instructions
so here's the label that says
it's already inaccessibility element by
default so all we need to do is change
the accessibility label
we're going to give it one that is just
like the tax on the label
except for replacing those unico que
rose with words
now I'm going to build and run the app
with these changes
extras folder to Abes double tap to open
hello goodbye extras folder to aP's
double tap to open
hello goodbye
here half again with these changes the
first thing I do is touch the logo
hello goodbye meet your match image now
voice-over users can read this
next time wanna touch on the matches but
matches
button and double-tap
matches back back button let's first
look
at what the instructions say right now
so I got to say hello
slide down to say goodbye guess that
much easier to understand
and now when I swipe to the right
profile photo
image voice-over is able to see the
photo in the profile
so that's how you do with just these two
properties already made
other partner accessible
but because we got some more custom UI
in our apt some additional
API will need to use to give voice our
users a really great experience
first I like to introduce the concept
accessibility treats
trace describe the function I love you
for example in the familiar timer app
each other we all the time
had the trait up adjustable and that
means that
its value can be changed up or down
the start button have the trade a button
and that gives the user a hint that this
is something that can be activated
again if you're creating your views
Interface Builder is really easy to set
the street
directly from excuse you I in the same
section we talked about earlier
you'll see a bunch of checkboxes for
traits somebody check boxes may already
be checked
in which case I would definitely
recommend leaving the salon
but at check boxes next to trace that
you think are important for you
encoded also straightforward to set the
excess Billy trace
but just remember that it is a bitmask
so if you want to at a trade
in addition to others use a bitwise or
operator
as shown here to combine them
next let's talk about accessibility
value
excessively value is a string on
properties so in that way it's similar
to accessibility label
if you use accessibility value for
things that are dynamic
for example uses on views that have the
adjustable train
to describe a numerical value
right now in our ap the H latter had an
accessibility value
nineteen percent that's a case where we
can override accessibility value
to return the age instead
next we'll talk about actions to actions
are how voice-over can control your app
to really common ones Rd internet and
document actions
to the reaction that are associated
specifically for views that have the
adjustable chain
and they allow the user to increase or
decrease an element's value
again in our apt a fly to right now can
be in Trenton or decorated
but right now it's doing that by ten
years
we can overriding netted to allow the
user to change your aid by a single year
another really important action is the
activity action
and that's what happens when a user
double taps normally when you double tap
something that just
taps the view but you can override this
method
argues that respond to a specific
gesture and I we wash our users can do
that action as well
easily for example in our apt we can use
this for the Preview tab
which currently only response to a
sliding gesture
and finally we have notifications which
a liar
app to tell boys are when something has
changed one really important
notification is
the lab change notification should you
should send this
when you're changing the layout oh yeah
for example adding or removing years
for example in our app right now when
you revealed a preview
washer/dryer might not realize that new
elements have come on stream
once you post a lab change notification
more server checks to find
the elements that are there currently
now we've put all this together in our
sample app to resolve some more those
issues we encountered
so the first thing we're going to do is
make sure that Bush every year's
can editor H to do that
I'm going to go to Xcode and click on
the each letter class on the left
here let's override accessibility value
now when you can return the age instead
of a percentage
all we're doing is taking the value fire
which corresponds the age
and making it into a string
next let's make sure the boys are users
can add
or remove to the range by was single
year
so to do that with override excessively
entrant all are doing here
adding one decided value we also send
the value chains controlled and now way
other parts were you I'd that
rely on the sliders value can update
accordingly
we do the same thing presently document
and now one nuance to this after these
changes
are each slider has all the information
that the user needs to know
namely the user's age so from a semantic
accessibility standpoint
that label showing up next to the slider
is redundant
and Mike even be confusing so
just hide to do that
I'm going to click on the profile the
controller on the left
and open the drop-down to find where we
add that label
to hide it we simply set it successfully
element to know
okay next let's make sure that bush ever
users can preview their profiles
to do that let's go in Xcode and click
on RP label class
so here's our roadmap for this we're
going to override accessibility activate
on the preview label so that we can
control what happens when the user
double taps
but we need to tell the profile
controller to show or hide the previous
civil me away
to communicate that to do that
let's set up a delegate protocol
an almost dark purple had a single map
in ever going to call when the labeled
acted
course we also set up a dog property so
that
you can color can set up a delegate
now let's go to the implementation file
here going to override excessively
activity
all we're doing is leading the delegate
no that the labels activity
and we return yes to indicate that the
action succeed
while we're here but also at abutment
rate to the preview label
and that way Bouchard users will have I
will have a hint
that they can double tap acted
to do that I'm bored override
excessively traits
and first for calling super to get any
treaty would have by default
then we use the bitwise OR operator
to combine that with the button tree
okay now let's go back to our profile
you can chill or
to implement the delegate protocol
so for someone to scroll to top it off
I'll and declared that this you can
chill or
implants that article next I'm going to
open the drop-down
and find where we at that preview label
to the view here
we've set but you can tailor as its
delegate
to finally let implement that protocol
my scroll to the bottom
and here we implemented the only
delegate protocol method we have
so when the preview labels acted will
first check whether the previews
currently showing
if it is we can hide it otherwise we
reveal it
one additional thing recall that when
you hire sure the preview
you're changing the layout at the screen
so we should tell voice-over that's
happened
to do that let's go to implementation
have revealed card
and dismiss card I'm gonna click on the
drop down to the top
and find those two methods
both these methods are enemy in the car
honor of spring
in the completion for that animation we
post lab change notification
miss do the same thing down here when
dismissing the preview
okay now is building an app with these
changes
hello goodbye
double tap to open extras folder
to aP's double tap to open hello goodbye
okay so here we are in the apt without
changes for signs have on the Profile
button
profile button and I'm going to double
tap to activate profile
profile back back button first
let's touch on the age lighter 37
adjustable
swipe up or down with one finger to
adjust the value
tonight at us much clearer we're
actually seeing the age now
and when I swiped up to adjust the value
it goes up by a single year when I
select the right
copies notice how we've skipped over
that redundant label to the right
now I'm going to touch on the pre tap
preview button this time
because its editor button I know I can
do something with this
song on a double tap preview and not
have a preview appears
so much like to the right profile photo
image
I conceive stuff inside the preview if I
tap on
see you again preview button and
double-tap
preview that hide the previews so I
checked the right now
I hear that sound most ever knows that
the preview has gone off street so
that's how we can make
even custom UI accessible to voice to
resolve the last remaining issues we
encountered during our audit we're going
to use a new API
added in Iowa State first let's talk
about the UI accessibility container
protocol
something you may already realized that
that isn't new
but we've updated and I'll 8 to make it
much easier to use
for those who are familiar with this
protocol you access Billy container
is a wage paternalistic cessna Lee Ellis
for love you
you need to do this if you have elements
not correspond to views
for example you might have a view with
the drying it
and you might want different parts for
the drying to be separate accessibility
allen's
in that case you would create an
exceptionally element
for each part the drying and returned
those elements using
the UI testily container protocol and
you can see last year's talk
for a great example how to create your
own elements but what many people don't
realize is that
this protocol is also a great way to
return existing allen's
in a specific order so for example
if voice-over is navigating things in a
different order from what we want we
cannot use this protocol to return those
element in the or that we want bush over
to see them
and now for what's changed
so currently in order to use this
protocol there are three methods
you need to override you know I was 8
there's a single property call
accessibility elements
which you can set to return a list
the talents and notice how now you don't
need to override some class
and you don't have to deal with three
separate methods so we think people are
going to find that much
easier to use Big Pimpin
next up we're introducing a new
class called the custom action you
should use custom actions when you have
more than one action for an element
for example in the app switcher
each ap thumbnails can you to be tapped
to launch the app
or you can slide up to close the app and
some
we expose a custom action for closing
the app and now a voice-over users can
do that action easily
without needing to do the sliding
gesture in our sample app we can also
use this API
to allow water users to say hello or
goodbye to the matches
the custom action class looks like this
you create a custom action object for
the name
that moisture uses to describe it and
you also given a target
and a selector so similar to what you
would pass to you I but and that
determines what happens when the action
is performed
once you create a larger custom action
objects
you can assign them to love you using
the accessibility custom actions
array property now let's use this
in our apt to fix the remaining issues
first
we're going to do is make sure that boys
are navigate
the use in the profile card in the
correct order
namely we don't want to go from age to
hani's and back to 32
to fix that was click on the car view
class on the left
here's our method worry at all the
profile views: when I scroll to the
bottom
after all OVR sub you haven't read in we
can set the
accessibility element property a park
argue to an array
%uh its abuse any order you want them to
appear
notice how I put the age title right
next to the each value
okay next
let's make sure that whatever you just
can't say hello or goodbye to the
matches
to do that I'm going to click on the
match if you controller on the left
first let's find out what we're doing
when a user swatch offer down without
voice-over enable
someone a click on the drop-down and
find our swipe gesture recognizer
handlers to put these cameras are simply
calling into math is called say hello
and say goodbye and which are
implemented by the pup
these methods are also great candidates
for the selector that we pass
to the custom action objects the only
thing we need to change
it make sure that they return booleans
to indicate whether the action sixty it
in most cases you can just return yes
now one more thing when you say hello or
goodbye
to a match the layout changes so again
we're going to post
only at change notification both these
methods are calling into a helper
call animate cards for hello which is
implemented
read about
so in the completion for this animation
we should post are we have change
notification
okay so that's how to set up a need now
let's create those custom action objects
I'm going to click on the drop down to
the top
and find where we add to cart to the
matches page
to hear a credit card and were
assigning swipe gesture recognizers to
it
alongside the swipe gesture recognizers
but now create our custom actions
for someone to create an action for
saying hello
here's how that works we give it a name
which in this case
is simply say hello we pass in the view
controller
at the target and a selector we pass in
the method that we just modified
to return a boolean we do the same thing
for saying goodbye now
we want the user to be able to say hello
or goodbye wherever they are in the
profile card
so for every element in the car view
ruinous set it successfully custom
actions poverty
to an array of these two actions
okay now let's build and run with these
changes
double tap to open
hello goodbye hello goodbye
okay what happened matches matches
button and double tap to activate
matches
matches back back button to the first
thing I'm going to you
is top on the photo and starts wiping to
the right to see what order Voice
oversees the talents
profile photo image age
32 copies cooking
bubble tea with friends travel not much
easier to understand next let's touch
any element in the profile card in this
case I'm gonna touch on the photo
and listen to what it says profile photo
image
swipe up or down to select a custom
action so we're given the option to
choose when the actions we created
when I swipe down say hello I hear the
description of the action
if I want to take that action I can
double tap now butcher users
can also say hello or goodbye to the
matches not how easy it is to use the
new API
we've added and I was aid so we kinda
talked and Bartok
and there if you take away that like you
have when you leave first
I lets users are divers keep in mind
that
there maybe you just wrap who'd have
different needs but you should accompany
when you accommodate more users
your widening your user base when more
people can use your app
more people well and finally
and accessibility is a low effort
high-reward business
we just seen how with only a few co
changes
we took a nap that was just unusable for
many users
and made into an experience that they
too can enjoy so
without needing a lot of work you can
make a real difference to users
for more information you can contact
are evangelist shake their hands or you
think cell
the accessibility programming guy for
ISL s there's also the developer forms
you can ask other developers your
questions there some earlier sessions to
this one
prior to this talk we had a talk about
accessibility on OS 10
if you missed it you can watch the video
tomorrow
W talk about designing aP's for people
on the autistic spectrum
and on Friday can learn how to make
even complex web applications excess
thank you all for coming
I hope you enjoyed the talk and have a
great rest at the conference