well everyone
so
I Mike Stern on the user experience
evangelist at Apple
and thank you all for coming on sticking
around after a really long day very
technical content
now this presentation is going to be a
bit different
right this is about design and in
particular
it's about designing intuitive
interfaces I'd like to
start with little exercise Magin
if you will that your house and your
in your kitchen and the phone rings and
the person on the other end the line has
some really exciting news for you
they tell you you one some money
not just a little bit of money but like
a lot of money
and they also tell you that in order to
claim your prize
you need to call a phone number
and then that hang up the phone
so you're sitting there in your kitchen
and you need to write down this phone
number
you need to write down this phone number
before you forget
so you're looking around for something
to
to write with your iPhone not around
right and
is casting around and you're starting to
get a little panicky because you really
want to remember this number in
right before you forget it you see a pen
and a piece of paper
and you write down the phone number so
that's a pretty
simple scenario right now the end of the
story by the way thank you
thank you very much so you had this very
clear objective which was to write down
this phone number
and you found a pen and pad of paper
with which to accomplish that task
and then you wrote down the phone number
now is it
well not really quite that simple
you're under pressure you're stressing
out a little bit
and when you're stressed out that can
affect your memory and it can affect
your ability to perform basic
cognitive tasks such as remembering the
phone number
and writing it down or picking out a pen
from a bunch of similar objects
things that look just like a pen and
assuming that you can remember the phone
number and
find the pen and paper and write it down
you have to also consider what are all
the skills that are necessary for you to
write
for starters writing involves a lot of
coordination and
dexterity just ask a three-year-old
they totally suck your writing
and so did all love you and so did I
when we're that age we went from writing
like this
to writing like that or
really something like this writing with
a pen takes years and years a practice
and there's all these small little
skills that you need to learn along the
way
there so fluid and natural to you now
but they weren't always so easy
you had to gain the high hand
coordination to be able to pick up
and manipulate small objects and it took
years to learn how to
hold the pen properly position arrest on
the table on your arm for stability
you had to learn how to draw basic
letterforms
right along a straight line you need to
learn the difference between upper case
and lower case letters
the list goes on but you don't think
about
any of those things when you're sitting
in your kitchen and writing down that
phone number
all those years
writing with different types of pens and
pencils and markers and
crayons have given you this tremendous
amount of muscle memory
and that muscle memory frees you to
remember something
like phone number if you had to
consciously
remember all those individual skills it
would be pretty difficult for you to
have accomplished that task
in other words
it easier for you to have written down
and remember that phone number
because the active writing is so
intuitive using software
is no different the more aP's behaviors
we expect them to
the more intuitive they are to us more
intuitive outs are to us
the easier it is for us to concentrate
on our true objectives
whether that's communicating with
friends capturing memories of loved ones
checking the weather are exploring the
cosmos the very best
user interfaces are so intuitive so
natural
that the disorder disappear and allow us
to focus on
what truly matters that is what we call
intuitive so with that in mind
what makes a nap intuitive well I put
together a list of what I believe to be
the top five characteristics
have intuitive user interface designs
this is not
an exhaustive list we could be here for
hours and hours and hours
talking about all the things that make
something intuitive we would order pizza
get your ex would be a lot of fun but
unfortunately we don't have the time for
that today
this list to five things
i think is the most basic and essential
characteristics what makes Iowa
for Mac App intuitive and I also want to
point out
up front hear that what's intuitive to
one person
may not be so intuitive to others I mean
this is intuitive if you're an airline
pilot
everybody and every square to read
display is there for very good reason
you know were everything is
totally natural pretty sure this doesn't
work
I also want to point out that these are
the most fundamental things the most
basic things
but the line is just like anything else
in life I mean
sometimes the most basic things are the
most important
the most consequential I've been
designing for many years and I've seen
time and time again
even the most seasoned the most
experienced designers
who make poor quality designs because
they've lost sight of the fundamentals
now in order for be
a pen to be intuitive needs to get some
very fundamental
for basic things just right and needs to
be wide enough to grip firmly
but not so wide that it can be
manipulated
easily if the pain is too thin
are too wide it becomes intuitive
because we become aware of it
for trying to think how we gonna right
with this pen it doesn't feel quite
right
or for Penn was too short
we will not know how to hold it right we
pick it up with your fingertips and
we'll be riding with it be going all
over the place in
what we right when it looked very good
would be very conscious at the Penn
itself or pen was too long been opposite
problem
the top it up and be swinging all over
the place and feel heavy
our hands which train again will be very
conscious the pen
itself designing a pen to have the right
diameter
for the right length seem like pretty
basic
an obvious things right yet there are
countless
pan and ap designs that failed because
their designers have lost sight
these fundamentals before we dive into
the say one more thing
which is that being intuitive not very
intuitive
actually pretty difficult to do you have
to understand the fact that you're not
designing just for yourself
you're designing for other people
and those people they don't know the
things that you know
and they frankly probably aren't as
passionate about your app
as you are so gonna tend to be a bit
impatient
easily frustrated fickle right
designing an intuitive interface is
impossible until you can
get out of your own head you need to
recognize your own assumptions about
things
about crew the people you're designing
for our what they're trying to
accomplish what they know what they
don't know
you need to see clearly need to hear
clearly
figure out what it is that you can do to
help them
succeed if you can do that you will have
done an amazing thing
people appreciate the fact
the you cared enough to make a great
user experience so let's dive in
and find out the top five
characteristics are starting
with platform savvy let's go back to
pens again
you see this
particular pan but your I could have any
trouble writing with that because
you've used thousands and thousands the
Pens before and those
experiences writing with all those
different pens is giving you this
generalized understanding
how all pens work they have
shaped your expectations and they're
going to influence your behavior
and when you pick up that pen and you
write with it
Chernoff work like you expected it to
you
and if it didn't you become frustrated
when someone uses your app for the first
time
they do so with all sorts of
expectations about how it's supposed to
work
these expectations are forms
and affected by so many different
factors but the most important %uh those
is that individuals experience using
other
Iowa or Mac caps those could be ones
that
were built into the device when they
purchased it or they could be ones that
many have you here today have made for
them and let's to take a look at an
example
swiping a table row to reveal some
actions
in particular let's look at swiping a
table row to reveal some kind of the
week but in our trash but in
now we're all really familiar with the
and we first encountered it may be with
male
and we thought hey that's its kind in
the right I don't have to go open
the email to see the trash but in so
that I can delete it I have to go into
some kind edit mode
I could just use a gesture to delete it
right away
and after doing this a couple times well
you got into the habit
a vid started to learn to expect
this behavior this interaction
now you open notes for the very first
time never seen this before
and you know notes look a little bit
different from male but not completely
different
are some similarities like male
everything is arrayed in a scrollable
view
and there's the little gray lines that
separate them
and you know you figure that like email
messages notes could be deleted
so you think to yourself well I should
be able to swipe to reveal the delete
button
you don't even have to think about it
fact
probably don't you try
swiping to believe because unconsciously
you believe that it should work
intuitively you think it should work
and when it does you're rewarded with
the outcome that you
expected and if it did it you'd be
frustrated
you would say why did they not do that
make so much sense
right you now have to get figure out how
your gonna delete
no swiping to delete is a platform
convention and it's among thousands and
thousands a different black
foreign conventions that i OS users have
come to expect
and not only do they expect swipe to
delete to work in whatever situation it
would make sense for it to work
they expect every aspect is that
generate I'm
interaction to match their previous
experience
from the center direct manipulation to
how far they need to drag the road to
reveal the bulletins
maybe even the color and the size of the
button itself
any deviations from these things no
matter how small or insignificant
could be incorrectly perceived by them
as being
meaningfully different or maybe they
just get this big sense that something's
not quite right
being consistent with platform
conventions in other words
is a very good thing gestures like pinch
swipe pan tap they should work in very
consistent ways no matter what type
ap views
same is true for control like switches
are buttons
for navigation bars tables
Tavarres and they're also powerful
conventions
about than labels that we used to convey
certain actions are the icons that we
use
now you this symbol may have not been
immediately familiar to you the first
time you saw it
but after you shared something a couple
of times he started to get a sense
what that symbol represents
you know a kind of functionality is
accessed by tapping
that but im and these conventions that
exist
police try less Mac are not at all
arbitrary
swiping to delete isn't just intuitive
because at the thousands and thousands
have
outs that support that same exact
interaction
it's consistent are stark its at the
party that but it's not the whole story
its intuitive to us
because it's like the real-world
experiences that we all shared together
it's like crossing something of a list
are you know being a two-year-old
meeting
food and swiping out here where at you
don't want it anymore so you gonna swipe
to get rid of it
there's countless countless conventions
that exist
for any platform for which you're
designing and it's important to
recognize what those conventions are
because that's what people are going to
expect
sometimes it's necessary to break those
conventions
this is actually not that common but
maybe you're designing an app that's
never existed before
new typeof experience for you designing
for a new type reviews are new tapas
nari or context
maybe you're just trying to solve a
problem that we ate out baller
other you guys have never tried to solve
before right so there is no precedent
follow now if that's the case for you
you have a responsibility to tell people
to inform them that you have decided 22
something different with your app now
let's take a look at an example
this is Leo's fortune we saw that one
ADA yesterday
that we ought there on the wooden scale
as you can see there's only one button
on the screen the pause button
everything else is done through gestures
and these gestures their intuitive but
they're not standard they're not really
obvious
so the game provides instruction it
teaches you about them one at a time
you use your left arm to move left and
right so that it moves forward and
backwards
for you you swipe up your right thumb to
inflate Leo so that he can
hop over obstacles like this ledge
these are non-standard interactions and
the developers at this game
knew that they had to educate people
about them earl's
players would be confused and they would
become frustrated
quit and leave the game wouldn't be a
very good
experience for them now that all I'm
gonna say
when it comes on boarding and help today
because we have an entire
our dedicated to this topic it's a
really great presentation and I
encourage
everyone here to go Thursday
the mission see you there
the next characteristic have intuitive
user
interfaces as that there easy to
navigate
how intuitive navigation systems do
three things:
really well first they just tell you
where you are
the clock out with the tabbar does a
really good job at that
makes it perfectly clear what you're
lookin
and I'm sorry it's so low on the screen
I know their own cannot crane their
necks in order to see it
now out to use navigation bar and have a
title also do a really good job of
telling you where you are the title
serves that purpose
the next thing that they do is they show
you where else you could go
show you what your options are so the
phone app
began with the tab bar there's a very
good job it just means
having everything on screen invisible
pretty simple
and the third thing that they do is they
explain
what's there meeting
the navigation system informs you about
what's contained within each section you
don't have to go
to every single section to figure out
what's inside
let's take a step back for a second
right
why do we need navigation to begin with
we the navigation
because there's way too much information
and functionality
in any given out to display on screen at
one point in time
so we groupings together
make these categories or sections
and these categories we come up with
they need to be understandable
and logical to people who are using your
app
it shouldn't feel like a mystery what's
behind
for what's inside you to these category
labels
for the phone app succeeds because you
to these icons and labels that's used
makes the content inside is
self-explanatory meaning it
provides a good explanation of what
takes up key information or
functionality
is contained within each section out the
app
so in other words intuitive navigation
systems answer three basic questions
where Am I where else can I go
and what will I find when I get there
now these seem like really basic things
right everyone hears kinda sparking it's
like
totally obvious but it turns out that
designing a navigation system that can
accomplish these three things well
is pretty challenging to make so with
that in mind
have a few tips for you about how you
can make your navigation system
really intuitive starting with
progressive disclosure
now if you're not familiar with what
this term is
it's pretty simple it just means not
showing things to people until they
actually
need it now
you do that by kind of creating little
bit deeper hierarchy here
adding a few more steps in a process
the seems like it might take more time
to get to your destination
get the outcome that you're after but
it's worth it
because it makes decision making simple
and an intimidating at every stage in
the process
so all to me earlier able to get to your
destination more quickly
and more confidently unless that is
you use category names that aren't
logical
are not meeting for so in this situation
if you're reading the
fly we're picking a mode of
transportation for getting from
one place to another and if we're doing
that
the first choice we have is do you wanna
go by air or do you wanna go by land
that makes a lot of sense right those
things are kinda mutually exclusive
choices
and these labels are pretty good because
gonna go by air we figure that 10 the
items
in that category is gonna be a choice to
go by airplane
or for going by land we're gonna have
options to go by car may be by rail
we don't know all the choices that are
contained inside we get
incoming we gonna understanding about
what things are contained within
now if we decide to go by land we get
the second choice
this is the disaster said i've labels
for us
now we can go take a motor
transportation that
uses fuel or doesn't use your now within
were thinking about
well all this okay card uses fuel
arm but if I wanna take train
that use your I mean
like steam power your her call
right what if it's electric but a fun
taking light rail
you know maybe that no filament
electricity but it could be solar
powered her
wind-powered a nuclear-powered instead
getting to where I want to go I'm asking
all these esoteric questions about the
nature
fuel and the meaning of that word right
these are not very good labels
that uncertainty is causing hesitation
and it's making me aware
up the interface itself and trying to
code it
again use progressive disclosure but
make sure
that it doesn't feel like you're trying
to figure out what's behind door number
three
now the next if I have is about being
predictable
everyone like surprises right except
when it comes to navigation
with navigation we do not like surprises
whenever addition changes on us
unexpectedly and in ways that we can
explain to rationalize we can get really
confused and tripped up
so let's take a look and how this can
happen
so let's say a word making a banking out
parade and we have a few choices
to select from and then once we register
and then login
is a few other sections that are added
so navigation is change but
I guess I can explain myself why things
changed in the way that they did
or maybe the bank decides they're gonna
add this awesome new feature giving away
free cash
right I wanna bank at this bank this is
a great feature
they put it right at the top because
they think their customers really gonna
love it
but then someone comes to their senses
and decides that they're not going to be
able to give away that feature
for free cash much longer so they
de-emphasize it may reduce its
visibility
in the west by pushing it to the bottom
so it's changed
for let's say we look to the analytics
and app and we've talked to
all the people who are using aid we
figured out that really people want to
go to
mostly to find location sir figure out
how to contact the bank so we move that
stuff to the top
now there's hundreds reasons why
navigation can change
some of them are good and some of them
are batter just terrible
who whatever the reason is there's
always this downside
retraining people on how to do something
that they're familiar with takes time
and it can be really frustrating for
people
may I think we all had this experience
where we've been going to like a website
or using app for a very long period of
time
and then it was redesigned and all of a
sudden we're thrown off
we have to study the interfaces figure
out where things went
to you we just been used to pressing the
red thing over there
right we weren't even reading the label
and now we have two study in
figure out where that went to even the
smallest changes can really true people
up
so by all means changer interface when
you need to
but you carefully and don't do it
frequently
now the next point is is really obvious
but it's worth talking about anyway and
that is that selection
needs to be immediately obvious I was
towel bars for example
we use color to show selection
and we also you shape so on left hand
side you can see sometimes icons get
filled then
and on the right side you can see that
sometimes they get bigger
now part the reason for this is that
makes it easier to show the selection
color see inflection color
but there's another reason for using a
thicker are filled in shape
let's take a look at the clock out again
now we can all see unless you're sitting
in the back
that the world clock is selected very
obvious right
let's say we didn't have enough time to
design a totally different set of icons
for the activists elected state
so instead we just use of state
but we tend to the Red we put that into
the interface
all right off the bat you can see that
selection is a lot less obvious
and it's really not obvious if you're
colorblind
just as a common practice something
always remember to do
take screenshots throughout bring them
into the graphic design tool your choice
Andy saturate them and make sure that
you can still clearly see state
and selection this is a really important
thing to do
with the filled in tab Rikon it still at
least possible
to see what selection if the color red
looks like great see you
see I and even if you can see every
color the spectrum just fine
using a field in shape make selection
more obvious
for all of us the case is doing the
right thing for accessibility improving
the experience
for everyone next
navigation systems that are intuitive
maximize continuity
now in the profession and worldview I
designed we use this word
flow all the time and all it really
means
is is the experience a moving from one
place
to another one you to the next one state
two different staters section to a
different section
and the intuitive you it have occasion
system
is designed to minimize disruption to
maximize
a continuity by keeping people oriented
as they flow through the experience
so let's take an example with the photos
outcry West and here looking at a
greater photos
and wheat Apple one of those photos its
rooms up
fills the screen and this is really
important for usability because
without having to think about it you
know that
the photo you tapped on is the one that
you're now looking at
you get that instantaneous confirmation
again without having to think about it
and animations go back is just opposite
reversed and this is also important for
the usability the photos out
because now you're back in the GridView
and you know exactly which photo you're
just been looking out to you know how to
proceed forward
or backward from that specific photo
now this animation have been done
differently
instead we tapped on the photo and the
big bustling in from the right
we wouldn't have the benefit that
continuous experience
we would have to remember which with the
photo look like that we had one to look
at
and then compare it with the image we're
now looking at the same is true we go
back
with remember what that forward-looking
outlook like comparative
the photos in a gridview now this is a
very simple
you I animation concept but it's a
powerful one
and it's used in all sorts of different
I was out so we make
as well as on home screen itself
an what's more as we use it all over the
place I know it's 10
as well for the very same reasons
K
the next tip is about providing hence
provide hints to people
when they seem to be getting confused
this is the app sky guide
again also 188 yesterday and it provides
information about the entire universe
right you get to see
detailed information about beetlejuice
and countless other
solar bodies that exist now
you may think that the way you get that
information is just by tapping on a star
that's pretty logical that pretty
intuitive right
that's how you get information about
something and just about any out
but if you thought that you would be 100
percent completely and totally wrong
the real way that you get information
about the stars by pressing the iPad and
over on the right hand side of the
screen
but that I but it was just sitting there
the whole time
well you wouldn't know that what it
represented you might think it's just
general information about the
app itself or you know like the cosmos
red so to clarify that for people
sky guide is a couple a very simple
things with animation to help you out
when you select a star when you select
star I but in fades in and opposes a
little bit
straws your attention to it when you
deflect the star
just fades out and that gives you
this understanding that there is a
relationship between star the have
selected an Info button
very effective very subtle I mean you're
not necessarily even thinking about that
and what's even cooler than that is it
if you happen to think that double
tapping a star also give you information
about the starr
as I did than I but in
with the key poor thing every time we
tap on that starr so it's elegantly
redirecting your attention
back over to the eye but in because they
can %uh for
in for by how you're interacting with
the app that that's what your intention
is to get information about
star and there's retraining you
redirecting
K and the last
and probably most important if that I
have is that
less is more picking between a smaller
number of choices
it's faster and easier then picking from
a larger number
choices told you it's a lot I really don
obvious things
giving people too many choices can slow
them down and it can be intimidating
you might think that your impressing
people who are using your out with
health feature richer out this
but there take way may be very different
they may think that you're out this too
much for their needs are just too
intimidating
we see a long list
like this we all know this we start to
skim over things
but wanted to spend hours and hours
looking at this hour
so we're just gonna glanced down really
quickly but when we do that
inevitably we wind up skipping over
things and the things we skip over
may very well have been the things that
we wanted to select
which means if we're skipping over the
stuff we want to select
the people who are using your app for
not getting what they want out of it
they're not realizing your app's for
potential and if you can't limit the
number of choices they are offering to
people
again use progressive disclosure
to help keep decision making simple and
an intimidating at every step in the
process now
that a lot about navigation
and I promise I'm gonna talk about other
things but I feel like I would be
remit if I didn't use this opportunity
to talk with you
about hamburger menus AK
flight out menus AKA sidebars
AKA basement AKA drawers
now these controls are very common
on i OS and on other platforms and I'm
sure many view here work on abs that
have been seen
you guys made the decision to put in
your app and I'm sure that you did so
with the very best of intentions
and I will say that these controls do a
couple things very well
for one thing they save space
so rather than taking up a bunch a room
at the bottom of the screen for a tabbar
just taking up a little bit area on the
top left corner for the hamburger menu
and you practically have the entire
height
the screen to show options to people
and if that's not enough gonna cram more
awesomeness NT rap
people can scroll right
but
this is
I actually haven't played around the
latest version of Xcode I really hope
that they haven't changed this
I don't believe you'll find a hamburger
menu controller and side effects go
now typically we don't provide design
advice about the things that we don't
offer
to you guys but I can't help myself
right I've had so many conversations
with people about this control
many hours and hours and hours talking
about it and
you know I think it's important that we
talk about it here today and again I'm
not gonna say that there is no place for
these controls categorically
I think there are some maps that could
maybe use one but I will say that their
value is greatly overstated
and they have huge usability downsides
to
remember the three key things about an
intuitive navigation system
that they tell you where you are and the
show you where else you can go
hamburger menus are terrible at both
those things
because the menu is not on the screen
it's not visible
only the button to display the menu is
and in practice
talking to developers they found the
South themselves that people user app
don't switch to different sections very
frequently
when they use this menu and the reason
for that is because the people who use
their app
don't know where else they can go right
they don't know because they can see the
options are maybe they sought at one
point in time
but they have since forgotten and if you
use this control you have to recognize
that
the people who use your out may not
realize the full potential of your app
hamburger menus are also just tedious
right if you want to switch sections
from the Account tab
to the transfers tab all you need to do
tap the button
and you're there instantly and if you
want to go back you tap that counts but
in
and your back where you started from
doing the same thing with the hamburger
menu
involves opening the menu waiting for
the animation to finish
reorienting yourself finding the option
you're interested in
tapping that and then waiting for that
mission complete getting back to where
you were before
and if you want to go back you have to
open the menu again
go through the whole process and there
you are again it takes at least twice as
many tops
to change sections something that should
be very busy in fluid
is made more difficult and the other
thing the hamburger many is quite
frankly
too badly as they don't play nicely with
back buttons
right I seen it for what back buttons
are supposed to go in that top left
corner position
but instead is hamburger many there so
people put the back button right next to
it
but no longer does this look like a back
button in anymore
it just looks like an arrow is pointing
to the hamburger menu looks ridiculous
and some participants
sometimes people recognize that the
looks ridiculous so when you drill down
into the hierarchy have an app
hamburger menu goes away now it takes
even more steps to switch to a different
section
you have to go back up enough times to
get to a level higher
even out to get to a view that contains
the hamburger menu
and sometimes people try to solve this
by putting the menu on the right hand
side
but that's not advisable either that
location
is a really important location usually
you can put some kinda action there
you know like a a plus sign to add
something or an headed by then
and finally
the downside being able to show a lot of
options
is that you can show a lot of options is
that you will show a lot of options
the potential for bloat and misuse
is tremendous they allow you to add
offer to stop that your users don't
really care about like
information about the app for version
history or credit
I hate to break it to you but no one
cares
and the other thing
the people wind up taking ads and
special offers
and making them look just like regular
sections and putting it in there too
that sucks on one side either
look jurors have any kind have a nasty
tendency
to fill with choc K
let's move on
thank you okay the next major
characteristic intuitive navigation
system are supported
we're not talking about navigation
intuitive user interfaces
is that they are clear now this applies
to the information aP's present and the
functionality that they present
information functionality need to be
straightforward and understandable
easy for people to do things are not
trying to decoder interpret what it is
they're saying
and clarity is very broad but very
powerful concept
just about everything I said about
navigation
really boils down to just being clear is
it clear where you are
is a clear world you can go is a clear
what happened information or functions
you'll find when you get there
the clarity applies to so much more than
just navigation
I would start with language obviously
we rely heavily upon the written word to
communicate with the people who use our
up
but how well do they understand what
we're saying
it turns out that that's a really hard
question for us to answer
and it's especially hard answer that
question before they've even had a
chance
to use the app but there are a few
things that
you can do to increase the likelihood
that you're speaking
and communicating as clearly as possible
here are
Sixways you can be sure you're being as
clear as possible
starting with using
simple words now if you're designing it
out for a large number of people
avoid using big words that people may
have trouble understanding
so here's to you this red circle
that represents your vocabulary now
you use words for your vocabulary to
write the tax that you're gonna put in
your app's interface
and that's great wall you're developing
it but want to ship
long come some other people and their
vocabularies are different than your own
they may not be native speakers have
your angle language
they may have different educational
backgrounds whatever the reason it
doesn't really matter
the the bottom line is that the number
of words you share in common
is limited so use simpler words that
most people
will understand most to the time those
words they may not be as
precise for descriptive as you would
like them to be but it's gonna make it
easier for more people to enjoy you're
out the next step
is to avoid jargon people shouldn't need
to be computer scientist to
use an app so for example we say
airplane mode on
we want a turnoff radios now turn of
radios those are really basic words but
most people don't understand your radios
means in this context they just think
it's like and from radio they have in
their house
so we use airplane mode much more
effective
and this isn't just about computer
mumbo-jumbo have come about everything
so let's just say we're making an app
about renewable energy
and this app is intended to be used by
people who own
houses are our office buildings or what
have you and your interested in doing
the right thing for the environment or
to saving money they're not necessarily
really well informed about all the
technology is
that they can choose from now they
shouldn't need to know
what a photovoltaic module is they're
gonna say solar panels right
it'll take 10 right
a better design is one that
leads with solar panels leads with the
commonplace term
and if you wanted to find it for people
that's great your educating them right
welds
kinda synonymous with photovoltaic
modules so now when that individual go
somewhere else and they see that term or
they're gonna know
what it means but there is a
have a qualification here and that is
that it's critical to know
your audience so in this scenario we
were designing af which is targeted
at a consumer at someone with a the
large audience the people who are
described right
and we don't know what they with a No
and they probably can't take anything
for granted so we want to use the term
like solar panels
but imagine we're designing an app which
was to be used by
the technicians the people who install
solar panels in people's homes
well they're probably gonna be a lot
better informed about the technology
maybe they intuitively are just
naturally would use the word
photovoltaic modules
more precise in fact they would be
embarrassed to use an app
which says solar panels that will work
Honeycutt that'd be plucked out by their
colleagues
so think about you're out now there's
there's a spectrum
it's important to consider retarding at
targeting a consumer or professional
correctly positioning your app on that
spectrum
is the key to making sure that you're
out
is intuitive for the audience who's
using it
now the next step is about being
descriptive
so sometimes I see that was an option
that says
home well what's on the home screen I
have no idea
home is very under scripted in fact
it always suggest to be that person
design out probably comes from web
design background
when I and I'll West we try to be really
descriptive
about what kinda content or
functionality you find on that screen
to use better words they're more
descriptive
and next be succinct
brevity is a virtue neck
avoid truncation
it's really hard to read text when it's
not all visible on the screen at one
point in time
being succinct and using shorter words
will help
and finally you could have the best
coffee in the whole world
I mean beautiful prose but won't do you
much good
if people are having a hard time reading
it so use a typeface
which is legible and make sure that text
is large enough for people to read
at a comfortable viewing distance now
they're peace
pressed against the device for the
computer screen
and if you're making an Iowa sap a
highly recommends that you use dynamic
type
this will pretty much assure that text
is going to be as legible as are built
in APs
and for those people who have a hard
time reading about I say
well they can adjust font size to suit
their individual
needs just as important
as speaking clearly with words is
communicating clearly
with visual symbol in fact a
well-designed icon
can often communicate a concept more
quickly and more effectively
than any word can but icons are really
tricky to get right
I mean what is this icon mean right
means nothing
made by the saw this so we think maybe
it's like a beach ball floating in a
fish tank
or its addition a dish rack or it's like
a super modern
door knocker I without any contact I
have no idea what this means
this is terrible icon so what kinda
icons
will work well well there's some icons
which are successful because they're
internationally recognizable
such as this information sign we've seen
information signs in museums
in mall and airports and we always know
what they mean it means getting
information about something
next their symbols which are so
pervasive we used in so many types about
like this magnifying glass we understand
what its trying to tell us
we know that this relates to searching
even if the particular format searching
may vary
and next there's icon that are
successful because
they represent these real ordinary
commonplace objects that we've
all used in our lives we've all own an
alarm clock or we've only seen one on TV
so when we see this icon that looks like
an alarm clock we know what it's trying
to communicate to us
so let's put this around a bit what
types of icons don't work well
well if your icon need to label
in order to be understandable that's a
really bad sign
if your icon represent a commonplace
objects that
many people have never seen in their
life
at the that's a problem
and if you use a really common icon but
in a very non-standard unconventional
way
then it's time the go back to the
drawing board and start over
and also if you ever catch yourself for
someone around you
says well I may not be perfectly clear
but people will learn what it means
eventually
then I'd like all a few people to meet
me over here after because I had
awesome bridge very much like to sell
you
ok it's not that i Kant can spew learned
it's just that they're not likely to be
learned
why would I find out what an icon does I
don't know what it means but even tap on
it or cook it
maybe it's going to do something
destructive and anyway that's a really
low bar to set for yourself
if you wanna make truly intuitive ap
don't settle for icons
that mean to be learned
and also want to mention that icons are
often used
because space is limited to they wind up
being
kinda small to what they were making
an icon above a coffee cup
we were making it we're using like a
vector design tool
have resumed and 2 30 to 100 percent and
want to really get creative with their
so yet coffee but you know it's hot
coffee
organ at a little bit of steam and we
want people to know that if they happen
to tip the coffee cups gonna be okay
because as a saucer which will catch all
the coffee and
you know who likes boring Blake Miller
coffee
mugs right Delfina pictures logo is on
them in coffee makes us happy so let's
put a happy face on it
but then when you display at the correct
resolution
all that detail gets kinda lost becomes
muddy
so don't know how all those details it's
better to render the same simple
symbol but with less visual detail
will be far more clear when it's
downsized the crack resolution
and if that doesn't work just try using
a different symbol altogether
look it's not always that easy to come
up with a great icon
if you can't find a visual symbol whose
meaning is
universally immediately and clearly
understood
and just stick with text
now pictures and words these are really
key in important ways communicating
information but there's another tool
in the toolbox that I'd like to talk
with you about today
and that animation animation can
sometimes communicate things far more
clearly
then other words or pictures one of my
favorite examples
this is the focus and exposure indicator
in the camera app
this animation the focus and exposure
indicator this 3 really critical things
very well
first but first appearing in scaling
down it's drawing your attention to the
object to the part the image which is
being used
to determine the correct focus and
exposure
because it's getting smaller its giving
you this hits that it's really precise
I'd zeroing in on a particular area and
then when it starts getting smaller
it just posted twice which tells you
that focus and exposure
have been locked and then it simply
fades away which tells you that that
process is complete and it's now okay
for you to take
your photo ready
set and go
that a lot information contained in a
very quick
and simple animation let's look at
another example
animation when you key in the wrong
passcode on your lock screen
without saying a single word two shakes
head no
that's not the right answer and a clear
out that your procedure centered and let
you try again
okay to the second to last
major characteristic have intuitive user
interfaces
is that their simple
now the common element have not
overwhelming people with too many
options
any one point in time for using more
basic language to communicate with
people
for reducing extraneous visual or
limitations from icon
is that the user interface in the user
experience
needs to be simple let's go back to that
pen and paper Knology for a second
remember you were in your kitchen and
you were frantically hunting around for
a way to write down that phone number
and let's just say that just like before
the pen was sitting there in the pad of
paper
sitting there on your kitchen table
but there is also some piece in the
paper and there is also some dishes
and their kids toys that pen could be
right there but you don't see it because
they're all these other objects which
are demanding your attention
complex out are like this in order to do
the most basic and simple things
you have to wade through a bunch of
things that you don't care about
simple out take the 80/20 rule to heart
as a lot of definitions for what the 82
20 rule means
one which is that eighty percent of
people are only going to use 20 percent
features for that eighty percent of the
time people are only gonna use 20
percent of the capabilities have any
given system
however you define it the it's pretty
simple
most of the time most people use very
little what you actually make
however you define it the takeaways this
if you show people information
that they don't care about our functions
they don't need
then it's all that stuff is just gonna
distract them
no getting their way and make it harder
for them to accomplish what it is
they want to do now I've been showing a
lot of my with examples here and I i
wanna talk about Mac per second and the
context
simplicity
now with the simplicity mean for Mac I
me max a very different than i OS
right me for one thing the screens are
much larger than iPad let alone an
iPhone's
so there's a lot of room to show all
sorts of controls and information
and a lot of times that's what people
really want mean if you're designing a
professional application
that's a good thing right Mac for all
about utility
and power sumac
that are designed for professionals take
advantage of this by offering
sophisticated and advanced workflows
and people use the zaps for really
extended periods of time
and as they do so they become
comfortable managing all that complexity
and when they become comfortable
managing complexity other concerns come
to the fore
such as being efficient and efficiency
is all about availability meaning that
everything is in plain sight
within reach to ca
so that's a good thing actually
but still keep in mind that if you're
not just designing for professionals but
a wider range of people maybe people who
are just went to pick up new skills and
grow into that profession
just new users are trying to learn the
system you don't wanna drop them into
something that looks like this
take the time to give them their and
allow them to graduate to something
it's more complicated
now finally the number one
characteristic
and that's corny have intuitive user
interfaces
is that they are focused
now the designer this Penn is successful
because it's perfectly suited for the
context for which he was made
it's a general-purpose writing tool that
works well in your home or in your
office
there's nothing about this and that's
extraneous
it's not me more complicated by features
that people don't really need
all that often just serves basic writing
tasks
there's no ability to change the color
of the pan
it's not double sided in case once I
breaks down
doesn't have any kind Elise are pointing
capability
all those features would make this pen
needlessly complicated
the designer's pen is a very Cingular
and focus purpose
every aspect to dispense designed serves
that goal
it's for invites us to pick it up and to
hold it comfortably with
a couple of fingers it obvious how to
click open the Penticton quickly closed
again
by pressing on the button at the top
it's obvious how to clip it to a shirt
pocket or a piece a paper so that it's
portable we can take it with us
in other words its intuitive because the
intense focus on supporting
just a couple have basic tasks like
writing and drawing and
thing portable it is uncomplicated
and therefore it is made intuitive to a
wide range of people and a wide variety
have contacts the focus can also mean
designing to support very specialized
turn
Neish applications this calligraphy pen
is intuitive to a calligrapher
everything about it they understand it
makes total sense to them
me the shape and never pen
but if you're not a clicker for and you
pick this up you try to write with it as
you would think to intuitively
as you would write with a pen the
results are gonna be pretty ugly
you can have a lot of flashes and walls
in the paper the writing on
the paper us the same thing this is
intuitive to a painter
but here not a painter you're gonna make
a mess
the designer these tools is optimized
for very specialized applications
and just like a pen adding any extra
star
will result in a less successful and
less intuitive
design
the beauty a bio s is that there are
hundreds of thousands I mean
1.2 million aP's out there
and many of the most successful out are
successful
because they to just one or two things
extraordinarily well
in other words they were designed around
clear and singular
purpose
focuses means that your app can and
probably should
do less if you're out does less
you have more time to iterate to
prototype
to implement polish contest if Europe
does last
you're gonna have less need for
complicated navigation controls that are
difficult to use
and you
if you're out does less you can spend
more time crafting
just the right wording are picking just
the right icons
and making sure that you have time to
build and animations that clearly
and meaningfully provide user feedback
and help people to stay
oriented
a summer the best UI design advice
I ever received was that the
great software starts small
you pick something that you really
passionate about
and is important to real people and you
try to figure out what it is that you
can do
to help make things in their life better
easier
faster more fun more delightful
and then you dive in
and you make that happen and you don't
ship and tell you how something that is
truly great
you don't ship until you have something
that you can
and should feel proud a
if you've accomplished that your app
will become indispensable people want to
read it
because the function it provides them
perfectly suits their needs
exactly what they want and the former
the app
how it's been designed perfectly matches
the functionality
that it offers to them and perhaps
most importantly people will sense
the care the attention to detail
and the love that went into making a
truly great
and truly intuitive ap
cat so thank you are I want to point out
really quickly
if you want to continue this
conversation here's my email address we
also have a lot really great design
resources
you available and developer to Apple
dock on including links to the Human
Interface Guidelines
a bunch of videos we also be the I was
Human Interface Guidelines available as
an iBook
you can go out to get that and also want
to point out that this is not
the last session about design with three
other really great sessions for you
this year are you talking about last one
there on the left
go check it out if you do in app
purchase we have a
really good session with tons of great
wise and
content for you to follow and then this
session in the middle
is awesome it's about prototyping how we
use it out for
to develop ideas and really refined and
figure out what it is you want to do
thank you very much for your time and
have a great evening