good afternoon
welcome to story boards and
trollers on a West End my name's Mike
and I work on the Interface Builder team
today I'd like to show you how you can
build your
I was 10 applications faster and easier
using
owning storyboards in Xcode 6 and
Yosemite
I'm also gonna be joined later by my
colleague wrongly from the up kit team
who will come up and take a under the
hood the new controllers API
to make storyboards work so just a quick
show of hands here
who is already building an app today
using
for I West using storyboards I'll
awesome cool so a your public notice a
little bit of one but to show you
is got pretty familiar so what are we
gonna see
first
I'm gonna start by giving you a brief
overview of how storyboards work
then I'm gonna give a demo showing how
you can quickly connect the top level
controllers
interface your up together using Xcode
sex
hopefully you'll see how storyboards can
help you structure your app
and modular in reusable view controllers
then
role is going to come up and show us
that view controller API
we'll see how all the pieces click
together underneath the storyboard
scenes
and he'll show you the best places to
hook into the infrastructure and finally
as a bonus he's gonna show you how to
use the new gesture recognizers
in West End without having to write an
innocent tracking
all you have to do is just drag connect
to your target in action
are so simple its simply amazing so
in Xcode storyboards are great way to
see all you I parts of your application
laid out in a way that understand take
for example an application like pages
we can decompose you to the major pieces
the you why
into each major section functionality
like the window toolbar
the document area and the shape picker
each of these use has a corresponding
controller
and we show that the storyboard as from
each scene
represent view and view controller pair
the lines connecting the scenes
know the segways sure the relationships
between
them some of these relationships
represent a containment
view controllers inside each other other
segue lines represent transitions
between view controllers
but each one represents flow data in
some form within the app
in your code
you controllers are where you the
developer actually get your hands and
controlling both you why
and the underlying data model each
top-level seem
in a storyboard represents one view
controller in your code
each controller is a reusable
self-contained module user interface in
control logic
within that controller seen you can do
everything you would normally do inside
Ibiza
file like place the Y set up auto layout
constraints
connect outlets and actions to their
parents you controllers
and it's represented object so how to be
seen
actually connect with each other well
segways are really in the glue or the
connective tissues
between each the major blocks off your
caps you why you may have noticed
the on I West Singh was usually
represent transition
between whole full-screen views we took
a look at
the relationships between view
controllers and West End though
we noticed somewhat different
relationship containment
on almost ten most applications tend to
group their views together
in the same window there are many
transitions bring
views on and off-screen because you
actually have the screen real estate to
show the mall
inside the same window summer grouped in
splits or sometimes hidden tabs
that's not to say that we don't have
presentation sideways on our 10 as well
we just have fewer of them
at modal dialogs when the model sheets
and popovers like the presentation
segways
on i OS in order to make these work it's
your responsibility to override the
prepare for Segway
method in your parent you controller
from there you can take the past and and
a storyboard segue object
get the destination view controller that
and configure and set the represented
object or do any other initialization
right before it's presented up on screen
so if there's one line of code that is
absolutely necessary and that you need
to remember
its prepare for Segway
so at build time each storyboard scene
is broken down
into each its constituent parts views
are separated from view controllers
windows are separated from winter
controllers and the transition segways
are embedded inside of their parent
controllers
this is done to make the process a
lowering your user interface
as lazy as possible at runtime then as
performance optimization
the container controllers absorb all
other child controllers together in the
same unit
this is because all those controllers
are going to be needed the initial load
time
the top-level container controller and
it's just more efficient
on archive 14 then each unit
is compiled into a net file and then all
the noobs
are bundled together inside about
storyboard see bundle
then that bundles nestled inside of your
applications resources director
and then appear up can go to the store
so we put a lot of our and work into the
storyboard compiler
to make sure you get the most fission
loading at runtime while in use the most
flexible yuan Lai
to be able to connect in rewire the
relationships between your controllers
on campus all with the absolute minimum
glucose
so we'll see how this all works over
here on the demolition
so as a way of testing storyboards
and to make sure that everything that
we're buildings actually working
we started by rewriting an all peace
sample code
that you may be familiar with called
sketch
in our story board based sketch the next
generation
we're taking a class a document based
app and we're
remodeling much in control logic
interview controllers
so as you can see here we have the main
story board over application
it already has a number of scenes that
we've pre-populated ins
with view controllers and
what we want to do is to show you why
that has
are campus where you can drop shapes
and use gestures to manipulate them and
then have a split
and on the other side of that would be
will be the inspector area
where you can see the different
properties the currently selected shape
so to model this I'm going to use a
split view controller
and I'm just gonna drag that out into
the campus here
and it comes with two controllers
already which I don't really mean
because I already have my campus
I can just wire up here
and drag connect and Chris
I'm out that and then we wanna where
inspectors well and you can see here we
have like a little preview
love with the campus in the inspector
look like and it's using
the auto layout constraints that have
already been set in those views
also to get this to show up we wanna
take are window controller
and connect the new split view
controller and say that this is going to
be the windows
content view controller so
a looks like all other boxes have old
lines connected to him let's
run this and shows up
top here is an app our application
and as iris 5 you'll notice that
you know we have a good enforced minimum
size from
our auto layout constraints but the
split is not
sticking kind of to the side where we
would want it as we resize the window
just keeps getting bigger
so I know what I can do to fix this
I just have to go to the split view
controller
and find the split view item corresponds
to that
and I can the holding priority
the split to be just a little bit more
than the default
and what we're here we must market is
saying can collapse because you know
might not want to always see details I
love the
shapes on campus cell let's run
help looks
alright now as a drag this we notice
that the
split view edge is actually hugging the
side window
as we won its so train at shape
0 and it looks like we don't have our
shape Add button hooked up so
I'm going to create a new kind of segue
and I'm going to show the shape picker
controller
as a popover
and in order to make this work though
there is one one piece of code that we
all have to remember
to implement in order for up these two
workers
the prepare for Segway
so I'm actually gonna open up the
assistant editor
and should see
the canvas you control it here we go and
it looks like somebody
has already helpfully written code for
me so I'm just gonna and comment
here and what it does is it takes the
destination view controller I love the
past in
and a storyboard segue and what we're
doing is we're
initializing to and saying that it the
ship container
is going to be the campus which is
ourself in this case
campus initiating the Segway and it's
also going to be the destination where
one add new
checked so let's build and run us
and when we click on great
so now we have a shape a can't
seemed do anything with it can't move it
by
I think I'll leave that for Raleigh
but as one more little bonus before I
leave a
I want to you hookup what is going to be
a Preferences window and I just wanna
show you just how easy this is cuz
this is on my favorite features I just
couldn't wait to show you
I am right here we have tab view
controller
that has both general prepping and some
keyboard shortcuts
and what I can do is I can wire the SUP
to the preference is menu item
and just say for the Sega demo words
gonna show this is a moral
dialogue and fire on this
you notice that we have
a sketch with
fully functional preferences you notice
the nice no new crossfade
between these two views which comes with
the temp controller
but this isn't look exactly like
preferences when to you still
one other really call options that'll
been added
to you have you controller is a new
style
besides just happens on top or tabs on
bottom
we can actually say we won toward bar
style tabs
and we actually specified the class
our view controllers in this case this
is the general
prep Spain you controller and this one
is the he Board Short
you controller I we will find
with in your document the
emit images that are named the same
as the class love the view controller
so when we run s now
you'll see
new Preferences window have the icon
and the titles fewer
the trial began
switch back to fly
so how easy was that just by wearing a
few segways on campus
and overriding prepare for Segway we
were able to plumb together the view
controllers
into a fully functional application
Preferences window
didn't even use a single line of code
cell
now I'd like to ask rally to come up
Angeles house reports
actually works under the hood thank you
Mike
now that you've seen how incredibly easy
it is
to design your application using
storyboards and the wire everything up
I'm gonna pop open the hood I'm going to
take a look at the machinery and any
that drives this whole thing
we got a lot to cover here just a little
bit of API with storyboards itself
there's a lot of new API we view
controllers we talk a little bit about
how window controllers fits in with
a arpa liberation %uh view controllers
that we're now adding
and wrap it up with gesture recognizers
and how they
really mesh ruling night with view
controllers
and designing application it's really
awesome
loved it right in with storyboards
storyboards
or every source file in your project
like nerves or
by default you the if you to the check
box when you create a new project a good
start off with the storyboard
are you discredit storyboarding in your
project a new one
in the setting for the project for your
target
you could just right there in the main
interface set which storyboard to use as
your main interface
are even if I'll if you happen to have
be transitioning from a no project to no
one
and the right thing will happen if you
by yourself with the need to dig down
into the unpopular stands at the keys
manually
the in its main story board file this is
the key you need to set near
if popular to bring up the storyboard
we load the initial storyboard is gonna
go through this path
just like you can use this API struggle
with name to load any so reported that
you have in your resources
you could order from a name and then you
need to instantiate the initial
controller
what's the initial controlling my task
well that the controller that has the
arrow pointing to it without
some beginning part to it this is the
initial guy there's always one upping
with your storyboard
that's gonna be the initial control
earnest generally when you wanna load up
when with OJ Mayo storyboard file world
automatically instantiate initial
controller and said it running
on your behalf not
every controller that you have in your
storyboard need to be wired back
up to that initial view controller I'm
you can have them they just stand alone
all on their own and can give the man
died in a fire and you can
access them by getting the asking to
instantiate the controller with identify
our
will find it in the store but with that
name will instantiate start doing the
wiring up
and headed back to you and you can take
from there
that's really all there is with
storyboards as far as a PI
its there's not much there they just
work it's really nice
view controllers move on to view
controllers there's
ton have new API here there's so much
like your view controllers that I've got
a breakdown in the sections
so we'll talk about loading and layout
life cycle there but container ship
it's really nice mister for container
ship triggered segways
as you saw the plus button to do the
popover and will wrap it up with how to
do things completely manual
if you need to get down to that level
so have a lot of properties in a in a
few controller for loading this plan
layout
all these methods here are new except
for view loaded which is the top one
and wanna talk about them is unknown
life cycle and how they're used
you have your view controller will get a
knitted and allocated
and it doesn't have a view yet because
view controllers like to lately though
the view so there's no view yet
you load it is gonna return 0 if yes
first property at this point
then load view was going to get called a
this is generally been the place where
you've gone ahead and
so class in a few control an overload
override load view
just the cost to burn normally by
default at get will go ahead and try and
load the nearby
with the name that you gave it a few
initial I did it with near where
the net worth name but new
on your seventy is that you will go
ahead and
if your nickname is nil will look for a
nearby that has the same
name as your view controller and
automatically know that name for you
so now you have the subclass view
controller to get the right near bloated
you just name your net file the right
thing and
it'll do it for you automatically
during load view said he was going to
get called in your view is finally set
your view controller you load it will
now return yes
they were returned from load view but
before we continue the run though before
we go back
to giving control unification view did
load is going to be can
called on your view controller it is at
this point now instead of overwriting
love you
you're right you did load and you do you
want I miss then she Asian
finalization stuff that you need to do
there so this is something that you only
do
want to be wants when the view is loaded
and you'll never need to do again
because
your view is going to be hanging around
now you gonna go ahead in which have you
in a window get the window on screen
and gonna go to the life cycle love you
so before you gets in the window as you
added into the window
I will call you will appear and there
are few other places that you will
appear gets called
whenever the window is becoming visible
for example
as ordering a front perhaps the user has
previously hidden the wind or minimize
it and now they're
on minimizing the window into this is
another case where you get
love you will appear see to do some
really interesting things here for
example
arm you might wanna so what
sector highlight color so the first time
that give you that the draw
draws with the correct highlight color
for example
generation is now going to occur after
you return from this
the window will be animated on screen if
you're on hiding the view are you doing
so got a transition a transition
animation occurs
when that completing your you is drawn
at least once
you did appeal because in the view
controller and now you can wire up
things that you didn't want to interfere
with that information
and you only want to be visible while
the window is visible in your viewers
displayed
you might want to set up 27 example some
animation that's running here
a the disrupt costly but only wanted
visible
at this point user interacts with your
view interact with the user interface
you gonna update you constraints on your
view you gonna dirty them
you can't really get the participate and
updating the constraints with the day if
you can't read
and you get informed when layout is
gonna happen with the will lay out and
after it happened you did lay out
see you can participate in this is you
normally would with
our way out arm but you get to do it now
if you control level
and at some point you can remove the
view from the window perhaps you've
changed had now the view with
being hidden are you hiding the one to
the user's hiding the window or you just
outright closing the window
any these cases your will be pursued
with a view will disappear
that animation we started in view did
appear this is what we would want to
stop it
then the animation occurs in the view
out the window disappears with the
appropriate animation and will call you
back with a view did disappear
and now you can release a any kind a
final resources that you don't wanna
hang onto as the window
is not visible or your view is no longer
part of the window
the life cycle just continues as you
switch tabs in the views come back in
Galway in Windows hide/show
we just continue the cycle
new in Yosemite in a few controllers now
in the responder chain
where for would start off with our
campus you with we had no demo
application there
in a benefit at the campus few inflows
up through the split view to the window
and follow you into a controller
if you control is there came a few to
respect split you control cannot
participate in this
and their automatically wired up in the
responder chain right after their view
so you can now participate in events and
more importantly an action methods
in action method the road is where
really comes in handy
up for example cut copy and paste in the
menu bar cut copy paste
this wired up to the cut copy and paste
actions to the first responder
that might be the campus view in this
case like Eva you doesn't really do much
more thorough logic is that our campus
view controller
and previously you would have had to you
catch pick up the pace in your view and
somehow back get a two-year
controller and now back in a few
controllers
in the responder chain you can put their
copy method writing your campus view
controller
and give you can be a totally oblivious
to this
and it works out really nicely I do want
to point out though that we only wire up
view controllers automatically and
respond to change if you're late on or
after ten 10
suitable for talk about to tame it we
got some really exciting things to do
with containment
you controllers can now have children
and you can't get back your parent
in the best way to talk about the
payment it with an example so let's
start off with pay per view controller
with that Deepika
into have you controller so in a Feb
controllers
going to manage in a February manages a
couple of other views and I'll get into
details there but
mainly manages the tab you it's going to
lately loaded have to use and this is
one of my favorite things
and a path life I've had have used that
had
a fair number of tabs on a lot a carton
in each one of those tabs
and loading this never far from death
took forever
now that we lately low that have used
just the initial select the tab is going
to get loaded when you first bring up
your interface
and it is much more responsive to the
user that way I really love this
its now much easier to customize your
had
using a tabbed view controller and I'll
get into specifics about that a little
bit
and as you saw in the demo it's
incredibly easy without code you can
get a nice profit is user interface star
using a tab you controller
and I'll show you exactly how you would
do that encode and its
just as easy as we as Mike did in the
demo and I B
I maverick's in a fabulous like this
there's
and Anna have you it manages the
collection have been a have you items
those
to view items each have a view and some
additional properties
such as the label so we know what label
to put in the tabs
with have your controller logically
things are now
%uh laid out like this there's an attack
view controller
and that have you controller owns in it
have you
and manages the collection have been
attacked you items
to have you in a February now has a
couple of additional properties
the image which is kinda fun she can get
an image in there
and of course the view controller and if
the view controller that
now owns the view and it can lead to
reload the view
as you switch to the steps
since in effect you could tell a manager
the collection of tap you items you can
of course
get that have you item array you can
also find out what the selected have you
item indexes
in this is cave you comply it so you can
observe this
is much easier to observe the selected
to view item index then it was
previously to
have a delegate and a have to respond
all the delegate methods
so you have to do that anymore as with
any sort of containment
API there's the at insert removed a few
items
and if you have a child view controller
that
is in what are the tags you can just ask
for that have your item associated with
it
be a tad view item for view controller
in a February damn also had this really
nifty a class method on it
to view item with a view controller she
could take any
no dinner view controller that you have
and you can create
a default have you controller for it
using this method
and what this does is it doesn't just
create a generic have you item it tries
to
populated with the appropriate
information from the
to view controller for example we will
take the title
a bitch i love u controller and said
that the label other have you item
and you will also take it a step further
as Mike should in the demo
we look at the a class them at the view
controller
and we try and find image resources with
that same name are we prefer
is the name with a dash to view item and
will automatically set that image
as the image other tab at the end of
have you item
so you can get the label in the item
just automatically that way
to view controller had a medicinal
properties which are pretty interesting
there's the tabs style as Mike show do
we have said made a control on top
it on bottom arm so the tab now drawn
with the segmented control
touch on it a little bit more real soon
there's the tow bar style
that's all you have to do you set the
taps out the toolbar
that have you control will create the
toolbar on your behalf
and place it in the window at the Tabor
you're done
then there's on specify which is really
interesting and I'll get to that a
little bit more
and just the second at the talked about
not
there is a segmented control that now
displays the tabs
you can get the segmented control you
can supply your own segments control
subclass if you want draw them
a in your subclass however you wish
but if you said it the PAP style to
unspecified
what you can do then is going apply your
own
a layout constraints to the segmented
control
and have the same a control appear where
you want to appear in to the layout
yourself
so you have much more customizability a
with to view controller then you've had
previously
there some transition options by
automatically by default we said it
across a
Mike showed in this damn in the demo I T
a change have-not provinces you I
did nice little cross fade effect you
can set it to nine and have
the old style we're just switches we
have very of lighting directions
up down left and right you can combine
directions that are on different axes
seeking a bonded up with the left
but you can't combine up with a down
that whitten
actually and made any think so we don't
let you that I do really wanna point out
those slide forward
and slide backwards
these are really important you gonna do
any sort of horizontal sliding because
they work
in the appropriate direction for user's
language so they were correctly and
right to left languages they will go the
right way and they will go
the a correct way for left-right
languages as well
an out do just let at get worry about
what the right directions or
and we'll handle that for you
as I mentioned in a Feb controller
manages a tad view item id owned it have
a and an author view it owned it have
you
so it's important that you let in a have
you control and manage it for you you
don't really need to get to it and
change it
there are a few properties very few
properties
that you can modify directly get a
better view
if you find you really need to do this'
look at the InnoTab 2 controller header
it specifies
exactly what you can set but in general
let's have you control a manager I also
want to point out here that
as interview controller is apart view
controller it has a view
view is not that have you capital has a
view that contains a tab view
at a segmented control and perhaps other
views as
have you could challenge to manage it so
let to view controller
handle it for you when you're using a
tow bar style
a in a Feb controller is the delegate
up the toolbar you might wanna
override these methods credit so casa
minha have you control an override his
delegate methods
perhaps you want to do something like
add some additional items to the toolbar
a that or taps for example a search
field right
you want to search for the purposes you
I search is a tab
so you'll meet ok override these two
were delegate method
an answer the search field yourself I do
want to point out that
these have the night and it requires
super attribute on them
so if you do override this method you
must call super and the compiler will
help you remember that
letter view controller let's take a look
at another example we're introducing
split view controller in your seventy
it manages in a split view it does lazy
loading a views
and it requires auto layout does all
love the
managing up the splits and how they move
with 12 resizing all view our way out
it would just start adding constraints
to your window
but we have all migrated our ups forward
to using auto layout so that won't be a
problem right
so it would you controller today on
maverick's it has a in a split view
it manages to a more views and as a
divider in there
with and in a split view controller
logic with no they don't like this
enough but view controller owns
and in a split view it manages the
collection of love you items
those items have some nice new
properties in a split
enough view item is a completely new
class in Yosemite
of course it has a view controller which
will easily load view
if the property such as collapse can
collapse in the holding priority
Mike showed you how important holding
priority is arm
days or property that you used to have
to override the delegate for split view
would be the delegate for the love you
control you don't need to do that
anymore you just said these properties
right on
the split view item so it's a lot easier
to do it that way
and of course you can create a default
view item if you have some child view
controller
Pro tip: if you wanna enemy aside a
collapsible
split you use the enemy to proxy on the
split view item
pieces per view item animator that
collapsed yes or no
an the collapse or expansion animation
will happen for you and I
nice animated fashion
medicinal properties since we manage
collections but you items of course you
can get to the
view items array the obligatory at
insert removed
view item and if you have a child you
control you can find its associated
view item by asking split you item for
view controller
now we'll take a look look at a couple
examples that we're doing that kid
I wanna point out in stressed the
pattern were using hear you
in this the pattern that we think you
should use as well if you find any to
write your own containment style
view controllers is you get a view
controller that's going to manage some
collection item so that it could have
the specific information associated with
that
that the item will go ahead in on a view
controller that will then be able to
leave we load the view
if you're familiar with Isleworth this
is a little different than Iowa
where I was you have to have a special
type love you control a subclass that
they may or may not also own
a special type item with inverted that
on
horse tenure seventy and 01 the reasons
is that now your child view controllers
can be a lot more generic
and the the pattern that we're using
on Austin yosemite and the pattern we
suggest you follow as well
there are some generic a container
API with view controllers that are
expose that in a future level
you can get an array of child view
controllers and add an Answer
remote job view controllers but these
API
only manage the collection itself
it's up to you the subclass to know what
to do with them like to have you control
will go ahead and create another
tab but what show the views although the
views yet were split view controller
will go ahead and Emilie added as
another split
so it becomes important to do the right
thing
in your subclass there but now with the
generic this dinner KPIs you can dig
down in
look at the chart view controllers
associated with a view controller
or if you have a job you controller you
can go back up and find its parent
and have a job you control you can just
call on it removed from para view
controller
and that's the easiest way to a take
apart the
parent-child relationship there
adieu control we have and this message
in addition from you control to view
controller
which will do a nice enemy to transition
on your behalf this is what
we have with view controller so it's the
exact same options you can do non with
the crossfade
or slide in various directions
and that containment view controllers
there's another type relationship with
view controllers and storyboards
are called triggered segways
Stricker said ways performer
presentation
in a presentation if they haven't
identifiers so we can find it in the
storyboard if needed manually
missed at some stores view controller
for example the
campus view controller in this case is
our source to do our shit picker
pop-up a destination controller which is
going to be a shape picker controller
and then a file and that we did a demo
the Segway star was a popover and a
in this was the Segway depending on the
style there might be some other
attributes need to set up
for example with the popover you need to
set up the acre view
that we've had dragged it directly from
the plus button a curfew was white up
automatically
but you can actually go in IB and set
the interview for the popover
as my pointed out 11 a code that you
really need to write
in the source view controller so in this
case our campus view controller
endorsers you controller you need a over
I prepare for Segway
from the said where you can get the
identifiers so if you have to deal with
more than one
said where you can switch on that get
the definition controller
and wire up anything that needs to be
wired up so that you can have the proper
lines of communication are you can get
the right model data objects and show
the UI with the correct
information often this is the
represented controller
the represented object and you can just
said the definition controller that
represented object to the right thing
there are a couple of additional segue
API's that you might find useful
should perform several with identifiers
center this will
give you a a a chance the step in a
dynamically
prevent a segue from performing if you
need to determine that pretty late
and if you determine that here we will
stop the segue from really getting off
the ground
that you can call perform said way with
identify our identifiers sender
and we will find the Segway in the
storyboard for you
and call perform which will flowback
through shipper forms over with
identifiers of course call prepare
for Segway any to wire up the
represented object
you get nothing else on this whole
talked and I today
arm its with your Segway you need to
implement prepare for Segway
in the source controller wire up you
represented object or whatever
pieces of information that you need to
bridge the bridge between the two
animate the Segway happen
using Interface Builder to wire up your
segways and do it all visually the
the easiest way to go with our
recommended approach
what we could take apart the engine a
little bit more time to look at the the
manual
API that's going on under the hood that
you can also call directly so we're
going ahead and we're exposing this API
you cannot go source view controller to
present some other controller
she at the modal window are the popover
and after definition controller the the
she'd or the model window the control
that is being presented
you dismiss yourself by calling dismiss
controller and
at get will do whatever the appropriate
thing to do the area's
n dismiss the controller for you this is
incredibly powerful because it allows
your definition controllers
to be a lot more modular and reusable
for example
when I can our first during the summer
project can I view
was like oh you know sheets the first
thing in there would you have our pic to
come down as she
and we were to present view controller
ashey
an up that was easy
that we said no no to a greater good
look much nicer the pop over to be Korea
so the only thing we had the change was
the set with type 2 presented as
a popover our definition controller just
cause dismiss controller
didn't need to know how to dismiss a
popover or that
dismissing a she in raw code is actually
dramatically different
just go ahead and let in its view
controller handle that on your behalf
and we'll do the appropriate thing
we can actually go to yet one more level
deeper
and there's at the lowest level present
view controller
animator and your is a view controller
presentation animator protocol
and where publishing this is well in
Yosemite
so you can create your own presentation
animator object implement the protocol
which is just these two methods
Adam a presentation a view controller
front view controller
so our when you do a presentation will
take the instanceof
your animator object call animate
presentation a view controller from view
controller
and you can help the animation however
you want
what the users finished and dismissed
controllers called the quill
bubble up to the right place we will
take that say missus that we had before
we stashed it
will call animate dismissal animate
dismiss love you controller from U
controller
you now responsible for doing any
dismissal animation however you see fit
and what's that we what return from that
we will go ahead and released
the animator object
that new controllers there's a lot to do
with your view controllers is
really powerful 0 you can't wait to see
what you're going to do with it
it's gonna be a lot of fun but not for
talk about 10 control is a little bit
and how they fit in with this a large
collection operator
you control is that we're going to be
adding to our applications
let's just look at some other new API we
have a window controller there's just a
little bit
namely there the car to view controller
miss the requirement
in when you are in a few storyboard you
need to set up a cut the view controller
to your window controller
in its window also has a car to view
controller property that's new audit
and what happens is when window
controller Lesley loads the window
it sets the windows cut the view
controller to be there cut a view
controller
that the 12 controller hath associated
with
scoresheet let you control you can also
get the story board that voted the
winner controller if one or the window
controller
Oro will return oh if you want a
controller was loaded from a storyboard
and of course 10 controllers like view
controllers
can be presented and you can call
dismiss controller on the window
controller
and the right dismissal will happen
it has won a controller also implements
the Segway protocol
so that the you can prepare for Segway
you can override that you can ask it to
perform so well with identify our
and you can toss course over I should
perform segue to do dynamic
a suppression and rare instances
what really does a window controller
responsible for now
cuz we have the view controllers and all
your logic loving way down a view
controller so
you into control should just manage the
window you know things like
should I really close on the close
button was pressed man as the title bar
in the toolbar make sure that
have the appropriate look there
manage the content view controller have
a cut in the window
10 controls gonna hit go ahead and
manage that
10 controllers over time has been has
become a place where
you put a lot of view logic I'm it was a
giving a place to put your logic that a
for various parts of your
user interface but now that we have you
controllers and a specified
parent-child relationship in a hierarchy
here with segways
you can move all that unrelated logic
down to their appropriate view
controllers and now you have
few controllers which are reusable
modules and
they're more cohesive independent
modules and you don't have
a unrelated code and you when you could
tell that you don't need anymore
she went to Tylers a lot smaller and as
a lot more readable and maintainable
that's 10 controllers let's talk a
little bit about gesture recognizers
I'm really excited about us to recognize
I'm in a bit guy at heart so like perot
thats so what you do things just
recognize the store them
yosemite they are the API's
nearly identical to it to what it is on
Iowa
there lotta fun
but when you're looking at on the
desktop motion gestures
are determined the same way that they
are on i OS on I what you have to look
at the raw touches and figure out what
that means
if you do a pinch gesture on the
trackpad on Austin
the trackpad itself recognizes that as a
magnification
and it sends magnification events she
don't have to figure that out
but not everything that we can recognize
as a gesture
is pre recognize force at the lower
levels
for example what is a click
you press on the trackpad which is gonna
emulate a mouse events good
are you press them out but you get a
mouth down a bit followed by mouth up a
bit without any drugs in between
so this is some different events and we
can look at the mall
together relies in combine them for you
go that a quick
so we can recognize a quick we can
recognize that independently as
and differently than something that a
quick a dragon release
that something else Janice it is just a
recognizers really good at helping you
disambiguate user input how good well
this is coded you might have had to
write a few had to figure it out
yourself
7 my 7
tracking loops deep above nectar that
match in math
and with the code is trying to do is
figure out
is this a click I double click a triple
click or a dragon is trying to sort all
this out no large that's associated with
just recognizes clean this all up make
it are much more simpler to disambiguate
user input
gives you folks to tap into there when
you need to add some custom logic
and it's much easier to maintain
just recognizes are really good fit for
view controllers
you really don't wanna have to override
mousedown in your view controller that
much shopping your view controller
should really be
doing in when you go to Rieger code in
your view controller you gonna see
meltdown and you have to try and figure
out with comments are by
really looking at the cold what is this
meltdown trying to do
you controllers have a target action
pair we will recognize the four click on
the four track for you and now you can
wear that up to an action in your view
controller
just having mousedown you have select
are you have drag and it's now obvious
in your code it's much more readable on
what to do
and is partitioned out better much more
maintainable Co
here's an example love using just
recognize is in place with code
this is Alexa knitting a modification
gesture recognizer you hit the target in
the action
or point out a slight difference here
from Iowa
on North 10 all of our controls in our
menus have a single target action pair
that the paradigm we use that the
paradigm we're continuing to use within
its just a recognizer
that's a little bit different than I owe
us what you have just a recognizer
a Alexa knitted you go ahead an upset
on some view just recognizes need to be
attached to a viewing recognized for
that
you optionally you may need to fit the
delegate
you just a recognizer to your view
controller perhaps you to set up some
more logic to help disambiguation things
then your poem attraction method mean
magnify in this case
the center of the action method is gonna
be the gesture recognizer
you probably wanna switch of the state
so you can for a magnified you look at
it started it began you set up some
initial state
you do you magnification during the
changes and when it finally
in you go ahead you commit your changes
to your
your data model that way with this
commit when you do and do you just get
one on do instead of just
part the magnification something like a
quick
there is another state which is Rick
just recognize
soft there's not a recognized that goes
to begin change ended
because it's just a single a collection
like a quick
your just check the recognized state
just recognize that we're exposing in
Yosemite
are the click gesture recognizer this is
a mouse down and up you could set which
button
to recognize or even korda buttons to
recognize
there's the pair just a recognizer which
is
a mouse button down drag and release
and a this is very similar to
depend just a recognizer on iowa's but I
West take touch
moving release an equivalent of that on
the desktop is obviously the mouse
knocked down move release and if I could
just recognize that you can set
which button to recognize or Core two
buttons
there's a press just a recognizer which
is our holding off button down
with the time component so up a long
press is another way that we set about
and in a press just organizer cook with
the time component
that we have magnification gesture
recognizer and rotation just recognizer
I mentioned earlier that magnification
in rotation are already recognized for
us in at the hardware level and that's
true
but they can still be bundled up in
federal gesture recognizer so that you
can
get this nice arm target action
association with it and it continues to
fit in
the model with these other gesture
recognizers in your application so you
have a consistent use
I love gestures inside wrap and of
course you can also set
the medication rotation Justin
recognizers to
work at the same time simultaneously or
you can have them
where no I only want to recognize
magnifications our rotations one at a
time
so you can why those up with you various
properties
arm I do wanna make one quick aside on
magnification rotation
gestures the raw ovett the magnification
rotation events
we've had the phase property to those
events so the event also have
began a changed in ended phase is
associated with them so you can
if you're looking at the wrong events
you can determine their faces right
there
the flow is really important with
gesture recognizers
um with looking out for us first about
press for an example
and maverick's would work like this of
press goes through and its applications
and events
if it doesn't get consumed their said if
it will send it off to the event
observers
if there are any if they've been
observers don't consume it it will flow
back up
to have sent a bit incentive it will
send off to the appropriate window
that windows in a bit method is called
the book to the event figures out
be a hit testing which view the Senate
to that you get a meltdown message
at the mouth if the view doesn't consume
the most down
it but was up to the responder chain as
normal and whereas
normal now and maverick's in a use an
excuse me
includes your view controllers
just recognizers are here there
what the Venice in through the window in
when in this one does send a bit
it will do the gesture recognizing you
might notice we have some dashed arrows
now is that a solid arrows
reason for that is just recognizers
might delay a bit
just recognizes will take a pan for
example which is a drag
you'll do a meltdown occurs will not
sure if they're dragging yet or not we
don't want any every other code to
start trying to go into a tracking loop
or do anything with the down yet we want
to wait till we know for sure if it's a
drag or not
and so you just recognizes can delay a
bit
if they into not consuming them then
they will continue to flow through the
system as normal
what's really important for you to
understand as developers here
centerville is a place that
as often overridden if you do over
rights and evident in its application or
in its window
if you consume events that just
recognizes have already started the
process
in that sequence you can really confuse
a gesture recognizer
and then you're out will not work right
at all
so you need to be careful about that and
think about that when you're using
gesture recognizers
this also goes for even observers if you
hadn't been observer
you can consume the events before the
gesture recognizer gets to them and they
just recognize a really needs to you
have all of them that belong in a
sequence together
if you're so close gesture recognizer
you can we fully support that check out
the
in its just a recognized its file
there's in in a subclass
use category this is where we've put a
category for the additional methods
that so classes need to work worry about
and you can write a subclass and
recognize the drug will call as
whatever you want to recognize it to be
I never got the details here so if you
want more information please come see me
or the lab
and I will be more than happy to talk to
you about just recognize
so let's put this all together a little
bit and let's go back to our demo
an let's get that chick to move
my could get the pic to move but I think
I can
okay so will run this again real quick
make sure we're all right back in the
same spot they were we were
we've added a shape and sure enough we
can't get it to move
well
I know
and then the camera's view controller I
wrote I select
action method here to drag with gesture
recognizer action method here
from so I know that this stuff exist
should be getting call so we need to
figure out whether not getting called
and it so you know just like a show
before you just switch on the state and
you do what you need to do there
so let's go back into our story board
and look at our campus view controller
and
and became YouTube my just a recognizes
out there so let's go ahead and add some
will quickly at a pen gesture recognizer
and will why the pair just a recognizer
up to the track and we'll go ahead in
magnified by gesture recognizer
ago there we are
well that and wire that up to
magnify now should be quite
obvious what code is going to get ron
runner-up
attache and
now we can drag and we can do a pinch
and resize the shape
any we can add another one and they work
independently of each other
an there we go view controllers
backing storyboards
superheated design applications now 10
controllers
just control your window but they also
have some nice
a new API to work with storyboards wire
up your a gestures with gesture
recognizers
it easier than ever it's a lot of fun
everything here
is really great kept wait to see what to
do with it
for more information you can see Jake
he's over here up in the front with the
nice
shirt it left automatic
commented on his shoes so I figure out
come in on his shirt today
check out the what's new in Austin
documentation we r
working like crazy on the documentation
for view controller so that is going to
be coming
it's going to be really nice related
professions such
check out the what's new in interface
Boulder this along with other things are
going to be covered
i really wanna point out creating Monaco
collapse on Thursday
if you're just new to writing absent Mac
OS 10
Monaco collapse will cover view
controllers a little bit but their cover
another a lot of other technologies that
you should be also implementing in your
application
as a Austin application so
thank you driver of the company