hello everybody in
thank you very much for my name is Kevin
McLaughlin
and I am here this afternoon to tell you
about home kit
you know it's been a day packed full of
all kinds of new information that I hope
you're very excited to be here as I am
excited to see everybody here
so he heard a little bit about home kit
already
I assume in let's talk about it just as
we're getting started here
so home kid is a new feature for I O S
that is bringing
has Craig said very well some
rationality
to home automation it provides a great
opportunity for us
you as developers must work together
to provide a much more consistent
experience for our users
as they start to get into home
automation and we want to bring this to
a much wider
audience then home automation has really
been accessible to in the past
so let's get started so today
I will tell you a little bit about the
features a home kit
and we'll go through the core concepts
how to use the API
how to get started and a few advanced
topics
that are either interesting to be and
hopefully to you or I know are
interesting to you
so it's good on with it to the first
feature want to tell you about
is something that is really important
and a score to delivering
the consistency they talked about
so we have a common database that is
stored in Iowa
and it contains all of the home
information
all the accessory information that has
been configured
and is available to Olive your caps
every time a user uses one of your abs
to configure a new accessory to set up
their home to set up some other
operation
those things are stored through home kit
through the framework in this common
database and then when the user uses
another application
for some other purpose and they see some
of their home information
in this other applications gonna see the
same information that they saw
or that they set up in there other
applications miss mean
to our users to your users everything is
going to look
a lot more connected it to make a lot
more sense this is starting to provide
that consistent experience everyone we
want to deliver
now building on that
as we mentioned yesterday we have a
great
interface for users which is period
to users can use Siri
to interact with their home kit
accessories
in a very natural way I just speaking
commands that make sense
I talk a little bit about how that
enabled as we go through the
presentation today
now in
creating home kit we have
put in a lot of effort to define a
common language for us to use to talk to
accessories
but we can't define
every kinda accessory that
all are clever accessory manufacturers
are going to invent
have already heard about dozens of
interesting things
that are well beyond
what we're starting to you can see here
garage door light bulbs or like these
are things that are common accessory
that we have defined in home cannot talk
about some more about as well anything
else is possible
we don't want home kit to be
restricted in contained we want home kit
to create
innovation in creativity and so
anything that an accessory manufacturer
can imagine and can create
they can define and make available
through home kit to your applications
all that exciting
you want to be able to use these
accessories
and so home kit also
provides access to your home kit
accessories when you are not at home
this is enabled through i OS device
connectivity
and there's no special requirement for
your application
or for the accessories to take advantage
of this great feature on K
but with all that connectivity
come something very important actually a
pair of things that'll
very closely coupled that security and
privacy
we take security and privacy very
seriously
we have spent a lot of time and effort
attention reviews after reviews making
sure that we have a great solution here
so we have end-to-end encryption between
i OS devices & accessories
and this enables us to have
security so that accessories can be
misused
it also enables us to ensure user
privacy is maintained
we don't think that it's good enough to
be sorted
private your data stored somewhere else
we think it's important to be take
privacy very security
yes seriously and do the best as
possible
in keeping with this paradigm of
insuring
privacy and security and making sure
that our users have really good reliable
understandable experiences when they
start using your home kit applications
home papi can only be used when your
application is in the foreground
this ensures that users know exactly
what's going on there's nothing for them
to be afraid out when they take that
first step
or second step into using home
automation
okay that's enough about the high level
stuff
let's get into some other details so
to get started with home kit your entry
point
is the home manager
the Home Manager provides your pointers
to the common database
accessed through the home's the Home
Manager
allows your application to manage the
homes
which one is primary adding or removing
as necessary and we'll notify you of
changes
now for examples somebody might have
for whatever reason multiple home set up
those may change this is where you get
notified about us you can start updating
your application
to match with the user knows they have
to the home managers represented by the
HM Home Manager class
you simply created instance I love it
and then you said
a delegate to be your application
to use the Home Manager
the most important thing the first thing
you want to do is you want to implement
this
delegate call back Home Manager did
update homes
when you get this call back that means
that
the whole manager has finished loading
are preparing the home data
and you can now save a pointer to the
rave homes
you can also save what is currently set
is the primary home
now if there aren't any homes
then you need to create a home for the
user to add a home with name
and that completes with a
completion handler would only fail
likely if the
home had the same name as another home
because homes
need to be uniquely named so homes
contain
all the data for a home so you have your
rooms have your accessories and so on
notifies you changes to that home
and the names have homes are recognized
by series so that users can refer to
them
when they're giving commands
on a home we have the name
we have an array of all the rooms an
array of all the accessories that are in
that home
to fill out the concept a date the
imager the
the map a home in every wanna call it me
to create rooms
so on the home you can create a room
are at a room with name provider a name
for the room
and again that would only fail typically
if there was a room that already have
the same name
so moving on two rooms rooms contain
accessories
room again we'll notify you of changes
and
rooms must be uniquely named with in a
home
solo homer created own namespace
everything within a home must have a
unique name
names have rooms are recognized by Siri
users can also interact with them to
maximize natural
interactions with their accessories
rooms are represented by the HM room
class
and they have an array the accessories
that are in that room
let's move onto accessories so
accessory corresponds to a physical
device
accessories are assigned to ruminate
that can change you can assign an
accessory to a different room
accessory objects allow you to access
the device
state can I talk to the success three
right now for example
will notify you of changes to that
accessory again they have to be uniquely
named within home
and names and accessories also are
recognized by Siri
an accessory is
the whole object that the user is
referring to
not talk about how the details that
accessory
are exposed to made available after this
so an accessory has a pointer back to
the room that im
and it has appointed to the rave
services
that represent the functionality of that
accessory good
important Delhi a call back for you to
implement an accessory is the did update
reachability call back so
an accessory at any point in time may be
reachable you may be able to communicate
with it
from your application are you may not
maybe
of may be far away from it
this situation we don't have access
in this case this car that will be given
to your application to let you know
when that reachability changes see you
might start out
with accessory that is not reachable and
for some reason it becomes reachable
you'll be notified and you can update
the UI in your application to reflect
that
these are knows what's going on
so to describe a little bit more about
how accessories look
talk about services so services
represent functionality
%uh accessories they contain
characteristics
so you could describe a service as a
grouping of characteristics for
characteristics
are specific parameters you can interact
with and I'll talk about this next
so services are interesting that they
may have
name and what that means is there are
some services that really aren't
intended for the user to directly
interact with them
there serve Morgan operational typeof
functionality
so here for example we have a light bulb
a service that is a lie Paul
would typically have a name because he
is going to want to name it you know
that light has a name I refer to it
but a service to update firmware on an
accessory
is something that a user typically would
not need to name
and refer to in many different ways it's
something that your application would
take a right for them
present at and in more user-friendly way
than saying oh here's your firmware
update service and here's to
the day listen to it so
in your UI generally will not expose
unnamed services
so this is a way that some other
messiness if you will or that
you can look at it with some the great
functionality the protocol
and at home kit remark don't need to be
exposed to users you just wanna
in Iraq to these accessories that
they've got
names accessory except services must be
unique within a home
and they are recognized by Siri and
importantly for services
we not only recognize names have
services but also we have
Apple defined service types
and three understands those types which
means that users can refer to
service types using natural language in
synonyms other things like that that may
not be exactly
the name provided to the service
services are represented in HM service
we have a name an array of
characteristics the service
typeof the service and a pointer back to
the XSD
the services are a collection of
characteristics
a good example justice issues here is
for light bulbs service
your main characteristic is the power
state
I've that light bulb services to the
power state is a characteristic that you
can directly interact with
characteristics provide some information
to meditate about it the characteristics
theirself describing see make it a range
making units
step values and so on you can display
appropriate controls to user when you
get a characteristic
you get the results to a completion
handler because it may not be
immediate and characteristics are
recognized by syria although they are
not named by the user
so we've defined a number of
characteristic types
and and your candor stand with those
mean caesar's can interact with those
giving commands to Siri
two characteristics can be a few
varieties
with these main one so some
characteristics you only read the values
from them so you might see what is that
current temperature outside are inside
you have a thermostat it tells you the
current ever hear me to write to the
current temperature you
can't directly immediately change that
with additional command
when you read from when you wanna change
the temperature you need to tell your
thermostat that you have a new target
temperature
your target temperature is something
that you do right to
in the ass to read from that because you
might say is why is it so
hot in here what is that current target
temperature at this
thermostat you read that may be right
and change it
and there are some few characteristics
that you only
right to writing right only
characteristic is something
to think about it a little bit but where
you tell the accessory to do something
and it's going to do it
in it doesn't matter what it may have to
say
back to you there's no feedback is just
that the country does it independently
on its own
so an example here an important one is
the identify characteristic which is a
special characteristic that Paul
accessories must support and provides an
interface
where from your application you can
where user
say hey I'd like you to help me find out
which one which one of my accessories
this
is you send in identify characteristic
right
to that accessory and then it
will do something that identifies itself
to the user so a light bulb might flash
thermostat my blinking LED a garage door
opener IP camera might be
maybe also flashlight whatever it is
this is accessory specific
and the purpose is to help the user know
which thing and they are about to
interact with
especially useful when a user for
example say
connects several lights and they say
okay now I need to set up my lights
which one is this
right they all have the same default
information not going to look them up by
serial number that's
boring so just identify that for me
and you send the identify characteristic
right to direct it accessory
it plans to use our notes which one it
is they can proceed
so characteristics are in HM
characteristic
you can read value with completion
handler to get the value of a
characteristic
and also right value with completion
handler
him
so now we've talked about
these these object these things they
correspond to physical things in the
real world
we need to be able to find and set up
these accessories
we do that with the accessory browser
so this cool lets you in your
application find out if there are any
new accessories available
and then help the user had those two
home
so you create in to YouTube accessory
browser
said the delegate and then when
appropriate
you start searching for new accessories
you'll find some you'll remove some of
talk about that next
and in later when you're done you stop
searching for you accessories
so it's responsible for power management
to stop searching for new accessories
when
no longer necessary to do that if left
the view
leaving application you decided that
enough time has passed and so on
so while you're searching for new
accessories you'll get
this call back
did find new accessory will come at a
pointer to the accessory that was found
and you can now for example add this to
a listed accessories in the UI the user
can select from for which ones they want
to configure
be if when you start searching there are
already some accessories that have been
found
you can get the list from the to
surprise her out the RT
found new accessories and then you get
this
come back every time anyone is added to
that list
in when you found the new accessories
and you'd like to set one up the mop
you to add that accessory to a whole
it's important to note
that this method is on
HM home it's not on the accessory
browser
sorry padded the accessory to a home
when the accessory successfully added to
a home it's time to name the accessory
and assign it to a room
also while you're searching for new
accessories she will sometimes get this
call back
especially you'll get this call back
when you add an accessory to a home
this is did remove new accessory this
allows you
in your UI when you have a listed
accessories that you are showing to the
user which
you accessories would you like to
configure and they do select one and
they do add it to a home
you get this call back to tell you it
removed from the listed new accessories
in this case because it was added to our
homes you can update your UI to take
that one of the list
so that's a 8 quick introduction to how
to get started
basic functionality
and if you like I have been recently
you'd like to
get right into it and write something
and you wonder
how we gonna do that we don't have any
of these hunting accessories yet
so we thought about that we came up with
something we have a great solution which
is the home kit accessory simulator
and this is available for you in Xcode
at this location and it's a great tool
and I'm going to show you
how that works
beautiful
so here is our home kit accessory
simulator macon see
that in this case there are a number of
accessories that have already been
created
in the simulator but I'll walk you
through it
to making sure it's big enough for
everybody to see in the back come
forward if you can see it
so here on the left we have the listed
accessories that are created and bridges
which I'll talk about briefly
at the end and on the right there's
information about
the accessories so I'm gonna do as I'm
gonna go down to this:
at accessory but here in the bottom left
and choose to add a new accessory
so make all this
assured demo 213
in at this accessory CRC now that
I've added a new accessory to the
accessory simulator
and let me show you what that looks like
in this very very simple
sample app that we wrote
so this is just the tab tab you can see
their new accessories I want have been
configured accessories
on the other his other accessories are
already configured
you see here that we have the chrysler
general accessory that I've just created
has shown up here on the new accessories
happen
but it's not very interesting yet it
just has an accessory information
services created by default because all
accessories must
have an accessory information service so
I can go up here
to added another service so this is a
garage door so it at a garage door
opener service we can see that added
with all these characteristics
and now since garage door openers
typically also have a light
but satellite and I see we've created
our garage door opener accessory and it
has
the Access to Information Service it has
the garage door opener service which
corresponds to the motor but actually
opening closes the garage door
and we have a light bulb service
correspond to the white the time that
garage door
so let's go ahead and configure
the successor so
when we go to add an accessory to a home
the user must enter setup code this
comes from the accessory
began the packaging on i-label around
the screen or LCD an accessory
in the simulator it's your right under
the name is he said it could
which looks like it's 9143
let me into that
had set that up and you can see now that
disappears from the listed new
accessories because it was successfully
added to the home
now for jump over here to the configured
accessories tab
I think I saw that I have a 8
revealing my practicing but here we have
the garage door
accessory that I just added and you can
see that it has
to services any details tab the Details
tab
shows the accessory information
is not something that we need to
interact with but it's there for
reference
we can also go and see all of the
characteristics
for the garage door and all the
characteristics for the way
and just to show that these are
connected we can see if I
click on a the power characteristic
hav the light the power
in the by Bob service at the garage door
goes on and off
along with that
sort of in the middle up there
okay so that shows you the basic you
serve the
economic accessory simulator and also
showing serve the test your browser in
action adding adding accessory and then
China services and characteristics let's
come back to bridges for a moment
two bridges are a special type of
accessory where you have
1 accessory that support tom cat
accessory protocol
that connects with iowa's and you have
some other
and point accessories that are connected
to the bridge because they don't
they can't communicate directly with IRS
for some reason
so a typical example maybe a heart that
has some lights behind it that are using
some
other protocol so in this case
the hub is the
first accessory that home kit connects
to
said come down here and i cant had a new
bridge
so let's call this
demographic more
so it created a bridge now when the
bridge is created you'll see that it is
actually
an accessory that's available so if I go
over to
you accessories that has shown up I
could connect to it right now
but it's really very uninteresting
we need to add some accessories behind
this bridge
so click on add accessories
so let's add a light behind the bridge
now we see we've added a light accessory
connected to this bridge
well we're here let's go ahead and add
another
late behind average p now have two
lights
in a/c on the right we show the
accessories that are connected to the
bridge on the left
below the bridge we have the actual
light
accessories listed here which show the
services of those now here
these are created only with accessory
information to start let's go ahead and
add
lights to them
now go back and look at the bridge issue
that we have a nice view to show you the
accessories that are connected behind
the bridge
and of course we can pair with the
bridge
just the same way we did before set this
up
8107 that appears over here we can go
down to our
connected accessories and I are gonna
see something interesting
the dental bridges there and we can
click on that and see that it just has
details which show
the accessory information at the bridge
but the lights are also here so lights
that are behind a bridge
are presented to you through home kid
like separate accessories and you can
interact directly with those lights even
though there's something in the middle
there's always protocol translation
other things going on
you have to worry about that you get the
accessory which is what the user really
cares about
and so you can then interact directly
with these accessories
they can be turned on and off similarly
okay
so that if the democrats get back to our
slides perfect
so the home can access we simulate urs
villain Xcode 6 it axed just like real
accessories so when you develop your
application using the simulator
using the hunk accessory simulator
you're doing the real thing
when you eventually get real excess res
to connect to
they can work the same way they're gonna
be exposed to the same way through home
kit
to this is a great way for you to get
started
and a great way for you to developing
tester home kit applications to during
this
presentation so far we've talked about
all the steps various points along the
way
for how to get the initial setup
have a home in excess getting
accessories added we talked about this
no one run through it for you to the
summary
so first me to create a home you to
provide the name for the home
then we need to add rooms to the home
user adds
provides names for those rooms again all
these names I will have to be unique
in the added any accessories to use it
as your browser
get accessories to the home the user
provides a name for the accessory the
user
chooses which room to the texas region
for the home and after that the music
actually going continue using accessory
can interact with it
three applications other applications to
Siri now let's
move on some more advanced topics
have talked a lot about services in
characteristics
and i've talked about
something defined by Apple and custom
one so here
on the left you can see a list of
services there are some of the services
we've defined
you can see the services correspond to
in a broadly
accessory type: sir functional groupings
oven
characteristics they see on the right
as a sampling of some of the
characteristics that we've defined
and are many more the and then
as I said earlier to
encourage innovation invention
creativity
we allow definition any custom service
any
custom characteristic an accessory
manufacturer wants to use
with all available to you through home
kit and all of these
services and characteristics that are
defined by
Apple are recognized by Syrian
understood by Siri
so that users can interact with them a
very natural ways
turn something on switch something on
right there some other ways that users
all of us I guess refer to things in our
home so
cook groupings of rooms like upstairs or
downstairs
or maybe the bedrooms two rooms can be
collected into zones
it represented an HM zone isn't it an
arbitrary grouping of rooms
this is just an association it's not an
ownership relationship
so a room can be in any number it sounds
zones also are uniquely named
and zones are recognized by Siri
we have another typeof grouping which is
to help
group in refer to functionality that is
provided by accessories
we may want to do something across
multiple accessories we don't
necessarily need to control
everything on the accessory so he called
service group
in HM service crew so you can imagine
you might have
night lights in your home or some other
night later their own accessory but some
night lights are to
it's a light on a coffee machine at a
light on a microwave it too late on the
refrigerator to light on whatever it is
and he can grab all of these light
services that are actually Night Lights
you can group them together into a
service group
and you can he easily display that to
use you can easily perform operations on
all of those
Night Lights services can be in any
number of groups this is Justin
Association
service which are also named
uniquely of course in a home and
into service groups are also recognized
by Siri and now
getting into couple more things that are
that are quite interesting
so first her action sets so
this is the
home kit implementation behind
collecting accessories into scenes
to how this works as we take a bunch of
actions
my actions or something you're going to
do to an accessory
and regroup those together into an
action set
so for example night so we may have a
night action set
or night scene and so this night action
set my turn off their lights like a door
closer I'd turn the thermostat down
that could be grouped together to be
easily refer to
for the user and usually executed all at
once
where they all at once I really mean all
at once
the order execution is undefined so you
can expect
that something is always going to happen
before something else in an action set
everything would be done at the same
time it's all going to get done
best efforts to everything action sets
again uniquely named and recognized by
Siri
so what are these actions
so actions are
HM characteristic right actions is a
very literal name
because what you're doing an action is
you are writing to a characteristic
so for example
he may have an action that is close the
garage
a single right to a single
characteristic
on the garage the garage door opener
service
and so that a single actions he would
create action
added to the action set so
actions that there are interested in
either starting to lie to do something
more complex
we also have triggers
the triggers Rahm timer trigger so time
a trigger is set up
to fire at a specific date and time they
can repeat
their uniquely named in a home but
they're not
interacted with to spoken commands but
there's something very special about
them
which is their actually executed by
I O S in the background at the time
when that trigger is suppose to be
execute when it fires so the trigger is
set
to run in action Sat and
that actions that can happen executing
attacks that can happen
even when the latter running or whatever
because the trigger is managed
by IRS she can imagine that
even with just being able to specify
dates and times collections and actions
to happen
repeating triggers you can start to get
some pretty interesting functionality
so I like to give you a quick Demel
action set and triggers work so we have
here hun get accessories simulator
still running and have another
very simple sample app to show you
place in March this time
so here we have in this home is in the
background
we have some action set in some triggers
already defined
so if you look at these actions that we
have the night action satire
example I gave earlier we also have
lights on in light of action set
so if you look at the night action set
were displayed here
all of the characteristic right that are
part
love this action Sep and
free go and look at for example some
things here so the
thermostats target temperature say that
with
said it seventy we can
go here and
unlock the door for example now you can
go here in this action said you can see
that the
door lock is gonna have the lock
characteristic
set to locked the thermostat is going to
have the target temperature set to 68
so I can execute this action set we can
see that
the lock has indeed changed to lock
thermostat target temperature has
changed back to 68
and these lights are off
so simple way once it's all set up very
simple way
to go in control many accessories same
time
so now let's look at his other two so
bites on simply turns on all the way
might of obviously turns off the lights
to these two actions that's just give me
the opportunity to show you a very
simple
demos triggers work so we have here to
triggers that are created
one runs the actions that lights on and
one runs the action set lights off
ok we can see that when I've turned
these triggers on Ivan able done that
these
lights just start blinking happen not a
a commonly used to use case in the real
world but a great
example for a demo so let's stop that
triggers and actions at
to go back to the side
so using action certain triggers
together you'll be able to script
or allow the user to script some fairly
complex and interesting interactions
and enable you and your users
to control many accessories very easily
very quickly
so
one more thing I want to tell you about
home kit
as you're looking through our
documentation going to see there are a
lot of delegate methods
and you might ask do i do I need
I love these delegate methods do I have
to
implement every single one and
now more yes there there for a reason
they're there because if you remember
back at the beginning in the
presentation we talked about the shared
database
and because the shared at the shared
database we get this great
consistency across the user experience
different applications that have
different specialized purposes
users going to see that all the tabs are
aware of their home
they have their home setup they have
their living room they have their
kitchen they have their ceiling lights
they're gonna see that in every app
right in a field great to users using
you don't want your apt to get out of
sync
with what the user knows they have set
up for their home
and because at this shared database you
can be updated
in many different ways many of those
ways are not through your app
for some other after some other event
accessories are changing
and so all these delegate methods are
how
we tell you what's changing
and some change the name in that room
that
accessory state has changed
someone has added a should be so lucky
at a lake house
to their their collection of homes and
so
when these things happen you wanna be
able to update your app
to the user sees that your app is
connected your apt knows what's going on
everything is being communicated to
these delegate methods are how
you do that
so that brings us just about the end of
my presentation in a fish timers right
I've got quite a bit faster than
expected
that's okay right at the end of the day
what you remember this
so home kit is
providing you the opportunity
to deliver a much more consistent
experience for home automation
through your applications the framework
has
been designed to be easy to use
simple to create a home it's simple to
have an accessory it simple interact
with it
you can easily get the lists accessories
that are available on display them to
users
we've also enable you to get an early
start an awesome
to be able to very effectively easley
debug and test applications using a hunk
accessory simulator
and there's information available for
you
if you're curious about how to get
started here at home kit or making a
home kit accessory
had developer Apple com such home kit
for more information we have our great
evangelism team
was there for you to reach out to and we
have
documentation available at all the
regular places including
unify program for accessory
manufacturers
so that finishes retail want to thank
you very much
if we appreciate the opportunity to talk
to you enjoy
rest the show