good morning everyone
I'm glad you guys could make it my name
is Bruce Nile
I'm one of the engineers on you like it
and
we're gonna be talking about all the new
stuff that we've up
brought into you like it for Iowa say in
case
on the once told you it's a big release
there's a lot of stuff in two weeks ago
when I was
a thinking about what i was gonna say I
said he's a cake
I'm just gonna list all the new features
on
I'm gonna also list all the things that
are going away
and I'm done right well that's what I
ended up with
and I realized I'm I really needed to
cut down on what I was going to talk
about so
this is where we ended up and
I just want to point out though that
there's a lot more
I than what I'm going to talk about what
are the most important things that we're
introducing
in Iowa State in case you haven't heard
is we are providing
API's that are more adaptive on what
this means is that your
user interfaces can more easily respond
to changes in size
I and other changes as well on
US would view controller used to be a
kinda up
pretty simple class well it's grown up
in Iowa State we're gonna talk about
some of the new features that you I
split you controller has to offer
we're gonna while we're at it
show how it's really easy to hide bars
in ways that
you've probably seen in some of our own
aP's on
then we're gonna shift gears a little
bit talk about
on presentations presentation
controllers have been introduced
and are part of a whole we architectural
revamping up have you are you
controllers are presented and how you
can create
great costume presentations yourselves
on that gave us the opportunity by the
way to redo pop overs as well
and pop overs have now become integrated
with you I view controller presentations
finally we're going to talk not finally
we're also gonna talk about new API
that we introduce that builds upon
transition coordinators
on that also helps your applications
adapt
and finally there's a subtle up but
pretty important change in terms of the
the coordinate space is that you
a grown to love and we'll talk about
that briefly when we wrap up
sup you've probably seen this picture
or a variant of it a few times on many
hierarchical applications on a phone
Mike structure themselves this way
inside the navigation controller and
there might be some detail
that you would see when you hit the back
button
and on up
iPad you might choose to structure it a
little bit differently
on again this is all kinda familiar
stuff
but there's no particular reason why you
shouldn't be able to do this on an
iPhone
I if it suited your application I'm
were show how that's possible so
prior to iowa say most of your
application
coarse grain structure I am
was determined by looking at the device
type and possibly interface orientation
as well as the size in which your user
interface was being
presented and I would say it we've taken
the first two
and abstracted a little bit into to new
concepts called traits in trade
collections
size is still available but typically
size is a finer grain typeof layout
operation that can be easily
accommodated using
I technologies like auto layer we're
gonna talk a little bit more about the
former
on will also address the latter a little
bit
so what is a trait collection I'm
a tree collection simply put is a
set I love Trites up too surprising
on the phone you might see on the window
I'll your application return a trait
collection
that has the following traits: to size
classes
an idiom and a display scale this
typically is the way
a phone straights on
our structure want most important traits
that we've introduced
is size clubs in size class
deals with on a course leveled the
available space
on that your application has and can
therefore make decisions about what its
structure should be
let's look at at that quickly here we
have kinda cartoonish representation
about iPhone
and typically the vertical access
is going to have a regular size class
where the horizontal axis is going to
have a compact size close
if you rotate a phone
we say the P size classes are
constrained in both the vertical and the
horizontal dimensions
not iPad is a little bit more free
its regular in all its dimensions or has
regular size classes and all its
dimensions
and that holds true when you rotate it
as well
but that's not the full store
this some view controllers like split
view controller
can determine that its children in this
case the primary
control child which is on the left side
I'm
has a more constrained I size class in
either dimension for size
for ops would be a controller it
constrains the horizontal
size clubs
sup a size class is all about
in forming your application up the
available space
in some course way that you can make
decisions about how you would
substantially alter the application
structure
we have a TI on specific objects that
vent rate collections
and in these cases they have values for
both the horizontal
and the vertical size classes now I like
to think about
the tray collections that come back from
these objects
as defining appoint in a trait space
we've introduced a new protocol that
a number for objects conform to which is
a trait environment
and you'll see the hierarchy on the
right is kinda window hierarchy that
starts from a screen and proceeds down
all the way to the leaf
view elements that you have all these
objects conform
to the trading varmint protocol which
means you can ask him for trade
collection
and what you get back is going to be a
point in a trait space
were every single trait has a value now
not not all these objects to find those
values directly
so for example if you ask for the scale
belief
up the scale trade a bully for the view
it might actually the system might walk
all the way up to the screen
to get that but the tree collection that
you get back we'll have a value for that
scale
finally you will notice that whenever a
tree
changes in a tree collection your object
the appropriate object will get a tree
collection did change just for that
object is lay at the laid out so you can
respond to that
so I kind of implied before that you can
that out
you controllers such as what you
controller can override the transfer
chop
how do you do this well we've introduced
a couple new methods
on you argue controller which allow you
to do precisely this
said override trade collection can be
used by a
parent indicate what the appropriate
traits are for anyone up its children
the tree collection that you pass in in
this case isn't a point in a trade space
it might just be a single
trade value which is then overridden
so what I wanted to do was before I go
to the rest the talk is I put together
kinda toy implication
which is to highlight some the features
that we're going to talk about today
this is kind of my canonical little
photo no
taking I toy at location
what you see here is basically a bit
pretty standard thing you see a
navigation controller on and I can hit
the back button
with this photos and I get a list which
is the simple table view
on I can select things that's great
what's interesting is that this is
actually split view controller
notice when I rotate I stay inside
a navigation controller however I can do
something interesting you see there's
the split button on the bottom
love this a toolbar if I hit it
you can now see a little bit more
clearly that this is in fact really
a split view controller you'll also
notice that when I
what's hide dislike in Tappan interact
with the bars I can't create
I can ha I can move that primary
controller off-screen
but one of the things we're gonna show
is how easy it is to hide the bars if I
tap on
on a view controller I can also get that
Safari look
where the bars contents really easily
alright
lech go back into a
regular old navigation controller look
and look at this note but note button up
is going to do a presentation this is a
you control your presentation on it
takes advantage of a couple new classes
that I might mention
as we go through the talk what's
interesting is is this is in fact
a popover presentation all get into that
a little bit later cuz it certainly
doesn't look like a popover presentation
but if I do something special on this
little toy up
well it didn't quite do at that time now
you'll see that that same thing is in
fact a popover will go through that a
little bit
um finally I wanted to talk about a
little bit about rotation
and to do that I'm going to present
another view controller this time it's a
collection view controller
which has a bunch a little thumbnail
photos and if I were to rotate the
device now
the normal collection view flow layout
behavior
we basically relay things out so that
everything is worry aunt it now
in the horizontal direction however if I
wanted to
change what happened when I rotated so
that it did something more akin to this
on there's some interesting things that
we can do
I and this is a perfect example of when
you would you sum up the
I methods like will rotate interface
orientation so forth so we're gonna talk
about that a little bit as well
alright so another taste of what we're
going to talk about let's go back to the
presentation
and let's talk about split view
controller
so as I kinda implied split view
controller is now available
on the phone as well as on the iPad
and it has this interesting new I
property
it has a property in being collapsed or
not collapsed
now what does it mean for us would be
controller to be collapsed
or expanded well
and Spanish fleets split view controller
it's kind of obvious might look like
this:
however it's not just a question about
the two
children being visible so
I'm highlighting the secondary view
controller at the split view controller
and you're gonna notice that there's a
little a button off to the left we call
it the display mode button item
when I click on that in I can expand
out this quick view controller and even
though we're only looking at the
secondary controller that's what you
controller is still
expanded it is not collapsed in the
reason why that is because it's possible
to show the primary controller at the
same time
as the secondary control
on the other hand this is a collapse
would be a controller you'll notice that
the display mode but night on that was
on the left side is gone
are you can now look no longer show the
primary and secondary controllers
together
they've been collapsed and you can now
get to the primary controller by hitting
the back button
which is up on the job top left corner
so that's kinda what the differences
between appts what you control or in its
collapsed a
and its expanded state it's important to
know that
what you controllers by default are
collapsed when they're in horizontally
compaq containers
so by default on the phone if you use a
split view controller is going to appear
in this collapsed a
so I've been plied that you can
enable the expanded say have a split
view controller on the phone already
how do you do that well it's actually
quite simple and straightforward
you probably know the answer already on
first of all you're gonna take your spot
you controlling your gonna in bed
innate parents container view controller
as fol- you're then going to
call set override trait collection
and you're gonna informed that child
split view controller that it is now
in a horizontally regular environment
the second you do that this what you
controller
Morse into its expanded or not collapsed
a
you'll notice that the display mode
button item which is titled photos in
the lower left corner has now become
enabled if I wanted to show
both controllers together side by side
I could click on that display mode
button item
but we've also introduced a property
called preferred display mode which you
can use programmatically
if you set the preferred display mode to
the all visible value
it's the same as the same behavior would
occur as if you clicked on the display
mode but night and you'll also notice
that this play mode but night a Morse
into this a kinda diagonal
double arrow on these
items this display mode item in this
behavior
is all customizable and this is via
delegate API
that you can look at in the header files
and I'm not gonna have time to talk
about today
so to go over summer thats API
for for display mode is an enumeration
enumerated values are automatic hidden
visible
and overlay automatic is the old
behavior that you
are familiar with on iPad's hidden
invisible or explicit met means by which
you can
control the layout at the split view
controller so that the primary and
secondary are side by side
and overlays an explicit way that you
can have the primary kinda
go over the top but the secondary
the displayed mode button item is also
accessible
in this API so you can ask that what you
controller for it and put it in whatever
bar you want
although I'm not gonna say it explicitly
if you were to look in the header files
that you are split view controller you
would find that most
above the API the used to be there is
now deprecated and replaced by new API
one thing that I'd like to say is that a
lot of people have always wanted to
control the split
which and we made that really easy to do
so there's a new math a new property
preferred primary column with
fraction if I were to set that too 1/2
say
the split with changes
the API that enables that is this you
can set a minimum and maximum
found at the split with in terms of
points
you specify the split in terms of a
fraction and you can read back
the actual point value: with the primary
column with property
so what we learned here one is is that's
what you controllers can be
used on both the iPhone and the iPad
this makes it easy to write code
it is kinda agnostic about the platform
that it's going to be deployed on
if you have a certain type of
application layout that makes sense
in either a clap state or an expanded
split view controller state based on the
available space
create a split view controller and this
with you controller will adapt
accordingly
split you controllers are collapsed by
default in horizontally compact
environments
the display mode property controls the
appearance of the primary or left
child view controller up the split you
and you can also is now specify the
split with
so there are a lot of other API that we
added to split view controller
there's gonna be a talk immediately
following this one which talks about
in more depth Alden new adaptive API's
that we've added to you I view
controller and UIs
what you controller that you can get
attend and get
more information so let's talk about
condensing bars
it's all about available space in
highlighting your content so we wanted
to make it
easy to do it's really easy now to hide
your bars
just up behind bars on top property
and they're gone up
if you
so what about that great you know can a
safari looking
a condensing bar behavior well we've
added a property for that tip
just set it to yes when you swipe those
bars can deaths
so we've got a couple of other
properties as well on
you know the bars can hide when you're
in a hurry up vertically compact
environment
they might condense when the keyboard
appears on
you can control the salt
programmatically within animate a ball
property called
navigation bar condensed well at least
you can control the condensing behavior
that way
on so yeah
that's it for condensing boilers
okay now the easy stuff is all done
let's talk about presentation
controllers
we have revamped the presentation
architecture for view controllers
on I O S eight
you might recall that my West seven we
allowed
developers for the first time to
customize what the
presentation transitions looked like
let's go back in kinda talked about how
that looked and how you did that
so first of all what you do is you the
view controller that you wanted to
present
you would set the presentation style to
custom
you'd also set a transitioning delegate
on that presented
on my view controller to be presented
and then you would just present the way
you normally do you tell a presenting
view controller present view controller
at which point the system takes over
you like it will ask the transitioning
delegate
for the animation controller that is
your object
that is offended by the transitioning
delegate that you've set
at which point you like it prepares this
internal
object which conforms to this context
transitioning protocol
to set up some information that you need
to know in order to drive your custom
transition
the views that are participating in this
custom presentation or accessed via this
view controller for key property
and then there's frame information all
that stuff now this object is passed
into
another method that is generated by you
like it
to your animation controller animate
transition
you do your animation the presentations
complete
the animation controller goes away and
everything's good
well they were couple problems with that
let's look at the view hierarchy
to see what those problems might have
been
so we have the presenting view
controller's view
when the animation controllers men did
we set up kind of the environment in
which this transition animation is gonna
take place
that's kind of the container view that
the context the
transition in context is pointing to
that your animation controller accesses
when we certainly animate transition
message to the animation controller
it's the animation controller now that's
problem in the view hierarchy
adding special views adding the
presented you controller's view
and one of the neat things it was a
feature on
in I was seven is that we didn't remove
the presenting view controller's view
and so this is what it ended up with in
the animation controller went away
okay so the first question that comes to
mind is
what object owns all these other these
views that are lying around
that guy Scott added by that animation
control
well there was a good answer for that in
fact that ended up causing a tight
coupling between
the animation controllers that we're
doing a presentation
in the animation controllers that we're
doing a dismissal
on sometimes I was easy to manage some
time to cause problems
it often cause problems when you
controller presentations were being
stacked on top of one another
so let's look what we do in iowa say
it's gonna look pretty similar in the
beginning
you're gonna set the presentation style
just like before
you're gonna set a transitioning
delegate just like before
you're gonna send the present view
controller message
to the present in view controller just
like before
however now the transitioning delegate
has grown
couple new methods you can now get then
this new object called a presentation
control
and now it is the presentation
controller
that's responsible for asking the
transitioning delegate for the animation
controller
and in fact four driving the actual
transition now there's a lot of neat
things under the hood that are going on
here
and there's gonna be a whole talk are
tomorrow I believe
about presentation controllers in depth
and how we use that
you like it sick introduce a new API as
well
but for now let's look at what's going
on in the view higher
so now you remember you have this view
hierarchy the car sponsor discussed in
transition
presentation controller still around and
it holds a reference to the container
view
which is where the whole transition is
happening
it also holds a reference to this thing
called a presented view
night I want to point out the present in
view is not necessarily
the view of the view controller that's
being presented
maybe I put a drop shadow around that
view
because that's what my custom
presentation demand
in order to accommodate that
we had to augment the context
transitioning protocol little bit
so we added this new method called view
for a key
you controller for key still exists but
view for key may return a different view
then the view controller for key and so
when you build a custom animation
controller you want to make sure that
you use
the view for key methods to figure out
which views are actually participating
in the animation
a presentation controller can also at
other types
views that are completely unknown to
other types of presentation controllers
say like a dimming view that it wants to
put over the entire
back up the presentation
I mentioned that you know I was seven by
default
presenting view controller's view was
left in the window hierarchy
or presentation controllers have a very
rich API and if you build your own
on you can specify properties such as
should remove
should the presentation a a few
controllers you be removed or not and if
you set it to yes
it will automatically get removed
there's one other property which is I'm
breezing here because I think
anyone to build a custom presentation
controller needs to at least be aware of
which is the should present in
fullscreen property what this means is
that a presentation
will affectively its container will be
in the window and its and the frame-up
that container view of actively be the
bounds of the window
on if you
implement a custom can custom
presentation controller and separate
property
to know your presentation will no longer
adapt know I know that doesn't make
quite a lot of sense yet but we're gonna
go through
some stuff and then it will become more
clear
so let's quickly talk about some the API
that
has been added for presentation
controllers
one is as you'll notice that it and
appear it conforms to the appearance
container protocol
the trade environment protocol and this
new protocol which will talk about in a
bit call content container
we talked about the container view
properties in the presented the method
and these two other properties as I said
there's a whole bunch
%uh methods in logic available for you
to create
fantastic new custom presentations
but that's beyond the scope of this
stock
so armed with this new architecture
let's talk about some features that we
that
for civil all the old on
iPad only presentations are now
available
on the iPhone by default they're going
to present
to full screen presentations but there
are some power under the hood here
so new presentation styles that are
available that we've added
again that are both available on the
phone and the iPad
is an over full screen presentation and
over current context presentation
and I think I mention before pop overs
are now presentations as well
every presentation has an associated
presentation controller and you can
access the
access these with these methods and the
reason you do so is could you often want
to set the delegate
on the presentation control now the plot
thickens because the delegate
is in fact the object that is going to
help your presentations adapt
two different rate environments before
we get into that
let's make sure we all understand what
the new presentation styles are all
about
over full screen is kinda full screen
presentation
that doesn't remove the presenting two
controllers for you
so you can create interesting on kinda
overlay
pipe so presentations really easily now
over current context is pretty similar
if you know what current context
presentations arts presentations that
are kinda constrained
inside a the presenting view controllers
Super T so that's what over current
context gives you
and finally we have pop over
we all know what pop over looks like on
this is a good opportunity for me to say
that worth were kinda soft deprecating
you i pop over control
on we're not hard deprecating it
but you should be aware that all the
popover controller
all pop over controller API is now being
Shane
kinda behind the scenes into a popover
presentation
this might create a couple a bit
differences in behavior
for the most part these things are
functionally equivalent
there are a few corner cases though that
you might run into
for example if you have a pop if you
have code that was presenting a popover
and then immediately dismissed it ended
another presentation
the next line you're gonna have to defer
that on
and you can do that pretty easily by
grabbing a transition coordinator in
scheduling the new presentation for
after the dismissal up the Popo
so let's talk about how presentations
can adapt
to change in Creighton farms as I
mentioned
I all these presentations styles
adopt by default and horizontally
compact environments to full screen
now it's possible to change that default
behavior
to be over full screen or to be not
which means
please don't adapt keep my presentation
controller
as is in charge
the way you control this behavior as I
implied was use up the delegate
and you're going to override a couple
arena implement a coupla methods on that
delicate
so here they are
the first is adopted presentation style
for presentation controller
it does what it its name implies
it's called when the presentation moves
into a horizontally compact environment
and you return one of those presentation
styles that I enumerated earlier
there's another method that might be a
little less clear which allows you to
actually return a whole new view
controller that should be presented nap
stop
and we'll see what that means in a bit
up
there's a popover presentation
controller delegate which I'm not going
to go into detail about
but suffice it to say that that they'll
get in addition to providing the
adaptive API's
also exposes all the properties and
methods that you need to get the
functionally
acquittal and popover behavior you're
used
will see a little bit %uh the code
example up that short
in fact very shortly on so what does it
mean to present a popover
NIOS a well you could use the old API's
as i sat on you I pop over controller
but i wanna show how you would do it
using the new APIs
sup the first thing you do not too
surprisingly as you set the presentation
style the Popo
now interestingly you can grab the
popover presentation controller before
you've even presented anything
that's important because you're gonna
need to do things like say
watch the bar but night on that I'm
pointing to in 10 my arrows look like
you might also want a suspect the fire
preferred contents of
so that we know kinda had a size the
popover
and finally you present the pop-up
so what's like it'll look like so I
wrote that code in executed it
just the way you saw on the previous
slide
gonna look like that now the first thing
I want to say is
it is a popover presentation
the second thing I want to say is
there's a couple problems
so the first problem
is that it under laps a status bar this
is why my favorite books I can't tell
you how many bugs I get
about my contents underneath the status
bar
I can go into that but I thought I would
just mention
the second thing is it looks pretty bad
n a more subtle point that I'm sure all
you got was
it's a popover presentation I can tap
anywhere to dismiss
okay so what are we gonna do what we're
gonna go to our friend
trustee presentation controller delegate
or to use some %uh those new adapted
APIs
and in particular I'm going to implement
I would implement adaptive presentation
style for president
presented for presentation controller
this moment have it return over for
spring
are going to use this brand new view
object that we introduced
I in Iowa State called the UI visual
effect view which will become your best
blurry friend in iowa say
and then inside that implementation I
can adjust the contents
like where it's actually position so
that should address a couple other
problems
so now I get this
kinda nifty blurred view which looks a
lot better than that ugly white
think ivory position my content
it's a different adaptation the reason
is boring so nicely is because I didn't
remove the presenting view controller's
view
underneath however we still have the
problem that there's no way to dismiss
the Popo
so how do we fix this well
you may give recall that there was
another
delegate API that I talked about that I
deferred kind of explaining why I
why it was useful we can go back to the
delegate in this time
we're gonna also implement presentation
controller view controller for adapted
presentation style
this is pretty nifty what we're gonna do
is we're gonna create a navigation
controller
whose root view controller is the
currently presented view controller
we're gonna added dismiss button to the
navigation controllers
are navigation bar
and they were gonna be good to go up so
now when I hit
No
I get this great-looking over full
screen adaption
popover presentation there's a done
button so I can dismiss it
such great what if I actually just wanna
pop up
well you can do that too let's go back
to our trusty delegate friend
and insist I'm an adapted presentation
style for presentation controller
all I need to do is return not
if I return on the presentation
controller is not going to be adopted at
all
and now when I hit note button I get
actual pop over
so it's gonna go over what we saw here
first is present cage presentation
controllers are a new object in Iowa
State
that make it easier and more consistent
to create powerful custom presentations
they are an improvement over what was
introduced in Iowa 7
every presentation is associated with
the presentation controller which can be
accessed and you can use that
presentation controller to do various
things depending
on the presentation control but all
presentation controllers
can use can have a delegate that
conforms to these adopting
delegate particles
one thing that is in on the screen is
that pop overs are also presentation
controllers
or our presentations that have been
associated presentation control
and finally if you create your own
presentation controller right mention
this earlier
if it returned yes to should present in
full screen it will be able to adapt
if on the other hand your presentation
controllers kinda current context I'll
presentation
it doesn't really make too much sense
for that to adapt so it doesn't we're
not gonna go through those adaptive
delegate calls in that case
alright that's enough for presentation
controllers although this topic
actually kinda overlaps or has some
overlap with presentation controllers
drug transition coordinators up again
those were introduced
and I was seven on
what is it well
it's an object that conforms to this
protocol
on in every transition coordinator
has in Associated transition
and that associated transition
is oftentimes deferred
and this transition coordinator is kinda
holding this freeze-dried transition as
it gets passed around to their various
pieces that code
they can then use this method called
enemy alongside transition completion so
you can pick you up blocks
all the animations that are gonna
execute in that kind of deferred
transition animation that is associated
with that transition coordinator
so that's pretty powerful was introduced
in Iowa seven and we're taking advantage
of this object in a few new API's
so to have these are you'll transition
size
with transition coordinator
next one is will transition a trait
collection with transition coordinator
now I'm not gonna talk too much about
will transition to trade collection
but I did mention earlier the tree
collections are kinda associated with
course
application structure on and one of the
best ways to
adapt a application it's not the only
way but it's warm
is to implement will transition to treat
collection
and when a trait collections such as a
size class
say that may change say if you
rotated device or if you set an override
tree collection
this method will be invoked and you can
actually do some coarse-grained
application kinda regenerate
if you want now again there's going to
be a whole talk that goes into a lot
more detail
on that particular method it's very
parallel to the other method
you will transition to size with
transition coordinator
that i'm gonna talk about by the way did
I forget to mention this is part of a
new protocol called the content you I
content container
I mentioned that you I presentation
controller conforms to this
you a view controller also conforms to
this protocol
these objects support the notion of a
preferred content sites that you can set
and that's kinda the request if you will
that
you like your content size to grow or
shrink depending on
the circumstances that your application
when you set that your parent container
object whatever that might be it might
be
a parent view controller it might be a
presentation controller
will get a preferred content size did
change for child content contained
in that method the parent can decide
what to do with the request
if it decides that actually wants to
honor the request
it may turn around its called you all
transition the size the transition
coordinator
on the child which gives the child
the ability to you I
animate alongside that size change
so let me kinda make a small digression
and kinda give a bit of wisdom and I
I realize that Anonymous is actually
jock schaeffer
girl I think I heard this from him on
and you might wonder why am i throwing
this random point now
first let's see what we mean here on
basically by rotating device in general
that's all it happen
the fact that there's an animated
transformer station is kinda beside the
point
and most the time your application
really doesn't need to do anything
it's gonna gracefully stretch and do
whatever it needs to do
I as the band's change
okay so what does that mean well you'll
recall that we have these
API's that have been around for a long
time
on well we get rid of a
and hi I thought you guys all love these
I'm so
what are the things about these API's
and I've I think I've been on the stage
before saying
you shouldn't do layout based on
interface orientation and you shouldn't
use these methods to drive your layout
they're really kinda focused message she
wanted to use them because you wanted to
participate
in this rotation at so now we've
generalized
we have this other method called you
will transition a size with transition
coordinator
it takes over so first of all
all those rotation call backs can be
replaced with this
more general notion a fuel transition a
size with transition coordinator
I talked about setting the preferred cut
10 size and that
you get this notification well so if
your widget in the Notification Center
actually wants to request to be
displayed in a slightly larger
space all or smaller space on
this this API will be called on your
widget
so that you can in fact animate
alongside or be no
run some code that executes after the
resizing has taken place
I said that you can use your own aP's
can respond to this
now at one point I was going to
have a whole buncha slides that showed
you how did implement your own
transition coordinator
on I enough time to do that but it's
relatively straightforward
and you can implement your own
transition coordinator that implement
that kind of is associated with your own
transition animation and if a child
changes its size
you can call the all transition sizing
passin that object
in the transition coordinator okay
so to really be a replacement for
kinda the rotation we can to give a
little bit
on can to get down on of a bar
high horses have you know
the way things should be an acknowledge
the way things are
and we added this target transform but
not so much the orientation that you
really care about
is it's like what's the transform thats
kinda have
being that I'm participating in an
animation
the reason this is important and I'm
gonna get to this later
is we've actually changed where
the rotation transforms lip some love
you guys may have noticed that whenever
you do a rotation that this larue view
controller the full screen view
controllers
I layer that has kind of the af line
rotation transformation directly
associated with it
that's no longer the case on IOSA so
when you get
when you believe you will transition a
size you can ask for the target
transform
and if it's not identity your insider a
rotation
resize at that you can do some
interesting things work
so to show how these are similar or how
this is a direct replacement for the old
rotation call backs
this is some you know skeleton code
where view all transition size first
called my will rotate interface
orientation
which is exactly when it the old call
would have been made
and then it uses the transition
coordinator
to animate alongside my wheel an image
to interface orientation call and
finally in the completion block
is when you would call my did animate
from interface:
orientation so you can kinda see that
will transition to size
on with transition coordinator is
identical
or provide the identical functionality
is actually more powerful
and from my perspective it's a lot
easier to read code like this:
okay I know you guys are all sad and
that these methods have gone so if you
don't implement the old transition size
a transition coordinator will still call
them
just don't implemented a subtle point
that you should be aware of
is most you controller transitions on
are immediate when the system calls on
this method what does that mean it means
that
if you needed to rearrange your
application structure in some
significant way
on and you do like push you controller
something like that
the entire view hierarchy is going to be
updated
immediately so you can do need things
with that in your transition animations
unlike I rotation call backs
by 24 we're gonna forward you will
transition to size
through the entire presentation I
hierarchy through the entire
on you controller containment hierarchy
all you need to do is call super to get
that behavior
if you don't we will no longer propagate
so you probably want to call super
finally I'm gonna say that you really
only need this I kinda implied it before
when you're doing some kind of special
size transition
more often than not auto layout and
other techniques are going to be
layout techniques are gonna more than
suffice
to handle size transition
so I wanted to I showed this example
earlier in the demo and I wanted to show
when
would be a good time that you might want
to use you will transition the sauce
so here's a collection view controller
if I rotated
what's gonna end up happening if I did
nothing at all
is I get all the default collection view
flow layout will give me something like
this you'll notice
kind of Houla the thumbnails have
shifted around in
things every size 10 maybe that's what I
want
but maybe I want something else maybe I
don't want the collection view
controllers you to rotate at all
and I want to apply the counter
transform on each of the cells
something like that so this would be a
great time to use you'll transition size
I and let's see how that would look
the first thing that you do you get that
target transform that I was talking
about
now we're going to invert it you wanna
grab our old you bounce
on and some things up for our transition
coordinator
so inside the alongside block we're
gonna basically call transition
coordinator animate alongside
we're going to update the transform
to basically undue the rotation
transform that's taking a fact you'll
notice that I'm composing it with the
existing transform because hell I might
be in a different orientation already
so I do that
and then squirrel away the counter
rotation which effectively is the
transform that is I am animating with
right now
my update my bounds to the old balance
because I now applied
the counter transform on the collection
view controllers use transform
and up we need not wrote the collection
view controller is a canoe
rotate and those cells are going to
rotate either
until I hit the completion block at
which point I'm gonna apply the counter
rotation to Egypt
okay so what do we learn on
transition coordinators are being used
in a lot of our
adopted API's
you can use a transition coordinator in
response to you
preferred content size did change calls
over the rotation call backs are being
deprecated
that's about it so let's talk about
spring court in its and this gets to
wear
the transforms are being applied when we
rotate
so when I was a I mean I was seven
the screen orientation was always fixed
to you
kinda the top left position
in Portree its gave she gave you affixed
unchanging coordinate system
if you needed it we ended up
communicating things like
keyboard size an and other things in
terms of this fixed coordinate system
even though the actual interface
orientation
was the current top left corner so I
would say we're changing that a bit
and everything is now interface oriented
so the keyboard size notifications are
going to be
interface oriented the other things are
going to be interface oriented
but you still may need a I'm
a fixed coordinate system
how do you do that well we introduce a
new protocol called the UI coordinate
space and by the way this is not in seed
ones will come out in a
on you know soon to follow seed on
we introduced a protocol called you I
coordinate space
couple conversion routines up to and
from these corn its paces
it also implements the balance call
you live you conforms to this directly
which isn't too surprising all the
existing conversion
routines by the way stay in place US
Green now has grown
a couple properties that band two
different coordinate space is one is
that the fall
interface oriented coordinate space and
the other is the old
portrait fixed coordinate space
so if I wanted to convert to and from
on that fix coordinate space what you
effectively do as you grab that dick
sworn in space
of %uh the on the Windows screen and you
can convert to and from views
so let's go over briefly what we
discussed today
we talked a little bit about
recollections how they affect
kinda gross course level application
structure
a viewer application how you can
override them how view controllers can
override them
and a little bit about how your view
controllers and your application can
adapt to those changes
we introduce some love the new you I
split new controller
I am features and there are a lot of
them
I encourage you to come to look at the
header files and attend the talk after
this to see
all the new UN amazing things you can do
with what you control or
there's a new simple properties on
navigation controller that allow you to
condense and high bars
we introduce presentation controller and
particular we've revamped the
presentation hierarchy pop overs are now
presentations we've introduced some new
presentation styles
you got some new API for transition
quote that utilize transition
coordinators
and these are becoming interesting
objects that are becoming more present
in more and more or APIs
we've deprecated the old rotation call
backs or the
existing rotation call backs in be
replaced by that logic can be replaced
by this
new method you will transition size
and finally screen Browns is now
interface oriented
on there's a lot of things in UI kit
that are new for IOSA this is just some
other
encourage you the talk right after this
one is a building adaptive aP's with you
i cant thats gonna go into much more
detail
about all these new in great adapted
API's we haven't you like it
tomorrow there's going to be a talk that
goes into depth about presentation
controllers
how we internally use them to implement
new replacements for search controller
and work controller
on we're there was a talk yesterday
believe that creating extensions that
leverage the fuel transition the size
API's
there's some nice talks on Friday where
there is a nice talk on Friday
about on how you can make your
basically your transition animations
more responsive
to user interaction for more information
please contact our evangelistic parents
will be more than happy to get you to
sample Lapan
answer your questions and tell you how
it all works
and have a great rest obscure
other conference thank you