either my name's Jacob Shaw and I'm
really excited to talk
a about building adaptive aP's before we
get started though
I wanna tell you what we mean by
adaptive the first
let's go back in the beginning there
with the iPhone
one device one screen was pretty simple
to build applications for
but then when you consider rotation
now you have this portrait and landscape
orientations
and then after that we introduced the
iPad
as well as the iPhone 45
with its 4-inch display and I have all
these different
devices and all these different screen
sizes and it can seem intimidating
design aP's for well
and I with eight we wanna make it simple
for you to build a
to build one application that's both
universal
and is able to adapt taller these
different devices
screen sizes and orientations so today
I like to tell you about the new
concepts that we've added
for adaptivity inside you like it and
then
we'll take a look at some of the changes
we've made to both you controllers
and Interface Builder to support this
new adaptive world
alright the start of let's take a look
its size classes a new concept that
we've introduced
and I with eight in the past
used interface orientation and user
interface idiom
to differentiate between portrait and
landscape an iPhone and iPad
but Iowa State we're recommending
against using
these two concepts and instead were
advocating
this new concept the week off 55 balls
let me show I'll
show you a little bit about what we mean
by these differences
they represented by five class if you
think about
a typical iPad application and the
screens that it shows
you'll see features like split view
controllers form sheets
and popovers but really
none of these features are specific to
the iPad itself we're just using these
in this app in this iPad version of the
application we have because we have this
large horizontal campus
the display with them now on the other
hand
if you look at a typical iPhone
application you have a much more
constrained layout
where things are usually presented
fullscreen and shown in a single column
however this is also not intrinsically
tied to the fact that it's an iPhone
this just a tied to the fact that we
have this
smaller scores of appendicitis you'll
see the same kind of thing
and the master side us but you
controller
and even in the content a popover
and both movies on iPad so we call this
difference
regular and compact and we call this
access the horizontal side class now
if we consider the same kinda
distinctions in the vertical direction
you can see that on things like an iPad
or an
our night phone we have these taller
full-size bars
whereas in a more constrained vertical
situation
like an iPhone in landscape we have both
convinced bars
and now and I with aid we even hide the
status bar completely
and we call these also regular
and compact but this time in the
vertical
five-plus now you can think that these
two sides classes
in a similar way the way size works just
like a size
has a horizontal and vertical dimension
so does the size class
so if you put these two concepts
together
you get a two by two grid that defines
and you've the possibilities a regular
and compact
in both the horizontal and vertical
directions and you can have a view
controller
with any of these four possibilities
which results in different layouts
like it see here in addition to view
controllers having any of these
aside class combinations our devices
also have
default five passes that they'll that
they'll use an iPad
in both landscape and portrait will have
a regular size class and both horizontal
and vertical direction
an iPhone women portrait
will have a compact core sample size
class
and a regular vertical size class and
went to landscape
it will be compact in both the vertical
and horizontal
five passes so this is all a little
theoretical
let's take a look at a sample
application to see how this works in
practice
all right so the sample code that I'll
be showing you today
is available on the WWDC website
just go to the sample code section and
search for adaptive photos
the name of our sample app it's a basic
photo sharing application
and this is what it looks like on iphone
you can see our list
our contacts and I can tap on any of
these
to see the photos that they've set sent
back to me
if someone is only sent me a single
photo I'll go directly to that image
and if they sent me multiple photos I
get the list at the photos that they
sent me
and then view individual ones
now on the photo page you'll notice that
in addition to the picture
were also showing a comment overlay and
a reading control
let me write the photos that they sent
me
alright now when I rotate this
application to landscape
notice that are bars become condensed
and the status bar
disappears entirely
this all happens automatically but in
our application
we've done a few more customizations
inside a photo view
when I wrote a the the
not comments will have a smaller margins
and the rain control
will shrink down to a smaller size
now our application is of course
universal
so let me run it and side at the iPad
simulator
here you notice that I have all the same
functionality
and all the same controls inside my
photo view
but watch when I rotate to landscape
all the bars have still have the full
height
and I love my controls here have shut
down miss it because we still have this
large vertical real estate
and in our application we're using the
vertical five class
instead of the interface orientation so
we get the right behavior
on both iPhone and iPad
now one of the new features we batted an
eye with a is a resizable simulator
so if you notice here at the bottom I
can type in
new dimensions
and you'll see the my application has
resized and everything still looks great
because we're using auto layout insists
that standard system components
but in addition to just changing size I
can also change
the psych class and now
you'll see they were showing the iPhone
version of our application even on the
iPad
just by changing the side bus
so I highly recommend you test out your
application with the new
recital simulator and I with a
alright so now the you know how five
passes work in general
how do you actually get one at the site
classes in your application
what to do that use the new system we
call traits
traits are essentially properties that
you can use to determine how
the layout your application should
change at the environment changes
they consist a set a property's
including the horizontal and vertical
five classes that we just talked about
as well as the user interface idiom and
also the display scale
now all these traits a wrapped up inside
a container
we call I a tree collection this
includes
the trade properties and also their
values
and this new object is called you I
tried collection
you wanted the street collections you
just need to use a trade environment
train by Mansur our new protocol better
able
to return their current trick collection
and these include
screens Windows you controllers
and also views all these are able to
return
the current rate collection to you to
use to determine how your interface
should be laid out
one other object that's also a trade
environment is a you at presentation
controller
this is a new helper object that assists
with you control a presentation
and it's also able to park participate
and adaptivity
we don't have time to talk about today
about presentation controllers
but you can come back tomorrow at 11:30
to the
a look inside presentation controllers
talk to learn more
about how presentation controllers work
including how the
work with traits and adaptivity
now all these trained by romance make up
a hierarchy
and the trick elections that they have
will flow from parent to child
so by default the track elections at any
given child trig environment has
will be the ones that it inherited from
its parent all the way up to the screen
which makes up the route treatment
now in addition to getting the current
recollection from train varmint
they also have another method and that's
tree collection did change
this gets called whenever the traits
forgiven trade environment
are have just changed you can override
this
in your view controller or view subclass
snow
when you should be changing I love your
UI elements
that depend on traits and was even an
example that a little bit later
in our sample application
now let's take a look at a typical trade
collection
the street collection is one you might
see on an iPhone in portrait
we have a compact or sample size class a
regular vertical side class
idioma phone and at this point scale up
to
we call this a fully specified trade
collection because it has values for all
its straight properties
out of a possible have a tree collection
that's missing some up its values
and we call these missing values
unspecified
generally though when you ask the train
environment for trade collection
you go back a fully specified track
collection like the one on the left
however if a train by meant like a view
our view controller
is not inside the view hierarchy you
might get back
unspecified values like the track
collection on the road
you also get back these partially
specified take elections
if you create your own trick collection
using one of our creation methods
like trade collection with horizontal
five-plus which would allow you to
create a tree collection just like the
one on the right
now one operation that we can perform on
multiple trait collections
is comparing them to each other and
comparing a trick collection
involves asking if one tree collection
contains another one
now what this means about containment is
that for any trade
thats specified in the Fed second tree
collection
the value at that rate in the first
recollection has to have the same to
has two match exactly so here the second
track collection
only has a specified or sample size
class
and this this horizontal side cuts are
equal so we'd say that the first rate
collection contains the second one
and the way you can ask this question
the up trick collections
is by using the contains traits Inc
Lexion method on you at recollection
if we were to change the for example
size bass at the second track election
to regular
you can see that now these two
horizontal size classes don't match
so second take: collection is no longer
contain by the first one
now you can perform these comparisons
yourself in your own code
to determine how you should lay out your
user view controllers
but you like it also uses this
internally for some
for some of its functionality and one
example of that
is the appearance proxy the Prince proxy
is a system
that we introduced a while ago for
customizing
the properties up your views and with
extended it and I was 8
to support recollections we now have a
new method
appearance for trait collection they
returned you a new appearance proxy
with a given trait collection that you
passed in any customization
the you perform on that appearance proxy
will only
take a fact on views better that
they conform to that take much in the
past in
so but you like it
general you pass it passed in a
partially specified track collection
like a horizontal 55 compact and then
you be able to customize all the reviews
when they're inside a compact or sample
size bus
this is really great for customizing
olive your views together
another class that we've added traipse
collection support to you I image
in the past you'd have a 1x and 2x
version view images
you generally put these in your image
catalog
however and I would state we've expended
this to allow you to add multiple
versions I've your image
for different recollections so for
example
we could have this smaller image it's
used when we have a vertically compact
size class
and then the other image that we use and
any other time
for any other trade collections now when
you use one of these images
inside the UN ImageView the ImageView
automatically
pull out the right version of the image
for its current recollection
so for example if our ImageView has a
regular vertical side class
would be using this larger image and
what's really cool
is when are image view changes to have a
contact
vertical side class it'll automatically
update the image that's using
to be the smaller image and even change
its own intrinsic on 10 size
to shrink down to exactly match that
imagesize
and that makes it really easy for you to
use images that have different versions
for different recollections
and automatically get the right behavior
and wherever your application adaptive
and like I said this all happens
automatically with you I ImageView
we also have a new class called you a
image asset because you even more
control
an image asset wraps up all of these
different versions are the image
and it allows you to ask for specific
image matching a given trait collection
that you can pass in
and you can even add and remove your own
representations have an image
using other methods on image assets to
check out the UAE image at that
header file if the old BB the detail
that how this works
now one last thing that we can do with
trade collections is added together
we add one trick election to a second we
get
the combined trick collection and we can
do that
with the tree collection with traits
from collections method
anytime that one of the traits is
unspecified
in except for in one at the track
elections that we're adding
will get only the specified trade in the
final take collection
however if there are multiple versions
up multiple values for the trait that
are being added together
then the last recollection will be the
one that wins
so here reading compact to regular for
the horizontal size class
to or resulting trade collection also
have a regular for example 5
us and we'll see where this can be used
a little bit later in our talk
now the you know heart rights work but
the how we use them in our application
so let's run our application on the
iPhone again
and we'll take a look again at these two
views the change their appearance
when the vertical five passes change
the first one is a rating control and we
can look at the code for that right here
although we're doing in this view it's
creating image issues
and sending images on them they were
pulling out are at the catalogue
there's actually no coding here at all
the deals with traits our site castles
instead we just have assets
that define and a regular version of the
image
and vertically compact version of the
in our Image you automatically updates
take this this resizing behavior
for ratings control and since we're
using auto layout
our entire control will shrink and
growth to match those images changing
notice that we also have black person
that these images here and returning
to be blue an application this is
because we've added
added image rendering mode support to
the at the catalogue
alright
next let's take a look are over labia
here
in our in trendy content size method
we're looking at
the horizontal and vertical five spices
they were currently in
and using that to turn margins to add on
to our ancient the content size
this is how we automatically
change between this larger and smaller
margins as we rotate
between a vertically compact and regular
sized us
however we also need to tell the system
winwood when it needs to update this in
turn the content size and we do this
by overwriting track collection to
change here
we check if either the vertical or
horizontal size pot has changed
along with the street collection change
and if it has we just invalidate are
entering the content size
not all we have to do now
one last few in our application is this
profile view
the show some information about the
current user as well as the last image
that sent
however when I rotate this landscape
you'll see that our layout changes
to show a side by side view and started
this
up and down D and wouldn't implemented
that by using
trade collections and five passes as
well if I go to my profile view
controller
you can see we have a method
that updates all OVR on allow
constraints and it takes
a tree collection that we passin checks
its vertical size class
and uses one set of constraints when its
compact
to show the side by side view and uses a
different set of constraints
otherwise show the up-and-down diem
alright
out the packets lied to them next thing
I like to tell you about
is some other details up our view
controllers have adapted the
adopted these concepts a traits and five
passes to automatically perform
be more adapted in your applications one
of the few controller classes that has
changed most and I was 8
is US but you controller in the past
he often uses but you controller and the
iPad version of the application
and then you have to write a completely
different you control a hierarchy for
your iPhone application
when I was 8 we've made this but you
can't roller
available on both platforms you can just
write one view controller hierarchy
that works great iPhone and iPad and
that's what we've done in our sample
application
however we've even gone a little bit
further their
and forced this but you can't roller
have it side by side to call and you
an iPhone and landscape just like you
would have an iPad
let me show you exactly how we did that
let's first take a look
at the trade environment hierarchy that
our application has
when is on the iPad here you can see
that the slip you controller
is inheriting it straight collections
from its parents
and this gives it a regular core sample
size class
witness but you controller is in a
regular for example size class
it automatically will show the two
column view that you expect
on on iPad however if we now change
to our to what our iPhones trade
environment looks like
and landscape here you'll see that once
again this but you controller is it
inheriting it straight collections
but here it has a compact or sample size
bus
industry is it to show the one calling
the want to change this in our
application
will insert our own container view
controller as the parent at this but you
control over
then we use a new method and I was 8
called said overwrite rent collection
for childhood controller this allows us
to add our own tree collection
to the one that inherited by the child
the controller
in this case we'll be adding a regular
for sample size pots and a trick
question
and notice that it's partially specified
so when we add it together
with the inherited trait collection are
split the controller
will now have a regular for sample size
us in addition to whatever else
it inherits from its train bombings and
this regular sized glass
will cause it show the two-column but
the appearance
so what this ends up with when we rotate
from portrait to landscape is the wall
change from one to two columns
alright now we've seen how we can change
the trick questions
other charge controllers let's take a
look in detail
how the tree collection transition
occurs for example when we were kid
in this case would be rotating from
portrait to landscape let's take a look
at the time line
changes that occurs the first phase we
have
is the setup where we get ready to
perform this transition
then we show animations did indicate the
visual changes
and all that's done we do some clean-up
to fit to finalize the transition and I
was 8
winter went recollections change as part
of this transition we've given you some
call backs
that you can tie into to participate and
exchange
the first one is will transition to
trade collection with transition
coordinator
and this gets called at the very
beginning at the setup before the track
collection has changed to its new value:
you can use this to get ready for the
change that's about to occur
after that the tree collection change
itself happens
and immediately following that we call
tree collection did change
as I mentioned earlier you can use this
in view controllers are view subclasses
over that's not the end of the story we
still have these animation
and clean up status and you can actually
use the will transition to treat
collection method
the time to those as well transition
coordinator that you get past
in this method has an enemy alongside
method
the last few to add your own animation
box
to this transition they will get run
along with the transitions
own animations for example the rotation
in this case
there's also a way to add your own
completion box they will get run
inside the cleanup stage so let's take a
look at where we might use these two
specific call backs will transition to
treat collection
is great for animating you controller
changes along with the street collection
changes
so we use this in our application and
the profile view that we just saw
since we want this change to occur right
alongside that rotation transition
however will transition to trade
collection is only available on your
controllers
not on other trade environment like you
I views
and so tree collection did change is
great for use and you a view subclasses
where you want to update your UI as the
trade to changing
so we use this one in our comment
overlay view
the use our earlier
another we've seen the straight changes
let's drill in a little bit deeper
into the behavior that happens when its
purview controller collapses
from a two column to one column for you
as part of this change there too changes
that need to occur
the first thing that has to happen as we
need to find a new primary view
controller
to show in this collapsed bank on state
by default split view controller will
use the primary view controller
from your expanded to call on state as
the new primary controller and you
collapsed one calm state as well
however you can also change this by
overriding the spa beauty
controller delegate method primary view
controller for collapsing
but you controller this allows you to
return any view controller you want
to be the new primary controller and the
collapsed version abuse but the
controller
now want that new primary controller has
been chosen
the next step that has to happen is the
secondary to controller
has to get merged into that primary
controller
and in general but the controller will
try to automatically do the right thing
here as well
in fact in our sample application we
need to add any code
to get the behavior the you see here
where the secondary be controller
our photo view automatically gets pushed
onto the navigation controller stack
that we had from our primary view
controller
to generate you will have to do anything
here however there may be some special
cases
we want to interact a little bit with
this change
one example that from our sample
application is the No conversations like
that you
we show this whenever were in the to
call and you
and nothing has been flooded on the left
however
if we just use the default behavior this
but you controller
would take that secondary view
controller and push that
on top of our navigation stack but this
no conversation view doesn't really add
anything to the single
on the hook because there's no way that
the user can interact with it
to really we'd rather have a view the
looks like this
where we just show the top-level
ListView control or when we get
collapsed
and it's possible to do that with
another split you control a delegate
method
collapse secondary to controller on the
primary controller
and I'll show in detail the code that we
used to do that in our sample app
a little bit later next let's look at
the
transition that happens in the opposite
direction we expand
from a single common view the to calm
the
once again their two stages the need to
occur
we need to find a new primary view
controller and by default
split view controller will also use the
primary view controller from the
collapsed view
an expanded view and once again you can
use
us but you control a delegate method to
change that behavior
this one is primary view controller for
expanding let you control or
now want that new primary view
controller has been chosen
we need to take the secondary the
controller and recreated
from the primary controller there was
collapsed
and s but the controller will
automatically do the right thing here
as well eye-popping of our photo view
and showing that as the new secondary
view controller and our expanded view
however once again want to do something
a little bit special
for the no conversation you here if
we're showing the ListView
when work collapsed want to recreate
that no conversation flooded view
and make that appear as the new detail
view controller
on the right so we can do that
using other but you control a delegate
method separate secondary view
controller
from higher maybe controller
now adjustment on you that's the view
controller is doing all these merging
and I'm urging the secondary controller
automatically
and that's not entirely true the primary
control itself
is actually helping to do this merging
and I'm urging
and doing this using these two methods
on you I do controller
collapse secondary view controller first
but the controller and separate
secondary view controller
first but the controller these get
called by the split the controller
as part of its default implementation at
the collapsing
and I'm collapsing that occurs and %um
navigation controller
implement these to push and pop the
secondary be controller for you
automatically however you can also
simply
implement these and your own container
view controllers to get the same kind of
behavior
the navigation controller has or even
something completely custom
for your application
now one other change that we've made
house view controllers work and I with
eight
is in the way that you show view
controllers in the past
if he had a leak you controller like a
table view controller
and you showed a different one perhaps
by tapping on the cell
that new controller would reach up
through the view controller hierarchy
and grab the navigation controller that
it with embedded inside have
accomplished you controller on that but
this is a pretty tight coupling between
the leaf you controller an exact
environment that inside a
we want to try to move away from this
pattern and i with eight
could
so instead reintroducing to new method
that happy decouple this
showed you controller and show detail
view controller
these methods work by starting at the
Lee you controller
and walking up its parent PID controller
hierarchy until the fine
the right container view controller for
that specific action
so let me show you how the specific
methods work
we'll start with show view controller
and how it behaves
win it inside when it's called inside
the UN navigation controller
here it would just push on navigation
controller
so this is a great replacement for that
self-taught navigation controller push
me controller
approach the song earlier and what's
great about this method
at that it will actually adapt two
different view controller containers
and do something different for example
when you're inside this book you
controller and you call this method
it will instead show the new controller
on the left side
at this but the controller as the new
primary the controller
in fact even when you're not inside any
container view controller then implement
this method
will still give you on a Mac behavior
here
will show the view controller at the
mole you control a presentation
so you can always be guaranteed that the
view controller that you pass to show
you controller
will be shown and exactly the right way
for its current environment
next let's look at show detail view
controller this works similarly
and implemented by but you controller
here this but you can't roller will show
the view controller you pass
on the right and its but however
it that's the view controller is
collapsed as you might see an iPhone
application
been awhile actually redirect that show
detail view controller method
to show the controller and reset it to
its own primary view controller
let's look at a more concrete example
where we have a UN navigation controller
as the primary controller at this but
the controller
just like in our application here the
navigation controller
it's the showed you can call a method
and will push just like you saw earlier
so this show detail view controller
gives you great behavior and it's that
dick Taylor
whale show it on the right hand side if
it expanded
but it will push onto a navigation
controller that's your primary
controller
when it collapsed
and once again just like with show view
controller show detail view controller
will show that the controller as a model
presentation
if it's not inside any container view
controller that implemented
so these are those two you can talk
those two methods and what their method
signature looks like
but in addition to being able to call
them you can also implement these
and your own custom you control methods
and the but you get exactly the same
kind of behavior
as navigation controller and split view
controller get inside a mall at your
custom
view controllers
next I like tell you a little bit apart
how these methods are actually
implemented
not using a new method called target you
controller for action
sender this does all the work
going up the view controller Harkey
until the right you controller gets
found
for example if we call show you
controller would walk up
until we find the navigation controller
since that the first view controller
then implemented
or if we called show detail view
controller will keep walking up the view
controller hierarchy
and tell you after this but you
controller interview controller fraction
works by looking at the view controller
and see if it's overridden
the action method that you passed in and
also whether that the controller want to
receive that specific action
and the great thing about this is the
10th public you can use it
to make your own methods the work just
like show view controller and show
detail view controller
and we'll see a some specific examples
of this as we've used it in our sample
application
the last topic but I'd like to mention
is you control a presentation
and I with aid we made this adaptive as
well
so if you show a popover you control a
presentation well now
automatically adapt that to a full
screen presentation when you're in
of course %ah plea compact side us once
again
we don't have time to talk about that
today I highly encourage you to go to
the a look inside presentation
controllers talk
which is tomorrow at 11:30 the show you
all about how presentation controllers
work
and also hi can use them with traits and
adapted
alright let's look at the demo how all
those new controller
features work in our application
first look look at their profile you
getting let me show you
what transition looks like in slow
motion
notice that our labels an ImageView are
moving right along with the rotation
transfer
transition
and as i indicated the way we do that is
by calling this
at the constraints for take collection
method inside
I will transition to treat collection
with transition coordinator
here we just use the animate alongside
transition method
at the transition coordinator call that
they constraints method
and then to make our view up they play
out
this will automatically cause this
layout these lab constraints to change
alongside that rotation transition
alright now let's look at how we can
override
the traits first but the controller to
automatically
get that landscape view that shows two
columns
will just add this fuel transition to
size method
and here if our with is larger than 320
14 add this a four straight collection
which is a whore has a horizontal site
that the regular this is one of those
partially specified track elections
that we talked about earlier
when we set that trick collection
will use the Set overwrite recollection
for child view controller method
to add it to our child view controller
which in this case is this but the
controller
now when I run the application again
you'll see we can rotate landscape
and get this took on the a
and everything just works an iPhone as
you expect
and landscape it works just as it would
on the iPad
now let's book in detail how we and
minute the collapsing expanding behavior
this happens nice but you control a
delegate method
first we had the collapse secondary view
controller on two primary controller
method
and here we want to use this from or
collapsing
and we're going from a No showing the no
conversation view
the hiding it and only showing this
top-level list
first well as the secondary view
controller if it contains a photo
and we did this by adding a category
method to you I view controller
to return whether or not any given view
controller shows a photo
and if we do not have any photo in our
current secondary controller
return yes this tells the the but you
controller
the we've handled the collapse ourselves
and turned off any of its default
behaviors
which would have pushed thats secondary
controller on top at the navigation
stack
we also have some logic here to make
sure that we don't push
a view controller on top venue
controllers that don't match its current
photo
you didn't look at the sample
application yourself
see exactly how this works finally we
return 0 here
when there was a photo and this tells us
but you can tell her that we didn't
implement the collapse
and so will implement a wall perform
their behavior itself
and that's how we get the automatic
behavior a pushing this photo view
of the navigation stack
now if we look in the other direction
we're expanding
arse but the controller we'll take a
look
at all %uh view controllers that are on
top the navigation stack
and any of them contain a photo will
return L
this also indicates to this that you
controller that we
wanted to perform its default behavior
here
so if we had a photo and we are
expanding
the net photo would automatically get
popped off navigation stack
and shine on the right if we didn't
contain any photo though
want to create are empty view controller
and that's how we re show that no
conversation view
when we're expanding
now let's take a look at how our
application moves between the
controllers
first will get the conversation to
controller
this is the one shown here when one of
our conversations
has multiple photos
if we look at the method think it's
called when we slept a table view cell
we create our new controller in the car
show detail view controller
on that new controller the show that on
the right
and thus that the controller if we're
expanded
and other mention it will push it on to
navigation stack
if we're collapsed without us having to
write any device-specific checks
in our code
we can also look and our list view
controller which has similar but
slightly more complicated behavior
and that's so that we can show a single
view controller immediately
if there's only one photo or this
conversation view controller
if there's more than one here
we check if for any given bro we should
show that conversation view
and if we're showing that conversation
view we created and you show you
controller
this method on always push on so that
you can
onto with navigation controller even
warmer expanded
and the two call India
on the other hand if we only have a
single photo will create that you
controller
a car show detail view controller which
gives us the same behavior
as we had in the conversation the
controller case
now one more thing the on notice in our
application
is that when we rotate to transition
between a single
and two column view this disclosure
indicators
are hiding and appearing missus to
maintain
the behavior it whenever tapping on a
row would push
we show with the disclosure indicator
and whenever it wouldn't
we don't show the disclosure indicator
so in a single
single column collapse you we push on
all on all of these
rose been the expanded view we only push
on these multiple conversations views
and we did that
by infant by adding our own category
Tulu controller implements two new
methods
well showing view controller push with
senator and will show in detail the
controller push with senator
these correspond to the show view
controller and show detail view control
methods that we talked about earlier
and they just return whether calling one
of those methods would cause a push to
occur
not which were used to determine whether
or not to show disclosure indicator
the way we implement the is is by using
the target view controller for action
method that we just talked about
we passin the same action
will showing the controller push with
senator and then we get back a target
the controller
that implements that method once we have
our target be controller
we just need to ask it whether it will
push or not
and if we don't have a target quarter
now
then we just need to override those
methods and navigation controller
to return yes that showing a view
controller here
will always push and will override it
since but you can't roller
to return I'll since here showing a view
controller
will show it in the left-hand column as
I mentioned earlier
now the behavior for will show in detail
view controller push
is slightly more complicated because
here we need to check if we're claps
first
Jennifer collapsed then what take our
current primary be controller
and will redirect the will showing
detail view controller method
to will show you control her and this is
the same
kinda behavior that sleepy controller
implements with show detail view
controller
so we've seen how those are implemented
let's look at how we used it
in a table view controller classes
here when we're laying out wanna
parcells will call
will show in detail view controller push
and that's because
the method that we would call when he
was tapped is show detail view
controller
will get back the result a whether or
not that action will push
and we said to set the accessory type:
either disclosure indicator
or none just how we get these
showing and hiding disclosure indicators
now
we also use I these methods to determine
whether or not to deflect a row
when it gets popped him and you can take
a look at the sample application
yourself
the fee that we have that works by using
the same will showing view controller
and will show in detail the controller
methods
the last thing I'd like to show you
is a new notification we had an Iowa
State you a view controller
show detail target did change
notification and this is important for
telling our
tableview when he needs to update its
disclosure abuse
this notification it's triggered by but
the controller whenever
the target they would have that would be
used for show detail view controller
changes
and this is when s but you controller
expands or collapses
so we use this notification
to go through all of our cells and
update their this their displeasure
indicators
that's all for our sample application
but I really encourage you to download
it from the
BBC website remember it's called
adaptive photos
and take a look at how and and plants
all these features
next I'd like to hang things over to
Tony the talk you
about some other changes we've made
Interface Builder for supporting
adaptivity
they take up high and Tony rich Rd
and I'm an engineer on the Interface
Builder team
Jacob just introduced a few new concepts
and I was a for developing adaptive you
eyes
such as size classes entry collections
now and show you guys a few new features
without a tax code to help you work with
these concepts
in Xcode 6 you can customize your layout
for multiple size classes
using a single interface builder
document means you can now target both
the iPhone and the iPad
with one story board or is it
you can deploy these documents backwards
to older versions via Wes
and you can preview your layout
for different devices Korean tations and
OS versions
all with an ex co now documents using
this feature will require Xcode six and
on a layout
so they won't be compatible with older
versions alexco let's head over tax code
and take a look
okay so here we have the storyboard for
an adventure game I've designed for the
iPad
today I want to extend the storyboard to
target the iPhone before get started let
me show you the app running in the
simulator
this is the main menu for my bench area
I love to have a few buttons that
control the content that shows up on the
right side
the play button takes you to this menu
for choosing your character which had to
be a warrior or image
the store button takes you to the store
page and the spine takes you to the
six-page
as you can see I've implemented issue I
using US what you control over here I
have my primary view controller with
those three buttons
Akira have my my
man character menu and down your I have
my
my store page in my settings page each
of these three buttons is connected to
one in the secondary view controllers
using airplay segue
i mean that that when you tap on those
buttons the secondary view controller is
going to your place
by the view controller that's connected
to that but
so as I mentioned today I want to enable
sigh I want to
extend the storyboard start the iPhone
and to do that I'm going to enable size
classes
I'm gonna head over to the file
inspector and check the you size classes
box
when I do that I get this dialog telling
me that my document is going to be
upgraded
upgrading will enable auto layout and it
will convert your segways to the new
adaptive segue types
if you do stores story boards before
you're familiar with the usual segue
types like push
mortal and replace that allow you to
display view controller when an event is
triggered
an expert 6 we've added some new Segway
types that correspond to the new queue
controller API to Jacob discussed
earlier
like show view controller and show
detail view controller
when you enable size classes why
medically upgrade your Segway so those
new types
so as you can see after enabled size
classes my view controller got resize to
this
480 by 480 square this way represent
sizes have any with
and any height so when you see the
square your edits were applied to
to all onto all size classes unless you
override your layout for a specific size
class
in my case I've already designed my
layout to work well for the iPad
and now I want to override my layout for
the iPhone
today I'm going to use this button at
the bottom of the campus well
this button I allows me to choose which
size classes and editing for
each of the squares in this three by
three grade represents a combination
oven with class and a high class
currently the middle square is selected
and Ike response to any with
in any heart when this were selected
you're editing your default layout
which is inherited by all the other
configurations
in the top left we have a square for
compact with in contact height
that corresponds to an iPhone in
landscape
in the bottom right we have a square for
regular with the regular height
which corresponds to an iPad
and in my case since I'm interested in
overriding my layout for an iPhone in
portrait
I'm going to head over to the bottom
left where I have a square for compact
with
and regular act
when I choose that square I made you
control it grows in a row and tall
to show me that are now editing for
contact with in regular height
also you might have noticed this part
the bar the campus turns blue to show me
I'm no longer editing for the default
layout
as you can see in this configuration my
image view and my buttons are getting
clipped
so this is gonna require public Texas
first I want to give my image viewer
smaller image
to use when the with this compact and
second I want to change those buns to be
stacked on top of each other vertically
rather than sitting side by side like
they are now
let's fix the image you first I'm gonna
head over to my ass a catalog using the
jump are
and then ima select my logo image set
and over to the inspector and appear
for the with that review I'm going to
choose any and compact
that gives me a couple have new on slots
here
the images that are put into the slots
are gonna be used at runtime instead of
my default
images whenever the with this compact
already have a couple images waiting
here in the Finder
so I'm just gonna drag those over
to add to the slots
okay nominee head back to the storyboard
and as you can see the image you has
been updated with a smaller image in its
no longer getting clipped
now sixties buttons I wanna start by
just selecting the buttons
so you can now take a look at their
constraints
for those of you who are unfamiliar with
auto layout and not gonna go into
too much detail and layout constraints
for this demo
I recommend checking out our session
from last year's conference
however I do want to point out that
there is a hidden view here between
these two buttons
and that you exists only to hold
constraints
it has a a couple constraints entering
in its container
and it has a few more constraints
pinning the buttons to it
the most importantly it has this with
constraint here
analyze me to control how far apart the
buttons are from each other
so fun ever want to move them farther
apart or closer together
I'll just leave it at that. with concern
however now that I want these buns to be
laid out vertically
I no longer need this view or any of its
constraints all the buttons together
so that the next thing to do is clear
the constraints by using this menu at
the bottom of the campus
and is gonna choose clear constraints
gonna do that
the the constraints disappear from the
campus
and you might wonder if that's gonna
cause my layout to stop working for the
iPad
however since I'm currently editing for
compact with the regular height
my edits will only apply to that
configuration if we take a look at the
outline view
I you can see that those constraints are
still there and my document
they just been turned off for the
current editing mode
ok it the next thing I do is remove this
view sense I no longer need it there to
hold the buttons
next to each other or is Ali so make
over to the attributes inspector
and down here at the bottom we have this
on this check box it says and stop
installed means that the view is present
in the view hierarchy at runtime
as a sub you have its container I want
this you to be installed
in all configurations except for compact
with the regular height
so I'm going to addict I mean use as
possible in here
data customization for compact with and
regular height
when I do that I get a new install
checkbox and when I unchecked that box
the view disappears and if we take
another look at the
at the outlined you over here you can
see that it's once again still there my
document press has been turned off for
defending
okay now I'm just gonna drag around
these buttons so that they're going to
be
laid out vertically I rather than
sitting side by side
okay then I'll select the buttons and
that label their and I'm gonna go back
to this menu in this time I'm gonna ask
Interface Builder to just give me some
suggested constraints for those views
okay at this point I could hit the wrong
button
and try this out on the iPhone simulator
but instead what I'm gonna do is show
you how you can preview your layout
directly with an ex co
so I'm going to go to the top and I'm
gonna
open the assistant editor
them ease the jump are to go over to the
preview assistant
and since I'm interested in proving
previewing for the iPhone
for engine portrait I mean users plus
button and use iPhone 4 inch
and there we go now I can see my layout
as it would appear on an iPhone portrait
if I wanna try it on a landscape I can
use this button here at the bottom of
the preview to rotate it
or if I wanna see both orientations at
the same time I can
use the plus button again to add another
preview
and now that lets me see both
orientations at once
as you can see in landscape the buttons
are are once again sitting out side by
side
and that's because we only changed our
layout for compact with the regular
height
an iPhone in landscape corresponds to
contact with contact height
and so those edits in the plot
just in case you didn't believe me now
actually run this in a similar
alright so I here we have my primary
view controller with those three buttons
as you can see it's now four screens
into running on a phone
when I tap the play button it takes me
to my character menu
and those buttons are are stacked
vertically just like we expected
and when I rotate they moved to sit side
by side
let's recap always on the demo first we
used auto layout
his to design a flexible you I that
works well for multiple size classes
for example my ImageView used a
horizontal center in constraint
to visit to position itself for both
contact with and regular with
next I show you how you can override sub
using constraints
for specific size classes when you need
to I did this to give my buttons a
vertical layout for iPhones and portrait
at rather and a separate layout for all
other cases
and finally I showed you a can preview
different devices and orientations OS
versions
even localizations all with an Xcode
using the preview assistant editor
today you saw a lot of new concepts for
developing adaptive UIs
Jacob introduce you to treat collections
in size classes which allow you to
modify your you why
in response to changes in size
he also introduce a new API that allows
you to decouple child view controllers
from their containers
and to collapse and expand US what you
controllers
finally I show you some new features
we've added to Interface Builder in
Xcode 6
if you'd like more information you can
contact our banja list sorry composed on
the developer form
we recommend checking out the other view
controller related sessions from this
year's conference
and will also be having an interface
builder session later this afternoon in
this room
and with that thank you and I hope you
enjoy developing adaptive you eyes I was
a