morning everybody thanks for coming
welcome to
creating X
shins for I O S and 80 S 10 part 2 I'm
damian
I'm from core OS and we apparently have
a user facing feature this year
so glad to see everybody is excited
about extensions let's dive right in
so before we talk about one extension as
let's talk a little bit about what in
out years and why
extensions are different so for now
it's still in iowa say even with
extensions
is the most important experience for the
user on I less the app
owns the entire screen on last 10 the
cursor focus goes the front most up this
is still
the number one priority for users and on
iowa's
aP's are completely managed by the user
via the App Store
and on the west and the user can drag
into the trash move them around
outs are entirely managed by the user so
about extensions
so extensions are important to the user
but they're not more important than the
current ap
they are there to augment the app's
experience and rather than directly
managing them
extensions common go with maps so the
user isn't going to be purchasing
or installing individual extensions
they're going to be
getting those extensions with the app's
that they download from the store
so extensions are built separately
they are separate target in Xcode so
what we have this new section
in Xcode for app extension template
targets so when you want to create an
extension
you're getting a new piece of code in
your app
that is actually a separate bond all and
admits
a separate execute a ble and with that
execute a ball
comes UConn a distinct set of
entitlements and we have
a separate excusable with its distinct
that entitlement Saunders
that allows the operating system to know
these two things
the app in the extension are different
entities
be and with that
weird get your getting a different
process so an extension
is running and isolated address space
from your route
and it executes completely independently
so this means that
the cistern even if your app is not
running
can still fire up your extension even if
you're up is suspended that doesn't
affect
and you have your extensions running for
the user
and because of this the system can
optimize each experience
separately so we can schedule them
and even if the app goes away your
extension
still sticks around so here's an example
love an extension and what the user
might do you
to invoke your extension and its you why
here we just have
a little a networks thing so it's and
new social networking app and its
bundling a social sharing extension
so we see it in the in the far right
there
with the purple icon and I go to the
site
and I want to share this with my friends
on my new social network
so the user we'll see and icon
representing my app
but what that means is that I'm going to
be using that the extension for social
sharing banded by that up
so in previous releases a iowa's
we've been we've been able to do this
but the Facebook and Twitter experiences
et cetera have all been provided by
Apple now we're letting
anyone who wants provide a social
sharing session not only provided but to
find their own experience
so in this case when user elects to
share
they're getting a window that is
designed by the
developer I love this social networking
app with
whatever experience you whatever
experience
that app developer wants to provide so
that's a high-level
love how a extensions are architected on
our system
let's talk a little bit about how we
actually
extend the experience %uh viewer app and
projected
into other parts of the system so as we
saw
yesterday in part 1 extensions are a
very focused
experience and the operating system
takes care of seamlessly merging the
experience that you provide
in your extension with the current ap or
just whatever the current
I system you why is
so you guys are gonna provide code
to make the experience your own and
thats
going almost certainly mean that you're
gonna want to reuse at least some love
the code for your app
so we hope you've been using the
model-view-controller paradigm
a features like extensions are exactly
why we
so desperately encourage you guys to
adopt this design pattern year after
year
because chances are with your extension
you're gonna wanna share
least the data model and probably some
%uh view controller layers to
you probably don't wanna share the view
if you're out because your app is
designed around
taking up the whole screen where is your
extension will not
but that's only one-third of your code
you don't want to have to rewrite
the entire two-thirds of it you wanna be
able to share code between the two
and if only computer science
head come up with a way to allow the
same code do exist
into processes without having to
duplicate those code pages
I think we might have a solution to this
and I think that solutions called
frameworks so
on iowa's im Iowa State
were now allowing you to ship frameworks
within your app on
don't get too excited so this is
obviously knew I owe us but we you've
been able to do this on OS 10 since the
dawn of time
on but it's a brand new capability the
tie less and what we're doing with that
is work also
encrypting the frameworks that you ship
in your app on bull
with the same I have encryption that
your caps
are are gifted with to give you that
same level of protection against piracy
and up well piracy
heard on so
its critical to note that these
frameworks are not
general share code sharing mechanism so
you're not going to have
many ups on the system referencing the
same popular framework
these frameworks are here to see
facilitate
sharing between ap and all its
extensions
so the code that that frame live code
that former contains
can be used by the app or any the
extensions upon dole's
but nothing else on the system so when
you use
of when you bundle a framework with your
app there are some implications for your
minimum deployment target
if you're ap links the framework
we're going to change its minimum
employment targets Iowa State because as
I said before
were in cryptic these frameworks in
previous versions of the operating
system
don't know about how did deak rip them
when you use them
however if you're just chipping your app
and then there's a few extensions you
have the all link in a framework
your aP's minimum deployment target
doesn't change at all
your extension functionality obviously
won't be available to previous versions
%uh I O S but the Apple still be able to
run without any problems
so that's a very brief
overview love embedded remarks on iowa's
to learn more I encourage you to go to
the session tomorrow at 3:15 in person
do.
building modern frameworks be where
will cover API usage how did
write a good framework how to bundle it
all that good stuff
but for now you got frameworks and it
seems like you guys are excited about
so
another cup topic for code sharing is
API availability
if you're writing one of these
frameworks sorry for bowling or these
frameworks
what code are you going to be are using
between your app
and your extension so
the vast majority of our API is going to
be available for extensions to use
but there are going to be some
exceptions and these exceptions are
going to be marked
explicitly with a new kinda
unavailability macro
and here's an example what that looks
like
so UI application
very with your application the shared
application method has been explicitly
marked as unavailable
I and you like it folks have helpfully
provided
and error message that says use a view
controller based solution where
appropriate I'm Inc or less
no idea what that means but I'm sure you
guys have an idea now if you're
dropping down to Super League API that
has underscores
there's going to be a corresponding X
availability macro there that is
evaluated the same way
by the tools and will generate the same
errors at build time
so that's are unavailability
like a certain vast majority of cases
you probably won't need to worry about
it
but if you if you do trip across an API
use
in your extension that is not allowed
you'll know as soon as possible
at build time before you can even run
the extension so I'll tell you share
code
with your extension and your app but at
runtime
you're gonna wanna create a consistent
experience to
and a consistent experience
often means sharing the same set
resources
and making sure that changes the user
has made to their data
in your extension are reflected in the
app the next time they see it
or vice versa so we have a few data
sharing solutions for you for extensions
so the first thing I understand is that
an extension
has a separate container from its ap by
default
on it's just like how to APs are
segregated from each other they don't
have access to each other's data
but for any extension you bundle you can
up to share specific bits of data
that will help you provoke provide a
consistent experience that
all of our users expect
and you can do this with what's called a
shared container
so this is based on a new a
a new concept called in ap group and
this provides a shared storage area for
kind of just general
datum sharing between your app in your
extension so if you have some custom
data models are custom databases that
you're wrapping extension need to use
this is a good place to put those files
and access them
however you have to remember that
there's nothing stopping
I your extension and your ap from
running at the same time
you're out maybe in a long-running
background task it may not have been
suspended yet
and it might be you writing some a some
data to that shared container
and then user might bring up your
extension so what this means is that you
have to make sure to safely coordinate
all the reads and writes those files you
have to make sure that you only write to
the file
when there are no readers contending for
it and that you're only reading when
the files in a consistent state
otherwise you're going to blow up your
file sports is gonna get corrupted
so we introduce some sort of
synchronization scheme here
so that if the extension rights hold of
the APN if the uprights hold of the
extension
and they're all both dealing with a
consistent view of the universe
in here a few those technologies
the first one is an ass file
coordination which kinda provides a
general
inner process synchronization strategy
four-year extension and
free extension and your app on if you're
using Core Data
you could get a lot of this for free
there'd certain core data dot
backing stores that are documented as
being called as being usable for
multiple processes at the same time
and sequel light also make some of these
guarantees
so if you're using on those who
technologies chances are you're already
set
but if you have something more custom
you're going to want to use in a small
coordination
but if you're talking about I more
structured data that
is save ended by Apple's API's like and
its user defaults
you can end up sharing much more easily
so
an app in its extension both have
different defaults domains
but you can set up a share domain with
peace
in it with sweet name API and you create
the sweet
and the API manages access to it for
your app
and your extension so you don't have to
worry about up
making sure that you're not writing to
that backing store when someone else is
trying to read from it
API coordinates all about for you and
this is a really easy way
for say the user to modify some setting
in the app
which then the extension can pick up on
its next
under sex invocation
there's a similar story for key chains
so the shared key chain
is based on an app group and the app
group
is up can encompass
a few aP's as well as your extensions on
so by default by they said the extension
the app have a different key chain
but you can set up a shared key chain
with an Access Group
a there's up there's an issue right now
in the first beta
where this is actually team id-based so
if you're familiar with that were you
prefix urban blight on a fire with the
team ID
in order to facilitate sharing that's
how you do it in the first scene
we're going to fix the supper at group
and by the time we ship
so I'm terms & privacy it's a slightly
different story
when I say privacy i mean the dialogue
comes up
when an app is trying to access certain
sensitive user data like
photos are Contax you'll get a dialogue
saying would you like to allow this out
to have access to this piece of data
and user commuter decline or allow
so when user allows your apt to have
access to a certain piece of data
its actually going to cover the the
entirety of your up on dole
including extensions so that the user
once they've approved your
ap for access your photos they don't
have to then go and approve all your
extensions for access to the same data
now there are going to be some
extensions this purpose are some
exceptions to this rule
but in general the the rule is
that approval covers the entirety love
your app
so let's go over back best practices a
little bit
as we said at the beginning the front
most out the still not the most
important thing
so it's very important that your
exceptions be lean
these things do not have the whole run
up the system like the Upstate like the
aptos the up still there
it's still using lines share system
resources extensions
are very focused very purpose built and
it's important they get in do their job
and get out and be stateless
you might know that we kill ap
successively or suspend them on iowa's
were doubling down on out extensions and
we're going to be more aggressive
and because of this there is no general
multitasking functionality available to
extensions
so no VoIP a no long-running background
tasks like anything
we do support a short ass completion
before we suspend or kill the extension
but this is meant to give you time to
flush
any dirty state to desk so that the user
doesn't lose their data and so that the
app can pick that up
and finally be awesome make these things
seamless
make them useful to our users and
as a user UHV your products I can't wait
to be surprised and delighted by what
you guys turn out
with that I'd like to turn it over to
hockey
computer into them part I'm a key you
know went from poker group
today I'm discussion and exciting new
feature
action extensions 400 s and were stabbed
yesterday
improper Kwame Ian mad got introduced
extensions and two extensions point
along with
key technologies such as mobile
controller and
a crucial walls Damien explain
foundational technologies for extensions
action
isn't extension point that utilizes and
integrates
all these based technologies let's get
started
hope so action
is the spiritual successor to services
%uh interpretation collaboration
technology available sister
first rulings up always tender action
operates with use a selection inside the
host reputation
got is it
extends the system freemen not just a
single produced for serbs
hurry in this conference
you have seen won the action Accenture's
mock operating inside me a pretty Asian
on your sanity impact this
extension is available to image
apartment
throughout the system like that
died into the details just like any
other extensions options are described
by
new populist first
inside and this extension dictionary
its identified by enough extension
point identify you com up online
services
next and if extension
we spoke last spy the man contour
of for you extension just like
gone him mad described yesterday its
typically a top-class Habib Yukon were
new control arm saw
now the
press spoke last is the main control for
you extension
as well past the pine to the extensional
APR of we've
a new view controller property cold
extension
packs you tend to and thus extension
complex up sir
which represents commercial too haha
petition through that
into after look out for some ary
car in this extension items each I think
we present them
a lot colder than you need coming back
for coming from the host application
n
you to touch on third beer
to that specialized in
moved in image warns
so also force the bitter is campaign
fly object called in this I think
provider okay let's back to the populist
inside the substantial happiness the gym
which spines exons
for specific atoms you the player
in this excision were also ordered
essential so small pipe
and some editor or viewer
in this example we are using in this
extension service wall type
editor that means its only presented
to the context where the document easy
editable
X hours
sure extensions you Casper spot at
special rules
with in the stock extension up special
rules
the term and this pretty fortify your
string
or the list up support the beer cups
now
let's to go now let's look at core
samples
Press new tender extension compact
through the
extend some context property next
you can dead excess of item
to item input items property future
returns
the ary are excisional items
finally you can get a touch
theater using about men's Propet and
its companion the in this I can provide
art
once you have in the fight and provider
you don't low bidder from haha petition
it's a lazy and secure using law-abiding
for Clyde
has been fun yeah options accomplishment
number and sparse
spike YouTube part hope your choice
in the States we are using a custom
bitter type my government UTI
and
use BestBuy hot representation
but the road numeracy in this case we
Art Museum and this
fear and it companions but custom data
former has the those not make UTI
once you have the bitter
new concept %uh use that nothing's
according to the beer
coming from the host application
yes with action
unlike she extensions its possible
her extension to return someone for a
beer
you see more up change in I'm watching
up
got image in place returned to the
mil-dot extension can perform the same
old thing
when user click
saddam Barack or similar action
new temp fall
them return under from modified beer box
either
or substitution the process is reber's
hard loading the bidder coming from
possibly tation
first
first UN instantiated in this I can
provide
will be appearing and it up
max you can create in a sec central
Aiken
and Apache or I can provide
finally you don't saying complete
request
written by dickens completion handler
to you exceptional i-ten we're I'm
array up excision items
this hot saree from cruise you extension
life cycle so
carry you wanna return you a bitter
and conclude your any you what operation
at this point
I like and opportunism yuup yuup I
you don't have to return any beer
back to the horse %uh petition
saw the PureView opportunism
just like share extensions
you gotten ball complete regress
returning items completion handler
with new art
so far I have Hubbard how to ride
haha extensions now
let me explain how you interact you can
read
extensions into your all applications
on I O S
you ought to be the new controller
drives both social and share
and action extensions
does she controlled by the view
controller
term in bowl admonish extensions for you
you what the PI wise there's not much
difference
for you acted view controller from the
previous moves
you still ustasha the new controller
with us like that
items from the user and up
you control it takes over and present
she an while
want the house met with how all for I
quest K
it's a sport fall editor
passions
we had at the new property cold
completion with I can humbler
to you agree control top
you at give you control with this method
they've gotten ball option his endanger
and wants to return bottom who could
risky the result and return items
away 10
you don't replace your docking comp
based on the weekend items
in the pics view
well ahead anybody
know in the audience I just can't help
talk about taxes every year
him what way or the other on west then
in a stick to view planes the central
and presenting extensions to the user's
by hopper on popup extension
course my homered extension on popup
pics
selection or image attachments the
president's
does this president Bob when menu
listening all the extensions available
for the complex
night I have with them a simple little
extension force them and unlike the
shoal
how yosemite present you extensions to
the user
I her attended bottom complains
ball path and beamish
my homeroom most crucial
on pot are tax
selection you can reveal the list are
extension supporting the pics beer
similarly by homering on pop are
attachments you can show all the list
are extension support them images in
this day's
admission to to sample extension I wrote
party pressure
the miss mock-up affected application
so you can see the mock up is from
extension
duck walks not just in mail but any
other pics view
inside the system so
let me explain this little extension
hold party crasher
just what many on you I like em out with
people
and in a by some pictures like this
I feel will crandall left out
soul with this extension
I can had my picturing
any manager pac-10
a good for sure so let's keep andar
change its save in the document
also the
is another way to BOC action extensions
on course to
hai hum 15 this tax credit application
by the way to treat the competition
he's a cool some property Sean Paul coca
publication so you can modify any way
you want
and my room to be stuff about Coco
with this texted a British aversion
picture that
a petition gun show
two more and other little sleep in the
toolbar
extension to ready still themselves
house to my eye 10 and can be shown
week any two more inside the system
and the house from is applied to the
crime selected
arms it can be tax what you make it so
on so forth
so let's in both the party pressure
full that selection
it opinions a missus XO two-mile
law to parten dude any pics election
in the system
Optionee are you can see
excision is action-adventure is so
powerful
you don't right simple extension are
like yes or you can still
up to are soft did art smock
the sky is just lemme I have them said
with them all have the most read
extensions fan support
what could be a apps
it is common that you wanna support as
in many been approached
has you warm more than a text you
support
its easier all users walk review
extensions
let's take a look up how you can change
your behavior
be based on that input data come from
the horse optician
in the city's first we will not share
if it's a tax bill type coming from the
host application
we use that kaup pipe tax
UTI type and it campaigns
men pics uniform
with hot item conform to cut identify a
method for lighting provider
you can check 50 I can provide up
against the Turks
here
once you make sure you damn
lolol the bigger is a lot I can for
part-time
identify your options completion handler
use in the real representation type of
your choice
since I can provide their house simple
Iraq war zone for certain
the time mad some did
to the party object data part
you specify in the States we use 'em in
if a QB the string
want you probably have been
set up user setup use and abuse
according to it
scenery if you are that's the rupture
fail you can check 40 million here
after chatting if its image you don't
know all the emails
and ass I mention I don't provide the
time course
world in a pipe into you like image what
tenth
image for you 10 if you happiness
on the year using doctors for huge
full all listed butts
common the new extensions using a prince
doesn't cover
Empire haha petitions window
just like more crap good girl new one
overall you is a you are using a piece
on pop up to
we're sorry presentation haha some
petition
is easy to accomplish
we have a national problem for in this
item provider
on Western
it's called source frame companions the
screen called me
for the original representation inside
the host a petition
if you did top rack
information and if it's not empty
hookah I just the frame according to
user interface needs
you might wanna have some additional
frame around or is that representations
of bite marks
are or party pressured us
don't set up to them in this new control
problems
prefers from orange and for fruit
contents of I loosely with my
presentation listen prefer Compton size
is sheer between stop
to build new Weezer an action extension
by thirty abuse problems got
new control system pics or more and
computer
your extends from using an apparent
former lead on top
are the
or is a ribbon or is only been in place
on in the horse competition
now and what to bring my colleague
the MB who's gonna be discussed some
really really kuwaiti to integrated
interrupted way I'm actions
here
thank you are
so I can show you how to create a custom
action evening show no estan
in today I'm going to show you how to
build a safari custom action
or how to take your custom action and
enhance it for the web
we think you guys are really gonna love
this feature so first you can see our
custom action in the bottom row
the activity view controller as I showed
you yesterday in the part one of this
talk
and it's called tiny scratch
it can't do everything as Big Brother
market can do but I can still pack a
punch
so first diving and
Safari custom actions its rich new
functionality in Safari on iowa's
it gives you access to the DOM
and there are two types its custom
actions
a view controller based custom action
the kind I'm going to show you today
and there is a no view action like the
Bing translate action
that Craig showed you in the keynote how
do these work
we use in javascript yours tension will
provide
JavaScript along in its resources
and safari is going to find this cell
here's what is JavaScript is going to
look like we're going to expect you to
provide
a preprocessing JavaScript object and
this object is going to have
two methods a run method and finalize
method
we're going to start by calling the run
method and give you access to the DOM
and what you're going to be expected to
do in this run method is to you
with to call the action arguments
completion function
passing the data you want to provide to
the custom action
when you're done and
when the action has completed when the
computation inside your
our custom action extension has finished
were again going to call your javascript
and this time we're going to cut invoke
the finalize method
and pass the action arguments the as you
can see in this case
word is calling alert and showing a
message which was provided
were the most important things for you
to remember
is this global variable extension
preprocessing JavaScript this is going
to be in instance if you're object that
provides these methods
to Safari and I think that should be
burned into your mind
because if you don't provide this we're
not going to be able to
invoke your javascript and nothing's
going to show up inside your action
so it civil
really easy to talk about these things
but it's far better to show it
so I'm going to show you a demo of tiny
scratch moving right and
let's build and run and see we've got so
what I've done here's I built a very
small
test application called tiny scratch
which contains my tiny sketch
custom action this is a good way to get
started
even might know why died immediately in
creating an extension for Safari
because there are a lot of moving parts
and it's a lot better to build it up in
pieces when you can
as you can see we don't have anything
here yet we don't actually have any data
and I action but is not wired up let's
go ahead and do that
going back to Xcode on
tiny sketch support is our new support
framework is Damien was talking about
embedded frameworks
earlier we're going to going toward a
model and because our application and
our extension may want to use the same
data model
reaction when provide the accessor to
the resources here
like this this is going to iterate
through the image earl's
in my on in my custom extensions
documents folder
well and support for their
and it will go back to the apt actually
wire up support for
imputed load get pictures and keep kids
except the indentation
and will build and run again and this
time
you'll see some pictures on my children
usually enjoying a day at the park or
its cool or or doing something else it
reset on this
Africa 374 we can tap on any these
images
and in they go you can see right there
tap on any of them it's really cool
art kept the custom action button
nothing comes up
well that's because we have a wide it up
yet is our key was telling you earlier
we need to set up to you I activity view
controller to provide data
to the extension so let's go do that
going going to our share method and
we're going to add some more comps
saying up to you I actively view
controller
as you can see it's are key talked about
earlier we're creating an activity item
using are selected image URL
and now we're going to add some code
we were just configuring the activity
item as we go as architect about earlier
notes we're adding a little bit more
code
to actually deal with receiving the data
items right here
we're going to take a look and make sure
that we were successful we're going to
count the number of items
and we're going to grab the item
provider which is provided to us
by the custom action and then we're
going to take the image
and save it back into our image
collection
and then we're going to read display
that image inside the collection you
now finally now that we have the
activity view controller completely
configured we're going to presented so
let's build and run this time we ought
to be able to tap on the
picture the key kids at least I think
you're cute tap on the action
I am and now we can see our custom
action
right here if we tap it becomes
it doesn't do much yet because while
we're providing the data to it
we haven't actually added any code to
consume that data
inside the action let's go do that now
going into our tiny sketch action which
is our target containing the
custom action and we're going to go down
to view did work which is where we
should consume the extension item
to add something to pull the extent the
input item from the extension context
and we're going to grab the first image
item provider
and we're going to make sure that it has
an item conform to our type identifiers
have a type image and iraq's going to
let that image
and with the magic have NS item provider
we're going to it's going to be coerced
from a URL
into an item automatically for you we
actually take a look at the signature
these block parameters and perform all
the coercion is behind the scenes for
you
I thought that was cool never going to
take the item
we're going to assign it to our image
property so we can hold on to it and
we're also going to show it
in our image you once we're done with it
scrolling past we're going to need to be
able to take this data
and send it back to the host testing
application so what's
set that up we're going to create an
extension item
going to check that we're not heading
for the web that will come later
ever going to attach the newly created
I'd
image that flattened image image
containing all the adornments
in to the extension item using and as
item provider this time we're just we're
not going to spy URL but we're going to
supplying
image and then as hockey talked about
earlier
we're going to finish the request by
calling complete request returning item
and passing the extension item as
building run
and what's
at it
pulling up annotating the image
and you can see we actually have data
flying across the wire
we can dismiss
and the data goes back I wasn't all that
interesting because I didn't actually
making and it's all making at this time
put a inappropriate
labeling here in the speech bubble
having fun at the park
it done and you'll notice now are image
has been replaced
the data has made it back from our
custom extension clark asked application
and we have ground trapped a custom
action
on iowa's now while this is cool I'm
really here to show you
about how this works can work with
Safari and the web
so let's go ahead and enhances custom
action to actually pull its data
out about live Dom and then replace the
data in that dominates done
let's do that now went back
stop and now
on you may have seen some on my notes
earlier about adding web support
we're going to scroll back up
and this time we're going to add
in else condition to receive the URL
from Safari
notice we're going to have an else and
if we have an item conforming to type
identifiers
Kuti property list this is important
because we're going to be sending a
dictionary
we're going to unpacked image URL
out at this dictionary also said I will
say editing for web black TS
and then we're setting up at NS URL
session download task to actually
perform the down
if the download succeeds we unpacked the
image data
and render it into you I image again
stashing image away
your property and assigning to the
ImageView if you're unable to download
walk in and ask blog not the other side
that
and done when we're done
editing the image we need to pack it
back into a property west
and I've got some code to do that here
you'll see that we're going to you
take that flattened image and write out
a temporary file
here and then we're going to actually
create a che peg string up that
and packed that into a web dictionary
basically creating a data URL
that Safari can then swap back into the
DOM so
everything's wired up there what's going
to our JavaScript
as I talked about earlier we are
expected to provide the run
and finalize functions let's do that now
run
we're going to on iterate over all the
images in the DOM
and we're going to send them over in the
image url: ski
to the custom action and we're also
going to send the base your eye
our custom action is only going to
consume the first image but you know
this is written for growth
and finally
with the data comes back from the custom
action we're going to replace the image
by taking that encoded data URL and
shoving it into the image using your
replacing the image source: property
save
building run outcomes our application we
know this works
at home out and let's go to Safari
I happen to have a web server running
local host
with the picture again in my kids just
hanging out at the park
let's see if we can edit this image
hitting annotate image
up slides a custom action
with the data from Safari now it's added
provide an appropriate speech bubble
get done and now you can see
there's a live replacement the data
right there
in Safari using the JavaScript that I
showed you
cell Safari custom actions
as you just saw provide the flexibility
the web married to the power extensions
you can transform Web data it's really
really easily
and you can float a native interface
right over the top with it which allows
you to create he's rich workflows that
were
unimaginable in previous releases says
Damien talked about
extensions are secured by default
they don't share data unless you tell
them to: and their
want to have a one to one correspondence
with the hosting ap
that way you have your own address space
in which to
make your man make your mistakes in your
reaction and the last thing we really
want to encourage you to do is just to
have fun with this feature
and that don't think about is sticking
new things on to things like particles
think a bit is constructing these
awesome new workflows that were you're
really unable to explore
before now for more information
you can talk to the man in plaid Jake
parents or
I'd urge you to read our excellent
documentation the app extension program
and I
at a developer dot Apple dot com if
you've never been to the Apple developer
forums
you can interact with employees like
myself hockey and Damien there
and provide peer to peer support thank
you for coming
burned out at camp and we can't wait to
see what you guys do with the feature
thank you