everybody good morning my name is Rachel
Roth then
I'm wanna Apple's user experience
evangelists
now the SSN is not
about monetizing about having
a great experience with an aperture says
because a great experience is what's
going to keep people coming back here
after game
time and time and time again thing about
the last time you had a really fantastic
me on a great restaurant
for its price you always want to come
back to write
for this is the bigger picture
have what it takes to have a great
experience with an aperture says and
today fashion is all based on the
assumption
that you already have a really amazing
ap
our game your app meets the needs of
your ID and
it's got a really intuitive interfaces
I'm
executed really well for game it's just
fun to play
an earth really know design secrets are
shortcuts around a fun
but I know that you guys all have a
handoff so we don't have to do well on
that for too long
now if you're using the free me mr. the
pay me a model with an app purchase
fares its so important that people can
enjoy our game without buying anything
I mean I think most of us are happy
experience you
get a new app from the App Store and you
download it launch it
only to find that you can't do anything
with it that's frustrating
need to make a purchase in order to get
from you carry out a bit
would be like if you bought mixer
for your kitchen and it didn't come with
any attachments you can miss any
mix anything be really disappointing
not fly mixers come with the basic
attachment that you can use said nixon
see how great the mixer and
and many by some additional attachments
for specialty
tasks like making bratter some kinda
pastry
and that's where you want it she with
your axe you wanna let people really
enjoyed the functionality and utility
quality a wrap and then you offer them
advantages or
additional functionality them advanced
features
when you offer those things you wanna
make sure that you make buying easy
I know this probably sounds obvious but
I'm not just talking about
sending a transaction for the App Store
getting a response back
you want to make sure that the decision
to buy something
is really easy for the people coming
here after game
there's a lot of friction to making that
decision to buy
and a lot of it if outside your control
but as app developers you wanna
eliminate
any obstacle to making that decision to
purchase something
inside iraq make easiest possible
that decision to buy that fleeting
moment and there's
many traps so one of the best things
that you can do
its integrate your merchandise and the
experience many people are gonna buy
things if they don't know what you're
offering
they can't see them talks a lot of
developers to
create a really great store section
insider there after game and then
they're really disappointed because no
one's going there
not buying anything ask if people know
what you're offering
kinda like a difference if I fad you
wanna buy something
fad how much like a really great drawing
tool
and and that's what you want to help
explain with a rap by putting the
merchandise out on display
integrating it into the experience when
you're doing that
I'm not suggesting that you become a
pretty self percent
about an nobody wants the sky following
them around
saying hey you wanna buy something hey
hey hey you wanna buy something
do you want to buy something to you want
to buy something every minute and that's
where you're risking if you're flashing
a lot of alert for notifications are
crazy animations to try and high-speed
contracts or
it's really about timing
and with some ap stats about
offering the right thing at the right
time like at a restaurant when the
waiter brings you
the dessert menu at the end of the mail
I mean you may not even want to for
right back it doesn't property that they
offered it
it would feel percy if they offered it
to you before he sat down
and why reading your appetizer
fear I think about what's the right
moment to offer something to someone
and do it in a way that's really
thoughtful
now with other absence about a
presentation
you I think about a really great window
display first store
I happened to be very partial to the
Apple Retail window display
sure I'll come as no surprise to you
guys
now they do a great job showing off the
merchandise and Ron you ran
makes you want to find out more about
the product really intriguing
and that's what you want to think about
whether after your game
you wanna integrate the merchandise in a
way that feels really natural
missus paper by 53 it's an Apple Design
Award winner from years ago
that is still a fantastic example
integrating
in app purchases into their experience
have you ever used at
app is designed to capture ideas through
scat shares and diagrams and no
and like that makes Turner catch and
they give you some basic drawing tools
for free
your pen and eraser you can see from
this example you can do to hands with it
but there may be occasions when you need
a more advanced trying for a different
kind of
liner texture and so that's why these
leave these empty spots here
where the restaurant Ross ago and that's
like that window display in a store
its putting them out for you see there's
no question what's available
what they didn't dare and Hyde
everything an art supply store
or attacking a pencil case but then you
to go push open to see what's available
that's creating friction at expecting
the player that
your audience to do work to see what
there
and another thing that they didn't do
its trick you into thinking that you
already own Dhabi
of because if you could see them all
then when you tap don't want to use it
it holds you the you paid money just to
test out a brass
well that would be disappointing at nog
that sa great experience
frustrating on and that's why this
design is
so al again and so great it's
informative
but it's not percy
known except let's look at that timing I
mentioned earlier totally different
kinda crap
Bloomberg Businessweek and this is a
business publication i has regular
updates
new content and without a subscription
you can still browse
read several articles browse all the
headlines in the introductory census
now if you tap on something that
requires a subscription
they bring up the subscription options
fight the dessert menu
you're interested in reading some other
content cell here
here's the information about
subscription see you can get it
for preventing it right at that perfect
moment
they're making it easy for you to get
the subscription
now they also have this subscribe button
down here in the corner
every screen and that's great you
but having that in addition to the
integrated method
have some reach more people for nothing
you can't have a store section
you just don't wanna make it up only
place that people can find
what you're offering
now this also works for games I don't
know how many have you played smash at
its relief an arcade game that involves
smashing things
as you might have guessed very
satisfying after a long day
the way that it works is back at the
arcade game and the more accurate you
are smashing things
the further you're gonna get you
progress through the checkpoints and
mocking them
and they also offer premium percent and
they have a great way of illustrating
exactly what that
via featured as 30 I'll
so here we are let's start from
checkpoint here maybe I can get a little
bit further this time
it good
avatar for pars the pre members and I'm
not ready to buy it
wide
pretty compelling right I mean if you
had any doubt about what advantage is
that they're offering
that spells it out for you right away
now I don't know how many have you
noticed that there's also this get
premium button here in the corner
and if you did would you guess that's
what the pre members and Matt
I mean summer view might have might have
tapped on its fine out and and family
may not have
and they have the details here about
what you get
but having this in addition to that
integrated math said
it's just much more fact there
explaining what the featured ads for you
an offering it to you at the time that
you can use that
23 member don't be that guy
nobody wants some one person in your
face
hectoring pestering people have not
going to get the results that you want
but powerful integration the merchandise
well
now another challenge is to help people
understand the value why you're offering
and FB if you walk into a clothing store
this is easy to figure out
you can touch the merchandise feel feel
with the fabric feels like
the filler luxurious for viagra cheap
the well-made seems following part
most importantly doesn't fit you look
good is it gonna see your purpose there
so letting people try all merchandise
before they buy it is a really effective
way
helping them understand the quality and
the value
and utility what you're offering
me when buy a car without taking it for
a test drive first
right the same principle
letting people use that will be the best
way for them to understand
how often they are again paper by 53
does a great job with that
in addition to providing a lot of FAM
Paul about that
what the tools are capable %ah they put
together an entire Journal
made by their staff showing of the
different tools in their capabilities
and of course they let you use the tools
the basic tools for free
every you have to use this topic and how
you patrols respond beautifully to your
finger
now me telling you that isn't nearly as
effective as you actually using the app
and so that's why
when you go to find out about these
advanced drawing tools they let you test
out right there
you've got the sketch pads along with
detailed information
and testing them out as is how you can
determine the quality and the utility
work i text Saturday provide how their
acts your finger when you're trying
which one is going to be right for what
you're trying to achieve
and each of the sketchpad have strong
already in progress
kinda like a test drive where they
taking on certain roads to show you how
well the car handles
paper by fifty three-a setting up the
sketch pads to show you
optimal use their service and suggested
uses for this trough
it runs great watercolors they've set up
a watercolor trying for you so then
you can jump and then an ad on earth try
your own drinks
and it might seem obvious to take this
approach for drying trough but I promise
that will work for almost
any controversial ban here's a really
different example on that line
that it's a popular messaging app you
can send and receive messages for free
now one of the things that
differentiates line from its competitors
is the vast array of stickers but they
offer
figures are kinda like really crazy
emoji
you can include in your messages and
send it back for their frantic
it gives your your text messages home
life
now line gives you a very generous fax
and have the stickers for free
you can't right now plus the ability to
earn
sicker without paying anything are you
have to do with that Hello Kitty is a
friends and then you get Hello Kitty
stickers
some people love Hello Kitty stickers
sir
and using them really helps me
understand how great they are
now another thing that they offer our
beam and when I first investigative
teams I'll be honest I have no idea what
extraction
I thought oh great are some free ones
let me try out the brown bear
have see what happened here so when you
choose the brown bear
theme and forgetting the standard you
are you can
bears her a everywhere all over the
propane
even the tab bar icon for rare
now sure they can refer to description
what if the man is there even a
screenshot but that wouldn't have been
nearly as effective at combating
what happens when you use the theme
giving preview of some free ones to try
out of the bath way
to really understand what they're all
about
and that's worked for publication to
anyone have any question about where to
get the free preview content
on the screen they've made it really
easy for everybody
Esquire magazine wants to make sure that
you now
that reading their content on an iPad is
the bath experience
of law and so they give you free free
content
check out it's got videos interactivity
and this is the equivalent to standing
in line at the store and flipping
through a magazine or
going to comic store in checking out
artwork
I have to really know whether the
reading experience is going to be good
and whether the contents going to be
something that you're interested in
and again this also works for games
now I'm pretty sure that everyone in
this room have played candy crush saga
at some point but for the two Vera
haven't it's a puzzle game
and and Bay they've done OK with an app
purchases
you know and tho what they do at the
beginning of every levels that they
offer you these boosters
and these losers give you a leg up on
completing the task
and they become much more valuable that
the harder the puzzle ass
nephew never use on you can just ignore
them go for that big pin play button and
endurance for puzzle game
so that's why they introduced the day we
do sir we are
every day you can come and get one of
their booster
for free so there is nothing at standing
in the way
you trying them out and once you try
them out you really know what a
difference that they can make
so that's what I mean about offering a
test drive
letting someone really experienced that
merchandise trying it out before they
buy
is the best way to communicate the value
and the youthfulness
and the quality and that's why it's
gonna make them
decision to buy something easier on
people
now another way to reduce the friction
to buying as to
sick with your theme it's really
important that every screen in your ass
or your game
is cohesive and you want to carry that
visual design all the way through
that interaction model needs to be
consistent
and you wanna put as much effort and
time and designing the screams as you
anything else in your app for your game
so this is Russell adventure and it's
got hundreds level the puzzle games and
all these various
see more of you start out in the 4s
any work for the different puzzles in
the fourth to get to
other lands now every aspect of the
forest
looks like the forests they've got
doesn't matter the objective of the game
you can see the fourth details creeping
in at every corner
now there in our purchases involved in
our currency
which you can use sedan by advantages
for the different level of powerful beer
and you can earn in our currency as
you're playing but you can of course
make an aperture further and a current
fame
so imagine you're up against Chief
smarty pants here and he's tough
so it might be worth getting some in our
currency so that you can
so that go buy some in our current be
seen it from his ministers
so mad then you're excited you want to
be chief smarty pants
that the next thing you thought was best
it would be terrible right having family
there's that
entirely different you either you have
to understand
you to think about it its release
sterile looking
not very well laid out stage right now
the experience how the forest anymore
and that creates friction makes it feel
more like work
that's making it harder to buy something
now
thank for a travel ban sir does not do
that I
they have a nice fourth fame purchasing
experience than all the
visual design and enter access concerts
at everything else in the game
so make sure that you maintain the world
love your game or the look at your apt
on
everything else crane and with
everything ok control
because many families snatch people I
know that we're all
and they have to deal with the new
interface our new look it's gonna feel
like work
and from the heart and buying we want it
to be easy right
add to the word of warning while you are
busy sticking with your theme
don't take it so far that language
becomes confusing
you want to make sure that people can
really understand exactly where they're
gonna be getting for their money
use clear language now I have you guys
ever seen a description for an apartment
or house that said something like
needs a little work and many show up in
its
now looks more like this
I think we've all had it for him now
with any purchase that so important to
be honest
at there's really a fine line between
try to be positive about something
highlighting the features and really
being
overly optimistic about why you're
selling nobody
nobody wants to be disappointed when
they see what the merchandise actually
yes
and especially when you're coming to
subscription Anzar
recurring contact you want to be as
specific as possible
set people's expectations crackling
when are they gonna get new content how
much content are they getting for the
price
maybe 25 something like this you know
now is that ok sam se
or is it a bargain I mean if its 12
issues than a year
less than a dollar an issue that that's
pretty reasonable right
points here issues as well
I don't now in fact content really worth
that much money me and see now I'm of
thinking about whether or not this is a
purchase I wanna make
and set up quickly coming to a decision
getting the new contact going off to
enjoy it
because that's what I've come to an apt
to do come to enjoy contact have come to
nap to help me achieve
happening Jamie Oliver does a much
better job with Beth
I he's a famous staff and he has a
recipes app
and you'll see here that here they'd let
you know that new contact is coming on
the FAC and Wednesday
every month crystal-clear
very a setback I know exactly went
extracting
fit star is a personal training
application
and they have a number workout and their
tailored to your goals and also your
actual
performance now they're subscription
screen gives you
detailed outline some of the programs I
mean
you can find out the length of the
workout you want something short
do you want something long they're
offering bout for that
the advantages them are you interested
in fat burner
are trying to do strength training
they've even point out which one is
recommended for me based on a couple
questions I answered earlier
and when you're ready to buy not from
scripts am
that screen is so clear about exactly
what you're going to be getting
I love the program's unlimited free down
there
maybe even highlighted the annual
subscription with a discount
they've made it so easy just through the
use of clear language
for me to make a decision about buying
something
and now I really understand what I'm
going for my money and I can appreciate
it
now another way that you can make this
clear to your audience is to
do the math for them I don't like doing
math
that's not that's not fun for me don't
make me do the math
it's your job as the app developer make
it easy on people to make a decision
so quick which one of these is the best
I am
I mean I'm sure some love you can very
quickly calculate best that most people
are not going to want you
it's the fun part hi and
and so that's why you really want to
help people understand which is going to
be the most cost effective for them
this is love you if they're dating
application and and
they offered 100 utility without a
subscription and you can
fill out a profile method users
there's lots of ways to browse essential
suitors including this is our radar
screen of what you're seeing here
see all the people of potential dates
around me
and of course they have from premium
premium feature
a happy get more exposure to people
and here is how they explain the
subscription options
for that pennies a day to find love
pennies a day to find have who can
afford pennies today
for lap now there's no gaffer care I
know exactly which
which subscription is gonna be the
lowest cost per day
but time porn if your gonna take it to
this level
and make sure that you're so calling out
the total purchase price
because again we want to be honest and
clear with our language
people are going to want to know what
what they expect to pay don't make them
do the math in reverse
right now if you're available worldwide
I wanna make sure that you localize your
currency
combat the huge roadblock if you down
so that's what I mean about about doing
the math for people it can be so helpful
in making that decision quickly
now another thing that's really helpful
as showing fewer thing
it's about quality not about quantity
too many choices you risk overwhelming
people
and I don't know how many have you heard
the paradox of choice
ineffectual means that the more choices
that you have
the harder it is to make a decision
and in fact when you too many choices
that choice over loud
its stresses you out and what you people
wind up doing is avoiding making a
decision of together
and you want people to make a decision
to purchase something
kind of like if you've ever gone to make
our recipe and it calls for
Apple of major making apple pie and so
you got your last year the grocery store
and then you're faced with death
well kinda crap all is it called in to
listen yes sir
rad USSR fuji here Pink Lady
year our it's too much it's overwhelming
too many of our and the four runs on you
just abandoning map high all together
you want to avoid that reaction in your
app too many choices become
stressful and that's going to result in
people
avoiding a purchase decision are
together
fair here maps it for different dating
application
again loads are you tell me where after
scripts an more than
our leading you test drive me out there
pastor Greg giving you an entire car
you can fill out your profile message
people on million way for browsing
including recommended partner
they do offer some premium premium
features that allow and one other things
are seeing
who's viewed me Sarah tapping on that
viewed me baton
brings up their subscription choices so
they're offering me that information at
the time that I need it
now look I've got three easy choices
here
maybe even highlighted the one at the
best value
three choices as an easy decisions Frank
I don't have to for all for a long last
have options are paged through screen
after screen with different subscription
numbers on it
and I have to remember them in my head
and try and figure out that makes it
hard
buying things shouldn't be hard so fewer
thing
all on one screen no paging no scrolling
people want to be able to see all other
options at once
now if someone's ready to make an impact
that decision to buy they're ready to
press
rabbi button you really want to execute
on it as efficiently
as possible you have you ever gone to
get a cup of coffee and then you're
faced with
a long slow moving line and fair you to
fight forget it
that's where you don't wanna have an in
your apt our game
minimizing but the time and the number
steps that it takes
make a per-share keeps people really
engaged in your apt not thinking about
that purchasing process
so this is super not it's a builder game
that takes place
in space not quite out worldwide you at
first eighteen very soon cuz you're
probably gonna fire aftermath
now right now I'm in the process of
preparing my TV hatin as you can see it
for all
have that I got the mama I wanna ask for
more timber
but this is gonna cost me 8 time and now
hi everyone so what happens when i press
that green button
I can get some jams right here I don't
have to go anywhere
I can stay right in that moment have FTV
hot repair
so in addition to clearly fading what
I'm gonna get 200 am
for $4.99 they're often reminded me why
I am seeing this in the first place
I need seven more only have one I needed
a and maybe even flock to the package
from Sams that's closest to what I
needed
happens that this is the smallest
Packers exams but then I can make a
decision really quickly
I mean yes they have exams star and yes
I have many more options in it
but taking me away from it. he had as
more disruptive
money we just a pair stay focused on
building
because building is what I came here to
do you
you never wanted to start a game prior
from playing the game
that's the fun part distracting them
makes it easier for them since walk away
entirely
similarly candy crush saga handle fits
really well of them
get you have those boosters at beginning
at every level
and you have the option to purchasing
them right here
they're not shipping me off to a candy
store with a million different things to
choose from
would you like this booster here's the
price buy it back in the game
fast and efficient right at the moment
when I can use that
now another thing to think about it
preloading images and data third fair
when people need it
this is because you're black that's
another kind a match-3 puzzle game
now yearn clients as you're playing and
then use the coins to buy rare gem
which then help you do better on the
very have of
now every day you can also get some free
coins from
the steering wheel
now you get one free throw in for David
of course you can by
more sense if you like and we all pretty
generous
so imagine that you're excited you're
like okay you know what I'm doing really
good in the tournament this week I wanna
be my friend
let me go get some more spans see what
happens what if your face
with death people don't like waiting
that's like that long line at the coffee
store your FM not sticking around
now thankfully which hope with seventy
you that faye
they learned everything immediately
where you want to do is be
aware what people are likely to purchase
based on where they are
any rapper Game and then you can look
for times to thoughtfully preloaded
so that their data and images are
available awesome someone need it
so this screen is only accessible from
that we off-screen
so it's the perfect opportunity to
preload those them into
cannot be available the images and data
will be there
people seek it out
and one final temp as you said cash
artwork appropriately
so it's not gonna have to load
everything all time if it doesn't meet
you
now after lunch in this room we have a
great fashion
about optimizing in app purchases with
store cat
so I highly recommend you come out come
back after lunch and check it out
because there's
a lot of great tips for avoiding common
pitfall
now finally what you can do to make the
buying process easier on people is to
inspire people
someone may not want something have a
don't know what the possibility of a
death
they don't understand how its ruler
feature could help them
or have what they could achieve with
that
now I'm not saying that you want to turn
everything in for an advertising
experience again we're not trying to be
pushy
but there's a lotta ways that you can
really naturally illustrates
how things can be years
paper by 53 does this beautiful a
they've got their sample Journal that
the staff is made that shows off not
only what the tools are capable of
but of a different ways they could be
used you know maybe 10 wireframe
with it or maybe you wanna make some
artwork
now another thing they do well as give
suggestive tired also the blank journals
maybe you haven't considered sketching
or journaling with a fat now we're going
to you
now have a gallery artwork created by
people using the app
regular people and ask our shows off the
variety of styles that's achievable
where you can do with the tools and also
how the app can be used
me you can make some amazing artwork but
you also might want to use that for
architectural rendering
and if that doesn't get you inspired
maybe the idea of having your work
featured here is very exciting
for you just gotta ho Arthur A ways that
you can use the app and see what the
tools are capable of
now again with games and with super not
South Perth very well
kind of a different approach for the
same idea
so after you learn the basic gameplay
with super not
their reward you for visiting other
people world
now like I said this is a builder games
to your working on building up
your property and seeing how creative
other people a ban is super inspiring
for your own place now this is how you
start of
pretty basic in the first 15 minutes
you're gonna get some real basic
structures guy
and after a couple hours you might wind
up with something like that or
something like my TD hat
and when you get for a couple hours
eating okay I know what's going on
I have an idea what's possible but it's
only when you go
to visit other people's worlds do you
really get a fan
for what's coming for what can be
created
so check these out these are all real
player
this is not the Super not screw
createdby
amazing right me my TV hat is super lame
by comparison
yeah yeah and now I'm excited now I
wanna go in at a drag an hour
you know a rainbow our flager messages
to my friends
I mean it makes it gets you excited
about spending more time building thing
make something really cool and you can
see what material are so forthcoming
so as you're thinking about how how to
make it the buying process
easier make sure that people can see
what's available with no after
how people understand the value what
you're offering
give them that test drive experience
and then when it comes to the
transaction make sure that you can
process on it fast
and efficient and don't forget to get
people
excited about what you're offering
but the story doesn't end here your job
not over just getting them to push the
buy button
there's a lot of things that need to
happen to complete the transaction
in order to contain have a continue to
be a really great experience
the first away its is and new feature
coming in the fall
and Tim touched on their very briefly
but I'd like to spend a little more time
because this is gonna impact
everyone and that's after by
fell in the fall you'll be able to
associate up to six people on household
as a family
and have parted that's we're gonna have
a new printer control called after I
and if it's a name of this means that a
parent is gonna approve or decline
any purchases that a child makes so it's
basically the criminal best
can I have it please 33 but it's all
gonna happen
through your devices so here's how it
works
today when you're out fans request
to purchase something you're going to
get a response right back
that purchase our fam
now without to buy we're gonna check
with the parent for
about survived the name out so you're
gonna summer across for purchasing
the child can ask for something on the
App Store is gonna check with the
parents
so what does that mean to you during
Mass
time you're gonna get a response back up
too far
and then once the parent accepts or
decline for a class
that's on the App Store will let you
know whether it's been purchased her fam
and this deford's taken off for up to 24
hour
while waiting for a response from the
parent rivers no response within 24
hours
it's going to default to fail and the
child can request again
so what does this mean from a design
perspective
well if you have moral situation
where people are doing purchasing you
need to shift over
turn a synchronous model
let's say your game offers boosters at
beginning a Lavar
and a child makes her quest to buy one
you know what that's how
stuck there waiting for up to 24 hours
see here
whether they can have a booster for the
next level right I can guarantee you
they're not gonna stick around that long
so what can you do while you have to
figure out what's going to be bath
for your after your game the important
thing is that you let people
keep using and enjoying your app during
this time
for child requested a booster well you
summer costs of
for the parents for proof but then you
could let them play other level of
or maybe they continue playing the level
but without the booster
and when that approval comes then your
bank and let them use it at a different
time
another thing that you want to think
about it giving some sort of feedback
inside application so that the child
remember
that something is pending but they've
already asked mom and dad
and felt that you could update no label
on the button
say something out or in the App Store we
show our method
help the child remember that it's
actually pending
power any people using a wrapper under
you need to start preparing for that now
that differed fate is entirely in a row
and you need to make sure you're
handling it well
make sure people can still continue to
use your app
for your game while that differed fate
is happening
and you want to make sure that if a
response is pending that they have from
feedback
there it's really important to note that
this isn't just
Iowa State Fair don't think that waiting
for up to a year after game is going to
get you outta best because it's not
going to happen
the ability to create families is what's
coming with my life a day
but this ask my permission is going to
apply
to older versions iraq Mac OS and Apple
TV
cysts are preparing now
now whether or not a transaction
complete immediately
or up to 24 hours later you always want
to confirm that
that transactions completed let people
now
sat on their mom help people find
whatever they just bought
let them now that it's available for
years
an example that you guys probably see
all the time as the App Store
Sarah soon as you confirm payment for
application
you see that the app starts down you get
that feedback something's happening
nothing's gone wrong your merchandise is
being transferred to you
and then you can open an app directly
from the App Store
you have to go digging around all your
home screen filled with maps to find it
you can just start playing threes right
there for hours
now another thing to think about is if
you have a game or
children top something really fun you
can make this a fun experience by using
sound and animation
so this is heads up at the game that's
really popular
with Ellen DeGeneres pipette honor TV
show all the time
a little bit like charades designed to
play it with real people in real life
each of these Dacca theme cards are
topics that you can
act out for your friends and try and gas
now they give you a couple theme packs
to get going to start playing
but then they also offer attire other
theme packs
to enhance enhance the experience so
check out what happens when you buy
wanna be I happen to be in eighties fun
she get that down and that animation
that lets you know something else happen
the purchase has gone through and the
name animate back up to the top
so you can see where cards arms are
playing right away
now confirming that the transaction is
completed
is especially important when asked by
because your customer may not be
at the same place where they were when
they requested the transaction right
so if you had a comic app and say the
child as browsing all the comics that
are available
may request on and while they're waiting
for Mom or Dad except at
well then they go and read one other
issues parity half
the need to think about if that
transaction complete
how are you gonna let people now the
complete at a later time how you gonna
let people know where their merchandise
fair
and how to find it
now no one wants a fee error code 128
right confusing and frustrating except
someone
and it can be a little alarming for you
wanna know your codes and present
information away it's going to be
meaningful to the people using your apt
not all areas may require spot you don't
have to tell your people everything
now if someone did cancel transaction
let's say that you're using an app or
game change your mind about something
you can split
is this what you wanna see it doesn't
make sense
you may not need to notify people at all
or you may just wanna make this a little
more
customer-friendly cell
the best experience of course is to
avoid errors entirely
so again this afternoon fast and
optimizing stark at is gonna have a ton
of technical taps
about avoiding errors and all those
comments fast
now another thing that I see sometimes
is that people tend to
over after purchase as you wanna let
folks get some enjoyment
out of what they just pop before you
start asking them to buy something again
again don't be that guy
it's like Christmas for you and rafter
toy
are all excited and then you realize
Arjan come with any
battery disappointing right
me just took something that was a really
joyous occasion and turn it into a
frustrating experience for people
so make sure that when someone by
something that they can use what they
just spot
give them that satisfaction they
shouldn't have to make a subsequent
purchase
in order to enjoy
and then like I said earlier less is
more
you wanna prioritized for Manning person
that
how people focus on what's still
available to them
if there's things they can't buy d
prioritize bad in the UI
especially with nonconvex of there's no
need to keep showing people something
that they've already bought
they already own it now in some cases it
may not make sense to hide items that
have already been purchased
but just don't let them be the star the
shower
and I think you're all aware that it's
very important
that you let people restore their
purchase that that they've made
previously
they could have made it on another
device or they got a new piece of
hardware
and it's important that they can
retrieve what they've already got
this is broken magazine and they make it
super easy
if you already have a subscription well
here's where to go to start that restore
process
but they took it one step further so if
you were to tap on one of the
subscription options
you get the confirmation for subscribe
to fight you an ex tax:
but if you can't fall
they ask if you are already a subscriber
and of course there's basically two
reasons why
you might cancel subscription
confirmation
one as if you change your mind about
subscribing
of course and that's a much bigger
problem for them to tackle
but the other is if you already had a
subscription so in this case for helping
get you back on track
now you all know it's an app store
requirements make restoring
available but a great experience is
gonna make it easy
art someone must have been there faction
and
and this is about notification you want
to use them
stop by and this applies to push
notification
as well as local notification
now you're not gonna have to notify
children about after I
purchases complaining because the app
stores gonna handle that for you
but you do you want to use notifications
to let people know about new contact for
Earth
scripts an or maybe and those dating app
speak about me know if I have new
recommended mass at circa
a great job with their notification they
serve up
bite 5 news articles and and they give
you updates as it's happening
now they're only gonna send
notifications FL article about I
explicitly follow
orbit something that they consider
breaking news
and its they're very to see about what
they consider breaking news
now this is not breaking news this is
what I followed earlier
writing on that notification takes you
directly articles you can read all about
it
so they've made it really easy for me to
return to the contact
see you wanna be really thought far
about the kind and the number
notification that you're standing cuz
too many notifications
just gonna know why everybody and not
only do your FN turning off
notifications entirely
they might just wanna to reading your
app if they get tired about notification
that not experience that we're after
right you what
of America cation that will keep people
coming back
make the app feel more valuable because
family there's new content there
okay so make sure that you consider the
saying
after customers Afghan completing the
transaction is super important
which brings us to the final third stage
have a great experience with an app
purchased at and not
measuring and refining with all good
design it's our important a rate
you want to measure the success and
quite frankly the failures
avoid try see how that has an effect on
paying
and then make changes based on our
I mean all the things that I mentioned
today are gonna work for all product
types in
audiences for the more that you really
fine tune your approach the batter
more factor animeme so here are some
questions that you can ask yourself
about the changes they made to help
determine whether they were successful
so when where the changes made and what
we're reading super important
I you wanna make a detailed note about
exactly when he may change as
and all the things that you updated
something the matter translator
you are trying to figure out how have
the number change it house number
purchases change
hopefully they've gone up rights
and are different things being purchased
from different places in the application
as a result integrating our merchandise
reselling higher value items
and what's the average revenue per
device and this is going to be really
easy to see in the fall with the new
iTunes can act because we have a
tired after analytics coming for you
offer free
and this helps you learn whether or not
a marketing campaign was worth it
if you invested a certain amount of
money per device
and you're not saying that revenue come
back and well back campaign
not gonna be going back at 4 a.m.
and finally keep an eye out our people
returning
more frequently because if they are
that's an indication that you have a
really great
experience but the quality experiences
Ghana
fat I hope that you guys will take at
least one other design tips that I gave
each day
and implemented any rapper Game and then
see how how it affects the overall
experience
coveting your gonna be really happy with
the results
and I would like to hear how character
this is my email address
fell let me now let me know what you
change let me know that
the fact that is having on yourself and
if you would like more design advice we
have time for that
at designing great app about developer
Apple com
and if you don't all have a copy of the
Human Interface Guidelines
it's a great resource a lot of good taps
as available on the iBookstore now
for here all the related fashion you
might want to see
ingredients and great games with
yesterday and that talks about how to
have a really great
gaming experience and so the video
should be available online and you can
watch it
and just before the fashion with the new
iTunes can act
which had all the information about act
analytics so look for that video to be
out later today
and then we have our optimizing in app
purchases later today in this room
times and great technical taps and
there's
a prototyping fast an term tomorrow
morning
that's gonna tell you all about how to
quickly integrate and test out the value
answered it's a great fashion to figure
out how to quickly
test things out that you might want to
integrate into your apt
and finally on Friday comes to
preventing unauthorized purchases with
her feet
because you're offering really valuable
things and we only want you to be giving
them to people who paid for them
Sarah can be a very detailed technically
heavy fast and I that you want to check
out
thanks so much for everybody and try to
rest