alright good afternoon everyone thank
you for
coming here to adopting hand of fun i OS
in OS 10
I michael jordan's I'm the lead
engineering project manager for
continuity and I'm super excited to be
here today to talk to you about
adopting handoff in your applications I
love it later I'm evil
joined by been speeding he staten field
to
to talk more in this session but as you
saw on Monday hand up is a huge part
have the releases for book for IOUs and
OS and
and I'm really happy to be the second
person at least
this week will talk to you more about
them so if you look at this feature
you can really see the big goal is that
we wanted to be
EV free for the user for love you to
take what they're doing in move that
between whatever Apple device they
happen to be using so
all continuity handoff in particular is
all about having that seamless
experience
between naps on different devices sit
out today
we'll take a look at what we're actually
gonna learn this session today so first
of all
will take a quick look at at what is
hand-off how does this feature working
cell with the about that
on Monday and so will dive into that a
bit more next we'll take a look at
actually
adopting handoff in your application so
at a super simple EP I am very happy to
be able to tell you that
their different integration points in
both ap kidding you like it for being
able to take advantage of this
in your app and so we'll take a look at
those and little round things out by
actually taking an in-depth look at some
had some pretty advanced things you can
do with hand of that are super cool
alright so what is hand-off
well I think we've all been stuck here
before rate you're using one of your
devices maybe you're browsing on a Web
site
and what you really want to be able to
do is to take what you're doing on that
device
and move over to another one and a lot
of times that can be kind of cumbersome
maybe
you have to go and fish out the app on
your iPad you have to go back to where
you were in that app
reload Ubuntu stayed maybe didn't even
have you Data Sync across in the first
place into it even more pain
and so hand of its all about making it
super simple to make that jump between
your devices
so is your on your Mac in your browsing
something like like Safari
on the lower left corner loves your iPad
or any the rest of your devices
you'll see icon shows up you can swipe
that icon up
and we immediately bring you back to
exactly what you were doing
in that application wonderful seamless
experience
and so I how we actually
do all this what's going on so the first
thing to know is that
this is entirely about the proximity
have your devices to your other devices
so we use BT elite actually
it actually let devices around you know
what they should show in that lower left
corner
and which devices actually show your abs
is linked to
the devices that you're signed into with
the same I cloud account
so we do is you we know that you're
signed into this device
and we actually use the cloud to I BT
leap here you different devices to each
other
and when you actually go to I had to
actually continue an activity on another
device
were actually moving that data directly
from
where you were to where you want to go
so it so it's a
saw about directly moving information
about that activity itself
now where you actually gonna find
the UI for for handoff for those two
places on both platforms
first which you'll find is that
on i OS in the lower left corner the
lock screen if you're using
your Mac another OS device you'll see
this icon show up
and this is your clue that you can swipe
this up to get right back to that
application
you also find that if you double tap the
home button
and bring up the multitasking switcher
you can go all the way the other side
above the home screen and you'll see a
pain for an app that we see that we know
is nearby
you can resume from there as well so to
different places
super convenient to get to those now on
the Mac
you've actually got you why that's going
to stick around for you here in the dock
if you're using an app on a different
device
so for example if I'm on my iPad or my
iPhone or maybe even a different Mac
I'm using something like male you'll see
it actually show up it
in the dock right at the end there you
can click on it
to get back to to what you're doing
essentially to start the hand of
you also find it in command tab so that
you can go ahead and he commands have
cycle to your absolute there and choose
to pull over the activity that you won't
be working with
here you see is is your mail that came
from from my iPad
okay so when it comes to adopting
hand-off there's really three main
things
the you need to think about the first
and releases kind the most important is
the siding
what activities in your app you really
want to support
now this this the skirmishing thing to
talk about the fundamental unit
in hand of is this notion oven activity
and what you really wanna be thinking
about
are what does the users think about is
they're using
your app about constituting say
different types of things so for example
in mail you've got a very clear split
between I'm reading email
verses I'm writing you know those are
two different types of activities that
you would want to have an indie that we
do have
in the case have hand-off so what you're
trying to do is
not only provide a nice grouping up
these discrete past
the not only just to make things simpler
for you but also because it will talk
about leader
when you go to resume these activities
on it on another device
having some clear separation between
what typeof activity you're actually
trying to resume
can be really important can help you do
so much better things in the user
experience
are to step 2 is actually creating the
activities in the first place
this is also really easy to do we'll
have a lot to go in to talk about how to
actually do this
and third and final you need to be able
to handle incoming activities into your
application so if you have kids
launched or gets resumed and the system
hand you this activity to deal with you
need to make sure that you are basically
taking the user back to where they want
to be
in your application so I mention this
before but the
the fundamental unit here is the
activity when you're dealing with
with hand of and specifically this is a
this is a single class it NS user
activity
I am very happy to tell you that it is
only one class it has only a few methods
and it's the same across both i OS
analyst at
so you get a chance to learn how to do
this in one place and its gonna map
completely to the other platform you
don't have to worry about
a huge difference is an API or anything
to super simple to use
so you're working with Dennis user
activity so you've got something like
mail for example
as you are composing an email this is a
great example love
a discrete activity that's being done
this as mail saying I'm
I'm composing and when you actually tell
this activity to become
active become current what become
current
does it tells us that this device it
should start broadcasting two devices
around it that a desperate the user is
doing something
the can be handed off and
there's the devices then can know to be
able to show things like
the icon the corresponds to that up
now again when you make when these
activities this broadcasting goes out
you end up with a very lower left corner
there you get this icon that shows up
and the UN the user can go ahead and
resume from there
now the key thing here is that when the
user actually slides up on the
lockscreen
the device where they're going to
actually connects back to you
the original device and what its
basically saying is hey users here they
want
they want this DataQuick give me
information about
the activity that they were actually
doing we handle all that for you
the activity gets packaged up we send it
across to the device words words being
resumed the system gets it your apt its
launch
and that's it super simple to work with
now hand-off also has I to really cool
features that you can take advantage of
even beyond just basic activities the
first is the ability to to actually
create
live streams between two different
instances have your app
on different devices so is part iv:
it's part of doing at hand often
resuming on another device
you can actually have that app connect
back to the original machine and just
get an open
an extreme on either side to be able to
keep talking back and forth
so you can imagine there's some pretty
cool stuff that you get that you can do
with that
now second I imagine for some people in
this room this will be a really big deal
we support handoff between native app
that you own
and web sites the you own so if you've
got
so if you got and I O S app and
a really great website you can actually
hand of seamlessly between the two
so that's really really cool art safford
today's agenda
we're going to a few things here and
take a look at specifically
ap kid and you like it is support for
hand often and what that looks like how
you adopt things
will talk about working with and its
user activity directly to seek
understand the PI their summer dance
things that you can do you
will get into you native app to website
hand-off
and also look at using these
continuation streams
between different aP's and with that I
like to hand it off to you Vince Peter
to talk to you about
adopting hand often you're out thank you
thank you very so a adopting hand-off
in your app there are a 3
key pieces to the apt kit and UI kit
support
in hand of a the first is creating
these user activities a and advertising
them to your nearby devices
the second is updating the user activity
with your
state about what the users doing in your
app
and the third is using that information
that you put in
to resume what the users doing another
device
so starting at the beginning creating
user activities
the first step is the kind to take a
step back before you write any code
and ask what do users do in my app
hopefully this is a pretty simple
question to answer here's an example
from
OS 10 what's the user doing here
well their composing an email message
here's another example from I O S what
are they doing
composing an email message it's the same
activity on a different device
some other examples of activities would
be things like reading messages picking
an item from a list
or editing a document these are fairly
continuous things that the users engaged
in in your
up up things like clicking a button
or typing the subjectivity email
are not really user activities those are
kinda part sir
actions that are part I love the user
activity
so they're fairly broad a and their
continuous
on be so once you
identified what your app is what users
are doing in your app
you'll find that usually there are some
UI elements
that are responsible for presenting that
to the user maybe it's a window or %uh
view controller
a and on I O S 8 and/or scan yosemite
a and this document you I document s
responder and UI responder
have a user activity property and
remembered that
responder is a base class for a larger
view I elements includes views
Windows new controllers window
controllers
so odds are good if it's in your UI it
has the user activity property
and use it kinda like this so the first
step is to create
and and this user activity instance and
you do that with
Alec in it with activity type and you're
passing it in activity type
which is a string that identifies the
kind of activity
that this is a it will also appear in
your info keyless
and we'll talk a little bit more about
that later
so after you have the Ennis user
activity instance you can configure it
it has some properties like a title and
then you said it on your document a
responder
just like any other property
so for document bass tabs a it even
easier
a all you need to do is add Ennis
ubiquitous document user activity type
to your in info keyless under each CF
bundle document types
entry the basic idea is you're giving us
an activity type for each of your
document types and it's perfectly okay
to have the same activity type for
multiple document types
and when that info cue when that is in
your info P list
we will automatically create units user
activity
and said it on your document when the
document is an eye cloud
on West Penn a since and this document
can move out with high cloud and back in
the high cloud
a we will be updating that user activity
when that happens so we will set the
property the mill
for example when it moves out of high
cloud and then create a new one if it
gets moved into high club
in you if you want to know that is
happening if you're using the user
activity and sharing it may be
a you can't use Kb 0 and just observe
the user activity key
on the document so for other APs that
are not document based
you still need to put your activity
types in the info P list
but it goes under this and this user
activity types array
that's at the top level and again we'll
talk more about activity types later
for documents in responders when they
have a user activity property set
on their a doctor in a responder
at Keeton you like it will manage it for
you
what this means is we call become
current
and become current is a matted on any
issues or activity
that makes the INS user activity v1 user
activity
the current user activity that the users
engaged in
any kids advertise to all other nearby
applications
so here's the with this kinda looks like
so the iPhone has an issues are activity
and become current gets called on it
and that gets advertised all your nearby
devices and they show up in the lock
screen or the doctor what have you
so become current on
you can call it yourself bud at can't
you like it will also call it at some
key points
so you probably don't have to on iowa's
a this means that when your app is
launched
comes into the foreground or tabs are
switched
you like it will walk the view
controller hierarchy
including presented view controllers
and we're only looking at view
controllers that have views which are
in the view hierarchy and if those view
if we find a view controller that has a
user activity
that's the current you directory and we
call become current on
additionally when user activity is set
initially on you I view controller
if the view controllers in a transition
will wait until it's finished
but if the view controllers views in the
window hierarchy
we will a automatically become current
on it immediately
so that's my view controller you I
document will not become current
automatically but it's really easy to
share it with a
share your user activity with a view
controller that will all you need to do
is set the view controllers user
activity to that document user activity
and whenever that view controller is
found according to the
rules in the previous slide it will
become current
on August 10 it's a little bit different
a apk it looks for user activity in
to places the first is the
mean windows responder chain we goal we
started the first responder in go
through the next responders looking for
one with the user activity set and if we
find it
that's the current activity we call
become current on that user activity
and will also look at the main window
controllers document
and if it has a user activity will call
become current on that
and we will also reevaluate this when
appropriate as the main window changes
or the user activity it's at
will do this search and find the right
thing to become current
on
so we manage it for you we call become
current
we will also call invalidate and
invalidate
is a method also on an issues are
activity
which means that the secretary is
finished the user's done with it
they put it away they your no longer
doing
what they were doing so that with
something kind of like this
so same setup as before the iPhone it
has the current activity that's being
advertised are you're nearby devices
and invalidate gets called and it stops
being the current activities so the user
can continue it anymore
they've closed the window it's finished
it's done
so that's creating user activities and
leading are you nearby devices no
what the user is doing
the next step is putting your
information
into the user in activity but to
let a so that you can
restore the stay when it gets continue
so a Ennis user activity has a user info
dictionary for this purpose
it is yours to use a
you feel it out when are you get this
call back so this is a method
on Minister a and this document you I
document and the responders
update user activity state
and you you in this message you fill out
the
user activities user info with the state
%uh your responder document and whatever
you want about what the user
is doing
note that the user info is empty each
time we make these call backs
so before update user activity status
called on your documents are responders
will
empty that out in on the user activity
so all you need to do is add to the user
info you don't need to worry about
clearing out old date or anything like
that
so look something kinda like this update
user activity stay
don't forget call super there's a
convenience method on an issues activity
called update user info entries from
dictionary
and that's a really easy way to get your
information into the user activity
and we will call this at an appropriate
time
but not necessarily when the user
continues
but just an inappropriate opportune time
we will call this to gather the
information about the user activity
and when the info that you put in the
user activity becomes stale
there's a need save property are on an
issues are activity that submarine
and all you do is set that yes and we
will call
the update user activity statement again
later
set need saved is very cheap you should
call it as your data changes
and we'll call you back later with the
update user activity state
so what can you put in the user info
it's a dictionary and you can store most
P was pipes are
all P was types and a few others
including URL's
and for euros file URL's
are obviously a little problematic the
the same
past might point to different places on
different devices the actual file might
not be there
%uh however value world and I cloud
are okay and if you're I was only
from a document provider are OK too
we will automatically do some
translation so
the file the file euro is pointing
to the right fine
a couple other things because keep the
middle amount information in the user
info
so just put what you need a to get the
user back to where they are
the transfer times for these things can
vary quite a lot so every bite really
counts
just include the state so don't include
your document
if you're using I cloud fantastic all
you need to do is store the file you
were all and then you can
use that a if you're
data stored on the web somewhere put a
reference to that new user info
also try to avoid platform specifics
since this is the
user activity might be continued on a
Mac or an iPad or an iPhone
there are a lot of things like the
visible racked up a ScrollView which
don't really make sense
across all those contacts it's better to
use a heuristic like
the middle item that is in my ScrollView
and storing our offset are a reference
to that instead
a storing a visible racked for each
potential thing you are continuing on
also an issue I document will add their
file URL
automatically in there update user
activity state implementations
with the Ennis user activity document
URL key so
you don't need to will already be there
don't repeat it
a a couple other things
think about versioning you're gonna
wanna future-proof your app
as you make new versions you're gonna
have changes to your user activities
so you might want to do something like
include a version in your
user info it could be something like
this
in here were actually using the
application did update user activity app
delegate method
which is called after any other
documents responders get that update
user activity state called
on them so this is actually a
a really good debugging point if you
up want to know what's exactly is in
your user info
set a breakpoint here in check it out
and we'll tell you what's in there
so now we have put
our information about what the users
doing
in the Ennis user activity
the next step is using that information
on another device
to continue and get the user right back
to what they were doing
so again this is on another device so
your you a the devices receive an
advertisement that
this user other user activity is current
on another device
and it's showing up in the lock screen
at the doctor what have you
and the user indicates that they want to
continue your application
and we will call this on your app
delegate
application will continue user activity
with tight
and note that there is no Ennis user
activity here
a all you have is the activity type in
that's because we have been actually
fetched
the user activity completely yet
we will start touching it immediately
after when you get this call
and you should use this to show the user
what's being continue you have the
activity type so you have an idea
up what kind of activity it is and maybe
you can enemy
a view controller in or something so the
wait is
a perceived less
so you should return yes if you're
handling this and you're showing some
kind of
feedback to the user our return 0
or if it's not implemented n you get the
system's behavior
now on iowa's this means the default
paying panelist and you get nothing
so it's a really good idea to implement
this weekend
here's an example of what that might
look like
shares you can see you were checking the
activity type and
if it's %uh viewing message activity we
know that we're going to need a message
view controller
and so we set that up and we show it to
the user
and then we return yes because we are
handling showing feedback to that user
about that activity type so once the
user a in the user activity has been
faxed from the other device
we will reconstruct the Ennis user
activity and give it to you
in this app delegate method application
continues our activity restoration
handler
and this is the place where you
reconstruct the users activity you get
them back to whatever it was they were
doing
again a return yes if you've handled
this user activity
return 0 or leave it on implemented and
we can continue
some user activities for you
so this restoration handler
it's a block that we pass in DFU and you
call it
and you give it an array %uh documents
in responders
there are presenting the user activity
and will call a method that's
restore user activity state that is
paired with that update user activity
state from before
here's an example what that might look
like
so we're checking the activity type in
interviewing message activity
so we get our message view controller
and that we return yes
and know we're also a calling the
restoration handler with this view
controller
and when you do that restore user
activity stay is getting called on that
you controller
and you can use the information in the
user info
to kinda reconstruct whatever is the
user was doing
but and a more local level so just for
your view controller
you can also call this manually as you
can see at the bottom a
it's perfectly fine this column restore
user activity state yourself
and that's actually useful pattern to
restore
the users stay in build your view
controller hierarchy
at the same time
so that if everything goes well it's
entirely possible since there are bits
flying through the air that some might
collide
and will fail to retrieve the user
activity information from the other
device
and if there was an air we will call
this on your app delegate application
did feel to continue user activity with
type:
air and you should present the heir to
the user and do whatever cleanup you
need to do here
on we make a guarantee you that four
every time you get will continue user
activity
you will get exactly one love either
continue user activity or did failed
to continue user activity so you can
rely on that will appear
those also take note that
the air can be an issues or cancel their
in which case a you probably don't wanna
bug the user about it
usually that will happen if the user
tries to continue something
while we're still fetching information
about a previous activity will
automatically cancel that previous
activities
so that's a all you need a but for
docking base taps
a II US you continue the user activity
kinda like this
so you want to get the URL out all the
user info using the INS user activity
document you are all key
and create your right you I document a
subclass and then you can pass it to the
restoration him learn that you I
document will get
its restore user activity statement and
called on it
so it's pretty easy on August 10
Aki can use in this document controller
to do this for you
so it will automatically get out the
file you were all find the right
documents some class to create
and created and then we'll pass
a we will call restore user activity
statement give you the
user activity object so you can restore
up
the user state here's a diagram to kinda
go through this
up continuing process so it's similar to
be for the iPhone has advertised the
user activity
to that then the user is continuing on
their Mac
and when the user indicates they want to
continue
we will call application will continue
user activity with type: on your app
delegate
and you've implemented it to you give
the User some feedback
that it's being continued maybe you've
animated in a view controller some
things so that
by the time we actually get the activity
maybe the animation is still happening
and the user doesn't even have to wait
so we will then ask the
a device were continuing from for the
information about the user activity
and we'll get it back and will recreate
the Ennis user activity instance in pass
it to you
in application continue user activity
restoration handler
in that netted you use the information
in the user activity to get the
the user back to whatever it was they
were doing
this might include passing some things
into the restoration handler
and if you do that we will call restore
user activity state
on them and then users
right where they left off you've created
a user activity on one device
put your information about what the
users doing into the indices activity
object
and handed it off to another device that
is able to continue
and get the user back to whatever's they
were doing
so there's still a few more details
about Ennis user activity
and there's a couple other really cool
things that Ennis user activity can do
and Q staten field will be explaining
that
thanks very much I excited to be here
and show you when working on for a while
I and has been said I'm explain a little
more
about how you might use this I'm you've
already seen almost everything that's
and an issues are activity by this point
um and ap kidding you like it provide
a lot of functionality that makes it
really easy to adopt this
but if you have some need to do
something for little outside the norm
it'll it's useful to understand
at the basic things what's there and
what you can do it thanks
arm jury originally said
and Vince pointed out you know and this
user activities are just objects are
allocated
I we've talked about this activity type
string a couple times
so let's go into that a little more you
create one of these user activity type
string sign your application and you
pass it to the Alexa net I'm or
I you've put it in your city upon all
types in the NFC because document types
key
I and where did you get the string from
I in a sense you just made it up
arm that string is a string that we as
the system use
are when an activity gets received in a
device
um to pick the application that we wanna
show
to the user and so in that sense it's a
lot like a file type extension
you know files have extensions in those
extensions bind them to particular
documents when I double clicked on or
otherwise opened
our user to type string to the same
thing are you make the mop
we don't display them to users so they
don't need to be terribly comprehensible
and we recommend that you
start with the basic your developer I D
or your company's reverse DNS name
and then add some suffix to the end to
that
to make it unique one for each extension
pipe that you have
and then once you picked those I you put
them in your code
at the point you be creating each of
those types of activities
and you put them in your info pls so
that we know
that your application would like to
handle these types of activities
are in your info pls to go on one of two
places
other either go in the CF want all
document types array
as the NS ubiquitous document
act user activity type are or they go as
a string in the NS user activity types
at the top
up your applications and populist
I'm we've talked about how their
used to pick the application that shown
in the corner
we allow all the applications from a
single developer to exchange activities
amongst themselves
come so if you have a and I was
application
an OS X application I you can exchange
activities between them
if you have several Iowa sects i several
I was applications
each of your applications could create
activities that were continue bow in
your
other hi Wes for OS X applications
we do this based on that team identify
our that
used in the way you've built replication
that means
in order to use continuity to continue
an item
are where they need to be an application
in the App Store
or you need to be signed the developer
certificate
um now applications don't have to claim
all the activity types they create I am
a corollary
applications can claim activity types
that they themselves don't create and as
example
I if you have kind of a monolithic
application on a West Ham
I say it's an application that creates
many different types of things for the
user
from the user's perspective I the user
can edit pictures of cats
the users can add cute videos about cats
users can keep all of their cat books or
all other pictures up their captain
there one application
arm you have that application he would
have a bunch of different document types
when you're creating
activities you know there are different
activities a user might be doing
I'm but I O S you might have three
separate applications
might have one application with the user
who looks at their
cat movies or plays their cat sounds
might have a different application for
their cat books
may have a third application where they
can see their cute cat pictures
with a cute cat captions my mother I own
when you build peace your applications
this way
you would create four different activity
types won the kind of map to beach in
your file types
and then your I was application in this
case one every applications would claim
two types
and your other applications would claim
other types and if you use our continued
from a West End I O S
the appropriate I can watch on a corner
when they want to continue from IRS back
to western
would all come back to your say
monolithic application
arm likewise we've talked about the NS
user activity object
and it actually doesn't have a lot that
you need to set a net
I'm activities have a title which you
can set
keep it short I just in case I get shown
to the user to know what they're doing
are they also have this user info
dictionary that
I anything you said in their arm the
machine that creates an activity
is gonna show up in there on the machine
that receives it I with minimal
translation only I love
URL's to point objects that are in cloud
containers to the same logical object:
on the receiving device arm we do have
the
add user activity entries from
dictionary to efficiently merge
are some additional information to the
dictionary if you just set the user info
then you're saying this is exactly the
user info I want to be there
after you created an activity in are you
or
ap getting you like it will call become
current on it system then knows this is
the activity that we should be sending
out
that a user could continue another
device if
your application was the application
that
the user was using at that point I'm I
and the far future you would call
activity invalidate to say we are done
with this activity the user
as close the document or its no longer
appropriate you'll get removed from
other devices
and then you just the outer
there are a few delegate calls as well
that you can take advantage of
so if you set a delegate on issues right
to the object
are when we've decided that we need the
information from your activity object
if you have implemented user activity
will say we will call
that delegate on at fault priority queue
to give you one last chance
to fill in the user info with whatever
you think is the correct info right now
arm and that means the
the model you should adopt is instead of
constantly trying to set user info
you know after every keystroke if the
user is typing something on one device
I you should set the needs save property
abuser activity
whenever the user does anything that
would essentially dirty the object from
the last time you told us
that here's an activity and the last
time we ask you to fill it in
and at some time in the future we will
call you
via this user activity will save or in
the UI kit an app get delegates about us
and we'll ask you okay now we actually
need the information for this activity
perhaps it's being sent another device
because the user's actually continuing
ed
arm there are other reasons that we
sometimes ask you to give us the info
and that's your opportunity feeling the
user info
I and when that returns we know that you
given us a consistent set of information
I we have another delegate which lets
you know that the activity was continued
on to another device
arm when the user does this we will call
on the first device user activity was
continued
give you back your user to the object
arm
many view probably won't need us are
hoping that you structure your
activities
so that even if they are continued on to
a second device
that they remain perfectly fine I first
device
user might pick it back up in a few
seconds and keep using it there
but if you have an activity this
transaction with nature
that's really only exist at one place at
the user's filling out a form
as an example and arm our current lease
if you're composing a draft message when
you continue draft message to a second
device
back in the first to voicemail clothes
that draft message
because male doesn't want the user to
have to draft messages into devices
not know which one is more recent I'm so
if you do have one of these
transactional kinda activities
you can take advantage %uh user activity
was continued
I and to do whatever you need to do
there for that
I'm not jury talked about are website
hand-off um what's ahead of is the
ability for you as developers
to in your native applications if
you have the kinda application where
you're kinda really backing data that's
provided elsewhere it's not
sitting if I like loud arm
you know perhaps at some time no for
social browser application
where you have a lovely iowa's
application
presents a great interface that takes
advantage of the features in the device
like the camera on the touch screen
art write a very high quality interface
to let people do things
are but your course also have a website
that other users can go to I'm to come
see the same thing
or to interact with your met application
in the same way
um your native application can tell us
that if our User another platform
doesn't have an application which claims
the activity type that we're creating
the user could also choose to continue
this activity in a browser on that
platform
I know is here Hooper upper second
device in the corner we seen Safari
and if the user clicks on safari they
would get brought
to I a URL that you provided
back on the originating device I am from
that
you know hopefully the user is able to
continue what they were doing in your
native application
I have to take a quick look at what that
looks like
you know you would create an activity
just as we've seen elsewhere
you would fill in the user info so that
if it is continued to another native
application
yours on a second device you get a high
fidelity full pass through
and you're also set this additional
field web page URL
you'd say here's an HTTP or HTTPS URL
if the years ago was there I that's also
OK
and that will get them to what they need
I similarly we can do the same type of
thing
out to allow a user in a browser or
not to continue into a native
application and iowa's
arm and you know what that would look
like
is if the user was at your website
um say on desktop using
I the information there when they pulled
out her I was device
in the corner they would see the icon
for your native application
and if they clicked on that know they
would get brought into your native
application
and you could restore them in your
native application to
the same thing they would have been
seeing in the web browser on the
originating device
now to do this you take advantage I'll
some new API's that happens providing an
IRS
out that allow you to securely kinda
claim
a domain name for your application so
that you can say I'm
this developer I truly on these domain
names and I'm willing to let these
applications
take advantage of that domain name
I and the way you do that is you add
these domain names
to the comparable but developer dot
Associated domains
entitlement on your application and once
you've done that
some code will reach out
to your website periodically from
the device and after to verify that
there are some information there will
say this application is allowed
to continue from this domain if another
device gave it to us
and if that happens you know we bring up
your application
I in your native application you know
again
your continue user activity restoration
handler is going to call
and there were you do is you check the
incoming activity type to see if it was
this special and ask user activity type
continuing from web browser
I never was you know there is any user
info there
you can take advantage of because you
don't have native code running and other
side
it's running a web browser you do have
the webpage URL that the user was askin
that browser
and from that web page URL you could
bring your native app pop
kinda looking at that same thing hi
you also of course would continue to get
any other user activity types that your
application has claimed
so if it's any of those who do the same
thing you saw earlier
I lastly let's talk about continuation
streams
continuation streams our way are for you
to get
and set up after user has chosen to
resume
an activity in a second device are a bi
directional pair
input streams between the two devices
the you can use
are primarily we think for interactive
purposes
if the user is going to continue to use
both devices you wanna
be able to throw things back and forth
very quickly
home on what that looks like you know is
the user's
in your native application on your first
device and we see your icon the corner
and the user swipes up and we bring up
your application
and then we setup a Senate and House
streams between the two processors
and once those are up you're free to
read and write from those streams
and communicate between the two devices
any
fairly hi performance manner
for whatever purpose is you want to do
on what that looks like in the code
again as you create and this user
activity I
you said a delegate and then you said
set this
supports continuation strange property
to yes
on the make a current and on the
receiving device
I when the activity comes in arm in
continues our activity restoration
hambre are you check if that activity
supports continuation streams
I never does I you know you can call
this
additional method get continuation
streams with completion handler
and that gets past the block
and we when you call that will reach
back
try to set up these pair streams to the
original device
and after their up will call your
completion handler with the streams
up something goes wrong I'll call you
with and and Essar
so if you don't get an error you have
streams you can start reading and
writing
back and forth between the two hours I'm
simultaneously
back in the first device um
the delegate method that you said the
delegate method
I love the delegate you set earlier is
going to get the did
receive InputStream OutputStream call
over there that's going to get the input
stream in the OutputStream
that are connected to your client and
your
free to start reading and writing back
and forth between the two
I sold
are so wrapping up you learned about the
app getting you like it
I it's very extensive it does almost
everything you need
I am and particular you learn but an ass
and you I document support which makes
it almost
completely free to implement this are
many have you can add about four lines
of code to your application
and you'll discover that it starts
continuing between
I less device I was device or if you
have
I less analyst and applications from
Iowa stars10
our meal by adding a couple keys to
infer P list
I and making sure that you're putting
your documents and I clout
are you learn about continuation streams
we have if you want to set up
interactive
in a real time ish performance between
devices after the user chooses to
continue
are you also learned about how you can
continue to a website or continue from a
website
into your native applications
of for more information our framework
evangelist
I'm not sure if he's here but it's Jake
barons there's his email address
are we have a very good programming
guide that out
and available on developer Apple com the
hand of programming guide
which we hope answers any questions that
you didn't get answer today and has
some examples of how you might do things
I would have the Apple developer forums
where we're sure new and other Apple
employees are going to start
helping each other I take advantage of
this
are in terms related sessions our
tomorrow morning there's a section on
Cloud documents
on as we said cloud documents are a
great way
to get the the actual data
behind user activities I sink through
the clouds so that when the activity
goes from one device to the device the
data
is available for it arm there's also the
session yesterday
which you can watch your app your
website in Safari
which top structured web credentials and
how you can lot
I was devices know the you have the
right to do things with domains
and thank you all for coming hope your
good afternoon