hi
hope hope you all a good lunch
the section 220 adopting advanced
features on the new UI
and Mac OS 10 yosemite on I'm Chris
treason
and the let me start by showing off some
others new
UI features in Yosemite so
up to be in with your the a simple
Finder window
and the big changes to your house the
doc is kind of
just grabbing the color from the desktop
picture likewise
the Finder sidebar is infused with the
the bright pinks and oranges
on the desktop picture and it's really
complimenting
do users content on-screen are
likewise we have a picture above Safari
here
and the continent harmonies radovan
Finder window
but a the toolbar is is just grabbing
that color from the web page
and making the you I really really
complement the
the web content here and %uh finally
we have Notification Center arm which
has been around
a little while now but in Yosemite you
can see it's using the
whatever you occurrences and its point
up the the really bright reds and
oranges and yellows from the desktop
picture
and it's not just the background of the
Texas pointed out the buns are pulling
it up
and we're gonna show you how to build
you eyes that also grab color from the
environment like this
a so to start with I'm gonna mention a
few
changes in existing acted API's
especially in this car and its image
then ima spend while talking about a
title bars and toolbars
section I like to call pile apartment to
a farce and a
after the alibi Corbin on stage to talk
about some
important new classes that allow you to
use these visual effects
particular bill that we like to refer to
as Byron C and
finally will top it off with the
discussion performance regarding these
new effects
about to begin reviewing our
are all the Bugatti API's the
this is Anna segment control in Yosemite
arm
you'll notice the be a finder in the
background in this picture so far in for
round
near the back four controls on these are
separate elements now
but they're not actually separate as
controls
this is the same in a segment rose
always we just configured it that
segment style property
with a new value the and a segment style
enumeration has been augmented with Anna
segments I'll separated
and this gives you the destroyed
appearance between the back and forward
buttons
so when you're up K that parents don't
throw to Aspen's at
just using a segmented control and the
senate segment style a
so I like to talk about and its image
now on
especially if you've been using you I am
and will be familiar with some other
things I'm talking about
but a was to start with this little
sample image here
just kind of a button or about your
background of some sort and if you tried
to stretch it using the SMS GTI ring I
put in as an interview where you draw
yourself
you're going to notice the image is
stretched uniformly
so the corners here the store as the
image is resized
and thats kind of neat but if we're
going for a button
or window background it's not really
affect me one and
you images had this for quite a few
releases
a but an estimate now joins it in
introducing the captain sets property
and the stakes in a sentence that struck
thank you thank you
ok States and its agents that's trucked
which lets you specify the
distance to the edges to make these caps
and
those Capen sets are in the image court
system
serve you the NS image court system
begins at a
are 00 in the lower left him in size and
height the right their way
he said the captain sat on an image and
wrought like used to resize
you know we're now holding the edges and
corners
constant while resizing the interior the
image so this lets you get the
stretchable buttons
the stretchable backgrounds a quite
easily I
there's one other thing I want to
mention about this up
so again if you're familiar with you I
am and you know the you a matter sizing
mode
we now have an asymmetry sizing mode
which offers traction tile options
stretched the fall it back to the
behavior we've used a Mac OS 10
pretty much forever now tiles a new
option and these are exposed on the
surprisingly named
resizing Road property on its image
thank you got
a so as an example here the senator
sizing mode the tile
and a you know doesn't quite do justice
as across the here but you can see how
the image is actually being piled into
these larger sizes
so if you have interesting detail you
don't want stretched you want replicated
and said
this is how you would pull it off and
you can use it with any s binder nans
ImageView
arm so to set up the slicing you buy
part you have your programmatically now
but you can also do this with Xcode and
to do that you just open your image
your ass a cataloging a nice preview of
it here here's that might 9 slice
checkerboard image and you can set this
up using the
ID inspector in this area here we've got
the
the slicing motyar horizontal and
vertical here for nine slicing mention
of the 23 sliced
horizontal to vertical on
and if you want to change the tiling
mode we have the structures option here
so you can do that graphically without
ever having to change your code
that covered in this image I like to
mention a few things about and its
appearance in Yosemite
so s appearances in a county had
Richardson maverick's
I we offer to a appearances and
maverick's
which you can get out using the
appearance named class method
on the ass appearance class and a
the default is and as a parent same aqua
which is what we use forever we continue
to use it as the default the parents
and we have this other parents are
called as a parent's name light content
which is used by pop overs
and in Yosemite we are saying goodbye
to write content don't use that anymore
instead
pop overs use one of our new parents
names which is by bright lights
and byron dark and poor man's gonna talk
a lot about these and his section
but let me just give you a preview of
what these look like we have byron white
on the left
and byron dark on the right you can see
how the background in the elements are
bike with pulling up that color from
beneath the window in this case and how
the house image
is is much more offers much more
contrast against that background
and I'm I did before assignments and
color here
so probably won't surprise anyone to
know that and a scholar has some notable
mentions here
about the day one is that system colors
are appear insensitive suffused by Matt
later by been dark
the system colors are going to return
different effective values
so something called the things I control
background color control text color
there's dozens more arm there in the and
a scholar header and the documentation
we also have to new system colors
and that's label color and secondary
label color and a Corbin will also
talk about these in-depth
alright my favorite section here title
bars and toolbars
we're all familiar with handle bars and
toolbars but
in Yosemite they have a new default
appearance and one of the key elements
that new default appearance is that they
blur document content
so up here's a slightly awkward video of
me scrolling a picture in preview
and you can see that I scroll the title
bar in tow bar are actually absorbing
and boring that content
in real time and a preview didn't have
to do anything two-game this they they
got that
feature for free up let me explain how
that
that works so if you have a ScrollView
and its adjacent your title bar Toolbar
we're going to automatically drawl that
that previously obscure content and
would work for you
if you're ScrollView isn't adjacent to
the title bar we're going to ignore it
C&C on the left that kinda made a
mock-up showing that the title bar
blurring that orange document content
and on the right it's not adjacent to
the title bar so we're not boring at
were absorbing at all and that works
really well
for almost all content out there but
there's a few cases I want to call out
where are magic there can use a little
bit help
so what are those is movie news
this is a big area where we can Tucson
Medical replicate the content for you
likewise opens your views are in a
similar place
you may notice kinda
hardware-accelerated thing going on
using the Jeep you
and that's a good observation some types
of players
also need a little bit helping users
movie layers and open Joe layers kinda
grandfathered in with the views
but other things like a layers with 3d
transforms and layers with core image
filters
also require little bit of help to show
up in the title bar and pool bar
let me show you how you can do that
we have to play some there explicitly
and we can do this using this new window
style mask called NS full-size content
the window mask
on as a simple them up by threw together
this is using a
asylum after does not include the full
size cotton you flag
and you can see our content view is
vertically beneath the title bar and
pool bar
and this content you just has a slightly
odd red box and black box
if we add the full size Khan a new
window mask
also on the the content the size hasn't
changed but I Warenkorb are overlaid on
top of that content you can see a boring
the red and the black in the title bar
there
so if you look at this mockup used
before size content you
when no mask a problem notices that
those controls you used have the top of
your window
are still at the top of your window but
the title bar
overlays them and unless you're trying
to play a very
interred at mine game with your user and
if you are your job is done
congratulations
you're going to want to figure out a way
to you get your controls to be anchored
at the bottom of the title bar again and
probably the easiest way to do this
is by using auto layout so
and its window offers a new property
called content layout died
and this returns an object to that you
can use
a layout constrain just like you would
use an ass few
the example here and creating a
constraint which binds the top of my
view
to the top of the windows content layout
guide and that means that the the top
corner to both our views is going to be
at the same place in the window
while at least them out arm
if you're not using a laptop sorry a we
have a new API
yosemite gonna layout constraints called
the active property
and you can now install constrain just
by sending to be active
you don't need to find a common ancestor
at at the constraint few
up constrained to in this case the
content lab guide doesn't necessarily
have a common ancestor
and this API takes care of it for you
if you're not using our way out we have
another property for you
called content layout wrecked and that's
just an ass wrecked that
represent the on obscure area up the
window
a its key value observing compliant
which means if you register as a
key/value observer for you're gonna get
called back when it changes
and that's important because it can
change the title bar can change height
the toolbar have items added or removed
or labels out and move you know from
small icon to large I come out
so it's important to be aware and
assuming we use one of those methods we
can outweigh our buttons
beneath the title by the way they want
their accessible to the user again
but the scroll view presents kinda
challenge force
we wanted to start of on obscured by the
title bar and we don't want the scroller
to be upskirt obscured by the title bar
either however if we just leave the
scroll the US position that
to take up the entire hi to the content
view it will be so in a way to fix that
and we have a way to fix that we have a
new API
on a ScrollView called content and sets
and this just adds margins
are around a ScrollView where we'll
inset the content you
arm ok so in this example I'm using the
content lautrec property at the window
and the windows frame to infer the
offset between the top of the window
and the top in the content area I just
gone ahead and set a content and sets
where its top property is equal to that
of Sep
there's an easier way of doing this if
you do this you're going to keep values
are the content where a property knows
when it changes
and a ScrollView also offers a boolean
called automatically adjust content and
sets
and he set the stage yes it will
automatically
mu are up adjuster content for the
scroller isn't obscured by the title bar
and the content itself will start on
obscured by the title bar
so we had back are all summer for
example here this is how the window look
like
up when it opened by the user when they
began scrolling
the scroll Yukon against all slide under
the title bar just the way we want
and we can get this a its appearance
love blurring the document content at
the title bar
without packet replicating it for you
a for like to take a yr trying another
screenshot here the picture
Safari and some your note about knows
about it is that
the title of the window isn't there
instead the window with its on the
toolbar
share the same row likewise here's a
picture up maps
it's doing a similar thing notice the
the title bars grabbing that content
from
the window again but it's also leaving
out the title in the window
so you want to do this in your app's
it's not difficult
we have a new generation called and
that's when the title visibility
has three states visible hidden hidden
one active
a in one active adds a little bit of
context so windows in the background the
title comes back
that can distinguish it from other why
some more windows
arm these are settable through the ass
window title visibility property
so stupid example here's that Finder
window again this is titled visible
and you can see it has a separate row
for the widgets in the title followed by
the to walk
whereas as well the title hidden it's
gone the title bar
the titles Don the window which is in
the toolbar share the same row
here's another picture this is a an app
called reminders if you if you didn't
know this was our miners
there's a hint the top a
but you can see the windows divided into
two sections they have a
a sidebar that runs all the way from the
bottom of the window
to the top of the window we all know the
sidebars not being blurred by the title
bar
ok likewise here's a picture notes and
they're in a similar thing
the the note on the right actually has a
size paper texture to it and that paper
texture goes all the way to the top of
the window again
and %uh this is also easy to accomplish
a and this window
has a new property call title barker's
transparent
so if we go back to my silly little red
box black box example
this is that went idle workers
transparent Eagles know and thats the
fall
so you can see the title bars boring or
content with a TS
the a the red box in the black box are
obscure so you can do tricks like could
use that go all the way from the bottom
of the window to the top
on or otherwise augment the title bar
so I'd like to invite corman on stage
he's going to talk about some new API's
that let you take advantage of our
visual fax especially one
call Byron C welcome carbon thanks Chris
so my name's Corbin and I'm not get
software engineer
so bottom and talk about today I'm gonna
talk about a new class apk it
to do these boring visual effects called
in a special affect you
my talk about his appearance and some
materials and how to get that
custom colors and whatnot that we have
democrat about piracy in how to get that
apartment E
and how doing your controls has gone to
control the napkin
and finally my discussed briefly some
the standard controls in at K
that dot these creatures and how we
doing how it affects you
so personal let's jump right and and go
to a demo
this demo is called visual fact
playground and it's not an actual
playground ap like you might think back
what has here's shows a lot of features
that I'm going to discuss today
there are a lot of buttons this app and
the show he's thing that I talk about
search in the developer site free
assembly for visual fact playground
you can find this taken apart and play
around and figure out how to create ap
psych this
something that as if I click when these
images here iShares Dow
how to create basically your own type a
sidebar I do some Byron C
there's a couple examples and how do
some type of blurring with an app Skype
application
how to get them we're here and also a
blender the tile bar to
another one showing off our dark look to
and how do you do something similar to
what they stand as
so these new visual effects I'm and talk
about new class called
individual back to you and here's a
screenshot of it and we see that
its blending with step behind the window
there's no screenshot that demo
application and its planning with stuff
inside the window
and now this is an important difference
to note because we have two concepts
here
we have behind 10 blending where with
whatever's behind the fuel behind the
window is blended with
what you see we have in window blending
so they're two different modes for this
and so that's reflected in the API
France visual affect you
there's an genome individual effect
blending mode
and has two options planning mode behind
window and
a blending mode within window and their
property said
so you can just set in code or
you can open up here at application
inside
your face builder and you can go ahead
and set the blending mode directly here
truly easy to do get that behind window
where and when to when
so how does this work how does the
behind window blending
actually behave and what does it do well
our implementation is ing
for graphics in the Windows Server this
means that as your window is moving
around
now the content years in your Windows
actually read wrong
its manage for you automatically bar
Windows Server
what is visual effect you guys the kind
to find regions with the Windows Server
the tally hey this is the area that I
want to be vibrant or two people heard
and do it automatically division affect
you
also implement fire in C numba discuss
about that
in detail in a little bit
cell one thing to note about this and
the visual thank you with behind when
opening
whatever is behind your view entire
application is going to be
poked out were knocked out so glad to
have you inside my window
thanks on top of an image you a picture
this elephant its gonna poke out
whatever is behind it
and so it kinda just just just knocks it
out said something to be aware of
in your application
saw how does within window blending work
within 10 blending utilizes for
animation to achieve this effect
as visual effects you is a special
where's special filters to do this
work behind the scenes quite missions
also used implement the vibrancy which
I'll talk about more in a little bit
now if it is in Coronation and you set
the property to be with and window
it requires their backing and so this is
a screenshot
what happens they're faced over if you
don't have it where backed in a show it
as
red 10k hey you're doing something wrong
major prime make it where backed
but you probably don't wanna make just
your visual fact you
the thing that's where backed you wanna
make the thing that contains it
be there back so in this case the
content do you ever wonder would be the
thing that you make their back
because it needs to be when those things
together and they both the coronation
where's
in order to achieve that
so how can he said it well you can also
set
I dis easily inside a tax code
if you don't to encode for the once
there a kiss check that box
enough merit that's been around for a
while cremation there
now let me talk about some state the
visual effect you has
inactive state which we see here
blending with the wind up
and it also has in on key or inactive
stay
so I'm actually removes the blurring and
just goes to being a solid color
fell this is also represent an API
so the visual effect few has property
called state
and it's in the new value and its visual
back state
and has as visual effects state follows
window active state
which is probably what you want to do
what this means is
when your Windows key and Windows Active
that visual effect you will be key an
active
but you may want to control more
explicitly seeking expert with that
active state
works closely set to inactive state
and actually have for powerful control
over this
now the things about that as I said
before you want probably always use the
followers
went to active state value because when
it becomes key and ninety
are automatically do the work for you
and you have to do anything
want to use the active state explicitly
very sparingly
it can affect performance and battery
life because if you have a lot of visual
factories around there always active
but you pry want to use in places where
you know that you is always going to be
active
and maybe it's a panel that can become a
key for whatever reason
internally we use in things like pop
overs and sheets which always want how
that particular look
so that was discussing some basic
properties official affect you
now let me discuss how to set the
material and how it works with in
disappearance
and issue of fact you itself
as Chris mentioned here are two
screenshots showing
two different parents is we happy in its
appearance name by Brightlight
get it to get this light appearance I'm
like controls
and we have disappearance same byron
dark to get the dark look
and dark appearance knows the controls
automatically look different
and automatically are changing the
colors as needed
easy to do this you can just use visual
fact few doubt appearance
and set the appearance to either firing
like her firing dark
can do it in code very simple or
as usual you can go into Interface
Builder selective visual affect you
and when you select the visual effect
you they parents
property when I have vibrant light and
Barb dark is options
other views won't have this option so
the
vibrant appearances work wire in this
issue of fact you
I'm gonna say more about this and that
why
that visual effect fuking be a direct
ancestor
perhaps to be a direct ancestor have
your child abuse
in order to get the vibrant a look and
Barbuda fact
however whatever material shown by the
visual effect on you
maybe different than what their parents
Assange
and let me describe that a little bit
differently
visual effect you has a property called
material
in a special effect material has several
Union values
the first one is what you will probably
use the majority the time
in this visual effect material
appearance-based
so let me show you how that one works
if you have a visual effect on you and
it's set to
NS issue of fact mature appearance-based
the actual material shown by the visual
fact you
is on a Mac be determined by their
parents
said he set the vibrant light appearance
the material light
will appear for that matter of fact you
set the vibrant dark parents
immaterial dark walk here for the visual
fact you
now you can explicitly set the material
and not set their parents which is why
didn't you know option
so the last option here is in this
visual fact material
title bar that's what this material is
for
is for you to create your own had a bar
like views
so you may have a need in your
application to replicate that had a bar
that we do
inside pocket and we just use this this
issue of equity up at a bar internally
and so you can also use it to create
your own had a bars if you need to
are so that was discussing visual effect
you appearance
and some other materials so now my talk
about vibrancy and cut some controls
first serve all what is a vibrancy
and byron she is just basically a
special blend were taking
two different pixels combine them
together getting a different result that
works
more vibrant when the combined together
its bankruptcy just
abstract term that week winding up kid
and that we don't have to worry about
the actual implementation
the actual implementation and blending
we do could be when your burn
a collar dodge by Steve Purcell it
doesn't matter reps tracking it for you
but if you don't know what those terms
mean let me give an example
so cures just a simple image have some
flowers and if I drop it low square on
to it
it's just the skies are grey square with
that doctor border
and if I set to be color burned are you
can see it looks more vibrant
so effectively this is what we're doing
to our controls and this is just a very
simple example
what color burn and what we mean by
vibrancy
so how does this work with visual fact
few
and how does the attacks become vibrate
let's take a look at at what you have to
do
for small in order to get any sort by
twenty you have to use the vibe in
appearance
they have to set the fire right reviving
dark parents an environment she is
on Mactan abstractly applied
so for this low piece a text here
in order to get this text to look
vibrant and it might be difficult to see
but it is actually blending with the
conference behind the window
you just use and a scholar label color
and it looks more like a bird
you may also have a need for a secondary
vibrant look
and this one just slightly lighter and
looks a little bit different
and again we have a new collar and ask
our secondary label color
to achieve this vibrancy in in this text
field
now let me remind you about some
template images
you may or may not be aware that in this
image has had at
a template property sense 10:05 and it's
really simple
you can't create your image as a black
and white image
and due Sept yes we have a specific
naming convention to make a template
I get your company image where we can
apply a tax on top and inside
apk it so if you're using a template
image
in this image you automatically apply
vibrancy
so here's an example have a regular
image
not a template image and I'm athlete
does not have RNC
however at this image below I'm at the
has I fancy
because it's using a temp damage so if
you in your application
use temple images can harm at to get
vibrancy
so that big the question was how does
something like image you
say hey I want to be vibrant or not the
vibrant and how is it dynamically
chooses answer
and the answer is we have new a API in
and ask you to do this
and this is basically the implementation
inside this image you
it says allows vibrancy is the new API
anti-cancer to allow tyrants he is
South the image that is template
purchasing hey if I'm a template
I can be vibrant I'm not template i
campi fiber
very simple so you may be wondering then
well how do i signal to the system that
that's change with my answers
changing based on something that I said
I change the image or what not
and just like normal ap get things if
you change the state a vibrancy or need
the question to be
and asked you again just cost that needs
display
and on that the call back and update the
vibrancy effect for your view
now in this text field also is vibrant
his text field he's a very similar to
end this image you
and it answers yes to allow siren T if
you're using their particular vibrant
colors
so if you're inside the fire in
appearance and using label color
secondary label color or any other
colors which might be custom for that
appearance
he will probably appear vibrant feed
don't want to text appear by bring
you need to explicitly opt out by
setting the control
pack scholar or some other color that's
not there
in its appearance also has a method
called allows haven't seen on it
this is using API and no effort
officially
particular appearance needs by means
you're not we discussed more about this
in detail later
but what this kansas is it gives us a
recipe
to let new know when a particular view
is going to be a vibrant
any view will be vibrant if all these
conditions up here true
the appearance has to say yes from
allows vibrancy which means currently
that it's the virus like retiring dark
appearance
your view subclass has to override
allows vibrancy
and say yes have used expressing that it
can be vibrant
and that viewer has to be inside the
visual fact you
the visual effect US order that the glue
that binds it all together
if it's not contained inside official
affect you arms he will not work
when all these conditions are met you
control will become vibrant
so let's talk about custom controllers
and vibrancy what you can do in your
control
to make them buy right so here we have
a custom view it's just drawing a
gray awful and then another great on one
side a bit
and this was appearing vibrant you can
see how it's deeper orange collar
graze being blended with what's behind
the window produces vibrant a fact
and went not individual back to you that
same exact heel
is drawing on vibrantly is trying its
normal great colors
with no work from you developer in
addition
and everything to play on this to you
this bottom view here
it is inside the visual affect you yet
it's not appearing by Bert
I discuss how to achieve that affect you
in a short bit
how do you actually go ahead and
implement this well for some all
in your cutting the subclass as I
mentioned before you overwrite allows
vibrancy
and your pie return yes that way when
you're in a buyer in appearance
you on that they will appear vibrant and
then inside you draw a racket pages do
whatever you're doing today
you sector particular colors fill up our
or do whatever type ad wrong you want an
alarm ACK to become vibrant
sure I'm just wrong with some regular
callers have
variation in black with a different how
to value
and this few on Mac it becomes byron
now because I Q says yes to allows
vibrancy anything drawn in fact that he
will
automatically become by rent even if you
do images
any taxed any caller everything inside
it will be vibrant
you don't have to use label color or
secondary label color
to get vibrancy and that you
however what you can do as you can
utilize named system collars
to have your application haircuts and
you be more dynamic
depending on what kind appearances and
its ally to parents are darker periods
suffering through something like and its
color control text color now is
dark when it's on a light appearance and
light
and inside dark appearance
something to be aware if you're taking
these colors and storing them in your
apt store the name collar
don't convert that car to a CD color or
don't compare it to a color space
don't extract RGB elements and save them
off because if you do that
you lose that dynamic nature of the
color instead to save the color
itself like to ask our control X color
and utilize it
again and again now again if you change
your parents on a particular view
I automatically knowledge the sub use so
you're calling on TAC color
not to worry about balloting things is
that automatically
so let's take a look at some code that
uses a system color because you may not
be familiar with that
we have colorless and sinking easily
grab
a colorless name system and what the
sample code
is doing and again this is providing
that demo application mentions the start
its gonna go and septum attributes can
you read through all the colors in the
car list
grabbed a clear color out Bayside ski
accuse the name in the collar
US at a bit and just do a wreck still to
fill that color
one after another so if we look at a few
where all its doing is drying the
scholars and this looks very
very I busy so let me explain it
this is what we would get this is what
that day my application does so in the
first column
this is just wrong the name a particular
color
next column is drawing day same color
same to you
in the Aqua appearance same color same
unify reply to parents
same color and same to you in the
vibrant darker parents
and if resume and say can see one
particular row this is the control text
color
as you can see there aqua every lighten
dark dark
the collars are all slightly different
depending on what we decide apt-get
to make it look for particular parents
way here they are different
thing on your parents so if we take a
look at that
custom view again that was drawing the
circles if you use his car label color
is color secondary level color that you
would look good
if it's an ally to parents or darker
parents without you having to do
anything
now one thing snow in his view at that
bottom there is
one is custom views that's not trying
privately 208
opt-out a vibrancy and what did it do
it's very simple all that view is doing
and this is just an inside Interface
Builder you can do in code
as I haven't selected and I glance at
their parents back to Aqua
ok and so it no longer meets the
criteria being a pirate control
and it won't drive I really
so the things to note: is that you can
opt out a particular controls from
vibrancy
one at a time or you can do I believe
you are key
cicada harkin controls opt in or out by
setting
I can't air to be want to take their
parents or not
not in and out dipping what you need
one thing to know is your view
that's apparent can't have already said
yes to allow tyrants a
because there are caveats with that
which I will discuss in a little bit
let's discuss how you would actually
achieve something like this
where the same to you words individual
affect your draws one way
and went in the regular aqua appearances
try another way in this case
went in the Aqua parents and drying red
and purple Justin be dramatically
different
so why would you wanna do this well in
application my want provide
different artwork for when you're inside
a vibrant vibe in appearance
than when you're not have I been
appearance and when you're inside her
regular
aqua appearance or you can use different
collars
or something or something along that
line in this particular case
I'm just using different colors it's
really easy to use
as I mentioned before in disappearance
has a allows vibrancy
property and its yes when it's in the
lab in appearance
and Serco kinky of that in this view has
a method
caught active appearance where it find
out what
the parents set on it or somewhere up
the chain
and you can query that and see if it
allows haven't see and if it does
it's that one particular color if it
doesn't you can send our caller
so here's just saying the red car when
it's in not an apartment
parents so let me discuss some have
yachts with vibrancy and lending
this is the within 10 blending mode and
some caveats with it
so let's say that we have this superb
you here
the one with the grace their darker
square around it
and has some seventies not that super
view says yes to allows vibrancy
what's going to happen is all this abuse
are going up
always be vibrant and so it's a little
difficult to see here
but now that sub you that image you
is doing a different blending it looks a
little bit murky muddy
because it's doing a fire in planning
and thats not desired
so thing to be aware of here is if your
custom view is returning yes from allows
carbon C
all your stuff he is going to be a
vibrant so if you're designing
applications you need to keep this in
mind and design are some used to be a
my written and or or to be aware that
they're going to be vibrant
were designed it so much that your
parent view is not saying yes to ours
having tea
overlapping with the siblings our
children
there also some other caveats with
behind 10 blending
has that same once vibrant always
battling a fact
but there's an additional problem here
than going to highlight
and wet is happening here is have this
little box which is saying no I don't
want vibrancy
however there's a text field on side of
it which is using label color
which as you can know from before saying
yes to allowed piracy
say tax 13 vibrant but the thing drum
behind wants to not be vibrant
are those areas are overlapping we just
described this to the Windows Server
and so what's going to happen is
anything in that square the tax
is going to be vibrant including what
was drawn behind it
that blue area and so it gets also
vibrancy apply today
so this is another caveat what you
should be aware and
and not do instead taiwan architects to
not be vibrant
or how that will control to be firing so
everything is Iran
another thing that we have is visual
effect you can have a mask image
property
the mask image all you can ask it
right here to visual effect is one is
the light appearance climate Iran are
used in a dark material
if i said im asking me johnnie to them
chest area blending behind it
to behind the window is only inside that
mask area
say just see that for the actual house
icon where the gear icon
and what was drawn in the window you can
now see the poppy flower
and again had em up occasion shows this
you can easily set a mask image or you
can use and its image image resize
and do the block and already created on
the fly
to hear sending it to be a as a power
just around wreck and when you do
something like this
it's how you would achieve this shown in
the demo app works around wreck
mind our window using them mask image
property
some notes about mask image Chris
highlighted some the new features
that we use with an S image so you know
set as captains had taken properly
structured mask image
and everything worked fine
okay so that was discussing visual
effect for you mask image
appearance and how to get piracy when we
talk about
love our standard controls napkin how
they do vibrancy
and things to be aware of for small
cable viewing outlined you and came here
now I'm you configured as a source list
is automatically opting into a farm in
appearance now
they see that something like the sidebar
and male
calendars et cetera
so how does this work and has worked
with your applications already
appears in the selection high lifestyle
have NSW selection
Alex dow source list that tells the
table well im view that
it wants to BS West list and essays you
set that
either in code for an air base builder
it is always had side effects
and these are documenting the release
notes but I'm gonna reiterate come here
out llanview's indentation is on Mac be
affected in control
to meet specific metrics new 10/10
we start tweaking the inner cellspacing
just slightly to make it meet new
metrics
if you think it will sell view its
position and imagery and texture I'm at
the control to where it needs to be
and we apply actually for the tax to
make it appear cracked
so if your application is using a source
list I like before and didn't make any
significant changes though I make to get
the new tent and look for source this
in sidebar the latter but here is
background-color: for the actual source
list for the table
is set to a magical internal color
it's important to be aware of this
because it has magical color what's
happening
inside a bad kid when we see that you're
using that special background-color:
we're gonna go ahead and put a visual
effect you behind your table view
and do the blurring automatically for
you see you don't have to do anything
you don't want that behavior after you
set this lecture highlights out the
source list
you can change the background color
anything else he could change it back to
clear
what to nothing and it will not do the
operation
and this is the way it's always worked
and so we respect or behavior
opting out about our phone caller white
background blur
say could do it manually and some other
super view if you need to for some
reason
now the No or thing to be aware of is
now on Mac the intent and
the sidebar so restless for cable
viewers on a Mac to get there appearance
set to the vibrant light appearance
for you and you don't have to do that
now the control inside pocket popover is
now utilizing
the light at like Dark Materials as
necessary
and it will have its appearance at the
barber like or vibrant dark as necessary
and you have to do anything for that
soap that was an overview the standard
app controls
and sad about get I'm gonna bring back
to Chris to talk more about performance
and we can do to make ya pass with these
new visual fax:
thank you for it alright that was fun
talk about performance which is also fun
so we're
you notice that blur we had and this may
not surprise you
a but the perfect isn't exactly free it
does cost something
and that something is graphics
performance and battery usage
and the sometimes though the cost is
worth the results
so something you should be aware appears
you're not trying to not use this affect
you wanna wrap up utiful
you just need to pay attention to
striking a balance between that
appearance
and the resource utilization so here's a
small example these two
images on the left and right appeared
that was actually control with reimage
views
and these byron template houses and
requirements requires a visual effect
you so there's actually
a few ways of accomplishing this but on
the left
which is to accomplish this with a
single visual effect you
meanwhile on the right we can accomplish
this with three visual effects use
and there some obvious reasons the
structure things on the right person
left
one that would be flexibility if you
need a different appearances are
different materials
for this house on the right you need is
visual effect is however
a you should be cautious about how many
visual effect is using and when you're
using them
in this case the number of pixels
affected here the surface area of these
houses
is almost identical between the left and
the right
and in that case a single visual effect
you is going to be more performance
there's less information for us to track
a
the option in this case is also true if
you had a window with say some very
small areas %uh vibrancy
and there are different and in the
window it might be more efficient use to
visual effect use
and set up a single enormous official
affect you
something else to be aware of especially
for in 10 colors
is frequently updated content on what I
am back from the updated content
well I mean Louise I'm animations I even
mean blinking cursor
arm these are gonna be updating at 2430
tips or 63 animation
or even to fit circling Kercher's and
the thing is whenever these update
we're going to have to re computer a
blur this is also true
for behind window blurs but you don't
usually control the content behind the
window in your apt so that's not
something you really need to worry about
a Corbin mention that layers are often
required
a especially for and window bars and
later usage is increasing just
in general a but something I want to
mention is that
if you're using layers the dirty shapes
on screen are any different
then if you're not using layers so
here's an example love a mock text you
that just blinks and insertion point and
this this %ah rectangle
when it's not later backed and you can
see here we we have this
waking cursor well you probably can't
see is I've actually it turned on color
flush in one of our debug tools
and this rectangle is turning yellow
every time the cursor updates
a for not only are back to you that
small rectangle is all that's left on
screen
if however we r we say we do want to
wear for this we're still using the
small to redirect
but whatever the view updates we see
this instead
the entire layers flushed it's not that
we're trying anymore our application is
still just drawing that tiny purse a
wreck
it's just that poor animation has been
built for GPUs to involve summit in
geometry in large batches
so we just watch the entire contents
layer to the screen
if for example you had a visual effect
you that overlaid the right side of this
this view even though only the insertion
point are insertion point on the left is
blinking
that blurs gonna have to be re computed
so that is something
keep in mind com something else to
beware of
if you're using update where are you
have your own where tree in your setting
your own their properties like the
corner radius or other ailments directly
will the entire layer still gonna be
flush in one on one pass their
so that caveat applies update where
users also
often though you can fix this by just
three factor in your view here he first
for a little so for example if you're
frequently updating content
try to put it in a small view and have
reserve large news
for static or and frequently updated
content
from an unrelated but very important to
be aware an S 10 has no pic property
and you shouldn't mess with it if using
Visual Effects use in the past if you
needed to punch a hole through your
window or have transparency you had to
set the stage
yes however if you're using Visual
Effects use you don't have to do that we
take care of it automatically
he said this to know you're gonna take
away a lot of information the Windows
Server users
to call obscured Windows and it'll be
doing a lot more dry in the necessary
so avoid this unless you're already
using it for other reasons
on I want to point out this option and
the accessibility preference
this in the display subsection called
this transparency
and that'll actually turn off or blurs
on a system-wide basis
and I'm not suggesting this as a user
feature in 72 just as a diagnostic tool
if you add a lot of visual effect just
your app and all the sudden notice that
made your window resize animations are
four screen transitions have become slow
you can set this to yes and the so avoid
the cost
WEA we pay it when doing that were
so if you notice when this is turned on
your performance is fine
with turned off performance is kinda
sluggish it's probably
you're using a visual effects that's too
large or too many visual effect use
and that's a cute dial down the the
transparency and boring
in the app some other things I want to
mention
is a to perform its all good news for
this
so I used courts debug Torana up
coloring and dirty areas that the
Windows Server had to redraw and that
can be very useful for diagnosing cases
where you may be drawing more content
than you're expecting
or when you're using layers and you're
drawing a little bit of content but it's
affecting entire
you something wanna point out about a
lot of are trying here is that
the perfect actually happens out a
process that happens in the Windows
Server and furthermore happens on the
Jeep you
and that means that profiling your own
process won't necessarily tell you as
much as you would hope
I'm store ever going to call out the
instrument store
because the the Windows Server and your
app archive competing to get frames on
the screen in a single display cycle
and at the faster you can make your app
in the letter G PU it utilizes
the more that is available for Windows
Server see you can still improve the
performance of the system as a whole
by just improving the performance a wrap
and instruments gives you the tools
to monitor all that comp if you're just
doing the
wider development on your app having
Activity Monitor open Internet be useful
it's certainly not as in depth as
instruments but it will tell you how
much CPU doing and more importantly
it'll tell you how much energy your app
a is is taking
to do what it's doing if you see that
offering a little higher than you're
expecting
that maybe another Q that your visual
effects and usage has
gotten a little excessive finally for
the purest amongst you who really
don't want to impact what they're after
doing by adding some do we stop the
profiler
you can ssh in you sample for example
which will tell you what your app is
doing
so we cover lots into quick summary
these things
I mention the m.s and Ron Haskins
especially Capen sets
also mentioned the new behaviors best
color the importance of Venice
appearance
and some significant role at the eye we
cover new window features
especially the full-size content view up
but also the title with Billy option C
you can make your title bars look like
Safari and maps
arm we also covered the transparent I'll
bar which is what notes and reminders
are using to have that Christmas parents
all the way from the bottom to the top
of their windows up
Corbin gave you a huge run through on
its visual effect you and what you can
do with our visual effects
how appearances environments they are
accomplished and finally
course remember like 40 seconds ago we
talk a little bit about performance
and I do hope your your cake summers
performance Methodist heart
a when you leave oh literally
wanna have failed to mention though is a
be a new escrow you API
they were using contract with full-size
content you didn't make it into the
scene you got earlier this week
but it will be available to you shortly
up so I like to point out Jay parents
are
primer to evangelist he is here in the
plaid shirt and be dark a vibrant
appearance shoes we have taken to
describing his appearance in great
detail throughout the course of the week
I'm here to see what we come up with
tomorrow
um we also for some documentation
available online
a developer Apple com is also where you
can get the courts to bug too I
mentioned
and of course Adele performs there some
relation related sessions
adapting wrapped in New why I was the
session yesterday that
available online now additionally later
this afternoon there's what's new in
Interface Builder which will cover not
only a bit what we
we show you doing their best for the day
but other use for fiscal yr tools for
design your app
and a tomorrow morning is creating
modern Co collapse
which if you found some of these new
guys interesting that will cover a lot
more what's going to Coco
recent thank you very much