good afternoon
my name is Brandon new and/or and I'm a
software engineer
on iowa's and welcome to creating custom
I A West user interfaces
if you take a look at Ohio West today it
is filled with really interesting
engaging unique interfaces for our users
you can see that in things
like the Notification Center which takes
a bit of a blur effect
to give you a sense love being at a
different dept above the operating
system
Notification Center also uses affects
like vibrancy
to create text that is highly legible at
all times
you also see interesting interfaces like
what we call the suggestions view in
Serie
forget we have these pieces a text
better animating
on and off screen at all times getting
the sense being polled on and off the
screen
we use a custom UI in a lot of places
across the system
and you might be thinking to yourself I
want to build really cool stuff like
this as well
the same things that you should think
about there are questions we also like
to ask ourselves
when creating new cases the view I for
the operating system
the first thing that you should think
about is where are you going to use this
you why
how does the students here ap and what
kind of purpose does it serve
for users and your customers sometimes
you want to create you why
that needs to represent multiple states
for example you might be creating
a download control the need to have
states like an title
odd downloading in progress cancelled
and complete States so you want to think
about those and think about how to
design
and craft your control in a way that
supports those different states and six
its intended for you also want to think
about what are you going to share this
control
or those peace and you I cross several
applications sorting and I'll essay
you can create frameworks for your app
which are a great way to share code
between naps that your team is creating
or even release it to the public
to help other people use the same kind
of pieces if you I
and in the last thing you might want to
think about
or what pieces have a PI can you
leverage to make your job
easier a lot of times we have you why
or controls in UI kit that will make its
very easy for you to create custom
things
without having the subclass code so what
are some API is that you might find
useful
if you were to want to take Avengers
things we offering you like it
what are those is the UI appearance
system you I appearance
allows you to configure certain
characteristics up the default you like
it controls
without having to subclass them one of
the most popular leader uses for you I
parents
is the tent color which allows you to
configure the color of controls that we
provide as part of you like it
without having the subclass them one
particularly useful piece in the UAE
appearance system
is the UN image rendering mode this is
something we introduce an Iowa 7
last year the lousy to provide a single
image
into your application we take a look at
the alpha channel from that image
and can apply to college to it so if you
would like to change the color this
image
during your apt life cycle orchid design
team would like to change the 10 color
your application will it and development
it's very very easy to apply universally
across your app
we introduce dynamic type with I West
Sep
which gives you a really great way to
respect your users request
for larger or smaller type across the
system and it's important that you do
the best you can
to honor those preferences to help
things be more legible
for users accessibility is a critical
part of Iowa's
we care very deeply about making sure
our operating system is accessible to as
many people as possible
and this a very powerful APIs around
accessibility
that are important for you to use if you
decide to build custom UI
in your application there's no reason to
not support accessibility
in your app and finally localization
another very critical part abiola's we
rely localization to extend I West has
many customers as possible
and this a new localization tools and I
was 8 that make this even easier for you
beyond those I like to introduce four
new topics today
the first is we're going to talk about
spring animations
which are a great way to make your
controls feel like a native party by OS
the next thing are some new techniques
for vibrancy and blur
after that we're going to talk about CA
shape layers
CSA players are great way that you can
drop custom UI
within your application and enemy
changes to it
and then finally we're going to talk
about dynamic core animation behaviors
and how you can make changes and have
even more control than you may realize
over the behaviors and that coronation
provides today
let's get started with spring animations
the first thing to understand is you
need to understand what spring animation
is
and you probably think I'm a spring
animation as a balancing effect that
mimics a springer a slinky in the real
world
and will you can create very bouncy
effects like that with spring animations
that's not the only thing you do with
springs
really you can think about spring
animations as a new default I'm anchor
for animations within your application
in fact we use that these new timing
curves
for nearly every system animation
starting in Iowa 7
nearly everything you see that we
provide as part of my OS
is built around spring in the nation's
now you can actually creates
new animations a spring admissions in
your app with out the you said you like
it dynamics
dynamics is an incredibly powerful tool
for creating physics simulations within
your app
but there's easier ways to get at Spring
animations
in fact the API for making a spring
animation in your app
is nearly the same as using the enemy
with duration block
that you're used to using today on you I
love you
so what do spring animations look like
on the road
up left side of the screen for you guys
i've a red box
that's going to animate using the
default even is out timing kar
on the right side we have a blue box
that's going to animate
with the spring animation both
animations we use the same duration
and they're moving the same distance but
when the animation start
you'll notice that the spring animation
very quickly gets up to speed
and then slowly tapers off as it reaches
its final position
compared to the e-zine is out animation
let's slow that down a little bit more
you can take a closer look
you see when the animation begins
the spring animation quickly moves up to
speed and then spent a considerable
amount of its animation duration:
reaching that final position its final
resting state
compare this with these in is out where
it takes a little more time to get up to
speed
another way to visualize this is the
plot what that Kurt
timing curve looks like overtime you can
see a default curve
very slowly builds up its velocity and
then immediately starts to slow down its
velocity for the end
spring animations however launch up to
speed almost immediately
and then spend the last third or so
other duration: reaching what we call
the long tail
or that slow bit where we finally
reached the the final position
where do we use Spring animations and I
West today one place
is watching aP's an opening and closing
folders
you pay close attention to these
animations you see it feels like the
the animation begins and very quickly
shows the user the content that they're
about to see
and then one closing very quickly pulls
the folder out on the way
another place that we like to use fring
animations is in the default
push and pop animations for navigation
controllers as well as presenting
moral views on and off the screen
and finally that serious suggestions you
that we looked at earlier
is both with spring animations we use a
single spring animation to pull the text
on-screen
of the bottom and allowed to slowly
drift across the screen
and then a second spring innovation to
quickly pull it out of the way
making room for the next said it strings
what is the OP I look like for spring
animations
it's like I said is a single method on
you if you that makes us really
straightforward for you to take
advantage of spring animations
in your app many these parameters look
familiar to you
but like to call out the two that are
unique to spring animations
and those in the damping and the initial
spring velocity parameters
damping takes a value from 0 to 1 and
controls how much resistance the spring
has
completing the animation at the end the
initial spring velocity
is used to give the animation a kick to
push the object into the
animation curve you can also use it to
synchronize the animation
with something that's in flight today
let's take a look at how these different
values
have an effect on spring animations
wanna start out with the same blue box
and a damn thing a .1 and you can see
when the animation completes there's a
lot of oscillation at the end
it feels like you would expect a spring
to be in the real world
you might want to subject but you might
not
by stepping the damping up to something
like .5 you can see we considerably
reduce how much isolation we get
with this animation this still fair
amount about think the end
but it's much more controlled bring the
damping up 2.8
reduces most that damping effect you can
see there's a very small bounce back at
the end of the animation
but for the most part the animation a
smoothly reaches the end
and finally bringing the damping up to
1.0 gives us know of elation at the end
it just smoothly reaches that final
position getting a very nice
fast feeling to the animation so it's
bring in
the initial velocity parameter we're
going to leave damping the same
but give our Spring a much stronger kick
to start the animation
you can see almost immediately launch
the box passed its first position
and actually overcomes the spring to
have it bounce back a little bit at the
end
and even stronger initial velocity can
blow even further past that final
position
but the damn thing value may quickly
posted in to rest
and then finally we can combine these to
make their unique effects
giving us a damping tell you that
resists oscillation an initial velocity
to give a nice fast K to our Spring
so where would you want to think about
using Spring animations in your
application
they're a fantastic substitute for
linear animations
that you're used to using with the
current you have %um it with duration:
in fact any place that you would like to
fit in to the native UI controls that we
provide
you should consider using Spring
animations instead because nearly every
animation that's part if you like it
that's part of the OS
is built around spring animations
spring animations also give your
controls and your animations a more
natural feeling to the user's
because springs are something that are
part the real world around us
it's also important to keep in mind that
we live show you examples with the
position property
you can use fring animations to apply to
any animal property in you like it
that means if you want to have the Alpha
for your layers are for your views
change
you can do that on a springtime in her
I have a demo application put together
and let's take a look at what spring
animations can do for us there
so this is my demo application I have
this very nice
rainbow gradient background and then a
control bar at the bottom
grab some custom controls that I can use
to configure
that gradients rendering I can change
number of colors
and I kill also pick how many colors
repeat within the gradient
now these controls corporately being
animated on and off screen with the
default
even he's out timing curve and it feels
very
very normal but it also feels like
there's a lot of time spent
with the control getting in the way of
the user actually interacting with it
so I was substituted substitute in a
pair spring animations
so my demo code I have a couple blocks
I'm doing animations and already
the used to present and dismiss the
modal view
and you can see here I'm already using
you I love you ended it with duration
and passing it and animation block
what I'm going to do is just replace
that with the spring animation
you can see the API is almost exactly
what we had before just with a couple
extra arguments
for my presentation we're going to use a
damping value of points 75
if you remember the boxes on screen this
will give us a little bit boss elation
early but have bouncing at the end to
the animation
I'm also going to use an initial spring
velocity up ten
to give even more the cake to get that
control on-screen quickly
also going to take a look that might
dismiss animation
again right now we're using the same and
it with duration
ever going to substitute in another
spring animation
for the dismiss I'm going to use a very
strong damping of one
I don't really want to be bouncing when
it reaches its final position in the
dock
and I'm going to give it no initial
velocity to just let the spring itself
poll that view back into the dock with
those changes
let's take a look at what that does to
the app just as a quick reminder
this is what it looks like right now
without the spring in the nation's
the control very smoothly slides in and
out but it still feels a little bit like
it's getting in the way
when we switch over to a version with
the spring animations
you can see there's a very different but
subtle effect
the spring quickly pulls the the view on
screen you can see that very small
bounce when it presents
but it feels like it's getting on and
off the screen and available to the user
much faster than it did before and
that's how we can use fring animations
to bring a new feeling the animations
within Europe
the next thing i'd like to talk about
something called you I
visual effect you before we get to that
however
I want to spend a couple minutes talking
about how we render things
on iowa's some other API's that we're
going to be talking about today
can have a dramatic effect on the
rendering performance in your
application
and it's important to understand how
they actually work within the rendering
system
so if you're take a look at the entire
system there's largely four steps that
we take
to render content for your application
we get your app a chance to handle
events
and uncommitted transactions to the
render server the render server
which is part of the system on iowa's
processes that transaction
does some more work and composites
layers which are handed off to the GP
you to be rendered
the GP will take its own block of time
to render all those layers
and then handed off from the display to
present your user
let's focus on just a little bit on the
except that we take within your
application
is largely for things that take place
within your app
the first thing will do is due any setup
work and ask your views to lay
themselves out
if you're using auto layout we're going
to take the time here to compute the
welfare at
every doing manual AL previews we're
going to call the outside the US
and ask your views from to lay
themselves out
the next thing we'll deal is due any
necessary dry
if they need using to draw themselves if
you implement a drought wracked
on some interviews well ask that to
occur here will also do some string
drawing at this time
next we're going to give core animation
a little bit of time
to prepare some images if anything the
code or convert them for rendering
before we finally package up the layers
and send them up to the render server
this is a very very broad overview how
the render server works
if you'd like to find out more there was
a fantastic talk yesterday
by their performance team that would
really encourage you to check out
they go to a lot of great detail on how
all the steps actually work
so with that quick understanding let's
go back to you I visual effect feel
last year to be the BDC we introduced a
new API
called drug new hierarchy and racked and
a system to go with that for creating
fast
static blur effect within your
application and we continue to recommend
you take advantage of this technique
if the content that you want to show
behind a blur is not
actively changing for the user the
reason for this
is just incredibly well optimized for
your application
so we encourage you to continue using
that as much as possible
however we heard that one or two if you
wanted something a little bit more
advanced
you want to do live were facts like we
have across Iowa s
and to that end we are introducing you I
visual effect you
your visual affect you to creates to
affects types
it's a technique for creating live
dealers in your application
and for creating vibrancy effects let's
take a look at what both for those
affect actually mean
alive for a fact is exactly what the
name suggests
it we could have content behind a view
that has blurred
and has some color effects change to it
as well all rendered in real time
on your device vibrancy
is used to create content that is highly
legible at all times
on top of a blur in the screenshot you
see right now
the FaceTime icon and the text are being
rendered
with the vibrancy and you can see that
text is always legible
no matter what colors or content are
being bored behind it
the
we have three styles for blur effects
the first to those is a dark color you
can see that we're darkening the
background here
were also D separating the colors a
little bit it's more than just
changing a blur a late bloomer fact
is almost the opposite that again we're
blurring but we're starting to wash out
some other colors as well
finally we introduce extra light blur
which almost entirely Dez at Reitz the
content blows out most of the colors
but still gives you a blur effects to
give you a sense of what content
is behind the view so what's up to me
make to take
to create a blur effect as I said it's
more than just a simple gal simpler
within your application
the first thing we do when we create a
blur effect ever wanted down sample all
the content
that's waiting to be blurred the reason
we do that is for performance
you are going to see the fine details a
review when we're going to blur at
so we've got a hand down sample that too
much smaller size
before applying blur effect the next
thing we do is modify the colors
and this is based on what perfect you've
requested well either D separate
or over saturate colors to create the
various styles
and in the final sup is we're going to
compute the blurs
and composite this back into your
application vibrancy effect
as I said is a technique for making
legible content
this typically placed on top of a blur
and we treat this with a few steps as
well
the first thing will do is Bruce the
saturation other content
and then we're going to apply a custom
blend mode to the vibrant content
and that put the blend mode is going to
change
based on what kinda blur you expect to
put the vibrant backed on top of that
way and for that reason
you need to tell us what kinda blur
using when you create
a vibrant effect so how do we use this
in your application
the first thing I'll do is initialized a
new
you i'd visual effects and you can
initialize either you I blur effect
or you I vibrancy of fact UN vibrancy
effect actually takes the blur
in its initializer so we know how to
create that vibrancy effect
for the poor you plan to use after that
you can instantiate you add visual
effects view and pass that
visual effect that you've just created
finally
the UN visual effects view provides a
content view
and you should add your sub used to that
content view that way we know what views
you want to have manipulated or affected
by the visual effects
there's a couple things you can do to
customize visual effect use in your
application
the first thing you can do is your
content the blurs
but changing the background color
property on the visual effect he is
content view
so if you would like to create a dark
red blur effect for example
you can make a darker a dark blur and
then set the content his background
color
to a red color to have the desired
effect you can also
do some animations for the frame changes
within your application
to change the position and size of the
blur fact no visual effects
also come with a number of caveats when
you consider using them
in your application the first I've those
is the idea of setting alpha
if you think about the purposes and
blurs an alpha
they're at odds with each other you play
alpha to a view
in order to make on Sat legible behind
another view to see what's back there
you use a blur effect to show that
there's something there but you're not
interested in the details
so it's not really sensible to apply an
alpha
to a blur at the same time and for that
reason we're going to drop the blue if
you try to change the Alpha
you should also be very cautious
about placing visual effect views in a
few hierarchy that uses masks
they're not going to work very well
together you also should be conscious
on whether you're going to if you place
a visual effect the UN group
they can have an impact on its rendering
either animation group
or opacity group it's very easy to have
a
to forget that US air blower or a
vibrancy effect really deep in your view
hierarchy
and then when you add an animation over
here forget that it's going to pick up
that visual affect you
and try to make changes to it so I
started the section by talking about the
rendering pipeline
and I'd like to highlight what impact
visual effect the US have
on the render him your application all
the work for Visual Effects use
is having an impact on the GPL
so if we look at a standard view in your
application it's going to take
a pretty typical amount of time to
render on the GPL
in order to create blur effects we have
to take all those steps that were
outlined
and render those off-screen it's just
the way that we have to create blur
effects
so when asked the Jeep you to stop
rendering your absent mean views
and create this blur effect off-screen
and then combine everything back
together
and that can take considerably more time
than rendering a standard view without
blur effects
vibrancy takes additional passes in
addition to the blur effect the that
they're placed on top of
so to add vibrancy into a view takes
even more of screen time for your
application
now the contrast this with drug you
hierarchy in rapt
we can do that considerably faster
because we don't have to do all those of
screen passes every frame
so this is why we still strongly
encourage the static for techniques from
last year
if at all possible let's take a look at
how we can use Visual Effects use
in that same demo application so going
back to the demo up
I still have these controls the come on
screen and right now they're just being
placed on top of the dimming
view and you can see I have this white
text label at the bottom
that it's not really legible anyway and
it just it doesn't look very interesting
we're going to use we all saw the
control bar at the bottom which is just
solid white right now
I kinda feels out of place on this rich
colorful gradient background
so we're going to use blur effects and
vibrancy effects to improve this
specter my demo application the first
thing we're going to do
is go to the gradient you controller and
we're going to set up the control bar at
the bottom of the screen
the control bar is that white bar at the
bottom with the different controls in it
and we're going to create an extra light
perfect the key things that you should
take a look at here
are the first part where we create a new
UI blur effect
and give it a style in this case were
using extra light perfect style
next we're going to create you a visual
effect feel and pass it the effect that
we just created
that extra light blue fact and then
finally will add this
to our view hierarchy we're also going
to do this
on the click wheel controller I want to
do what the blur background
and a vibrant title here first we're
going to make that blurred background
view
very similar to before we're going to
make a %um blur effect
but given the dark blur effect style and
then
another again create you a visual affect
you and passes that blur effect that we
just created
and then add it to our view hierarchy
the next thing we do
as you want to modify that title able to
use vibrancy
you can see right now in creating my
label and just giving it a white color
it's pretty straightforward to upgrade
that to use vibrancy
to do that we're going to make a
vibrancy effect on you notice the
initializer
is affect for blur effect
we're going to grab a reference to the
bar affect often that backdrop you that
we created right up here
and pass it into the vibrancy effect
because we plan to composite this title
label
on top of that background blur same as
before will make an EU official affect
you
and give the vibrancy effects that we
just created and then down for the
bottom
we're going to at my title label to the
content deal
about I'll up that new vibrancy effect
feel
so those are the three steps I need to
take to add blurs and vibrancy
to the demo application let's take a
look at what those look like
immediately see that we're picking up
that blur effect that extra labor affect
at the control bar at the bottom of the
screen
it's reflecting the purple color of the
gradient behind it
we bring our controls on screen you can
see that we're blurring that gradient
as well as picking a vibrancy for that
text label at the bottom you can see the
purple in the white from reviews behind
it
taking place now you're probably
thinking well that's great Brandon but
you probably just picking with that live
player that static Worthing
I promise you we're not because I start
school in this
you can see the blur effects are all
taking place in real time and you can
see more
that the vibrancy is also picking up all
those really cool colors
behind everything and you also see that
control bar picking up those colors
behind itself as well if that easy to
add
vibrancy and blur to your application
so moving on
next we're going to talk about CA
shapewear
sachet player is a really powerful tool
for drying custom busy and pouts within
your application
CA shapewear as the name suggests
is a subclass a CA lair which makes it
very very easy to use
in all your apps existing hugh
hierarchies because on iowa's
all your views are already backed with
the layers the other really powerful
part
RCA shapewear is that all of the
properties on it the control its
appearance
are an available so where my users to us
shapewear
one place is if you were going to create
download control
similar to the one that you see in the
music app orbit different store aP's
the thing to have a few different states
one that shows
thinking state where there's a ring
that's partially completed that spinning
it shows a state with a stop and it also
shows the download progress right
completes the ring
going from zero two hundred percent this
would be a great thing to draw
with CS a player in your application I
like to show you a few of the more
interesting properties on shape layers
right now
the most important one is the path
property
as the name suggests this defines what
your shape layers actually going to look
like
you create these bike handing us a CG
path
rap personally I like to work with you
are busy a path and then hand of the CG
path
version of that at the end so there's a
few steps we're going to take
to create the curve that you see on
screen even think about creating pads
very similar to drawing on a piece of
paper remove your pencil to appoint
and the move the pencil on the paper to
draw lines
the first thing we're going to do is
moved to a specific point where we want
to start the line
in this case Roy start on the lower left
hand corner
the next thing we'll deal is add
two curves to the point and you notice
we pass this a pair of control points
busier paths are defined by a point and
then a pair of control handles
which is seen blue on the diagram above
those control points
define what the curve looks like between
the first
the previous and the current point so
we're going to add two curves
with their control points to my path and
then finally set that path on my
shapewear
the next set of properties
control how what the line looks like and
there's a few particularly interesting
properties
on the line the first is the line cap
property
this defines what the enzyme each line
look like by the voltage to flatline
in this case we're going to sit around
line cap on them to give them a nice
rounded effect
the line dash pattern defines
how we draw dashed lines and gives you a
lot of control over what that looks like
he create a line dash pattern by giving
us an array
Amanda numbers and we go through this
array to decide how many points to draw
and then how many points to not drop so
in this example
were asking the CSA player to draw for
two points
and then not draw for four points draw
for six
and then not draw for the final six and
then repeat that pattern
across the link to the line wind dash
phase is used to control how far into
that array we start the blind dry
so I something aligned us there is a for
essentially ships that dash
pattern four points along line the next
set of properties
relate to the stroke up the line which
is what we actually draw
like those obvious one it's called
stroke color
and as you would expect it defines the
color line
pretty straightforward to use the help
the next two are a little bit more
interesting
and that's the stroke again and stroke
and properties
stroke again defines how far into the
line
we're going to begin stroking it are
drying it in the video above
I'm actually drawing the original path
in a dark red behind that
so you can see the difference between
the actual what the code is doing
so I setting are struggling and 2.2
we're going to skip drawing the first 20
percent on the line
stroke and is very similar
but defines how far from the end we're
going to draw that perhaps so I think
it's points6
we're going to not draw the final 60
percent in the past you can imagine this
particular property
we very powerful if you are creating a
download control
because you could take that download
progress from 0 to 100 percent
and directly map that onto the stroke
and property
on CA shapewear which is again animated
so the shapers automatically going to
end in a between states for you
the final property that you'll probably
find useful in some cases
is the fill color you always want to add
still color
it doesn't always look awesome but it's
a very powerful thing to have you want
more of a close-packed
shape layers also could have a big
impact on the rendering performance in
your application
so let's go back to that rendering
pipeline one more time
in this case shape layers have an impact
on all the rendering that occurs within
your application itself
and as a few things that we wanna talk
about when you're entering shape layers
when you have a shapewear we have to
rest rise the shapewear
on the CPU within your application what
that means
is what we're doing all your view
drawing we're going to actually have to
ask the shapewear to compute itself
and then draw into essentially image
that we can composite later
we're going to some that restaurants
lehrer over to the render server for
later compositing
and this process can get very expensive
in terms of CPU time
especially if you have a very complex
path for shapewear
the more complex it is the longer it's
going to take us to draw
and prepare that shapewear so one thing
you can do to minimize that affect
is using use more layers with less
complexity
and then stack them behind each other to
get the same effect that you're asking
for
for example with that download control
that showing the downloads a
you might want to draw the square is
once a player the outer ring as a second
shape layer
and ensure the download progress as a
third shapewear and then composite the
three of them together by just stacking
them in the same place
in your view hierarchy you should also
be very conscious
a frequent changes to shape layers
within your application
everytime shapewear changes we have to
redress to rise at
and send that new result over to the
render server so if your shape layers
changing every frame
were constantly having to read ride and
hand this new object of
which can get very expensive have a
negative impact on Europe's performance
I actually have a shape layer hidden in
the demo application that we've been
taking a look at
so I'd like to show you how that's
implemented and then we'll make a couple
quick changes to the appearance of my
shapewear
so first let's see where that
we look in the demo application you
probably noticed this to controls that I
haven't touched yet
and those affect the line and and the
dash size
suffering the stroke and all the way up
to 100 percent and you see I suddenly
get this nice
red box its the world's most interesting
shapewear
I also have a deaf size property the
controls the link to the dashers
in that a red suffering I def size up
we're creating a dashed line effect
instead
every bring the stroke and back down to
something else like sixty-eight percent
you can see we're only drawing the first
sixty-eight percent of the line
by say players line starts in the upper
left corner and then progresses around
the box from that
let's take a look at how this is
implemented in code and make a couple
quick changes to it
what I've done is that created a custom
you love you subclass
I'm calling shape feel and my shape feel
like all news and I West is backed with
a CA layer
we give you the ability to actually
override what kind of player
your view is backed with by implementing
the layer class method
and I've asked my view to be backed with
the CA shapewear instep
in my week from the I'm going to do some
configuration work to create that
shapewear
the first then we'll deal is create a CG
path raff and trade with the rectangle
that represents my views balance
that's how we're creating that nice
simple square shapewear
we set the path and then spent some time
configuring a few the properties of my
shapewear
the stroke color again is what defines
the color we use to draw the outside on
the pathway
in this case a red color we're sending
our line with 26
to make a nice invisible on top in the
background ahead
the stroke and started 0 Sat Nav you
would see the shapewear in advance
I also have the line joining wine join
defines what the corners on those lines
look like when they come together
and were defaulting that to around join
we're also saying the line cap
which is again what controls the edges
in each line and making those round as
well
and finally I'm not using it tho color
for my shapewear
down here at the bottom I have two
methods that are used to configure
properties
based on those controls that you see on
screen one controls the stroke and
the other setting that lined Ashley
right now what I'm doing is making an
array
that creates to Ennis numbers that use
the same value for both
the this is to draw and the distance not
to drop
we're going to make a change to that
first I've decided that
the dash is just got too close to each
other so instead what we're going to do
is first is the same in this number to
draw for a distance
and then we're going to multiply that by
four to have a much larger gap between
our daschle's
I'm also going to make a quick change
two-line join up my shapewear
and switch over to a bevel angina let's
take a look at those changes in the demo
application now
so again we're gonna bring that stroke
and all the way up first to see the
changes we've made
and the first thing you see is the
change that we made to the line joining
if you take a look at the corners of my
boxers instead of having then I
surrounded the fact
they've just nice like diamond-cut champ
from the edge that looks fantastic
we're also going to take a look at those
deaf size changes we made sold out that
up a bit
and you see a dramatic difference in
what we had before we're drawing a very
short dash
followed by a much longer gap
and again just illustrate those changes
let style some these effects back
and you can again see the difference
this makes are shapewear
now you might have noticed in code that
I have a tap gesture recognizer setup
on my shapewear let's take a look at
what that's doing
every time a tap on my shape layer I'm
picking a random
alpha value to animate to and changing
the opacity of my view
and at the same player itself
it's an interesting effect but it's
kinda boring and I'd like to do
something a little more interesting from
a user's
and to do that we're going to take a
look at how we can create dynamic
behaviors
with poor animation as you're probably
aware
you like it and %um you provide a lot of
interesting innovations
for your application and you have a lot
of control over how these animations
look
and behave core animation provides
implicit animations on your layers
nearly every property that you would
change on a layer will be implicitly
animated bike or animation
that means you set the property and CA
will just provide an animation from the
current value to the new value for you
automatically what you might not be
aware of
US a developer have the ability to
override the implicit behaviors that
core animation provides to you
and you might be thinking that's nice
what what I want to do with that
one thing you can do is you can just
disable the implicit animations
even to say I you know I don't I don't
want any other nations thanks anyway
don't do anything at all and that's fine
you can also use the steak capability
to change the behavior of the default
animations the coronation provides
for example you might want to have your
your lair or your view
show different color while the opacity
animation takes place
you also might decide that you're
implementing OS 10 we'd and you won't
have that path
be less than linear as it moves from
point A to point B
if you're to create a new CA lehrer
subclass you can also add your own
properties
and they can enable with this technique
the key part of this is that we can use
this technique to define behaviors
that are inherent to custom views within
your application
this encapsulates any custom animation
behaviors you'd like
and bakes them into the view itself so
if you want to reuse this view
elsewhere in your app or in a framework
it just comes along as part of the view
how these work
in this case I have my view which like
all views and I owe us
is backed with the CA late
CA layers have a seattle Mayor Daley a
protocol the all the views implement
and your view is always the what the
delegates for its layer
so it's a my application I want to
animate the Alpha
I'm calling you have %um it with
duration and setting the Alpha on my
view
20.2 let's take a look at the steps that
take place when we request this
you see a layer is going to ask its
delegates action for layer
for key and that's going to be called on
my custom view
if you haven't implemented this it will
automatically go to the superclass
if you have implemented it you have a
couple options
the first thing you can do is called
back to your super class and just say
action for layer key and pass the same
result back on
to Coronation if you decide that you
would like to have a little bit more
control over the animation
instead you can create
a new action result and pass that back
you create objects that conform to the
CA action protocol
and hand that new action object back to
Coronation
the CA action protocol defines a single
method
run action for key object arguments
and you can implement the CA action
protocol on any object
typically want to just make this on and
as object a very nice lightweight object
to pass back to core animation
you can do whatever you would like in
the implementation abroad action for key
typically you're going to want to
actually run some animations there
but you might decide you'd like to do
something else fires and notifications
starter cancel timers keep out or
something
whatever your minds come up with you can
do whatever you like and run action for
key
this two arguments in here there
particularly interesting
the first is the key this specifies what
property
just changed on the CA l'air that you're
being asked to interact with
the second is the object argument this
is providing a reference
to the CA lair that's being animated
right now for having values change i
right now
and this is how you have access to the
new values that have been set
as well as how you can apply these
changes to the lair that you've been
manipulated
it's hard to talk about this and slides
so on said let's take a look at it back
in the demo application
we're going to go back to my shape you
class
have decided I'd like to add some
custombehavior for when the opacity
changes on my lair
and on my view the first thing you need
to do
is create a new object that conforms to
the CA action protocol
to do that I've defines and opacity
action object
and it has a single method and its
implementation run action for key
object arguments let's take a look at
some other steps we're making here
the first they were going to do is
checked what the events is that's being
asked for this animation
are for this action and we're only
interested into doing things here
if the layer's opacity was asked to
change
and we give myself a nice pointer to the
CIA later that was passed in
and define a duration to use for all of
my animations
I'm going to create three see a basic
animations from application
that take place when is a pass the
change occurs what I've decided I'd like
to do
is have the background color of my layer
change as the opacity and needs as well
and we really do that with these few
steps
now the things I'd like you to notice is
first the from value
coronation needs to know what to start
an animation with and what
ended with the from value is a finding
the beginning at that
now my lair already has the new value
set on it
when my action object is call
which means I need to know what it looks
like on screen and layers provide
what they call a presentation layer the
presentation layer
is a representation what the lehrer
looks like on-screen to the user
at that instant in time some asking my
presentation layer for its current
background color
to be the starting point in this
animation my to value
is the new value that we're requesting
and what I'm doing here
is animating changes to the hue value
and leaving the saturation and
brightness alone
if you're not familiar with Q saturation
and brightness even think about the
color wheel
where the hughes defining what point
along that circle
what color using so we're taking a pass
the value
and use that to define by Hugh I'm also
going to make the same animation to the
stroke color is mild shapewear
but this time we're going to use some
modifications to the value that we're
setting on the hill
and then finally I do in fact want to
end with the opacity myself
and since I'm overriding the action I
have to provide my own
a pass the animation as well saw set
that's
using the same presentation layer and
the two value
and that's all there is to making a new
action object now I need to make sure
that my action object is actually going
to get call
we're going to do that within my layers
to implement air my views implementation
itself
so I view is going to implement action
for lehrer for key this is that CA lair
delegate method
it's pretty straightforward I will check
if I'm being requested to make provide
an action for the opacity
value if I do I L again that a new
instance half mile past the action
and head back to Coronation in all other
cases
I'm Way call through to my super class
and allow the default behaviors
to be returned and those are the steps
we need to take
to provide a custom CA action within
your application
let's see what effect that has on our
box
sore back in the demo app again I'm
gonna bring that box all the way up to
full visibility
and to make sure that it's you're really
gonna stand out will bring some more
colors into things as well
actually I like it with los colores so
that
preloved SI's on just for fun not
remember the way this is configured
is I'm going to tap on the box which
will pick a random opacity value
and animate to that over the newly
defined point seven five second duration
whenever we get that you'll pass a value
we're also going to animate the hue up
the background color
and the stroke see can see every time I
step on that
we're getting a very interesting set of
color combinations
and we're also still making changes to
the background very interesting and
their unique effects
we can see the opacity better this way
the opacity is changing
alongside the hue for the backgrounds
and the stroke colors
and the really powerful part of the way
I built this is all these behaviors are
inherently part
my custom view so anytime I use that
view
I can add it to my view hierarchy
anywhere in the apt and I don't have to
remember to and they all three
properties
I just set the Alpha at automatically
gets all the new behaviors
that I've requested a really powerful
capability
so to summarize what we've talked about
today
we presented for new techniques the
first is how you can use fring
animations
in your application think about spring
animations as a new timing curve for
animations within your application
the make them fit in better with the
rest the platform and feel more dynamic
engaging for users UN official affect
you
is a great new API energy since I was 8
the light to create live
blur effects as well as vibrancy to keep
content highly legible
on top of blurs say shapewear allows you
to define custom busy a pass
and running within your application and
enemy changes to those properties
and we talk about how do you see a
action to get more dynamic behaviors
out of core animation if you'd like to
learn more about these technologies
there's some great documentation are for
you like it
and for coronation you can also talk to
Jake he's %ah wraps framework evangelist
his great shoes and he loves getting
email from olive you there's some
fantastic news that
sessions going on this week the talk
about more these type
topics we've covered many that happened
yesterday as can be a fantastic session
on Friday at 11:30 in Presidio
I really encourage you to check out
thanks for coming I hope you enjoy the
rest your time
have you ever this is