okay eyler body my name's that they've
also my money i at team
I'm here talking about optimizing your
earning power with
I add for this view don't know
somehow I as apples to do it advertising
platform this is what you use to you
have seen it in
other app soviet-style s accusations
radio and all the ads you see it in 3d
return my iPad
so that's what hired his other two parts
this presentation
really talking first about modernization
how you can
use I had inside your apt to drive
revenue for your app's
a and the second part is promotion are
you can use I had
to get more downloads erupting users
your app take
get your app how in everyone else's
hands Sault star of monetization
sort of fewer pieces talk about here
part but some developer benefits what I
acting do for you
part watson core concepts certain
advertising 101
we'll talk about improving performance
how you can best
use I added get the most out of it we'll
talk some
details about the actual code you have
to write in a great I had inside your
app which is
for sleep pretty simple what little
about testing I had making sure your
gracious actually working
for you now on the App Store and then
just get pucks so it start off with
developer benefits you
up for small I had provides rich
engaging this is a
platform that value great ads to go into
the great aP's
you create their high production values
rich media absent rich media ads
involved here these are things that
involve
video they involve animations their
immersive
these are sometimes entire games
presented inside
ads other isn't allowed recently that
was literally a game once ap
on it this is you things that your users
are actually interested in engaging on
interested in tapping which is great for
you as
a drivers publisher is our award-winning
at
you're not just fly by night you know
one of taps her ads with
link tags and then they're going to
annoy the heck users is a carefully
crafted at
that actually look good as part of your
in addition
Apple is providing this SDK I
as a result the same care that Apple
takes
with respect to privacy and power
efficiency on the rest
Apple system Apple invest in hired as
well
that means that we take care all love
the
power and privacy considerations for you
so you don't have to worry about them
no need to worry about a ban would add
tracking switch
you know by Eva your don't worry about
location permissions
or making sure that your users privacy
and personal data is protected properly
in addition
because this is an apple right STK its
party the IRS 2k
integration is simple there's nothing
else to installer no
static libraries to include there's no
third-party headers to
drop in your project clear things up
it's all there to begin with
be up and running with minimal code see
later
it's about two lines of code to get
banners in your in addition
along with the rest of the coded other
her with the rest to the SDK that apple
provides great documentation great
sample code available to you
on the web sites I did global reach
for fourteen countries now a costly
expanding
larger list two countries than we showed
up here last year a
that means that you're going to get ads
in all those countries
inside your app so soon as you get your
ap in all those countries
you're going to get revenues countries
as well just like
the actual app purchase and then in app
purchases as well
journey get seventy percent of the
advertising revenue from I at insider
Apple takes a 30 percent share and
everything else goes to you
from whatever we taken from the
advertisers producing these add
to run insider its
very easy for you to get into the IET
ecosystem
I a contract on the iTunes Connect Apple
com site you have to sign
that's pretty easy here at the I a
framework that's what the rest the stock
is going to be about
and they submit your app review and
that's really all you have to do
okay so that's sort of what I can do for
you talk about some core concept teaser
some fundamental basics advertising and
some terminology
you're going to see especially on the
iTunes Connect website 12 integrated I
at
and are trying to track the progress you
getting revenue from my it inside your
first well there's an add request you
see this come up
again later you'll see this and metrics
where that request
at the network arrest acres from the
device through the IET framework
its gonna go out to the I ad servers up
the crowd
and hopefully ads will come back down to
you a similar ads available for your
a particular app in the current
situation up
you know again if the user is in a
country where not in
your community at their Fort
once you start getting ads from be
difficult request
you want to look at your story this is
the ratio
ads delivered by the ad server to the
number request that you actually make to
the server
this is again in beats per min by where
users are located
what type ap you have how well your app
is done with I had in the past
we'll get to that little bit a little
later as to how that can be
really important driving your story
once you got Nats a your got near 48
shown as the user
there's Picasa call the tapori this is
the number
the ads that your user has actually
tapped on and thats
does not count %uh accidental caps at
the top if
taps on it includes a cousin really mean
it that doesn't count
number tops that the user actually meant
to have happen
relative the number as you displayed
user this is something you attempt to
maximize inside
your again though accidental caps don't
count so
trying to play games not a good idea
at engagement
obviously you need to display the app
erupts when the add to the user doesn't
matter how many have the request from
the server
you're not going to get paid for them I
and at you might as well not bother
want to do that make sure actually fully
visible
as well %uh the fact that it's on screen
and only one pixel over showing because
you've got it covered up with something
else
that doesn't really count either I'll
you wanna make sure that the ad is
visible for as long as possible
leave it on screen again if it shows up
and flashes for two seconds known Norris
I
doesn't matter you wanna make sure to
add her on screen this is
has to benefits 1 it's not distracting
to your user
unknowing people by flashing things on
and off screen all the time that people
really don't see
in addition the user has time to
interact with their time see it
its icy its message their time you say
hey you know that actually like to tap
on this
engaged with and see what's going on
I that reason to allow interaction
really easy to put something on screen
accidentally cover up especially
actually covering up for something the
block user interaction
he put a banner on screen you cover up
with something that is a
transparent you that does not allow user
traction
can't happen again turn good that I get
situation for the ad users can be trying
to tap on it
nothing's going to happen hi it's very
bad experience
in addition again your act together
revenue you're hoping for in a certain
situation
because the I wasn't really on screen
gets us some socks for core concepts
talk a little about
what you can do to improve the
performance I at once you
actually integrated insider first row
revenue starts with your ap I if you
have a great app
it doesn't matter how many energy show
doesn't matter how many show
know when using your app and you're not
going to make any money so the number
one thing you can do you
to drive revenue ads in your app start
off with great
that's what the rest up to this is about
but a couple
so small things we can mention here
first or
ap engagement I'm if you're if it
happens
you're trying to drive revenue by
showing an you need to make sure that
you have sufficient engagement time for
users to actually
do this if it's a utility app that the
user is going to pull up
it's gonna be on screen for about three
seconds and then they're going to
closure app again
that's not enough time to actually show
at Caesars allow interaction
and get interaction from those users so
you needn't out
actually is going to be on-screen and
that you actually want to engage again
%uh once you've done that you wanna make
sure that the ad is placed carefully
with in that
think about what the users doing on the
various screens your app make sure the
ad is placed
appropriately within the app if you
could gain for instance
a and the user's tapping and swiping
placing constantly
maybe that's not a great place for
banner where they're going to be
actually tapping
the ad will pop up over the top of
everything you're going to be knowing
your users
and you're going to be harming your app
morning here
helping it with
up phone back into wrapping it in time
user loyalty
you need to come unique users to come
back to the apt
the app repeatedly that's how you get
more screen time that's
more time for this particular for
showing ads to users
in addition your loyalty is what drives
I had
ap engagement with tribes app downloads
serve
network effects never before more people
re: using your apt more
they want to use it morning to tell
their friends about using an
more down you're going to get therefore
the more i bothering it looking at
within your
I'll I mentioned that I as in 14
countries
that means that your ap should be in 14
countries if you want
get as most the most revenue from as you
can
market your apt to the country's were I
it actually is
your if spent the time in a great I it
into your app
you wanna make sure the rap is in all
the places that I it is see you have
the largest reach possible to
potentially get the most users
possible for your a big part of that is
localizing your the only thing you've
done is right here happen English
you're trying to get in all 14 these
countries are gonna have a hard time in
countries
where English is a small presence but
you take the time to look closer
appropriately
drive users in those country
back into ad placement a little bit
because this is a
the sonic you coming back to you ad
placement is
extraordinarily important thing
you'll recognize hi use areas inside
your am
you wanna make sure you put banners
inside those areas there's the places
where users are going to be a
looking at screen for a long period of
time to have the opportunity to see the
app
the at their apt to engage with yet
at the same time as I mentioned avoid
actor perhaps
axle caps are bad for user and they're
bad for you
%uh they're gonna know your user and ir
doesn't like actual taps either's
you wanna make sure you are using the
framework in a way that does not
encourage them
is your Apple ultimately end up being
penalized for this
your contacts is really important unit
taken into different types of ads based
on what the users doing a given time
say the user is on the menu screen your
game maybe that's a great post
banner at the bottom screen looking at
the menu maybe they noticed the app
at the at the bottom maybe happening
gate with
the same time if they tap to go to the
first love your game
and you immediately Papa full-fledged
add an interrupt their experience what
they've
once they've done their first actions
game that's just going to annoy them
you're gonna drive users away
want to engage with the ad that's what
you want to try to avoid
be very careful about where you're
putting ads within your
once you've integrated I add new can
start looking on the website
you'll start getting reports about your
revenue when things are gonna notice
everyone always nurses and brings I'm is
that revenue will fluctuate
this is perfectly natural consumer
spending is seasonal
advertiser spending is also seasonal
because consumer spending is
you need to be aware of this and watch
for it you can also take advantage of
this
market your app accordingly started
summer
back to school holiday season these are
the times when
users are going to out to get new
devices going
how to get new maps and advertisers a
going out to get
eyeballs insiders maps so that's when
you want rain get
dude try and put all your money and
pushing your app
okay we talked about ads talk about
impressions
talk about captors we talked about rate
this is a virtuous cycle gonna get as to
begin with
they really don't pressions impressions
are lead to tap throughs
more tapped as you get more agile and
get from the ad server
corporations are gonna get
okay so that performance now we've done
that knowing going it's an actual
details about how you
actually about a great deal stuff
certain me to stock
as for a performance banner as
interstitial ernie direct
and there's a pre-roll video ad we'll
talk about it these foreign
turn I as I mentioned earlier you can
watch you the correct
add for your app in the various contexts
within your app
so all four these types of ads are
important
from many many perhaps
start of a banner
so what is a banner slim device with you
both bought a mature content
continuously load ads United other
I S Decatur at a stick is where you got
makes
West this isn't that you create a view
shop the bottom the page
and continuously load ads over time as
new as a delegate from the answer
something you have to do to manage that
one sees a taps on it going going some
sort of four screen at experience
at supportable iPhone iPad has been
since the beginning I
integrating banners in your app is about
the simplest thing that you could do
there's three steps this you can link
the IET framework
you're going to you import the IOD
import the I editor which is the first
line up there and reconfigure your view
controller which involves setting
can display banner ads property yes on
your controller
that's it if you've done that you've got
a banner inside your apt
so does that look like okay loading at
you got your review the moment you set
the can display banner ads property on
it
we're gonna do something under the hood
to your view controller
your view is going to turn into original
content
we're gonna move your view over to
original content you and we're gonna
take a review in your view controller
very important for you to remember subs
subsequently attempted to access your
view on that you can't roller
willing to make a request that the ad
server to come back and hopefully a
better
load at that time we're going to you
move the banner on-screen resize your
account
you appropriately with the for free
animation to move the thing on screens
user can actually look at it
want to spend on screen for a while over
the years gonna go ahead tap on it
at that point before screen at
experience gonna pop up
when that happens a couple things you
need to do for switches to pause
activity if you will disappear your app
is probably doing things the background
banners on screen when the user wants to
engage with the ad you want to get
out of the way if you're playing music
if you're running a game simulation you
doing anything else
tensely intensive or distracting
menopause activity and you will
disappear
so that it out of the way at
eventually the user will be done
interacting with the ample dismiss it
you know yet if you did appear resume
all that activity
has gone you wanna start the music up
again you wanna start games
nations her
eventually said user goes out of network
connectivity or something
you may not have an Advil anymore when
that happens
the better going to be moved off-screen
your original content you will be
resized
and and you can to wait hopefully
reloads again
in addition to waiting for the network
connectivity just movie bareback
screen you can control the better
visibility whenever you would like
if something happens within your app
that you would like to move to bear on
screen Temperley
go ahead and do so just go ahead and set
can display banner ads
no just don't forget said backed yes
when you wanna re enable it actually put
that back on screen
whenever you actually need
okay that betters what's likely
interstitials next
second major type banner her to batter
very different and better rather than
something being permanently on screen
their immediate for screen display
immediately take over the entire screen
when you want present them
is very is immediately able to interact
with them
they were iPad since I was 4.3 and their
interest
on phone in Iowa 7 last year
there's two major ways to handle
interstitial presentation
first automatic presentation just like
banners
it's pretty simple to configure here
residents I think and display banner ads
you're gonna set interstitial
presentation policy
eighty interstitial presentation policy
automatic
what that does is tell the I framework
hey this is a great view controller
show ads all and whenever you as the eye
from work thinkers
great time ads go ahead and do so
at moment that means that we're gonna
show ads when this me
it when issue controller for on-screen
it appears
take that as an opportunity to show airs
if one is available
so to do that just take your view
controller put it on screen make
in your allegations back or however you
want on-screen that moves in
and we're gonna pop and add up over top
of it when the user's done interacting
with them
he'll come back all mission to
automatic presentation there's men your
presentation
just a presentation policy to initial
presentation policy manual
and instead of of automatically
presenting it whenever the moves on
screen
you can call request interstitial at
presentation to attempt to display it
whatever you think it's an appropriate
time for at
pop over top your content
next preparing for inter for for
presentation I
because interstitial don't have
something on-screen something
sitting there requesting and attending
this playthings all times
you want to notify the iron framework
that you would like to present printer
future so we can go ahead and make an
add request have an air strikes
interstitial waiting for you when that
time comes
do that you're going to want to you call
you a view controller prepare
interstitial ads inside
something early in Europe's life cycle
application did finish watching
options good opportunity here you doing
a lot of other work
that point maybe for a little bit but
you wanna call this prior to your
attempted
present show for the first time back is
the II framework
enough time got network a question had
have everything ready to present by the
time you walk 12 percent
present prevent you from missing at
opportunities
it's that banners in your specials
where we go from here into a quick demo
a just have
the API's I just went over switch over
to you
my demo machine
I'll or start off with a router from my
lap
is a very simple Master Detail
happier shares news articles i cant
click
here news articles and bring it up and
we would like to take this app
and as a matter monetize I had
cell quits again here
what do you want to do here first first
thing your gonna do
is at a banner the bottom the master
view control at the bar
article list so insider matter view
controller here
we're going to you import the eye at her
like this an inside
a week from New already has cost set can
self Kansas display banner ads yes and
that's really all we have to do
up one more thing we need to go in here
faces and ensure that we link
NCIS framework make sure the
API's are actually available to us back
to you master view controller
run and
will see that with two lines code and
one link
we have enters the bottom or screen and
are automatically
in line with our view controller now
we only set that on the master you can
that means
we go into an article there's no and
there a little bit unfortunate
so the next thing we want to do is take
advantage have
the other time add we talk about
interstitials to present an add
to the user prior to them actually being
able to read the articles
tap on the article title
one at the pop-up up the screen before
they can actually see the article
so what's good with this again
miss time we're going to you
down here inside our prepare for Segway
want set up the detail view controller
that
shows the actual article we're going to
you
grab this destination interstitial
presentation policy
eighty interstitial presentation policy
automatic so we can say that
on this detail you can to learn things
showing the article we want me i a
framework to manage
presentation interstitial ads over top
this
view controller once we've done that
that's gonna get interstitial showed you
control however
we want to make sure that hired from
work knows to go out and look for
interstitials
before the user taps an article for the
first time is to do that when you go
over here bring it to our
app delegate here I was gonna grab you I
view controller
prepare interstitial an ounce make sure
we for the headers well
that so tired hey governor social at so
they're ready for
are you there and save this run our
demo again once again
at the article view here we've got a
pair looked at the bottom that happened
now on taps nurse the
interstitial as going to pop up over top
the article
once the hurry time's expired user done
interacting with this
thinking going close that and the
article behind and they can go in Surrey
article so that's basically how easy it
is
to you integrate banners and
interstitials
to your am so go back to sleep
it so it's better than your specials for
the first two major types
%uh ads for I add they're also the first
two types
as I those are the ones are available
from the beginning I
a couple newer types that we've got
first you type
some prepares sorry
for small use can't believe in rats
and initial presentation policy under
controllers
as much as possible we talked about had
engagement we talked about the user
having the opportunity to see the ads
leaving them on screen is having the
option to engage with yet
setting these properties is a big part
in addition rumor user to content when
you actually use can display banner
it's very important that 12 seconds bear
as you realize that
you've given over control you too the
right framework
and original content view is yours to
continue using
victory transitions for interstitials
think about what your user is
doing at any given time when they're
transitioning from view controller you
controller
and make sure that interstitial
presentation policy automatic
set on the appropriate view controllers
for at the show up
when they first pop-up for instance in
the
news-democrat showed you having that
show up on
the main article: list probably not
appropriate I would just be distracting
and annoying
use having on the article view
controller
on the other hand just gives a gating
function to allowing the user to
actually future content the appropriate
for the interstitial
be consistent writer navigation stacking
yes
up this is particularly important for
navigation controllers
record deep navigation controllers I'll
what I mean by this is in particular
with can display banner
if you have a deep navigation RK you
want to attempt a sec and its way better
at times many
love the view controllers going to
prison pushing in a hierarchy is
possible
to ensure that the ad remains on screen
as the user navigates throughout that
hierarchy
otherwise you have the possibility the
at popping up on screen for second
taps on something akers back away it up
have to something else yet comes back
that's distracting
your user at the same time it doesn't
allow the ad stay on screen
long enough for the user to actually
engage with that
okay now our with their specials
let's talk about media wrecked which is
the next major type
had that I it provides
what is a medium racked is n
International Advertising Bureau medium
rectangle
standard at time positioned in line with
your content
standard I saw as the same size as you
may have seen
browsing the web square rectangular as
in line with wet contact the same type
and got
just like banners they automatically
cycle overtime
so you put them on screen new ads will
be loaded
II framework feel appropriate will
automatically manage making requests and
putting
for you and just like banners
there's a force creat experience once
the taps on engages with this banner
their introduced Iowa 6 on iPad
and happy to announce that and I was 8
we're adding this to phone as well
yet so it's a medium light rectangle
life cycle look like
%uh because these banners are not
managed by the I add
framework a you have to do a little bit
more work
to put these on screen
and create the banner explicitly rather
than just selling property you
controller
you configure delegate school hours tell
you when certain things happen we're
getting thicker
this backslide implement the delicate
protocol
so you can actually take their citizens
thing on and off screen as the
better load on loans
show the banner when you receive the
better view did load and property
are dog collar you're gonna pause
activity
in better view action should begin will
leave application this is analogous
to getting you will disappear message
from
interstitials or banners and
you want to resume activity and
interview action finish analogous to you
will
here your high the banner
interview did fail to see that there
important this indicates that year
better no longer has loaded should no
longer be taking up space on screen
so does look like first or creating
better
import the I had her Top Gear
implement a deep interview delegate on
whatever object you would like to
actually be managing this particular
banner
there to create the better view do that
with in it with at type
Adia type medium rectangle and there to
set the delegate
to the object implementing tell your
protocol
sort that out a protocol like home first
I was a me im recollection costar
unloaded we first create there's nothing
in there women request
something to put on screen so don't put
it on screen when you first created
it's just going to be a blank slide and
we're gonna send you an air
once you get a better view did your dad
that's your cue that
there's an ad available inside your
redirect you should move it on-screen
early the better on screen as long as it
has an remember to
that this was something its first
repositioned in line with your content
when you move it on screen when you
leavin screen make sure that it
within the rest if your company if you
have an article and you put me in right
on screen with the article texan flow
rounded inside ScrollView scroll with
the
rest your content that's what this type
at is intended
for
remove the bareback off-screen better
viewed it failed to receive
with their again once you move it off
screen is your responsibility to reflow
your content
to fill the hole left by the
at that time 10 screen your ebook
this is what better loading or unloading
to look like you're in there is too
important tell your call backs here
interview did load and I in which case
is gonna put the banner on screen
randall layer a better view detailed
receive an
air he removed from the review you need
to converse
again layout free for your content
around the whole
left by the bear
the best practices from erecting again
this a great for reform content
the sort of thing put inside ScrollView
within
the rest your content that may scroll up
and down
along the device thing on and off-screen
its
sort static with the rest your content
flows around
fill the hole with inside the space on
screen
it's got a full screen out on top.
remember that
a tension that they are they'll get call
backs for will begin action
did finish actions you can pause and
resume activity
positive interview action should begin
and resume activity in the interview
action finish
thats medium rectangle little bit more
complicated than the banner
because you have to manage position
yourself but still fairly simple to
implement
okay fourth typeof ad that we're talking
about here
is the pre-roll
was a pre-roll video pre-roll it's a
short video that place between
before your own media content
for screen at on tap just like the other
better times
added Iowa 7 and
and I 07 we had on MP movie player
controller
and knew it I was it we're also adding
it on AV player view controller
you a ticket visitor introduced to DC
this is available on both iPhone and
iPad it has been since
action I wanna circle back to the very
first
bullet here short video please refer
content this is really important
this is not an interstitial style this
is something we played before your
contacts so you need to make sure that
you actually
a video to play after we don't want
not support for you to attempt to use
this just you land random at Interbrand
I'm sure that you have content followed
so the
API sign for
so setting up in playback also fairly
straightforward here sort of by linking
the media player I
frameworks important media I at heathers
a great player help pre-roll video
an airplane cockpit video very
straightforward it
almost all those except the IOD thats
and they play pre-roll
you already have to do if you got your
own assist few
pay additional lines so is that look
like
first important nuclear import I had
Creek and in the player controller in it
was cut in Euros you already would
add that movie player into your you
iraqis
on-screen called your layout for once
there as well and their call play
pre-roll ad with completion
input call this unserved immediately
calling plan this still
I add hey try to put a pre-roll video in
there if you've got one
play that first this takes a completion
handler
return air possibly if something went
wrong inside the completion handler is
your cue to start
your content you wanna make sure you
don't automatically for your country you
wanna Paul your company until this
actually begins
playing or two the people finishes plane
you want to begin your
content for a ticket
almost identical occurred if the player
view controller insider
import the ATK headers a and your call
again played hero I with completion
handler as identical semantics
and media player controller ones inside
the completion handler
your call player play to start your own
video-content
afterward this is new I see
just like interstitials because this is
something that is going to happen at
some point
and you won't have I it prepare for need
tell the IAC from work hey
I'm gonna what play freerolls in the
future
that allows us to the opportunity to go
out the ad server grab ads
and be ready for your request freerolls
that we can actually play one when the
user does something that requires it
to do that just interstitial don't miss
these early impressions
to get a lost art add request early by
calling MP movie player controller
prepare pre-roll ads again probably
application did
launching options or some other early
wraps life cycle period so we haven't
had an opportunity to get
hats for you before you call guys
if using AB kit almost ethical I every
player controller prepare
croats instead
go best practices for video then
don't play content until the I completes
if you called a pre-roll ad and
ap second later you call play before
with culture
which inhaler we're going to interrupted
you know killing is a very common case
for this
this can interrupt playing a free ride
me it's kept going to go to your content
like the ad never played except that
it's poor user experience for users
you'd like to try to avoid this one
possible so make sure that you
wat into our completion call to call
play
for verifications is frequently means
recording the fact your content is
ready if you're already calling plane is
notifications arm and search cause
calling play
record that fact inside the completion
handler check for that fact and then
call play
so early the for UI customization
many in aging UI customization topple
the media player controller present
custom controls are present custom UI
rounded
week you that until after we called
handler
the Pierre already has custom UI you
don't interfere with our custom UI
with your own customization that again
going to perform
provider poor experience for users
okay so now we've got that would go back
to our demolition here in a quick demo
setting
that up as well
its cool those him
that hola
quick little demo this as well
run this this is a very simple little
app just provides a few
quick little video clips here can click
on a visa and
got a quick video now what I'd like to
do is now that I've got this
video-content
my user id like to engage with I can
monetize this by playing a pre-roll ad
prior to the user actually being able to
view my clips
skirt and quickness and see what we have
to do to get that done
we can star of your the very first thing
to do
is as for dinner specials wanna make
sure that we tell
I had hey I'm gonna be playing career I
it's go fetch them early
start off in our app delegate here
and we will import
I Adam wimpy import the media player so
we have the perfect classes for APRs
and well go ahead and call repair
pre-roll ads on MTV Movie Player
controller once we've done that we need
to actually
incall prepare paper Lance so we're
going to our
view controller here which is doing
actual display
and we're going to scroll down to at the
bottom here
collection you did select adamant index
per this is
what happens when you're actually caps
on it at the moment all we're doing is
creating
MP movie player view controller saying
the content URL
and then calling present the player to
have to start playing automatically
we wanna sorta interrupt that briefly
and instead we're gonna go ahead and
call
play pre-roll at which completion
handler
and again inside the completion handler
to that that's run a call
and PE the controller the player play
backups top here and ensure that we are
importing I as well so we get the I add
API's available
good save that we can run again
this is where I know it's going to you
want to help you to go in here
make sure that the eye at framework is
linked
out there can we gotta add up
where a ap up here again same
quickly videos we can go ahead and click
on one of these now
and before the video-content actually
play as you see that we've got an iPad
workbench ap at the comes up instead
user can
you this a add content once they're done
with it they can cite
skip had a bit and we owe me it back to
you
the video content for the app itself
and that's pretty much all its involved
in
implementing freerolls what you've
already got a media player content for
their pre role to play in front of
okay so those or the four different
types
I'll ads we have for integration with I
had inside your apt
up what you're using now let's talk a
little about testing
for small their couple things we add
we've added to the developer settings on
the phone
to help you test the integration I it
within your
first you can adjust the story this is
inside the the app's the you have when
you're testing them on the device
you can just how frequently you're going
to get ads as well as you test air
conditions
large test always working additions and
make sure that your app handles those
conditions
appropriately in addition you can adjust
the refresh rate
for things like banners and medium racks
this is going to just frequency with
which
new ads come in in addition in
combination with the store rain
this allows you to rapidly test error
and non air-conditioned
moving thing on an off-screen
most importantly there's a switch call
hi likely banners
if you're using the can display banner
ads this
isn't going to affect enters very much
but this is very important from medium
racked
it's very easy to accidentally occlude
part of the medium wracked with some
other UI element
if you do that that's part of the medium
wrecked that may not be seen by User
its part in the medium wrecked you that
user may not be able to tap on interact
with
this will the text back you turn on the
highlight clip banners
button we're gonna provide a greener red
overlay over your meeting wrapped
or bears are insists that matter that
will show
when the user can actually tap on all
parts this better
when it is officially on-screen
invisible you wanna make sure that any
banners show inside your apt are always
green
remember this only affects your aP's
your developer mode adds
to you run from xrecord and deployed
onto your device
so now you can just store it 0 for all
the other I at
using ap psych advice only affects
developer aP's
okay so that's mine is Asian assert the
first major portion
talk talk next a little bit about
promotion so the other half for the eye
at ecosystem
this is how you can use I add to try
downloads
a your own
so there's three major parts they were
knocked out here for something you
really quick
intro to I at work bench there's another
session on that market
more in detail so it's just a quick
overview and then there are two
new API's they were interesting IOSA one
for ap attribution
and one for app audience sry targeting
talk a little about those new APIs
what sort of the I had workbench was I
had workbench
and workbenches I itself servicing
advertising platform
I especially when app on the Apple dot
com I had work bench that Apple dot com
this is how you can manage being an
advertiser
on at and in create mobile ads
it up later and banners you can use open
templates ignacio I producer
to create your own I had assets
what you've done that you can use this
chip reach the users who are most likely
to
actually download your app I had isn't
iowa's advertising platform you're going
to reach a whole bunch
users who are on i OS who are already
using our app so I less
nor therefore highly likely to engage
with the ad
but advertising Europe and download ap
you can also manage your campaign
performance here this is where you can
see
how you what senior I had how the
campaign is doing
capture rates Center for your particular
advertising campaign
such workbench again there's any other
session tomorrow kind more detail
next important part talk about SM new AP
as we've got for ap
actual bution K what is that actuation
apparition allows you to track app
downloads up your apt that originated
from
I at its gonna let you measure the
effectiveness
love your campaigns you created
workbench that you're running actually
promote your the API's are available at
Iowa 7
are Sarah 7.1 or other and we've
enhanced a little bit and I was
8 as well so that's a new one I'm States
so are the FBI actually look like very
simple genyen include I had
I at that age has everything starts with
for I had
and the recall eighty client shared
client on that in a call lookup
add conversion details
inside that you can use the two eights
that are provided completion handler
to determine whether or not this
particular installation
up the app was due to I had
these dates are gonna give you two
things the first is the ap
purchased any the date at which the user
actually made the purchase of this and
and
then the date the impression the date
that the user sawing interacted with the
ad
prior to them purchasing the amp K
if all these dates are there and true
that can indicate you that as far as I
was concerned
this was a installation if your app
directly attributable to the user
interacting with
seeing eye at promoting your ap
it's very important remember that these
dates are going to be nil
if they're not actually a diode they'll
also be nil if the user has limit ad
tracking so
regardless of whether or not this is an
eye at driven insulation
user has the mad at tracking enabled
they don't want their address and data
tract or shown to perhaps
is going to be no we're not gonna give
you this information cases should be
aware that if you're trying to use this
phrase
analytics in addition
you want to avoid look up so the stain
on every launch I'll try very tempting
to add this to your apt at Finch
launching
look at conversion detail set some state
flag and do something on every single
launch
ap try to avoid doing there is some
costs you
actually doing this' look up you wanna
for doing this look up to you actually
need to you
and in cash today afterwards
sets after bution the next thing we talk
about
is the app audience re targeting APIs is
a new API's IOSA
so what a nap audience regarding again
what is returning allows you to group
the user's a viewer app
that particular audience into various
categories
depending on their activity with in your
app or things you know about them
from their use viewer app
this might be frequent in app purchases
it might be
a very high usage rate relative to other
user here
in my pee Dorman users users who use
drop a while ago but you haven't seen in
a while
you can then use this information to
target new ads
you know I workbench directly its
specific subgroups
up your users to reach specific
audiences
within the user's here
each group defines what we call a
segment
thats terminology to talk to the next
couple slides that's important
no a specific group with your users is
that it
with a specific name is a segment
so why would you want to use let's say
your game app developer
you want to promote the new I had
version of your apt to all your iPhone
users
your we go back in reach those specific
user into hey
I've got a great new a iPad version come
try it again
comeback this app if you read out loud
it there's new features that affect
specific subset severe abd you can use
this to reach those specific users
at going to ensure that the as you
create gonna reach precisely the
audience your
tempting target with that
%uh visit similarly you can really good
doormen users to get
users that you haven't seen while you
can craft a message
specifically designed to try to pull
those people back in your apt to
reengage those users may not
strapping sometime
if your retail app instead for similar
reasons to use this
you can remind users may have abandoned
a shopping cart your app
segment as in something send them a
message hey you can your shopping cart
maybe should come back and
being ate with this app a few store
purchase those things
if you got loyal customers maybe you
wanna sell a special offer may be onto
something a gift for being a loyal
customer
you can't do that with an attitude well
you can reach target specific
ads to specific segments users
if they've you grouped customers into
specific categories based on their
previous purchases you can promote sales
based on their previous purchases
all these are done by segmenting those
users and specific groups
and recording that city you can we
engage with those users
specific acts so I was actually work
first thing it using on I work engineer
going to create
segments a rest tell I workbench hey I'm
gonna groupie people and
ten different segments please give me
some segment fires to use for that
support to notice that you cannot create
segment specific segment identifiers
I workbench doesn't stead and this is
partially for privacy reasons
we manage the specific segment
identifiers
once you've done that you doin up to
your app and take avenge the new APIs
you can actually associate specific
segments with specific users
makers at the server so we can actually
record that information
what's that done you go back to at work
bench and you create your
new workbench campaign re target those
customers with some specific
at message okay so
how do you actually do this actually
very simple on the client side
you're going to you include I had you
want to create an array of segments
and these are segments the second
identifiers in which you already gotten
from work bench
you attempt to send random segment evers
attired we're just going to ignore them
make sure you're using the ones already
created and set up inside workbench
so maybe you decided segment a is loyal
users segment be as frequent purchases
and you wanna so she ate the current
user with those two segments
increase segment array with segments in
it
and your call 80 clients your client ad
plant two segments
replace existing I this
is by default would replace existing no
going to add
these segments to the current user if
instead you like to say hey these are
all the segments I'd like to associate
the user
which might also like to remove all
segments user
you can just update that replace
existing yes just completely replace the
old set
with news
okay so thats basically I at
for promotion the new AP as a bat an
eyelid say
so what we learn
for solar some best practices for using
I had reporter notes banners
we've doctor for not sad to talk about
as a banner there's interstitial
as a medium racked and as a pre-roll
they all have their place
take revenge the different ad formats
that we've given to you
think about where they belong in your
out and
make sure you use the appropriate at for
the appropriate contacts
as part of that consider the user when
you're placing thats yes
ads are very valuable for generating
revenue from your apt I had can help a
lot pitting
but great revenue in great app star
with great users well your own alienate
all users
by horror ad placement but poor adchoice
you're not actually going to happen that
way you want
really make sure you hear center focus
to where you're picking
to put ads whichever actor choosing to
put their
in addition
there's a cycle here between
monetization and promotion
K optimize your ads performance to begin
your
ap sad performance to begin with that's
going to generate revenue from it
but don't forget to take a measured by
workbench and really promote your app
it's important to continue to get new
users for your app if you wanna continue
get revenues
from here but to feed into each other
you want to generate revenue
you want Spencer your event re
advertiser Apple acquired
users them
this is our best practices for a for
more information me on this
we've got mark loser I had technologies
evangelist you can reach him
the email address Paul I had programming
guide online /a
it with along with the rest to the IRS
SDK developer
information there's some Apple Developer
forms we monitor
you've got questions UN other developers
and us will be modernised answer
questions
hopefully help you out a couple related
sessions here
ODBC unfortunately remiss the new iTunes
Connect which sucked a little bit about
I add
that was yesterday are you can watch the
video tomorrow morning at nine in Nob
Hill is what's new in I had work bench
was going going to a little bit more
detail about the
actor bution in the audience segment
retarding that I talked about
at the end of this presentation that's
it
thank you very much