good morning everybody
welcome
I think
referencing I Prada long-winded on
Julian mythic
and Mark Allan Stein from a team ok with
this session for today
wealth for developers the company chopin
act when to be expected
solar developers alright
people who don't coated all anyone
alright great very review
and designers designer
yeah I all right and management I'd
I
third out you guys yeah
your plan today
we're gonna design and prototyping ap
we're gonna go through the steps we
would go through to try something out
and we're gonna show you a variety of
different prototyping map it all day
it can be with focus on prototyping
experience not trying on API are testing
out some kind of technical feasibility
so who are we
here we come here and tell you how to
make your apt
well worth mall secret team at Apple we
work across
all about this product we explore what
new interfaces
mean to our devices operating system and
application
and we do this by making interactive
prototypes
everyday sometimes 24 hours a day
said today
you're all very lucky I'm gonna unveiled
all love you today a world-changing
disruptive application
and I'd like to show it to you
right now
different application to explore and
discover artisanal Coast
on the streets of San Francisco browse
for toasted near you
find a poptart in town
going to get food to go share the toast
with your friend
take a picture
share with your friends or loved one
today
I give to you ladies and gentlemen
post-modern
thank you thank you everyone
and it's available now
to go and get a except if not
none of this is real it's just a
prototype
so why why we go to the trouble
creating this beautiful world-changing
disruptive application that is
completely fake
well this is the picture and most people
had
I have an idea then
I build my application then
step 3: profit
except when I see frequently is that
people have an idea the builder
application
and somehow they're disappointed by the
result
maybe the experiences and what you hope
for
maybe just doesn't resonate with your
customers and building applications are
difficult you guys know this takes time
take money people
sleep hard a
and frankly a blood-typing so that want
to work for something
but you're not happy with me and so
instead of going from the idea
directly to building our application
we're gonna go from the idea
to a prototype in Van Gelder application
and its best if we can do that
over and over again the more prototypes
we can put between our idea
in her application the better the result
is going to be
and we we do this is by beginning with
something fake
and then gradually adding elements that
are more real
along the way sprinkling it with
interactivity so they're too important
reasons to prototype want everybody to
keep in mind
threat today number one
if the test ideas to save time and money
building the right things for your
application number two
is to get new ideas to make the
experience up your ap
even better Emir so how do we do that
actually really simple makes a cap
show people and learn from their
feedback
again make fake ap
show people and learn from their
feedback
do that over and over and over again
until the experience severe
out feels great so how do we make fake
gaps for them
well after self three questions before
we begin
the first one is what needs to be more
real
everything else is going to be fake but
what one element
are we trying to explore and get
feedback on the second question
is what can we fake and that everything
out everything else will pretty much
just be a picture
the third important question
is where we'll be in use it we want to
make sure
that if we're making a prototype it
something that we can try out
on the device in the play where people
will be using
so we've made a fake ap
now it's time to show it to people we
wanna after BAM
three questions as we're showing them do
you know how to do
this one particular thing that we have
protect is it
EV to do that thing in general
how can we make a bit better wanna
solicit kinda reform import on how we
can improve our app
you be surprised interesting things
people have to say
so who do we show our fake apt to
make sense the people you're after is
for
so if your apt given for engineers
going fine for people who are not
engineer don't
argued defend or diff
you're not bear to debate the pros and
cons what you prototype
you're there to get information from
people and learn from so we showed some
people
we probably taken from note three probe
if asked a few questions
now we ask ourselves three questions
about what to do next
what's working and what we showed them
what's not working what do people not
understand when they stumble over with
computer with confusing and someone
and what other ideas to fifty about
about what we might want to do next so
again
make showing learn we do this over and
over again until the experience of our
product
is great and today we're going to do
that in a few different ways for you
guys we're gonna protect with pictures
just drawing for the device they were
protected animation
so we can see how different screens will
be drawn work together
and then we're gonna prototype with
interaction
we can see how the entire experience
field in our hand on the device
now to protect the pictures were
actually gonna do in Kenya today
Tina fact easy and cheap and love you
probably already have it on your
computer
but in practice you can use anything
that can shop up pictures
and rocky basic shapes
for animation we're actually also gonna
prototype with keno
which is a surprisingly sophisticated
animation tool but you can use anything
that can move pictures around on the
screen over time
and a prototype for interaction were
actually gonna use objective-c Inc or
animation
that's what we knew three can lead to
prototype concept
and if actually easier than you think if
you're not a developer
if you are developer you're gonna see if
you that in a slightly different way
then you might be cell
I'd like to recap for you the key
features a postmodern
are beautiful world-changing disruptive
application we want to find 250 feet
near me
wanna find the top toasty post ofc
rate toast reviewing discussed host with
my fellow test aficionado
your light oak features so record is
gonna pared down to talking about
the first two fighting talk to a sticky
and
finding toasty near me to begin the
prototyping process
I'd like to ask me the donkey come to
the stage
thanks Jeff good morning fell
so to figure out how finding togther app
is gonna work
where to begin by making pictures for
here we third of by drawing just attack
high enough different batches
to quickly get down only ideas in her
head
for ways we can show nearby as well as
top rated tho
now on party we always start
from hand-drawn concept I'm gonna really
emphasize that you guys all do it to you
if you're not already doing that this
just no faster
or cheaper way to get ideas flowing to
explore
hope fluid direction and they're drawing
and Ryan find
like who doesn't want to dream up a 10%
increase the disposable ideas now you
guys rape
and keep in mind you don't have to be an
artist to do this
maybe your drawings look more like live
whatever I mean don't go showing that
flight board meetings or anything but
the point remain that we're trying to
emphasize but you should
not star prototyping from just a single
idea
you want to explore and understand the
whole space
in order to figure out the best
direction for your app
so when we were comparing all
re-do therefore that stood out as really
compelling
this let's grid map
and gallery so why did we choose the
former well
not only do they convey are typeof
information really well
and they also unlike some of the other
ideas
part overly complex or to elaborate
we want to start simple also
they represent four distinct directions
that are app can take
as opposed to being variations a single
idea
and great every move of them that we
found
all this out super quick on paper before
devoting a lot of time
exploring just one concept and so
I've got my sketches and it's no big
deal now
they're just sketches so I can just
throw away all the other ideas that
didn't work out
to just focus on making these for more
real
and to do that we're gonna turn them
into from faye caps
so the first question we're going to ask
ourselves is
what needs to be more real why are we
making these fake abs
what's our goal so right now we just
have drawing
sobibor even think about touching any
code we're gonna determine
how these ideas will look on the screen
in our hands
second question we're gonna after South
what can we fake
watch or cat can we take well we can
take pretty much
all the content we don't need a database
so
tell was photographed a location we can
make up filler tax and we're gonna use
temporary icon
and Napoli where were you
well we're gonna put the screen on
actual iPhone
and use them outside said
we're gonna start off with this catch a
a toast with you sorted by rating
now before we dive straight into
translating this to the screen
we'll see if we can save yourself some
time by borrowing elements from in this
thing I what's up
and just term browsing on my phone
I've noticed that the music app actually
have a relief similar structure
to our sketch so what used this I have
our way to kinda layout rido and
the way we can do that as we're just
gonna take a snapshot
on the screen for my phone and imported
into keynote for Mac now we on our team
use keynote really frequently to make
super quick prototypes because I have a
tiny really useful tools
that make aligning photograph and images
relieving
but you guys should be using whatever
image editing
tool you're most comfortable in so if
you've done this type of stuff before
maybe you're in Photoshop or pick for
made our sketch
if you're a developer who's never done
image editing
for a great place to start of is preview
for Mac
so we got our screenshot what do we do
next
we want to block of the main areas %uh
the UI in order to create ourselves the
table template
to drop in our own content into
so the way we're going to do that and he
know is actually open up
the shape menu and Robin just a ton of
boxes
to block of the navigation bar
all photograph the borders
in the background so great now we have a
basic structure to work of both
next up if they get that navigation bar
to be the right color so to do that
Aquino
you open up the color picker and using
that magnifying glass tool
sample the color the status bar about it
and
now we've got ourselves a blank
navigation bar now that was a really
simple right
well that's because we're using a
screenshot if you don't need to know
exact pixel dimensions or even colors
you I lament
in order to recreate them which they've
us a ton of time
and so the next thing I want to do is a
add in some content
and in particular some images so
here is that some photographs I took
this morning on my
delete host excursion and gonna have
put in this good-looking one and now
what i'm looking at that photograph
I'm thinking maybe instead of just a
plane square thumbnail
we could do something cool where we crop
the image to a circle and fill you can
see the plate and the toast
and for luckily for us can you actually
have a great Federer options to be able
to mask and image
to any shape so we're gonna choose the
overall math care
aum's now we've got a perfectly cropped
played host
that we can yeah thank you guys
that we can cut into our playful there
and
we're just gonna repeat that same
process for other images
now know if where does using the fame
three images
over and over again and that's because
we don't want to spend more time the
necessary creating content
3 picture the terrace for all your
strength totally fine
and so one please images are in place
now we can get rid of those playful
there's
and right off the bat I'm sure you note
is a mess you can see the play protest
on a background
so how do we fix that 3 at Borders three
and drop shadows do we change the
background image
what like what are the parameters are
you well
whole lot those are all visual design
decisions but we can make
further down the line if we even decide
to go with that stir
this direction for now we're gonna do
something super basic
and just add in a simple one people
border
around all over image oath and on
where already more than doubled we don't
worry about the details on that later
and so now we've got my images a toast I
wanna way below
and fed to help with or without we're
actually gonna take that way box where
you have a background
and make a transparent so this way the
music app is now picking through
and we can see how the way both and that
screen
are laid out in order to help us
way out m5 are intact
and I noticed the location doing the
you can get her with with go butter and
trout on it
that nothing we're just faking tax
because it quick
and we don't have to worry about it for
global production really coming together
we just can appear pathway in the back
on again
and make them little tweaks and
adjustments about the layout worked for
or composition
so the only thing that's missing right
now is ratings
and so for this I'm actually gonna go
into the special characters menu
with someone you guys may or may not be
already familiar with
for here we actually get a giant with a
pre-existing them both
and characters that we can repurpose
icon
for our layout so I found my father
really knife
star some old but I wanted used to
represent
ratings I was gonna drop it on other
then
align them together and we've got some
reading of them
now I think it puts pre doke but
I think the stars could really use a tan
color cuz I wanna make them look
active later so what particular color
used now
doesn't matter so we're just gonna go
into keynote
default color palette and choose the
color that make that
so here it is orange because the Peter
whose TF color
the rambo great now I've got some porn
stars
and then look more active already and I
really like that color so much you gonna
change the border the image to be the
same color
and now we've got a nice relationship
going between the picture the terrace
and its rating their color
and so last but not least I'm gonna add
a control to the top right hand side
the ap so that someone can add in a new
photograph
a putative and
here we can get all fancy with custom
shapes and masking and
doing all sorts of intricate stuff but
remember
we only care about temporary icons right
now
so instead we are literally going to you
at an attack sparked
tape in the plot them all and
now you have designed an icon in five
seconds graduation
alright yeah fattened
and must not leave just scribble on a
title for your screen
and there you go one freshly baked green
ready to be tapped
now one thing to really keep in mind
when you're making three in on any
program it's remembered in the room
out to the physical 5 the device that
you're 30 going to live on
it's really easy to get caught up
working at a zoom level
were everything is big and clear and
legible
to remember every time you added a new
element onto the screen
to view Mount and check if that peace
attacks
or that picture is by the readable
legible
and have a ball catch that early on
so now I thought 13 muddy and that
Sprint I guess about 10 minutes to make
if we were to have worried too much
about
all the visual nuances about the screen
that have
we would be here for the next hour and
it should be a really boring
presentation
instead we take shortcuts and that's
fine
because these aren't going to be our
final three
and so in a rinse and repeat that
process up screen shotting
masking arranging object and adding
basic content to the rest the right idea
like orbit you idea which much like the
camera roll
and and practices like kinda
too much to ask for a lot of the lookout
or our map idea which I know that looks
pretty interesting I think that would be
really fun to play with
or our gallery weather app idea
which just like looks really cool
and so now I've got my four screens and
again they're not gonna be our final 25
there's many places where we can refine
the
visual a parents and/or
a the styling overall on the screen
but we're not gonna do that because it's
okay because we didn't make
these applications to become forge
appear shop
we made them so that we could test out
how successful each concept will be
that way when we do you devote our time
and efforts
polishing the visuals over final screen
we're doing it to the right idea
and so what's next well we have a screen
we're gonna
drop them onto an iPhone and give them
to people to test out
for the way we're gonna do that is when
I go back and pick you know
exporter presentation into images and
specifically PNG
and then use whatever method you want to
get those images onto your phone
so that might be photostream the new I
Cloud Drive
or you can just email them to yourself
and then once you've got them on your
phone given to your friend
given to your coworkers given to a
variety of people
and just observe them like booking app
experience right now
see if they can even figure out what
this app does
theater read differently indoors as
opposed to outdoors
it probably will and then once you've
just observe them for a little bit
you want to ask them three questions
do you know how to find top-rated toast
what about nearby toast and the feedback
that we got was
yeah raining the star I can't make it
really
obvious how to find top-rated terrorist
but
there might has is really hard to figure
out if it not laid out on a map
so that's a really useful information
for you to have in order to make
iterations on your screen
second anyone ask if it easy to browse
through tears
and it seems that yeah people are having
a pretty
easy time reading through all the three
innings except for
course that great view that no one likes
because it hurt in the retina
and then lastly how can we make this
better how can we improve
ans maybe we just got the confirm for
fat you know you guys should really go
through the list and the map you that
things are really resonate with people
we should probably refine the
interactions and those two screens more
and so to tell you how to do that with
animation I'm actually going to invite
Julia mythic onto the stage
thank you enough now we're getting the
feedback I'm going to take you through
another spin around the Spurs I think
cycle
we should take a step back and learn
from
from the feedback we got with working so
far
well we have a variety of methods
organizing with information we have
live and galleries grid map
we don't yet have one best way
to find and discover Toth we have a
couple
sometimes people theme to prefer to look
for toast Buy rating
and sometimes I just wanna find the
closest
the perhaps our app could let people
choose
sometimes people could search for toast
Buy rating
and sometimes they can look for it on a
map
would like to make a prototype to try to
understand how this could work
the thing that we want to make more real
in this prototype
is the connection between screens that
have topped oath
and a screen has a map on it because the
rapid can have both these things in it
at some point in time
we don't yet need to make fully
interactive screens will need to be able
to tap
on each piece of toast we going to
scroll through these lists we actually
don't even need to have
final designs for the screen because
if we're doing things correctly were
probably actually going to go
back and redraw them to the screens
based upon what we've learned
as we make a more realistic prototype we
should also
maker contact a little bit more real so
in this case
this is not the party the app forward in
a restaurant taking pictures
we're still trying to find the
restaurant we will be at
so I'm probably walking around
on a busy sidewalk starting to get
really hungry
looking for a piece of toast the I'm
gonna be kinda distracted not paying a
lot of attention to my phone
this means that I'm not going to spend a
lot of time trying to
figure out how this app works and
navigate through it I'm just looking for
this restaurant
other was mentioning before the thing
that we want to make more realistic in
its prototype
is the connection or relationship
between two different screen
at one point in time this app is going
to have a screen
they will have top two the rating at
another point I'm
this Apple have a screen the live nearby
text for a map
foods app is going to be changing
overtime
between these two screen and a change
over time
is an animation rate now
there are a variety of tools that you
can use to make animation
if you're a designer you might be
familiar with tools such as motion
after-effects records composer
if you're a developer you might use
tools such as
HTML CSS animations for processing
either way we think you might be able to
use tools such as hype
I had producer for Tina
as jeff mentioned earlier we're going to
be buildings animation think you know
we can actually run keynote on her
iPhone
and see the animation life there we can
make modifications rapidly
back on our Mac and see the changes
reflected our iPhone
really quick and if the tool that we use
a lot in our team
so we're just gonna open keno and we
will grab
the two slides that we made earlier
and drop in and have the only two slides
in our presentation
we will go over to the enemy palette and
you the transition
here we'll just use move in from bottoms
up
let's just think about looks like
so this flight in from bottom to top is
perhaps
like some other sheet animation that I
left has where
from temporary information laid on top
I'll other information
maybe with move out for example E well
this was a lot like that navigate back
animation you're going back up the
navigation hierarchy
maybe we could flip it over
maybe this is
some kinda setting or information behind
another screen
the thing that I'm trying to get across
here
is that any animation you choose is
communicating something about the
relationship
the screen have with one another even if
it's no animation at all
it's just the pop that something that
shows almost no relationship between the
screen they're just being replaced by
one another
but in this case that's not really
what's going on here
but we have is two different views the
same information
perhaps those three restaurants that are
in the map
are three restaurants from that list for
something we want to communicate as we
transition between the screen
now before we get a little bit further
within keno I just like to explain
something about
two different types have animation we
think you know the first is called a
build animation
either animations that happen objectors
shapes
within a slide you can
build into shape perform actions on it
build-out
you can use the builder power to set up
a pretty sophisticated
sequin a build animations all with an
applied
but there's another type of animation
called a transition and the transition
is an animation that happens between to
slide
those are the animations we're just
playing with now there's a particular
kind of transition
called Magic new that's really
interesting for our purposes
would magic move does is it tries to
identify
objects are shapes that are the same on
the to slide
and it will create an interpolation
love the position sizing opacity and
other properties are shape
so for example if magic move identifies
the three circles as the same on these
two slides in might produce an animation
like this now if you're familiar with
animation tools
you may recognize we're starting to use
the slide as if they're keep rain
in a larger animation that makes it a
lot easier to
sequence out and separate the different
that the animation for you to go back to
Kenya
and choose the enemy
palette now that you know that he knows
two types of animation or does note here
real quick if you have a shape selected
the enemy palette will show you build
animation if you have no shapes like
that it's just the slide
that's when you'll get these transition
animations that we're using today
we're gonna change the transition to
magic move and without changing
anything at all about those two slides
that we've dropped in
but the magic new gether you can see
there's already a lot more interesting
than the transitions we're playing with
earlier because we don't be floods in
keno
and use the same images
on both the left and the map the magic
new transition
moved those images over and we can start
to see that maybe those restaurants in
the famous to screen maybe that's an
interesting way to do this transition
but there are a couple things we can
make better
%uh the first thing that I noticed was
there within our prototype
we don't really even have a take way to
get between these two screens
for to make it a little bit more
realistic for the weekend kinda imagine
how you would navigate between the
screen will just drop in a tabbar
for now and this tab or similar to the
thing when it was showing you earlier
is just a rectangle from the
shape tool encina the star could be from
the special characters and star-shaped
and that little map icon that's just
using the line tool to
draw quick littles a quick little
playful there
these don't need to be perfect just yet
because we don't even notice and the
direction we're going to take
I also noticed how the list
they did out we had white for a while
and in the map stated in this is because
what magic move doing
is feeding out shapes that won't exist
first for the first after the animation
and then after that midpoint
the second half for the animation is
speeding in new shape
so we can get around that by making sure
that are shaped exist
on both flied some going to copy
that map image that I I want to feed in
throughout the entire duration of the
animation
gonna copy that from the second flight
piece that
on that first slide move it all the way
behind all the other shapes
and then just for fun make it a little
bit larger
than it is on the second flight fluid
with the magic movie animation will give
us
will be maybe a little bit other
perspective shifted the
map is shrinking at speeding in
a few that look like
pretty
but there are couple other things we can
do to make this even better
because right now we're not writing any
code so we can try out some
maybe over-the-top animation and
take them out later pared down to to
just what it means but for now it's so
little work to
explore a lot of interesting
alternatives that
we should just try everything we think
we might try in this example here
I am looking at the title
others to slide the title was another
one where
we faded out that top tooth title and
then faded in nearby texting defeated
three great
but I don't really like like how that
worked
so I'm gonna copy the top two sleep well
from the first slide pissed on a second
flight
do vice versa so that both those label
this number of life I'm gonna shift
the one that should be fading out
horizontally
off to one side drop at the past 30 down
you're having a little bit higher def
you can see it but
the fact that it will give is the title
will be
stating in and sliding horizontally at
the same time
as the other one is spitting out else
wanted to do something
about those restaurant names on the list
unlikely to speed it out in place
so I copied his restaurant names from
the first slide
that list pay for them on the second
flight
the map and I ship them the way of the
side of the screen
will drop their path to be a little bit
so we're gonna slide out
now a little bit approach appear if you
stagger them horizontally a little bit
the animation speeds will be a little
bit different
for each item so they will feel like the
think items
not like part of one she sliding away
because the third think items in a list
and would like to reinforce that
finally
15 built up both the Flies to the point
where I'm pretty happy with them
I will have an animation from a lift to
the map
but to get an animation from the map
back to the list
all I have to do is duplicate
that first flight that list and place it
at the end
as a third slide and now without doing
any extra work
I have an animation back in the other
direction it's important to test they'll
both directions
and it really didn't take much to do
that we'll see what we have
after rebuildable animation in the back
now so too little flower thing and he's
in the details maybe this isn't
as well as we would have it in the
relapse we did all this without having
to write
any code you can see how maybe some love
it is a little over the top
thank you to maybe something to the
little over the top but
its so much easier to pare down and take
away things when you don't have to throw
a code
it is moving shapes around that the
really great way to try out from really
sophisticated animation
we also really liked this
the very graphical gallery view that
Linda called out of
pretty cool earlier wanted at the howled
work
if we have these angle plate the toes to
me zoom in on one of them just
the Detail View back out
might have to back button and also the
few get a little flower
the thank you so how do we build this
animation
well if really was not all that
different from the process I showed you
earlier
that one piece of toast the reason in on
that an angled image
behind all the other shapes the other
pieces of toast
are similar images but there masked out
and on top
that navigation bar the slide then
that the black rectangle that we've
shifted off the top of the screen
so we should offer a little ways up
there so it slides in a little bit later
in the animation
and that detail view
the toast that's that same toast image
rotated back straight
a me a bit larger the other piece in the
toaster just
shifted off the top and bottom of the
screen that's really all there is to it
moving from images and shaped around
until you get an animation that
that feels pretty good now that we've
built examination think you know
we're gonna launch keynote on our iPod
Touch here
and either through I cloud over email
however you prefer to get them across
actually open that same presentation
in her hand on the device to get a sense
for how it feels we can hand it to
someone and see what they try to do
now here you'll notice
that were tapping
on with seem like interactive element
those aren't actually
interactive it just so happens that you
can tap
anywhere on the screen to ban for flight
in keno you can kinda pretend
that the interactive elements work
course you tap anywhere else it's still
going to bat for Floyd
we can still get a fan for
where people are trying to interact with
your screen than animation
and what they expect to happen we can do
a similar thing
with the tab bar
and
after we show people and let them
express what they think these animations
on the screens are about
we can now in a couple of questions to
try to get specific be back
so we ask if they know how to find
nearby too
well they were able to find toast
although they didn't understand our plea
for icon
but that's fine because we knew those
icons were playful earth
and if we decide to go in this direction
we can refine them
we asked if it was EV
to switch between these two screen
certainly they were able to use a tabbar
they've seen those before they could tap
at the bottom and
which screen but
when we asked how could we make this
better that's where we got some really
interesting feedback
someone suggested they might want to be
able to the restaurant name
while they're looking at the map another
person suggested they'd like to be able
to see the map well they're looking at
the rating
perhaps they want to make their own
calculations love
highest-rated the closest to was removed
really interesting
that the feedback and I think I'm going
to invite mark-up
to discuss how we can explore these
interactively thank you
good morning let's have a look at what
we've learned
from the feedback so far what's working
the transition between the map
and the list feel great do in showed us
how we can do some really cool
animations
without writing a single line of code
what's not working
you still have to switch between two
screens to get
to all of the information about toast so
what other ideas
does this give us well maybe
we can put the map and the lid on the
screen
at the same time and that
a map on once-great
great now we've got all the information
accessible on once-great problem solved
but wait a second if this really a good
idea
if you think about it the map is only
hop up its origin of ice
so with the lead we have to pan the map
more
we have to scroll the list more in order
to access the fame
number of information to figure out
whether it's the right thing we need to
be tried out
and that's why we create an interactive
prototype we make another fake ap
and we start off by asking what needs to
be more real
finding nearby post on the map need to
and scanning the list for the Best Coast
should be Maria
you want to be able to pan the map and
scroll to this
now what can we fake what can we do
to speed up our process of making the
prototype we can fake
the map handle it by making using
draggable images but more to more about
that later
and where will we use
a lap let's keep that up in in our mind
while we are creating
of a cat and of course no case
it's when we walk the streets of San
Francisco trying to find the hippest
toast and tell now making fake ap
it's really easy we're following one
principal guideline
that is to make pictures move in
response to touch it and one more thing
its to make pictures move in response to
touch it on the device
that your prototyping for you
whatever you want that can do that
if you up from a web background check
accused html/css
a bit of jQuery if your game developer
who happens to you unit unity3d
it's another great program to make some
pictures move around
in response to touch it or
you could use sweat we are super excited
about swift
but today we're going to use Co
animation
and Xcode with objectivity this
because that's what we've been using an
hour prototyping group so far
quick word about writing code for a
prototype
it's different from writing code for me
that
the idea is not to engineer at to pack
it together as quick as a cat
it doesn't have to be good coat or
reusable code
because the idea if that make a
prototype to make a better decision
about whether you really want to spend
the time
engineering that we think
we general you three steps to bird an
interactive prototype
first step but the picture on the device
once you have a picture on the device
it's a good indicator that you've got
your work till sorted out
second Sep break up the picture you want
to prepare the picture so you can apply
interaction
to selected areas on the screen
and set that moved the pictures when you
touch them
this is all about implementing the
interaction
alright first step get the picture on
the device
credo picture in Keynote and the one
thing we have to consider if that we
work
to the actual pixel dimensions of the
device
we export our like as a PNG and save it
into the for the structure of alexco
project
now it's time to write a little bit of
code and what you see here
the setup function in a class costs
create
now another class to be with the Lord in
all cases the Costco player
and for those of you who know about
coordination in
it simply just inherits from you I
ImageView site also has got all the
functionality of you live you
all we did it at a little bit of
convenience functions
a to make a lot you get a position as a
a
and to load an image into that layer
by the default we have lacquered screen
it stretches across the whole of the
physical screen
and so to get a picture onto a screen
week rate and I'll
and another layer called picture and
without
our image into into it
that's it we press play
next coat and hit it
of first fake at looks pretty re already
done that
thanks right let's get on second step
you want to break up the picture in our
case
we break it up into another occasion bar
into an image of a list
and an image of a map let's start with
the lead
I use keynote again and Linda showed how
you can really quickly create
take much of it now this time we want to
apply some interaction to the american
we want to be able to scroll they met up
and down
so that make sure that is much longer
than the screen height
or device
next thing we want to create a fake
image of a map
where do I get it from we improvise a
little bit
I've got the eye with 10 laps up I open
it up make it full screen take a
screenshot
put it into keynote and there it is
we also want to display feature at toast
on the map
so sprinkle a few I can on told my toast
map
kind of an partisan away no need to be
precise
work with latitude longitude values just
get it done
again make sure it's large enough so we
can implement some track behavior on it
and possible what here we have or three
discrete images
now it's time to rearrange the images so
they become one screen again
them public coat crate they're called
map a lot my map image
position is love roughly crater another
lift
layup while air cordless rather
and the time I'm gonna position at
roughly down
hop of the screen height and I me that
actually okay had already left my map
and so does the navigation bar at the
top
call we are ready to go
let's make some pictures move when you
touch them
I want to talk to you about at the track
misbehavior
what happens is you hit the map
a touchdown event happens then you move
your finger
and you get serious of touch movie then
on and on each touch with you and we
actually moving
the underlying image with that and the
last event
is a touch-up event lift-off my thing up
now in order to make an image mu we
essentially go into it well within
each touch movie then week ended Oct the
death for translation between the
previous touch position
and the current touch position that's
what we use
to move the image the problem becomes
more clear
in Cote so this is a bit of
this the coat block that get call it
every time a touch movie event happens
on on that play a
what we do that 3 ghetto a touch of Jack
from that we can retreat the current
touch position and the previous touch
position
and we calculate or Delta Pi subtracting
the previous
but tough position from the current
touch position
and added to on that position
and we do the same thing for the lead
but in this case we only applied to
translation to the y coordinate
cause we're just going up and down
quick look at how it looks like court we
can track the
the map and we can scroll the list
now we've cheated a bit here you can
feel a bit of inertia and the author
constraining
the movement with a bit of a spring
behavior if you're interested in that
you can download black spot project
after the session
let's move on want to divert a little
bit
to the a the part of our prototype
well we can share toast for the idea to
take a picture of you toasty at a little
bit of information
and then he posted best thing is
I need a camera P
for now I just hide it at the lateral to
screen
and no I need to bottom but I realized
then already created
love the plus button in my navigation
bar
so why do with i hook up a touch-up
event onto my navigation bar
and so when you tap that poss pattern it
were true got this line of code
which and make the camera image back in
and this is just an example of how your
code doesn't have to be beautiful
but we can to pack 6 together with what
you've got on the screen
it s have to Talk button you see the
camera image
now so probably that there was a live
camera preview
we added that to at a little bit of
reno's to it
but that's why we stop when you press
what hap the shutter button
we've we switch to a fake image of the
toast
and that's what we continue with yet a
few
a information about your toast and
posted
now how did we do the keyboard typing
sequence
probably already gave it away of course
we just use a sequence of images
I didn't bother about using any dynamic
textfield or
a key but siding and I did all of the
images
just from one flight in Keynote and this
brings us back actually to what we
actually do it
we're creating a prototype by making
pictures
move in response to touch this me doing
that
to help us make better decisions about
whether we really want to pursue
idea and part of this decision making
process
it to show you a prototype to people
and if it's an interactive prototype
it's really important that you let
people tried out
with as little explanation as possible
the first impressions are really
important
look at what people are struggling with
the interactions like a crater
and also look at what they liked them
and of some questions like to know how
to fight nearby toast
atop toast the value your feedback
if the one which is Kritika if they tell
us on the map and the
say there something we didn't really
think about
when we had a genius idea of putting the
map
and the list on 213 something we should
result before we built the real say
is that you to explore toast
it's another good question and of
for suggestions how can we make this
better I wish I could sort it out in a
few more different way
yeah I make sense not everyone wants to
spend
for dollars or more for a slice of bread
but this way I want to read
introduced to to summarize all session
had concluded
thank you thank you mark so we learned
some very important things for marketing
director predator
quick recap
do much better then we saw how the
pictures work together
using from animation and then we built
an interactive prototype we could see
have a whole thing work together in our
hand
now couple quick comparisons to hit the
town
the screen on the raid takes lot a real
code
for our prototype all we did was move a
picture around in 2d
removalist up and down that was really
quick this
Greenview a toast we're taking home in
true real code for our prototype
we just made a quick drying which with
enough to realize that this concept
sucked
what we learned today
well we prototype a picture and we learn
how to take screenshots map
women to rearrange them so we can make a
lot of different options we prototyped
with
animation me learn how to animate
pictures
using magic move in keno we could see a
different screens work together
and we prototype with interaction
and we made pictures move on the screen
a response to touches
so we can see how the whole thing felt
together why do we do this
to resume hope your member number one of
the test ideas
and number two if to get new ideas and
how do we do it
this one I really hope you guys remember
make recap
show people and learn from their
feedback
and do that over and over again until
the expiry in Figure ap
feels great so here's what I want all
the view
to go into you near if you're a
developer to company
I want you to tell your management the
prototyping fifth time and money
by helping you build the right thing if
you're a solo developer
I want you to draw animated hack before
you go and build something and if you
can code it all
again thank you for coming draw and
animate
you don't need code yet but the person
next to you might be able to help you
with that part
designers don't just drop pictures
also make animated and interactive
things to fully understand your design
in our management types we've
going make time for your designers and
engineers to put it thank you
there's a lot to Turkey code on the web
got a ghetto thank you very much
everybody