hello harm
welcome to section 225 what's new in
court in a
I am with Turner I want the engineers
who worked on core data and I'm gonna be
here talking to you
about sort of all the new stuff that we
have been doing stuff
you're likely be interested in cell when
we do talk about today
well first on the list first on the
agenda is
new API batch updates and a second
session
I'm going to talk about the implications
love those two APIs for those of you who
have implemented your own incremental
stores
but talk about their critic unhurt
two-story
thats the theme that seems to come up
every year in our presentations
given I cloud update state affairs
and I'm gonna talk about lectures on all
of your minds
swift that updates
what are they why do you care well
their way to mass
update data in the database bypass a
managed object context
and editing the store directly
on primarily centrally intended for at
after updating attribute values and it's
really a performance optimization
because if you think about how Chordata
works up until now if you wanted to edit
say 10,000 20,000 lines in a field
gone on vacation and left her phone
behind then come back to discover that
your coworkers have been really really
busy
you have a lot if SCM messages
she wanted mark all those read in one
fell swoop you would have to
load all the objects into managed object
context
edit them and save them and there's a
problem here
which well kinda look like this which is
that on a memory constrained device
loading every single object into memory
doesn't necessarily work that well
jetsam may take a fact
servers into was simply that you would
do this in batches you closer lot if you
object
edit them save them load a few more
objects
edit them save them
the server problem with this approach as
well
and it kinda looks like this it takes
time
and usually likely to encounter a
progress indicator as they wait for
whatever set of changes
it was that you were making so it done
now
years we've added a new method tennis
managed object context to text your
quest air
it takes an honest person so request
some you're probably familiar with that
class name
it's the base class for and as per NS
such a question and a save changes
request on
now new parent class for and is backed
up their quest as well
talk about that slide X your request
returns a persistent store results
that's a new class it's sort of an
abstract superclass intended to be a
parent
anything that's rich returned from this
map it I've added an S patch update
result as
its first child subclass to return the
results
have about job their quest that such a
request itself should look pretty
familiar
to those of you who are familiar with
such requests it allows you to specify
an entity
that's the entity whose instances you
want changed well as you to specify the
effect
stores one or more stores containing
daddy wanna change
well as you give predicate specifying
which specific instances you're
interested in changing
the same kinda predicate you said on a
special quest has all the same power and
flexibility
you can use upgrades if you want to well
as you specified properties update
on this is a dictionary specifies the
property as
a key there either the property name or
the house property description
and in essence expression describing the
update as a value
Picasa value expression a function
expression operating I keep out
in the the object graph
pretty much anything that sported as
part of properties to fetch
is supported here pretty much anything
that's either a valid left hand side or
right hand side effects predicate
is the move out here else also allows
you to specify a result type
and the result I possess kind of
interesting because you always get and
NS batch update result
from X your class that will indicate
whether
you know your operation succeeded or
failed
the existence love the instance itself
but it may also have affection result
parameter lot property set on it this
resort property can be a couple things
if you're just interested in finding out
whether or not anything changed in the
database
there's you can set a Twitter account
which will just give you the number I've
rose they're actually changed as
resulted that batch update operation
or if you want you can get allister the
object ID's
up the Rose that were changed operation
and thats
interesting for one particular reason
which is that because this is about
update operation
and because we're operating sys directly
on the store itself
bypassing the managed object context
none of the changes that are made in the
store
as a result of that operation will be
reflected in the managed object context
and to you call refresh object on those
objects
so if you're interested in updating your
database on mass
setting a feel setting off a flag on a
particular calling for example
and they're reflecting the changes in
the UI you're gonna need yet
the results or that match object ID's
backs you can tell the object
tell the manager that context to refresh
the object that's it.
another implication a the way to set up
is that
well context doesn't know anything about
the changes you're making so the
validation rules
are not run I'm this means it is now
possible for you to add bad edit your
database
please don't do that your customers will
not appreciate it
on but
if you do this accidentally feeling
about field what it means is
customers the next time they load that
object
edit the object and try and save are
going to get a validation failure
maybe may be fairly confused as to what
happened since they may not have changed
that actual field
we do update the optimistic walking
version in the database
for all the rows that are change on this
means now
30 even if you're in a single persistent
store coordinator
your circle managed object context
single prison store coordinator
single instance savannas persistent
store all the changes
you make go through that setup you can
now create a merge conflict with
yourself as you go down at the database
and context doesn't know anything about
those changes you're gonna need to
remember set to merge policy
on you managed object context if you're
using us
API because well otherwise you may
confuse the heck other users as they get
say failures
and now I'm gonna do a demo show you
that this actually does really work
okay so what here what I have here is a
simulacrum love a male system since this
is the
the case were I most frequently see this
kind about something happening
girl application that displays you know
messages coming in
my manager asking me if I've got my
graphics ready for the presentation
managers are so demanding and me saying
I L
has a few days old thank them through
and as I edit the
as I slept these messages you can see
that the red indicator
is be marked as well or the undead and
caters being
damaged come down here look at this
other mailbox
which contains a whole bunch random cm
messages
that well nobody cares about and that
reset my database but I'll
on I can come up here and Matt batch
mark these as red
I'm gonna wait wat wait wait wait wait
because well this mail box contains
200,000 messages and credit is gonna
have to load every single one of those
at them and say again and that takes a
little while
matter fact if I come down here and work
at
I project find out it to
several seconds let me come down
this mail box contains the exact same
for messages the previous night watch
dat
come down here mark it as read new style
that took less than a second
so yeah we think you developers are
going to become happy with this and just
as
are your customers and be happy with us
and just as sort of a frame of reference
this is the effective command that I'm
running in
as to a light to make that up to happen
and you can see that we're pretty close
to just the right SQL
update times so as I said
changes are not reflected in the
database when you I updated in that
application that was being done by
KVL tracking that I'd updated 3 property
are fresh the objects that were big
displayed in the table looks the table
he was set up to be lazy fetching
all your senate Chordata make this up
perform
nice responsibly tracks validation rules
as I said are not run
kinda running with scissors please don't
hurt yourself for anybody else
we update the just walking version the
database i'm just repeating all of this
to
to reinforce it bring it home create
merge conflicts on yourself so
outset emerge policy
letter for Snow White API our second the
API is a second such
what is that why do you care well this
is actually feature that a lot of
developers have been asking for for
quite some time
it allows you to XQ to fetch in another
context will populate that managed
object context
with actually blocking access to that
context for the duration of the facts
its counsel which means if you're user
loses interest in whatever triggers that
fetch
you can tell us to stop doing it and
price progress reporting
along the way
little brief refresher housing
construction works you got a managed
object context
effect request XQ fetch quest on managed
sends a request down to the store which
takes some time
thinks about it
returns a response K shaper Vanessa Rae
updates non-drug context and returns the
result to you
well a sickness fetching is a little bit
different
on returns future which is returned
immediately from
XQ request there's no waiting
their quest specifies a call that block
will be in
X will be invoked whenever the fetch
finishes executing if the fetch
specifies
this is an especially West got more
detail in a couple slides
that the context should be updated as a
result the facts
that will happen and this means that it
occurs fishing is only supported
for managed object context that are
using either the private Cuban currency
type or the and its main you can pretty
tight
because this is the only way that we
have a separate
cue that we know has soul access to
the state and managed object context
it's not supported for the confinement
hard to type to the sister how its
inspection
marks again you have managed object
context only now
you have an assistant in such a blast
X your quest on context context
immediately
creates returns in a synchronous
factions of same time
it takes the it's been such a question
gave us and send it down to the store
you can now continue editing manage
objects in the image
ida context you can do fetches faults
yeah all kinda work you gonna want to do
on you manage our tax at some point the
store all finished executing that
request
and said the results back update the
context as necessary
and invoke the call back on the units
such that you
that is on the it occurs factors request
and tell you hey you have data maybe
should do something like that
so it is a secret special quest is a new
subclass urbanised
star-crossed on as I said it's
initialized with
affect request an instance events that
request now to completion block should
be invoked
when fetches finished you pass a text
your quest error
which will return immediately its the
initiative has fetched
results or know if there something badly
badly wrong
with effect request
it necessary to such results also pretty
simple classes on
again it's a subclasses interspersed
store result
this will preside provide results
immediately on property
on fetches I'll in or you there'll be an
error on it
after completion if Summerset reason the
fetch failed
turn return immediately for XQ request
error
or you now no if there's an issue
how do you set one up pretty simple here
we're just setting affect requested us
fetch for all instances have my Anthony
I could if I wanted to add a predicate
at sort descriptors all the usual
goodness is fully supported
creating an assistant professor quest
with that fact request and completion
block
we should watch here just takes it but
it would normally take an SEC Chris
fetters all
just a little bit to want to put on a
slide on
completion walk checks to see if the
result has a final result
and if so it does whatever processing
you want done as a result of that such
finishing
otherwise you'll need to handle your
what you set up the aging process
request
just tell the context perform block XQ
a circus fetch request and a way things
go
said something about tracking progress
how does that work
on pretty simple we use and its progress
standard you so that's progress you
create your own before you call ext your
quest
core data will notice if you have done
this and
will go off and create nested child as
progresses which will
report their progress the parent and
this is also how we allow
cancellations you wanna Council request
can Spanish progress
has set up for this work well again it's
pretty simple
tren esta to Venice progress set the
your Account 21
why do we say your account to one has a
post the number of objects we expect to
get back well because database
operations or streams and this Kevin
definite
how many objects you can get back may
get 100
you may get 1% we can't tell up up front
so we can only ever say
finished or not finished progress become
current
pending an account one and this is the
same context perform block we saw on the
last slide
progress resign current and you're done
at this point I'm going to bring my
manager Ben up and he's going to show
you how all this works
in real life
good morning everyone
manners been trouble and I me apparently
unreasonable manager
the credited him so I
to you give you a demonstration bad what
we've been working on
and we had a sickness patching and
partner supporting I we're gonna show
you a little simple app here
and in order to give you something that
you guys can actually witness racks are
gonna need a pretty long operations you
can observe the progress
so in this case for can actually be
working a database as 10 million rows
Amrani fetching about five million of
them into memory
and a for the purposes in the demo
the app is pretty refuted the total
number of objects in the database
I don't actually recommend doing this
that can actually be kinda slow in and
of itself
but as much as I mentioned did his grace
are sort of streams
you don't really know how many residents
back into your done and sometimes your
audience must positively know exactly
what's going on
so me gardepe reply to that so I'm to be
quick demonstration here
and as you can see in status bar it's
counting on
and Weaver
populated the last few objects near a
appear in the table you I have not
actually just put finally object to
Table View
because that would be pretty cool I and
as you can see sort of in the background
there from the that request actually
goes by pretty quickly
critical actually spend multiple cores
if the fact quite as long enough
and I've been months in the cave you up
its BC there so than
wanna get things we can do here's
cancellation it's pretty straightforward
so do the same patch again and as we're
gonna long weekend
decide to cancel it and wound up
happening is
the Federal Board and predator will turn
and issues are cancelled air
and see the status bar update their that
that we can so that
and that's pretty much all there is to
it on
we basically must work is going to be in
your cave your observer
for doing something on the Ana's
progress so in this case and dispatching
back to main thread to
update status bar and doing some
throttling the updates
so you get progress part it's probably
work faster than might otherwise want if
you're
touching 10 million rows and that's what
we have
so onward incremental stars we know so
you have implemented them
we've seen out there on web and that
means that some if you're going to have
a few questions about how these new
API's
affect you if the snippet if yes affect
you
well the kind you know on
if you want to just
publish your store and haven't used by
random people your
implementation XQ request on your
incremental star is going to now need to
handle the new core data request types
if you're curious and some you probably
are playing well
does that mean I can now in front my own
so classes love
as persistent store questions persist or
response from the answer is yes you can
do that
if you want talk a little bit but that
in
a couple slides if you don't want to
support any new request types
arm please fill gracefully by this I
mean
do it seems reasonable probably you can
want to return an error
and say I don't know how to do that this
is why the persistent store quest allows
you to specify which stores you actually
want to target
with any given resist are classed
I'm doesn't make sense Center quest
store that doesn't know what to do it
what to do with it whatever you do
don't run exception that never ends well
your quest types com
you should still be using with your new
request types and is managed object
context XQ request air
this will cause the access to your
purchase in store quarter
she realized this is kind of important
if you want multiple things running
around
talking the same coordinator want to do
what we've done with
fetching in batch updates create
request/response pair
the context is going to return it
aggregated results
which will contain a result of all the
individual stores that knew what to do
with your process with your new subclass
and the default stores
aren't actually going to recognize
customer quest types of you're using a
quoted a stack that has multiple stores
some of which are defaults and some
which is your custom store types
you want to target their quest being
executed specifically at the stores that
know what to do it why might you want to
add
Europe's your own subclass and this
person stork last
won the big things that we've heard
repeatedly is that well
on minimize requests minimize trips the
store
this is particularly relevant in cases
where
on you've got to destroy object your
house and as part of your apt watch
you want to bring in instances of what's
a different entities you don't want to
have to call
excuse setrequest for and different
parts of your subgraphs that can get
expensive if you've got
10 shucks your graph have met ten
separate network calls
that take a takes time and be maybe a
lot of overhead involved in those calls
going across cellular network that your
users don't wanna waste about let's
so that's one thing you might want to
consider in for dinner special quest for
is a
a launch time setup you may want to do
something object object refresh
hi database I got these 10 objects set
me back data
for the objects that need to be
refreshed and only object need to be
refreshed
minority status checks that kinda thing
that's just a few other things that
people talked about over the years if
you're gonna do
and a synchronous request you one model
it pretty much on what we've done
in this a second special quotes return a
future immediately
message that future call black when they
request completes
if you're going to be update in context
as a result
whatever you do a synchronously remember
to use perform blocked a pic context
because that will make sure that only
your on
only your request updates are happening
in context at any one time
will make should stay the same as
impatient yes this does mean that
if you're going to be a forty year on a
quest types than your contacts must be
using either the Private sheep currency
type for the make you can print side
which brings us to
concurrency at this point I'm gonna take
a little bit
a a winding path to get to our new stuff
and her to retrospective the evolving
core data concurrency story over the
years
wanna do this well it has changed a
number of times and well
if you go out and hit up your favorite
search engine
up to golan your somebody for example
or I'll say and say okay tell me how to
record a concurrency
you know I def responses and this is her
intended to help you filter through
those and figure out you know what
really is the best current advice
and I'll talk about you now also the new
state of affairs
so making sense what you see on Stack
Overflow
in the beginning and has managed object
context and as persistent store
coordinator in from a DNS walking
protocol
and what this meant was that before a
developer
started accessing the managed object
context and that included
things like accessing properties on its
managed object created by that
object context developer had to walk the
context
they want it messes a persistent store
coordinator they needed to manually
lock store coordinator for them
set whatever message they wanted and you
know
because this will a locking protocol
they're also gonna need unlock
after they're done the context report
respectively
this kinda works like this you've got a
context it has an object in a
you want to do something you walk the
context
you make your at it maybe more than one
saver unlock and things go away
this actually has a couple problems with
that them the biggest
which is that it's easy to forget the
locker unlocked well
forgets probably the wrong word
occasionally something with throw
you fed great at that predicate yes to
all generators through
exception went straight up narcotics
locked
on that can that state of affairs cuz
anything you trying to now gonna
deadlock
of a tricky doing some UI programming
because a lot of the binding stuff for
example doesn't really have a place you
can hook in
a lock or unlock as you attempt to
populate your table
cell that really wasn't a satisfying
answer and we moved on
to thread confine is heard about the
first step of our evolution towards you
now
more interesting and robust answer how
to do
currency in CoreData enter confinement
is
space for stepping back and saying OK
wire developers trying to
you now at the same contacts and turned
out there weren't actually a lot a
really great reasons for that
Joe Kay study that
managed object context should only be
edited from a single threat
on developers making sure responsible
for making sure that
only one thread ever uses managed object
context
and at this point a lot of us learned
about things like thread local variables
because that was for the easiest way to
associate
context with the thread and make sure
that no other context ever had access to
it
and this model the developer still had
to walk
coordinator further used and the skull
like this
had a thread that threat had a context
that contact had objects
you could edit the objects the context
as much as you want no
you don't have to walk and
sort of because people do want to do
things in parallel
if you wanted to actually make changes
to you now other objects would set up
a separate thread that had its own
context she wanted past data back and
forth between these
you generally do it by well how to
manage object ID's
back and forth and having the context
for fresh data from the store
this is kinda awkward on
stole a bit difficult to get right I
mean it involved you know
making sure that you didn't accidentally
message thread a context from another
thread
fire falls on another thread so
wanted to make working with the context
easier
and about this time another group but
Apple was inventing a really cool
technology or technology we at least
thought was really cool
you're probably familiar with it called
GCD or the dispatch if you're working at
the sailor
we look at this and we said you guys
are solving this huge problem that we
have we like you
on and in this case the concept context
encapsulates
the threading model basically each
context got
its very own cue and that Q is the only
thing that whatever access the internal
say that managed object context
his call the actor pattern for those her
familiar patterns
there if you can't gurantee types who
set up private you compare it to type
which says
this context has its own private you and
everything should happen there
a main thread contract to type which was
used for operating
primarily from the UI on because
accurate as we all know
likes to run a main thread
especially said that as long as
whatever's happening tapping on main
thread
you can message manjaca context as much
as you want
we also had the concurrency thread
confinement I've on
well that said I'm gonna I got legacy
code and i wanna
continue using that legacy code in the
same way that I have
had it working for however many releases
I don't want to have to rewrite my
application
under this model when you wanted to do
something for managed object context
would pass it
a block tell it form blocker for walkin
white
Miss Molly also no longer had lock
Courtney before use
credit that slide that's just a contract
to text talked about
mean private fine and this can invert
the previous order we go from having a
thread that has a managed object context
to a managed object context that has a
cue
and any thread can create to work lot
and dispatch
that block over the queue for processing
heard the context for processing
the prime context will do whatever it
wants to update all its internal stay
and then return returned to the calling
thread this actually made things and
what meter a lot cleaner it was
much easier to talk to the context and
get it doing things right
home and at this point we had bonding
mechanism
it was default you watched replication
com apopka create a contract to debug 1
we would be very very picky about how
you message threads and we would
very very vocally let you know if you
had done something wrong
thus require downloading a debug version
framework on
from ABC it was is that the Dr these
days
mom have one problem which is that it
often but still because it's
hard to push develop frameworks through
that mechanism at the same time we push
OS updates and it wasn't available on
I'll ask this now
I austin I don't on the firm's
frameworks
celebrities us to today
well the story at the context level is
exactly the same
context is still an actor styles cue
still have charity types so has the same
thing for two types
on you still message it using perform
block before walking away
we've also added for Wat from walking
away API
to as peace in Stourport matter this is
mostly relevant
those view her subclassing in its first
store coordinator should now be using
these methods which is what our existing
methods do they'll wrap party fun
mock my restore coordinator though
because
it doesn't actually need to message
directly by Hackett
always uses its own private kill
debugging default is now available
everywhere
as a seventy
as I V 70 and I was H if you want your
apt with
combat apple core data that concurrency
debug1:
we will be very very picky about how you
do concurrency we will let you know if
you have done something wrong
and this is about one hour as well no
special debug version of the free market
necessary
looking ahead this is in the sorta
predictions not process because making
promises
way above my pay grade and Esther
confinement is pretty much
actually on that includes the
confinement currently tied
we saw earlier with the sickness
fetching that he just can't be supported
in a confinement her tomorrow so as we
move forward it's likely the one more
kinds of changes
also only works for context that are
using you the private you or make you
can't gurantee types
as bonus API make that go down a little
easier because debugging is hard enough
already
we've added a name property Fernandes
managed object context
and person Stourport Manor it only
applies if
your actor is using the Justin the
privates you can't gurantee type
if you do said in a modern context or
your coordinator
this will be used displayed lol DB and
Xcode
when you're debugging she'll be able to
see which queues are actually associated
with which
which managed object context in your
application
on Tyco out sexual gonna be a fairly
short session cuz must have what you
need to know is encapsulated on the
slide
internally I'm sorry or
at present at the conference a former
teacher you've heard some buzz about you
know
changed I clout we are transitioning to
new infrastructure
you should see some reliability
improvements in to performance
improvements for those of you who are
using the court I don't like that stuff
but all the changes should be completely
transparent to developers
if you're using the patterns that neck
and then showed you last year in their
presentation
nothing has changed application
completely completely everything will
migrate over
just transparently everything should
work it should just be more reliable and
faster
I do wanna talk about cloud kit since
that sort of a new one
related technology that might be of some
interest you but in order to do that I
sorta wanna
assess the the full scope of the
i cud related technologies up on certain
using context to decide if it really
make sense for your application
they should a technology is the key
value star
says allows you to store small out today
to on an application by application
basis
great for things like preferences sorry
you know
do you stay that kind of thing a
synchronously kept up to date
and it has in Daytona constraints only
allows you small
Ste store a small amount of data as i
cud documents
since approach million viewers about you
who in from a document based
applications
fairly simple API basically replace
all whatever is in the cloud with
whatever I have just created
on Mac OS 10 is greedy and automatically
download everything that's in the clouds
you gotta whole of Lancashire volunteer
documents
is good for instructor unstructured data
and is tied filesystem
has good if you want to replace
everything on
all your devices with whatever the
latest greatest state
from one device no we can't I club
called it a
this is good for when you want to merge
data that is
created across multiple devices instead
of replacing
add a contact on machine one you want
that to be added to your global cloud
data store you don't want to replace
your I dislike use key private data
user data structure data in sync
across multiple devices and its
replicated between all your devices
but his single user data which brings us
to cloud get
club kid is the new API
and somebody and I say client-server
model
which means it has no local store its if
your gonna be using it you
users are going to need to be connected
to the network at all times
and last reported a square East not
before power
Chordata gives you but her really
substantial and pretty much everything
your
reason we're gonna want to jail and its
application center data
what does that mean well the data is
public and shared by all users of your
application
or can be if you wanna implement a there
now
restaurant reviewing application where
are all here
users can see what everybody else
thought they were given restaurant this
is probably technology one look at
it restructured structured in both data
and it allows for large dataset dataset
scale fortunately with the number users
of your application
use iPod account and has client directed
data transfer and I don't know either
those means he should probably go
watch the video of their session
somebody gave me the slides
and asked me please talk about party
that's about it mom
so that's the I cloud on
alternatives that you have on our
platform some you may want to actually
go look at Club get
and you now do interesting things with
that which brings us to the session I'm
sure all you have
wondered about since monday's
announcement which is
swift you have questions and I'm here to
give you answers
this is a fragment from an email that
came through one of my mailbox is
sometime over the last several months
basically says
well dress the message basically said
Swift is intended as a language for Cup
programmers
cocoa is nice and powerful and dynamic
core data is a very dynamic and very
powerful piece
Coco well swift must support coretta
period to adults
you get the full power Chordata in swept
you can create managed object subclasses
in swept show you how to do that
backslide and make sense for your
application
you can mix and match between Chordata
and swift files
all same story is they've been telling
you in all the others were sessions with
what
how do you create
man judge subclass well they're pretty
much like objective-c only instead of
using at dynamic
you'll be using on at and is managed
this is a corner desks for property the
12th
swift compiler that acquitted a runtime
is gonna be responsible for managing the
data storage
hands accessors for properties that you
specify that managed unfortunately not
gonna be able to
you now create your own then
mechanisms facts are facts about that
one
change other than this to you you'll
need to remember that my trip if you
view up is that you now need to add the
model name
in the data model when you specify the
class that your HD is gonna be using and
that's just done
appear in their modeling tool where you
specify the class 9 you didn't specify
the
arm fully qualified class namespace
stock last night but that's really the
only change
this is one object to C Class A plus
looks like you should mostly be familiar
for
with this if you're in a session on
import Chordata
query interface acquired properties
you're done
but we've also got a separate file and
this file was actually pretty basic
working
important header file as well that
actually works Claire
where you're from station to clear that
put it is responsible for these
properties
and you're done switched classes both
the youths into a single file
looks a lot like that mom small sleek
contains all the same information that
you saw in the previous two files
in one place without you notification
lines stinks remember about swift is
that on uses types it's very very
firm in the belief that static typing is
a good important thing
credited has not does not use types
but if you want to use types and you
probably will in your swift code
arm priority creating your own
and and this managed object subclasses
custom subclasses
see can use that's a plus names typename
otherwise you're gonna have to use
minute Ennis managed object because
entity names are not going to suffices
type specifiers
that's correct I don't like this
should be what you pretty much expect
having
had a chance with his left and nominated
demo
talk about how
things work and swept so here we have
a swift application or work project
that builds an application that looks
awfully like the last thing
i download got an app delegate
all a few standard code sets up
I V outlets for your controllers at key
value observers see you notice when
things have changed you can refresh
content controllers
got back just a code
to run batch updates all the same stuff
you'd expect
got utilities class and I've actually
split
Mike order to stack set up into you of
into utilities
nets to the way that Swift handles
variable initialization
on either initially something to
a simple type or
set up computer property but he said a
computer property
that gets reevaluated every time
somebody accesses the property
is not what you want setting up
according to stack
what access at once on
I was playing around as I built this see
can see we've got
a lazy property setting up Matt binding
deferring binding the managed object
models
data until you actually try accessor
computer property for persistent store
coordinator
set up my staff be properties can deal
with no at least he is not happy with
Nelson is another
minor gotcha there on
you're in better function that set up in
returns
I managed object context it look the
familiar
to those view personally with Chordata
all nations calls it the same
mailbox who've got my message instance
which has
Kb observer setup
set it up in the net ne third
whenever the observer gets triggered
will update I read bob's
messages controller does the same thing
the previous matches controller did
I'm gonna build and run
well its worst application
using Core Data
that actually lower faster from the
objective-c version
so yeah and if I come up here
Mark as Read will
thread so I talked about that updates
talk about it even fetching an
incremental stores and what that means
for you
talked about occurred to changes
American currency story over the years
if you're sensitive you know where we
were where we wanted to be
I caught up they touch but West covered
everything
3 get see Anthony the alligator tonya
file a bug
we can't fix what we don't know about we
don't care to affect what we do know
about
but you know we can't fix what we don't
know about
file a bug report on helps if you give
us steps to reproduce:
really helps if you got a nap give us an
app that replaces your problem
well we fix those first casino we know
what sex
is it too if you want feature requests
and have her quest for in tissues
documentation stuff others to bug
reporter
more information you can talk to David
along he's our technology evangelist
on apple.com or consented send
whatever your feedback is take a coffee
back at Apple dot com
we have a lot of documentation online at
developer website
there's a programming guides examples
tutorials code fragments that kind of
thing
and there's always the Apple could
developer forums
when sessions I mentioned this there was
a coke its session
interesting quirk it Tuesday at 3:15 if
you're interested in that you probably
want to watch the video
they're also although it is not
appearing on the slide was a what's new
in Cocoa session
on Tuesday may be interested in watching
that as well
arm and welcome and thanks for coming