thanks so much for coming to what's new
in table 1 collect
cover special beer enough to my heart as
we give it every year
well not exactly this session but
something on collection to have these
really get to talk about
and that's really because table views
and collection views
are tool that get used in nearly every
single application
and we recognize that as we went through
to add a lot of improvement ISA
we really wanted to do things that made
your life easy here doing awesome things
with the tools that
as I said just about everybody uses so
what we're gonna talk about today is a
is a few fundamental improvements
to both table view and collection beyond
and mobile
beginning with tableview in particular
the big thing that we're going to be
talking about today is how did too
dynamic type adoption in your table
views we're going to be asking that
Hall applications that deal with tax
than I was 8
adopt dynamic type and you'll see in
fact that all of our system app
have already done that so users are
going to expect that your application to
death
I'm gonna show you that it's really
quite simple to do and I think I have a
lot of fun with it
the mechanism but we're giving you know
for
adopting dynamic type itself sizing
South
we think this strategy
thank you this this strategy is really
going to improve the way that we
architect our table views
number one because you can encapsulate
logic right in the cells
into the fact that you can't do that
make it so much
easier to have cells that are not a
hard-coded compiled time known
heightened
which means you can easily adapt to
dynamic
fun changes so additionally we've got
some new things and collection view
and number one really great is we're
bringing felt sizing felt the collection
view
also and
for all love you custom layout authors I
know there's a lot of you out there
because
every week at least I see a new app that
has
a really great layout that really
impresses me we have
something we want to talk about which is
smart
invalidation which will allow you to
write great layout
that are also super performant so we
begin by talking about
tableview and dynamic type adoption if
you've never seen this screen
from Iowa seven is only introduce
dynamic type
this in a screen in settings where you
can
change the text size to fit
what feels appropriate for you and if
you're somebody who likes
packed a little bit bigger so that you
can you can see things easier
when you can fly that over and and
magically the tax
changes are in the Interfaith and impact
in Iowa State all internal aP's
will adapt and change our text size
based on
on the slider value that you've set so
that
great because it makes your phone truly
feel like your phone
and adapts to your needs and turns all
of the internal
after doing this adoption I'm we will
expect
third party apps to do that as well so
let's talk briefly about what it takes
to get there
well we can do it by
using built-in labels built-in labels in
tableview cells
have dynamic fun on them automatically
and Iowa State
so if you're using the tax label the
detailed text label
they have I already dynamic fun and as
the you change the tax five
those labels are going to change sides
if you have your own custom labels
it's really as simple as adding a
preferred font
to that label this is another API that
existed
in Iowa 7 so hot new was just expecting
everyone to use it now
so simply changing your fonts from
something that may have been you know
setting up onto the particular sign
to instead using a preferred font you
now have been am a type
in your label but Matt brings in a
wrinkled
things and that wrinkle is now
all things are dynamic and its dynamic
because I've the sizeof the taxpayer can
change based on what the users that
so everything come a simple table views
like settings for like messages
I guess but notes actually I'm messages
and Mail or contact I'm
be there all simple table views that the
and I was seven
the row height was known at build time
you can say I hate up a 44-point Cairo
and that's always
true put on high alert 8 that's not true
you to change their text size all of
those row heights
change so even the simplest
table views from Iowa 7 now need to
think about being dynamic
in Iowa a so we have a few strategies to
achieve dynamic
one is the simplest case
if you're like one of those very simple
table view that we saw
on the previous page then you can use
BRB existing property row height
and even though you dynamic you can
still use that property
because when the text size changes when
you get a new high
you can change the value of that
property to something different
and in fact this strategy has are
an advantage if if you truly are
you know unknown hyped that will be the
same for each sound
because if you can set this property for
all our
same size South then you get the back
throwing performance possible
because no calculations mean to be done
on the fly
while scrolling the next strategy is
something you're probably of familiar
with for using
dynamic sized cells and that
implementing the delegate method
tableview hype for an index that
strategy is still valid
and something you can use an ISA if
you'd like to
size ourselves one at a time I give a
high for each row
you can still do that of course
the disadvantage to this and why we
wanted something new
is that if you implement that delegate
method
all love your row heights are act for up
front when the tables loaded
here if you have twenty thousand rows
we're gonna ask for
height a all love those rose when we
love the table
and of course no cells have yet been
created see a delegate needs to
understand
without creating cells what height
to make those cells based on your
contract and that's been a challenge up
to this point
so that's why we have the third strategy
which is
South I think cells
so let's talk a little bit about
you know why this is in NY you know this
is a big deal
if we take a simple table cell like that
in mail
there's a lot of parameters around
sizing this Sal
I we you know we look at this and okayed
it is actually a lot going on here
there are three different font and in
order to size
the cell correctly we need to know about
the size and all those points and how
big they draw
additionally there are margin
between the text we need to know how big
does margins are in there are several
about so we have to not respond we have
to know these margins
at the lot and knowledge if we were to
do dynamic sizing in the delegate
so in 8 I'll show you how things work
and I get out of the way so you can
really see this I'm
imagine that we've got a few rows on
screen and then we've got
a fourth row that's not yet on screen
and I was
a if you're using self sizing cells and
in fact
part of this is going to be using the
Iowa 7 API
which is giving an estimated furrows
something we introduced last year
so that fourth row is going to be size
using an estimated high-fat you provide
here either via the property estimated
height I
order to delegate method for that too
now
when you scroll running use our schools
rather
at that time we need to bring
on screen row for which up to this point
only has an estimated high
cutback time we will create the cell
after creating it
we were asked to sell how big it should
be van
we use that size it different from the
estimated size
to adjust the content 5
the table view and only then
after adjusting the content eyes and
taken aside from the cell do we actually
put that sell on screen and so
what you probably don't wanna now is
what
what happens in step 2 how do how do we
actually sigh for sale
we're talking about now and there are
two ways that you can communicate
information about how big your cell is
from the cell
back to the table view so that we can
get you the right thing
and number one is you can use on a layup
if you're
already using either way I know that
many have you are you may simply have to
do
nothing here you constraints if they re-
I
determine unambiguously the signs have
the cell
then we would just use those constraints
impact
the way that we've implemented this and
I was a is that
tableview calls system way out five
fanning five
on your cell and system outside but
inside
smart enough to understand if you
implement constrain
in your cell and if so
the outer layer engine delivers a size
and
if you haven't implemented out about
constraints system we have five pink
size
calls I size that that and then
you can simply return a size manually
based on your own
logic so by adding size that fits
you don't have to use on a layout if you
don't want to
if you are using out a layout at notre
Pere you want to add your constraints
to the Content Viewer cell you always
think about
whatever content you have goes in the
South content view and this
plays into what the API contract is when
we are sizing your cell
because I their survey there's an In N
Out situation
the into your style is a wet
in that wit is the with the content via
what your cell returns is the height
up the content you so when year
implementing 5 that pits for example the
size that we send you
will have the resolved with what the
with the content view was going to be
and then the value that you return has a
resolved
height and even still with your
constraints you should think about how
you build your constraints
as assuming that you got a whip the
content view has a wet
and I was predetermined by the table
view based on how wide the table view is
you know whether you have an image
viewer accessory views that will make a
shrink the content view
and then from that with your constraints
define height base on the content that
you have
so I'd like to spend the rest of the
time much to the table view time
telling you are showing you encode how
to actually do this
I we're gonna see that this is quite
simple at its base but I also
kinda wanna run through I
gotchas but you might run into that
other people have run into
in the past so that you can come to keep
the idea in your head
hey this is simple but if I go back to
my hotel if I go back to my company and
I start implementing best
and it just doesn't seem to work come
back and watch this video
because there's a good chance I will
have covered what is causing
your code do not do what you think it's
going to do
so
let's start off by I going to starting
and working out excise right now I've
got it
set to be the smallest thing all pawns
put it to
regular on and
this application I've got right now just
has a very simple table view
and it doesn't do a whole lot it just
has a
one line text label and
cells that are all predetermined to be
44 points tall so
one thing about this that is interesting
if I ma I was a as you take a look at
that and if I i
change my text by and I bring it all the
way up
van run the app again
you see nothing changes
and that's the problem we want something
to change I
say we won our apt to be adaptive to
what the user wants
cell cent in this case I'm using a
custom
label called headline label here I
create it right in my cells initializer
the problem is that
I have sat the have my labels font
to be a specific 5 and actually what I
want is to use
and dynamic by typed popped and so on
just change the
to preferred far for textile you I
fought textile
have mine is perfect and a fire on that
now
will see that the tax didn't get better
and that's great it is adapting to a
future wanted
but this looks a little weird now
because missiles are the same size but
they were before
I want the cells to grow along with
attacked because the five giant axe
small cells
things are weird so
what I'm going to do is a use
constraints via auto layout
and I've got a whole bunch of them here
I'm gonna walk through them we could do
this
I'm an Interface Builder as well but I
thought
if we walk through the sink code it'll
cause a little bit more understanding
about what we're actually doing
I'm so I have four sets of constraint
logic here
I'm what I'm doing with this first one
is
setting what happens at the top on
selling from spacing
at the top of my label something that
the first
first base line is equal to
the top of the content view plot the
constant
and a multiplier and the reason I you
know i i
pick these values somewhat arbitrarily
but the reason that there's a multiplier
as I want the space between the first
base line and the top to grow
not simply equal to the Grove
the font but I want it to
grow a little bit more so that we we get
even more space between
the top attacks than the top as the fun
grows
so then I do something very similar
setting
a padding at the bottom
so that's just setting an attribute
bottom
for my content view to be based offer
the lack baseline a the label
again with Irvin I are confident that I
just picked
and a multiplier for the same reason I
have a multiplier
up here again these values are not magic
values they're largely values
but I picked out of thin air I'm so I
can sleep having at the top
and the bottom have my contact and as
the content grows
then I will still have that padding and
the fellow will actually grow
with it the last thing
I did here for height and I am wanted to
have a minimum
the Human Interface Guidelines says we
wanna touchable things like table views
be at least
44 points tall so I thought a constraint
that says I want my content views
height to be greater than or equal to 44
simple back so even if it excites gets
very
small I actually still want to keep the
cell to be at least
44 points tall to meet the human
interface guideline
for the I'm horizontal axis
I've just use a a simple I'm
visual format language to say but I want
fifteen-point margins
around my headline label and I'm just
adding goes to the Iraq
at all those constraints my content view
another have done that don't want it to
happen
well
at actually looks but same
and I have something really scary
here I have a bunch have auto layout
constraints
failing messages
thankfully there's a solution
so I mention this earlier but
part love being dynamic herself sizing
cell
I aware and using that in your
application
is that you use row height after mation
rather than literal row height in your
table view
so if we look at my view controller
imputed load
previously I was setting the row height
well if we do that and we have some
citing cells
this helps I think I think again because
I've said row height is 44
and that for the end all be all for
tableview
what I really want now in Iowa State
is to that the estimated or
so when you run into this problem try to
remember
Luke said use estimated row height not
row height
IIFA and then when you run it
got look solution didn't even work
well so has one other got sick here
which
actually will be fixed in the next feed
but I wanted to show you
wanted to show you so you don't think
I'm a liar where'd you go
back to your room a so if your cell cut
or if your table view is coming out over
never storyboard
I then it are row heights property will
be
that's when it comes out about
storyboard
we want it to be the default is actually
the new default for row heights
and I was 8 is
you I'm tableview automatic to mention
that means
had a however I figure it out I
based on other information and this is
already
the default for programmatically create
a table views
and as i've seen to will be the default
for
table view that come out of storyboards
and names as well
it interesting actually to know this in
general
that this default has this default value
is changed because it used to be 44
and now it's automatic to mention
because if you were doing math
based on the value table B row height
and just expecting be defaultValue to be
something that is reasonable to map on
I'm
that's not true unless you have actually
set the right value
so if you run into weird things like
olive your table cell suddenly shrunk to
nowhere are no hype rather I'm
look and see if you doing math with the
rope a property
so now that I'm done back how
thank God no more weird layout
constraint method is an actually
mice overgrown abet they they
look more natural for this text size
not bad it's true there's
there something else I can do here
now and is go back to my cell
and i wanna make those labels which are
all clipping of
the end of the screen not do that
anymore
so let me take
have I'm label number line
make it vero so it should
growth the high above the label
according to the content but then it
fire on that now now myself all become
alright by based on
them
and
that at high don't have any delegate
method how tall prove it to you
nothin for suffered an expat I mean
got about right so that's it that's all
you need to know
to migrate your table
from and Iowa seven style table
to an Iowa 8 style table and
I could you do this right away because
you want to be ready by the time
we ship ISA to have your fully adaptive
aP's
that respond to dynamic type and I'm
just fabulous for users
so that tableview and Iowa 8 and we're
gonna spend
the rest to this park talking about
collection view features that I
mentioned earlier
and I would be a good match will come up
to enlighten a
as it were
budget I my name is a really good person
I love collection views
so today we have
to new features in correction do for you
first one of course is self sizing cells
we added that to Table View and
of course we had to enhance
connection with you to support their
sizing cells but
connection issue is quite in every class
and a key thing you didn't connections
you is
you can actually build your own layouts
and when we implemented self-closing
cells
we headed a new infrastructure to do
that
and what we wanted to do is to actually
open
that's for your custom layouts so if you
have
a custo me out you can actually
implement
the same sale closing sales techniques
we have
in or default layout so
social things out we think it's a major
new feature in connection with you
we serve holding cells you can strip or
easy be
dynamic type we're making that have
anymore
in you I collections you flow layout
which
is or deport layout
we provide in you like it and
it's ready for your own
stone wraps but first
elected a very quick demo
of self-loathing cell in you I
connection with you
flown a doubt so this
is very simple correction to you I could
try to make that seem for
bouts I couldn't so it's a floaty I
which
and we just sets the item size:
ornamental elements on the screen
to be the same TG size so we don't even
have a gauge
we just use the item size:
property on you I can assure you for a
way out
and your connections you say out
here are extremely simple it's basically
just a label
and everything ills sized
the same way so of course
it's not great and
when you want to actually I just your
item size:
based on the content of that sell you
can actually do that
right now you have to implement
delegates
on the UI connection you for layout to
compute the correct size
for a given item and banned the sale
is going to be sized with what they're
doing layout
which arms but it's written convenience
because basically in your data source
in your delegates you have to compute
a size based on the phone to ring to
using this label
and then yourself is
implemented with the label or so you're
basically duplicating code
and that's what great so
what I'm going to do now is agree to use
the exact same connection to you
the same flow layout the same cell class
I'm not going to change to a different
layout
I'm just going to enable surprising
sounds
on you I collection you floated out and
that's what we had
its dynamically sized
floated out steelworks the same usual
way
by dynamically plowing adding said House
line by line and it's a new feature
in you I correction you floated out the
only thing you have to do
is to have yourself class
imprinted with us totally out or
using size that fits so
what do you size sales
with you i connection with you the usual
way the classic
way to size items on screen
with a connection with you is to
actually have the layout
compute I terms size and position on
screen
so in that case and that was what was
happening with
I with 6 and a US$7
are the question you lay out defied
everything but fair is just
we are just in forcing aside from the
cell
so US age we riding
this self sizing sales mode
which mean that's just like with us
tableview
you can actually use constraints on
yourself
thank you or if you're using
money or layout just have to ride side
that fits
but when setting sales
own screen was a connection with you a
note but the computer a set of
after use ed in B that reduce we have
position size but all things like
I'm up or even transform
and we are actually opening thats
also at the cell level it mean that's
if you override prefer layout attributes
fitting attributes in your cancer class
you can actually twitch whether layout
itself computes its extremely powerful
so to summarize the first mode
the classic mode the layout decides
computer attributes and the collection
use going to create a cell
and enforce that size
the second mode is rearmed is going to
compute
an approximation provide attributes
the question who's going to do the usual
saying
you creates a out and then
just their is going to add just if
needed
that size and the server node
the yard gain estimate yet reviews
but then the cell can act on each week
any property on the layout attributes
including France for
so we're making thats available as a new
feature of
you are corrections you for layout
ok any use that took
it's like three easy step 1:
we have a new property its estimated
item size:
because I'm correction view we're really
talking about
with and height it's a CG size
but or from thats it's basically the
same model
nuke describe for table views
how do you enable thats just sets
this property when non-zero CG size
that was that what step two is
there is no step 2:
if you want to use fair finding sellouts
in your own predictions you've shown a
doubt its 1 like
that was my dinner I replaced item size:
with estimated item size: and that's it
that's critical
now I'd like to talk about
how that works and how that changes
things
in the corrections you model
safe sizing heels really a collaboration
between
36 layout the connection to you
careless out
the first being a funny out
is going to do is to compute
a first-pass a first approximation
of your layout and based on this
information what's going to happen as
the correction view is going to teach
you
creates missteps
we're going to send size these items
again using all the way out or sigh that
fits
or preferred layout attributes for
fitting
attributes and then
we r ok to be sending back that updated
information
to the layout the layout can now decide
if it wants to react to that
in actually said and fine or
layout attributes we need work to reduce
place there's
on-screen so a very important thing
about this mother is its actually the
same old are you
were using miss correction you so layout
is in charge and is always in charge
but the catch is
now we have the way to actually
communicate
to the layout thats maybe we should
actually
I just things because of their size may
be slightly different
from this first approximation we
completed before
that's up very jittery an extremely
powerful
mechanism so
no I'd like to talk about
custom layouts and smart invitation
but
first I'm going to refresh your memory
about how
correction view layout in politician
works
so if you have a custom layout
if you cut it into a custom layout you
know that's
the first time we try to prove
themselves
or supernova reviews or decoration views
on-screen
the first met her we are calling on your
custom layout
is prefer layout
usually that's when you can actually
freaking cute things or cash
some attributes have
Eric idea but what's your layout is
going to be
because Nick thing we're going to ask
you is
the overall size
of your just on layout
and beat them thats and based on what's
section up this layout
we want to show on screen going to ask
the layout to provide
earliest of attributes
for I Thames in a given racked
for instance usury the he's able to
bounce
all the collection de
based on this are attributes the next
thing
is the correction you is going to do the
usual work
of securian creating
say hours possibly corning size that
fits
or applying to layout constraints
so in that case you would return
arm 6 in six-plus
this approach a review attributes
describing what is
in this rack
now you might actually
later invalidate this layout
I for instance because you want to apply
some special effects
when you scroll like a cover for all I
each are effect in that case you have
two core
invalidate layouts which is basically a
way
to tell the correction you that's okay
we are starting to gain
what's going to happen is going to
corporate or lay out a gain
and that 4-cycle stocks okay
so oh you speak
through the sole a small problem here
if each time week or are you calling
validate layout
you after we compute all these
attributes
not the best way to have I performance
layout
so we actually have
a great solution for you for this
problem
be lazy or smart
or leaving an spot which basically means
we compute only what you need
and that a strategy you can use
right now in iis7 wheels
something week or invalidation context
because that's a class that we
introduced in the US
sever and this class
is basically a tour for your custom
layout
to indicate what changed
because it's your layout so you know
what to do
to invention context you know US seven
were
leticia way to provide fine grain
information your layout when things are
invalidated
we were actually using the A's in many
different contexts class
ready for things like partition
in you a petition you floated out and no
where you think that's force their
sizing staffs
so US$7
when using the traditional text it's
actually easy
you have to be fine a correction view
invalidation complex up last exposed at
your layout lever and
instead of corning invalidate layout
which is the
very generates remove everything
I in validation method you can actually
call or
invalidate layout with context and pass
an instance of your class where your
probably
I added some information about what you
should do
in a given invalidation situation
we also provided an override
point for a bounce change which ills are
a common thing you want to do so if
you're a layout is continuously
invalidating on scrolling on bounce
change
or rotation you can actually just a ride
that's
and return your invitation context
wheels information you can you
them you're right after filtration
we actually adage no US seven induce
invitation context two additional
information
sometimes wherein we invalidates
it's because the data source changed
you have items coming in on
or out or we just have to invalidate
everything in some situations these were
two properties
the correction you with setting up for
you and you could use
in your layout implementation
so I US several in very difficult thanks
were really
a class for your own use pasick
so what's changing in the US 8
now US age you need additional context
our real way we establish a
communication between
your way out and the corrections you
you can tell the correction view that's
here is my invalidation situation maybe
you can actually help me with that
and information you can pass
the correction view can be useful for
things like
high-performance floating editors sticky
rice like in tableview
when you scroll and you have this
section
Heather on top
and the use cases Sep citing steps
apps
because when sales can actually change
their size
it might actually change overall
correlation view concise
it might change the upsets and
in addition context are a great way to
tell
the correction you that's your layout
is attacking without citing change
the first
fine grain invalidation
we added three new methods
on in very difficult action a US$8
invalided items that connects pass
invalidate super rotary elements of
kinda
at index pass and invalidate
decoration views of kinda express
and you can access this later what's
great about thats
first you can actually call
this methods several times we're going
to aggregates
that information one that mean
for your layout let's take a very simple
rely layout
with Section Editors and
you want me implements a sticky header
on top
in I US
7 you basically had to invalidate the
entire
rack US
8 you only thing that is actually moving
if that's a problem to review so what
you really want to use
is on your invitation context terror us
that's I'm invalidating thats appellate
review
at index pass the road in that case
we know that only one thing is actually
changing
so we're going to ask for a layout okay
give me an updated version over that's
occurring to reach you
we are directing going to court this
fine grain method
on your layout which is already here
may I don't use for support a review of
kinda
section editor action express
and one think we are not going to do
escorting layout
a fuse for elements in Iraq so instead
of asking you for
14 attributes
in that's invalidation situation
we are just going to ask you for a while
its
I'm using for high-performance layouts
years a situation where you want to use
an invitation context is for
sayre sizing selves if you want we
implements
self-loathing sayre in your own custom
layout
well you can actually tell
the correction you that's the common
size
is going to change that sailed well as
bigger-than-expected so you at two
and your arch you're often cites and
you can do that's wheels the first thing
or property on the very difficult axed
which is a common size adjustment
so you can give us the Delta
the change between what was computed
before
and the new size but of course because
a cell might not be what will you
expected
its mean that you're upset where you are
in the collection you can change and you
can tell that
to you can sets the content of that
adjustment in the reddish in context
and man the picture is going to do the
right thing
and at Shaw ste the position so
you don't see in the John from
opposition to another
just because your layout updated itself
you either
feature we adding
to help you with us self-serving set out
in your custom layout
is away invalidates
for specific attributes
and that's a new method all you a
petition to lay out
if a cell return a different size for
instance
different layout attributes meaning to
ask you if
we should invalidate Sunday Oct and
because we walked
fine grain invalidation
we have Nova right point
many additional tax for prefer
attributes
based on the original or attributes
so gain first step your layout
computers a first approximation
we satisfies the staff's which my
changes attribute
and we passed you these attributes
in your layout and a gain the layout is
still
the final decision-maker what should be
on screen
so just like to summarize that technique
for a custom layouts
is a very simple line based
store layout something I bats
but that's my overall corrections you
lay out I have
five sellouts and I going to compute
that first approximation by you think
the usual or
layout attributes for elements in Iraq
so I'm going to assume that's all my
stairs
at exactly the same size
but then collection is going to create
this there's
and say our size and the for sale
let's say adjusting the size
based on size that fits or fully out
or preferred me out tributes
and abuse me because of that size change
my layout is not over when i waltz
so I we have to have dates
the position for is all the steps
so in my layout implementation
I can decide if a cell
as different attributes from what i
computed before
that I should actually updates the is
also sells
attributes for the reals
one last problem migration you put on
size
is no longer are correct
if I want to make that call system so in
my in addition context
I'm going to tell the correction you
that's
we should ajuste connections you put in
size
and actually it's not the
out only thing I need to do because my
previous state whereas
three sellouts in this was able to
bounce
mystery those for sale to sickle cell
and part
other sorts out for the next thing
is tending the corrections you that's
based on this new seller information
we need to actually adjust the offsets
so be sure to be we r in the exact same
States
it's of course completely lay out
specific you could imagine using this
technique for
circle layouts line layout screen
layouts
be is more layouts up
it's an amazing way to implement
extremely high performance layouts
and add new features like dynamic type
and go through the like to bring back
Europe's
thanks so much love you
by the public on a theme here I
that is we've brought felt siding fells
tableview brought self I think cells to
collection view in the former flow
layout
and we've also brought fell sizing cells
to your custom layout
if you choose to adopt that methodology
I so what I want you to go home with his
remember that every app
should be adopting dynamic type if
you've got text in your app that is
which I imagine if every single one of
them
II when you're doing your
think about using self sizing cells
it'll probably help your cause
and if you're using collection viewer
specifically
if you are the author uva custom
collection view layout
this I can't stress enough use
invalidation contact
this is like the key to the world for
writing
high-performance layout in collection
view
in fact things were going to the lab
right after this I'm I know some people
are going to come with
performance I questions
I'm going to tell you my first question
for you
will be are you using invalidation
contact
and so if you're not learn how to use
them they're spectacular
I there's another great talk on
collection view
later today particularly for those who
view who are
writing custom layouts this is advanced
user interfaces with collection views
and there's some really great tips in
here for how to
accomplish non-standard things and
things that aren't built into
the flow out that we ship and get truly
great
interfaces that use collection PO for
more information
always feel free to contact our
framework have endorsed Jake parents and
check out the documentation thanks to
come