good morning
names Jim Turner and i'm peter hey just
and where engineers
on the UI kit team and welcome to the
presentation on a open look inside
presentation controllers
so you a view controller presentations
have been around since I OS-two but only
recently
have you had the chance to customize
them in your apt in Iowa 7
we introduce the concept have an
animator object
this is an object who's responsible
for in a meeting your new controllers
content on-screen
however if you wanted to build a
totally custom you control your
presentation it involved burdening that
in a meter object
with far too much responsibility so
that's why I was a
we're introducing you I presentation
controller this class is designed to
work in concert with an inner objects
to make the job of presenting view
controller content easy
and simple to manage and execute so
today wanna talk about just a couple of
topics
the first being some presentation basics
what do we mean by presenting view
controller content what's the difference
between chrome
and could content itself and what do we
expect you a presentation controller to
be responsible for
next we'll go over how you like it you
to you I presentation controller
to expand our own EPI and finally wind
up with the demo
the brings all these concepts together
so you guys can see how you can use you
a presentation controller
in your abs first let's start with some
presentation basics
Here I am on the Settings app on iPad
and I'm gonna tap that
create new Apple ID table cell the new
account sheet slides up
and we're ready to go in %um view
controller terminology
we would call that new account she the
presented view controller
and the setting split view behind it the
presenting
you controller when we talk about the
responsibilities
have you I presentation controller we
would say that that new
a new account she is the content the
presentation
it's the foreground stuff for your users
mint interact with
we would then say that the background
content that stemmed
is the chrome its dim to help accentuate
the content
your presentation to help manage
the content in chrome in your view
controller presentation we're going to
use
you I presentation controller at its
heart
you a presentation controller is the
presentation management ap
a class that you'll use in your
application all
you a view controller presentations in
IOSA are backed
by you I presentation controller because
you I presentation controller
can provide chrome it can also provided
own animations
for that chrome or and this is really
cool
you I presentation controller can
animate its chrome
alongside your existing in a meter
object
custom animations and we'll take a depth
look at demos that
additionally throughout the conference
you heard about
are pushed to make your applications
more adaptive and UI presentation
controller
is built from the get-go to handle
treatment size class changes
additionally you a presentation
controller
respond to these changes even while your
view controllers presentation
is on screen so you can adapt seamlessly
between a changing environment
and finally because you a presentation
controller
is a great Cocoa Touch citizen its
reusable
you I presentation controller object are
not coupled
to animator objects or transitioning
delegates you can use the same
presentation controller
with different view controllers or
switch out the presentation controller
for the same view controller to create a
truly custom look
prior to iowa
aid the enemy object has petered mention
was
kinda overburdened with some past when
presenting a few controllers
content on screen its primary task with
obviously I mean my controllers content
men includes any kind of sub you
animations things like on 10 of sensor
in sets as well
but he also needed to figure out its own
positioning on screen
if you're doing any kind custom
presentation we would give you
reasonably good information for where to
start more to end
but it's probably not what you want for
your custom presentation
and so the enemy object had no more
about the presentation
than it probably should have and that
goes along with the chrome as well
that prison the animator object also
needed to know
the entire layout with the presentation
was going to in
incumbent compass but now a presentation
controller this responsibility for
positioning match
you controller and for handling the
chrome and other views that go along
with the presentation
are handled in a much more logical
object the presentation controller
since its long-lived knows more about
the presentation is it has a better
vantage point for what actually going to
occur on screen
and we've mentioned before presentation
controller
is what drives adaptation in your
application
this object is going to be responsible
for helping you switch out
view controllers in wholesale switching
on a presentation controllers which we
will look at
in just a moment
so now that we know about a little bit
what a presentation controller actually
is
let's to show you how we can you like it
use it to improve pop overs
alerts action sheets and search and Mark
Peters taking off with poppers
sure thing as you saw on our talk
yesterday
we're introducing a new you I
presentation controller class
to help manage popover presentations in
your app
it's called you i pop over presentation
controller
its intended to replace you I pop over
controller in your application
but it is functionally equivalent in the
customization
that it provides for the presentation
but it has some additional features
it has built-in additivity help
facilitate your
you controller adapting to a changing
environment you i pop over presentation
controller
wealthy mostly handled transitions
between regular and contact with
environments
let's look at how you used to show up
popover prior to I was 8
with the old API you create your content
view controller
said on your pop over controller and
present that pop over
but this isn't really the whole story
if you had a universal application and
many have you do
you actually had to have to code paths
we check in for an iPad
and make a popover controller otherwise
we do
a present view controller traditionally
and you had a litter this bifurcation
throughout your app with you i pop over
presentation controller
you'll just have one could pass here's
how to use it
first you'll set the view controllers
more presentation style
to pop over this is a new value in Iowa
State
you like it will look to your view
controllers motor presentation style
to determine how to show your view
controller
then you'll get it popover presentation
when presenting a view controller you do
not create a presentation controller
instead you ask for one then you set up
any source information
like bar button items or permitted air
directions and because it's a view
controller presentation
you just call present view controller
now
notice how there's no idiom checkout
screen that's because my running an
environment that does not support
popovers
like on the iPhone you a popover
presentation controller
provides the opportunity for your
presentation to adapt
Jim can we take a look at it after
popovers sure
track so ever fairly simple and basic
application here
it is a just a view controller that
shows important people
and the super poor people when you click
on this little button here you get a
popover
and it's a popover super important
people
and so what we want to do is show that
this pop over when it goes on
a in a compact with environment like an
iPhone
even though you present as a popover
you'll get an adaptation to an over full
screen presentation
will change the width 320 and will
change the size class the compact
and we'll play it and now you see that
we actually have
the same table view has been re present
in but now it's in a view controller
that is a full screen presentation
and we can actually even dismiss this
and we can re presented again
and even though worry presenting as an
over full screen presentation
we are the Coens never change we still
actually presenting a pop over here
and a show that's actually still working
will go back
to our regular with and in the popular
shows back up again
so to do an activity with pop overs
it's fairly simple
going back to Peters code that we left
off with
is that this code is an actual change
all through that with this was the code
they presented the popover
but to influence other pop over actually
works we need is a delegate
on the popover presentation controller
and we need implement just two methods
the first is adaptive presentation style
for presentation controller
in from this method you can return one
of three different methods fullscreen
over full screen or none bill the latter
meaning that you don't want any kind
about activity but for here
we want to do a full screen adaptation
the second method that we won't
implement his presentation controller
view controller for adaptive
presentation style
you don't have to implement this method
if we hadn't implemented this method
the table view controller would've been
Reapers and it has a full screen
presentation
but the table view by itself doesn't
allow you to dismiss anything or show
with the the name that we were selecting
so what we want to do is wrap that you
controller and something that
allows our presentation actually
continue to look like how we
we wanted to look and so we're after in
a navigation controller
and we just said is this review
controller the presented you controller
which was our people controller and
that's it and that is how you get from a
popover
in regular with to a over fullscreen
fullscreen presentation
when you're in a compact with
environment so
now that we've looked at you how you
like it used presentation controllers
to improve the API surrounding popovers
let's talk about something
near and dear to my heart alerts in
action sheets
prior to Iowa State alerts in action
sheets works post
to your application for plane you I view
subclasses
you I lurve you and you action she
but because they were you a view
subclasses they had to really implement
some of the logic that we already had
a new controller for example to appear
in your application
they created a new window strategically
appear a
strategically positioned about your
applications count 'em
that they'd show up above everything
additionally
they predate modern language features so
they had to rely on Delhi DPI
for button call backs let's look at how
an action she presentation worked
prior to Iowa State so I mean I R seven
ap
in landscape and I go to show an action
she
behind-the-scenes the primer creates a
window on Europe's behalf
but this predates I would say when the
rotation behaviors this window is
technically
still in portrait we then at the action
she to that window
and mimic the transform hierarchy the
present in view to get into the right
orientation
when looking at the requirements
applications would have to meet
when implementing add up to 30 and
customization power
offer to us are you a presentation
controller it was a natural choice
to rebase modern alert API
in iowa say we're introducing a new you
controller subclass to replace alert
view an action she
you eyler controller it's used for both
alert in action she's and you can switch
via preferred style
additionally because it's got a modern
runtime: its block-based
so it works perfect
it works perfect with blocks in
objective-c enclosures and swift
additionally because it's a view
controller it presents
in your window which means that there's
no more ambiguity
about what framework provided
presentations are going on in your
application
and using did adaptive API the gym
showed you earlier
action sheets will seamlessly adapt to
pop overs using paper presentation
controller
let's go through how you can create and
show an alert controller
in your application
first you'll ask for one via the class
method
then you what actions to it with a black
and learn to handle on that actions tap
and then because it's a view controller
presentation you're just call
present view controller now that we've
seen how you like it
use presentation controller to improve
alerts an action sheets
let's see how we did the same thing for
search
search and I was a consist primarily of
two parts: you a search bar
in you I search display controller both
have been around
in the St Cape sons some from the
earliest days
and their creation was formed a time
that was far more simple
view controllers were Mormon suggestion
the requirement that they are now
there was far less translucency things
that inflow underneath other things in
there was it certainly wasn't things
like blur
to deal with and so when you presented
search
it was very easy for the framework to
reason about how search was going to be
displayed
in your application but we're looking at
search display controller and how it
would react to an adaptive environment
we realize it had some deficiencies that
we just we're gonna be very difficult to
overcome
the first as it provides very limited
configurability
for you guys it's great that you can
show your search results in a table view
but a lot of other things have happened
since I was three that you couldn't
show search results and things like
election views and map news
and search display controller just
simply can't handle this
second search display controllers not a
view controller although it tries to act
like one
really hard and as the view controller
system became more intelligent and more
robust
as the STK matured research simply
display controller had a harder time
trying to understand your intense
when displaying and this lasted to have
to actually
guess in some situations and it didn't
always get it right
and finally because it again it's not a
view controller its presentation was
done via add some view
and show you how horrible was actually
was if in your application this was your
search bar with your content being
honored on the balloon you tap that
search bar
search display controller
behind-the-scenes goes in creeds a
content
view as a dimming view to it at the
table view to that
and then add some view to the search
display controllers
container our content view contact
controller's view
at this point in time your application
has a view that it didn't expect in a
tie Rakhi
and the framework is trying to manage
the fact that that view
was probably a ScrollView and things can
move around when we
we don't want him so it's clear that in
and
relativity this wasn't going to really
function all that well
but was looking at this search display
controllers really just doing a
presentation
I mean it already had its own container
so it kinda made sense to rebase this on
top of
you I presentation controller and that's
what we've done
so when I was 8 we're introducing you I
search controller which is
a view controller based replacement for
the now deprecated you I search display
controller
and it has a number of features
the first which is that it can present
on any view controller in your hierarchy
not just ones that are full screen
second is that the search controller no
longer tries to get in between
presenting the the thing that's showing
the results and the thing that's driving
the filtering and the results
this means that any object in your
application that's capable of filtering
search results can directly drive
the UI that's actually showing up on
screen
you can influence the search for
animation through to a custom and Amir
object
and because of course it's built on
presentation controller search control
has the capacity to become adaptive
and what this means to you guys in the
end is that's far more control and house
searches displayed in your applications
in far fewer assumptions made by the
framework when you're doing some
so taking a look at used to do this in
before I was a
we would create a search bar and we give
that search bar search display
controller
but then we have to tell search
controller who the data source in the
delegate were
for the table view that was gonna show
the results and then finally we would
make
the search bar the table header view
other table view that was already on
screen
now under I was eight with search
controller the first thing you want to
do is create
results controller and as I mentioned
this could be absolutely anything
a collection view or maybe a view that
custom to just your application
you give this results controller to the
search results controller
and then you tell the search controller
who's going to be responsible for
updating the results
in a lotta cases this will actually just
be the results controller but
it could be literally any object in your
application
next this is the one common cold line
between the old world is that we take
the search controller search bar
and we added to the table or sit at the
table header view have an existing table
view it on screen
now if you notice we don't actually
present this new controller at any point
in time
and that's because search is usually
event-driven the user's happening on the
search bar
other tapping on a search within your in
your user interface
and so in those cases search controller
is going to perform an automatic
presentation for you
based off of where the search bar is
located at in on the screen
of course there's a delegate method
allows you to drive us if you'd like but
for the most part
the the default animations are usually
pretty close to what you guys really
expect
finally is one piece %uh VP on its been
on you a view controller for some time
and it's the fines presentation context
when using you my search controller your
probably gonna need to define this
on the view controller in which he won
search to be presented
because search controllers trying really
hard to play with nicely with your
layout it needs to know exactly where it
is going to be displayed
and defines presentation context allows
it to know where you want to go
I'll show you a real quick example what
I mean here
take for take this example is a fairly
common case application
as the applications root view controller
is a tam bar controller
and as that have bars controllers
selected the tab is displaying a
navigation controller
and the navigation controllers route you
controller is our table view controller
and as we've seen before the previous
examples the search bar is that people
view controllers
table views table header view
and so you probably want to have the
same behavior that you've seen before I
would say does that when you tap on the
search bar
the navigation bar disappears in the
search bar takes its place
and the search result take the place at
the table view
in this example the table you control or
news the defined the presentation
context for the search controller
if you were to admit this you control
your presentation behavior
says that we will walk up the chains we
find somebody else who defines a
presentation contact
overuse the root view controller in this
case that would be the tab bar
controller
and so this may actually what you want
but it's something that you needed you
be aware I love
when using the new search controller is
that you need to tell us where you want
it at harvard is gonna go presenting on
the group you controlling so now that
we've shown you how you like it has
leveraged
you a presentation controller what are
the benefits to you guys for us having
done this work
well first off its controllers now all
over the place everything the controller
no matter where you look
and this is good for you guys we are no
longer trying to shove their views into
your hierarchy
or no longer trying to transform Windows
about everything
its controllers it's a view controller
system and allows you very
unprecedented control and how these
control how these new controllers are
displayed in your application
additionally because you a presentation
controller provides an
excellent abstraction between the
content have your presentation
and the chrome around it you a
presentation controller
provide a natural home for these things
to live no longer
to system provided you controllers
contain their chrome in the view
controller
and finally additivity we keep things
over and over again but we needed to
make our own controllers
at adaptive ahead for your guys period
is applications
so now alerts and search can add abt
with your applications I'm all the other
adaptations that you want to do
the major applications work in this new
size class world that we're going into
him
so now that we've gone through how you
like it as use these thing I use
presentation controller
that showed them all that can oppose all
these come to a concept together
use a custom presentation controller and
a custom animator to make a really cool
interface Peter let's do it
I've been working on this awesome new
photo management and editing application
here we have a collection view and when
I tap a photo
we're going to do a view controller
presentation but it looks different than
a default view controller presentation
you notice that the presented view
controller slides in from the right
while medium the rest to the screen and
we kept him in view
were hit the Save button will dismiss
good at this photograph
looks great so I'll hit safe
and we dismiss that you controller we
should go through
how this presentation uses a custom
presentation controller
an animator object to control placement
animations
let's go through you can build a custom
presentation like this
in your application we're going to start
in the root view controller a wrap
you'll notice this p in the corner
with added colors and tax at the legend
so that you know what controller
or object we're talking about in the
root view controller
we're going to create a new overlay you
controller
this is what you saw presented as a
sidebar in the demo
we just stop then because it's a view
controller
will just call present view controller
now
if we had stopped here and not
implemented anything custom
what we get well
we have a review controller and we go to
present me get the you like it the fault
a slight up from the bottom foreskin
presentation
that looks cool but what you really want
is a custom presentation
so when we present the sidebar it slides
in from the right
while we'd im the presenting view
controllers content
let's talk about the objects that are
going to be responsible for this custom
presentation
we are ready now that we have a root
view controller and are presented
overlay view controller in Iowa 7
we introduce the concept have a
transition in Gallia in this
presentation
this transition delegate will be
responsible for providing the animator
object
which animates a controller contents on
screen
this is the same API that we introduced
and I are seven
but new in Iowa State this transition
delegate will also provide
the presentation controller this is the
object that will drive the management
the content and chrome in this
presentation
let's start with getting that dimming
view on an off-screen
first back in our review controller
will create a new transitioning delegate
to use for this presentation
this is the object that provides the
animator object
and presentation controller and we'll
set that transitioning delegate
unrepresented overlay view controller
now in our overly view controller will
center motor presentation style
to custom this indicates to you like it
that we should consult your transition
julliard for custom presentation
controller
to use for the presentation insider
our transition delegate will need to
provide their presentation controller
by implementing presentation controller
for presented view controller
presenting view controller source the
controller
here will return the presentation
that we're responsible for the lifetime
this view controllers transition
let's implement some methods in the
presentation controller
to manage the steaming view we're gonna
implement two methods
to coordinate the timing to you the
first
his presentation transition will begin
this is called when we're about to do
the presentation transition here we've
already set up a dimming view
in it and we'll just said that during
these frame to the container views
bounds
this way the pro the victim and he was
always full screen
will also set the offer the dimming view
20 so it appears
fully transparent at the beginning of
the animation
will make sure we insert the demand you
above all the other content in the
presentation
and then this is really cool
you a presentation controller can
provide its only animations
for its chrome in this case the dimming
view or
it can enemy alongside the existing
animations
in the animated object and that's
exactly what we want
we call the presented view controllers
transition coordinator
to animate alongside the current
transition
inside this block was that the dimming
these offer
21 this way the animations
both begin at the same time in finish at
the same time
and it looks great now let's implement
the second method in our presentation
controller for managing the demand you
dismissal transition will begin here
we're going to undo we did in
presentation transition will begin
in this case we use the same transition
coordinator API
to animate fading the dimming view 20
alpha
but the others looks we go to present
the movie fades in and it fades away
looks great but we should probably get
are presented you control on-screen next
first will need to go back to our
transition delegate and return a custom
in a meter object will do this by
implementing animation controller
for presented controller presenting
controller source controller
this is the API that you used I was
seven
careful return our custom view a custom
class
which is in charge of this animation
will also implement
the inverse if this method dismissal
are I'm sorry animation controller for
dismiss controller
you like it gives you the power and
flexibility
I'm using a different in a meter object
for the presentation
and dismissal but here will just use the
same one
now as you saw in the demo that overly
sidebar
was a third the size of the display to
size it appropriately
willing to implement several methods in
our presentation controller
the first is size for child can tin
container
with parent container size and this
methods really simple
will just return a third of our parents
with and therefore parent tight
that were always a third of the display
next will implement frame-up presented
view
in containers you this is where we
return
to the view controller transition system
what frame we'd like to present view
to have will use the same size that we
return
from sites for child content container
with parent container size
and fit the origin the prevent presented
use frame
to be right aligned in the container
let's see how that works
perfect the overlay is a third the
display and right aligned
bought we also want is when we rotate
into landscape
that sidebar should always appear as a
third the display
no problem implementing rotation in
presentation controller
is really simple was just need to
implement
one method container view will layouts
abuse
first will set the dimming these frame
said always the full size in the
container
even when the containers changing
balance
then will set the frame at the present
in view to the same value we return
from for frame presented view and
containers you
and we're done weekend rotation
now that we've seen how view controller
sizing works in presentation controllers
it's important to understand the
messaging that happens
between presentation controllers in
their manage new controllers
new and I would say there's a new
protocol you add content container
and it's implemented by both you a view
controller and UI presentation
controller
and it's a collection of methods the
describe how the view controller and
presentation controllers
communicate changes in the environment
to one another
and it's important that we talk about
these methods in regards to how they
flow between
that the objects between the controllers
because I
the forwarding is done automatically for
you and less you interfere with it
and I'll show you why you'd want to do
that was a couple different
I ideas here so we'll start off with
transitioning to a specific size
there's two methods specifically here
you will transition the size
with transition coordinator and as peers
to show you size for child content
container with parent container size
these indicate to the view controller
the pair that the presentation
controller
but the physical size the view has
actually changed
and this is best kinda shown throughout
a diagram that shows how the messaging
flows through
so this give ourselves a review
controller with a couple child you
controllers
and let's have it present if you can't
or doesn't really matter what it
actually is
and is peter is mentioned previously all
presentations view controllers are
managed by
a presentation controller so we gotta
have one of those guys too
so now that we have this set up this
give ourselves a few will transition to
size call
maybe the device rotated and that we're
getting a different size
are different bounds for that view
these messages always start with the
root view controller
and from there that controller will
message any child view controllers that
it may have
but the size that we pass it to the
rupee controllers probably not the same
size that you wanna pass into the child
it might
is probably a smaller size so this is
worse I was for child content container
with parent container size comes in
we'll ask the Ru controller to size
child one enroute
that method returns a size that we will
pass on the child someone
tell one's you will transition to size
we continue on if there are any other
child you controllers have this
controller
and then any controllers that are
presenting view controllers that means
that they have another view controller
presented on top of them
will have their presentation controller
called next
in this case the Ruby control the child
you can't or excuse me don't aren't
presenting anybody
but the root view controller actually is
the review controller is not a container
for the presentation controller
so the size it gets passed to it is the
same size that we gave to the root
controller
but the presentation controller is the
container for the presented controller
so we need to ask the presentation
controller a size for child Konkan
container passing on presented view
controller
the messaging flows basically as a
depth-first search you start with the
root view controller
any child controllers they are present
will get called
but any control over that is presenting
UConn presenting another controller will
have its presentation controller Cup
messaged
and then it's presented controllers
messaged and then
the process repeats again if for any
reason that you
implement one of these methods and you
call super this messaging
still is performed for you but if you
implement these methods and don't call
super
the object or the class that does not to
pass the message on any of its child
controllers or any of its presented
presentation controllers will no longer
get that message
it's something to be aware of
group there is a more next up is
preferred content size and their two
items here
preferred content size and I
preferred content size did change for
child content container
and this is arm methodologies for
allowing a presented view controller a
child you controller to say
ID more or less size to its container
controller
I really good example this is the
Notification Center widgets
will do this your notification your
widget will actually say its own
preferred content size
which will message its container to
allow the size to change
sure this looks like in our example
see the present a controller ones that
grow by 100 points
so what sets its preferred contents eyes
to what it would like
and because the presentation controller
is the container controller
love the presented controller it gets
the message
preferred content size to change for
child content container
now for the child wonder child to you
controllers had
requested more side when the route you
controller would have gotten this
message so
it's just been messaging up to the
container controller
at this point I'm the container has a
decision to make does it one on or the
size request
in and if so how much of it doesn't one
on you can simply ignore it there's not
any space to give
oregon say well you asked for a hundred
points I can give you 50
if you were going till resize the view
it's important you call back if you will
transition the size we transition
cornerback
on the view that made the request this
coming a receipt for that you control to
let it know that the requested size
it's gotten the size or whatever much
size you the container gave it
and it's allowed them to for that
message on to any child containers it
may have
and key rate in the key point here is
that after you sent this message
the container needs to resize the child
contain
your child you controller sending the
message you will transition to size
does not actually perform the resize
itself at something that the container
needs to do
finally our tree collections and is one
method here and that is will transition
to tree collection
with transition coordinator and this has
the same kind of messaging semantics
as the fuel transition the size at a
flows in the same
order and if you don't call through
super the the message chain
ends there if you hadn't seen the the
talked yesterday
bond building adaptive applications with
you like it
are I highly recommend checking that out
because it goes in the tree collections
and depth and how they interact with the
rest the system
but is a really quick overview what they
are case you haven't read the
documentation
trick elections are simply a collection
okie value pairs the described
environment to a view controller
or have you already our screen and there
are four properties
horizontal size class which describes
with vertel's like this give me a
vertical size classes describes hide
the user interface idiom that describes
the type device that your own
and in the scale that the signs then
scaled advice
so for an iPhone in Papillion
nor in portrait the where's all size
classes compact
its vertical size classes regular if the
phone so its users is a founding has k
love to you
know all these methods are trying to
allow you to
have your application respond to changes
but
some you may be petted the ones that are
be paying attention most probably
notice that we have two methods that
actually send moved somewhat the same
information
you will transition to treat collection
has the notion of science classes
but we also have this method view will
transition the size that's sending on
the size
so why do we have both these methods
that's a great question before actually
tell you why
I did and two more methods to this you a
presentation controllers container view
will lay out some views
and you a view controller's view layouts
abuse
starting with will transition a tree
collection
this is intended to be a very core
screen control over
the layout of your application when you
re see you trade collection changes
it's an indication that the structure
the overall structure replication is
probably going to change your needs to
be updated
a great example love this is of course
additivity
in every the example them like TV before
with the popover went to full screen
that's not just a view being swapped out
that its view controllers and
presentation controllers being exchanged
wholesale
a dramatic significant amount to change
your applications you
interface but it's not just all about
science classes
screens can have different scales you
can't really can be on
a did the main device can which has a
skillet you back to two
to axe but then an external monitor
clever one XScale
and moving that view controller from the
primary screen to that secondary screen
could completely change how you I need
to be laid out
and the not it's not always about entire
UI changing a fax
an example of this would be now and I
was eight
when we go from IA enough iphone-like
device when we go from a compact with
regular hive
in WI roti into a compact with compact
height environment
we're going on to hide the status bar
for you
and we do that not because there's less
space lab does not less physical space
that you can't roller
it's that it makes more sense in that
situation
to remove a status bar so that your
content has more
more area display itself
next up is view will transition the size
and this is the medium green control
approach for and responding to changes
and as I mentioned before this is an
indication that your view actually has
more or less I is the deal with
and it should actually add more content
remove content depending officer how the
size changed
a great example this is the child cunt
the child controller requesting more
size
in this case it's not an indication for
that view controller tell actually lay
itself out
it's an indication that it needs to
actually add more content
you also get this gone rotation with
rotation and her I was eight
it's simply a bounce change so when will
you when the device rotates
your view controller Walter told that
its eyes will change in your problem see
that the with
in the hype that's want and finally you
also see these guys
these a messages called when the recital
similar changes that size
so many buying out the same here you'll
see that as well
finally is continually out some views
and you lay out some views
and these are the fine green controls on
you I presentation controller
and you a view controller respectively
it works just like you I views layouts
abuse
and is meant to do fine adjustments to
disabuse love your hierarchy and that
includes
include includes child content use as
well so when your presentation
controller got that message
that the presented you controller needs
to have a different size
you would change that present view
controller size in container view will
lay out some views
so now that we understand how the
messaging flows through the controller
high-ranking
let's take a look at the time demo that
shows how we do at the data added a
additivity to our demo app and then also
shows how to use multiple presentation
controllers to show
I did this by the same you can filter
content
so we're going to go back to the same
demo application we're looking at
earlier
my photo management application
using the same API the gym talked about
for you i pop over presentation
controller adapting
we can adapt our custom view controller
too
as you remember we have the sidebar but
we transition
to a compact with environment what we'd
really like to have
is just a full screen presentation
here will change the way it 3 23 here in
and the size class to compact
and check it out we get a full screen
presentation
this is using that same adaptive
presentation style
adaptivity API and presentation
controller that we show you
in Papa presentation controller but
what's really cool
is that we can still use our custom in a
meter object
see you notice the one we dismiss the
view controller by tapping the Save
button
we slide off from the right and we
present again
we slide in from the right this is
exactly what we want
and to show that it goes the other way
or change the size class
back to regular with the with have 768
points
and boom the transition transitions
perfectly
and gets placed correctly next
I'd like to show you something really
cool
because presentation controllers are not
coupled
to their presented you controllers we
can switch out a presentation controller
that's used for a view controller with
zero changes
to the present a new controller I'm
gonna tap this little switch in the
corner
which turns on cool mod this flips
some internal state in my view
controller to use it different
transition delegate
which will provide a totally custom
animator
and totally custom chrome to its
presentation controller
so when I tap a photo incentive that
overlay sidebar presentation
the view controller slide in from the
Middle beautiful leopard print appears
from the side
and we get some totally custom chrome
you'll notice some things about this
custom presentation
when we do the presentation while the
unicorn
and flower appear alongside the view
controller
in a meeting in the leopard print
inmates
by itself this is because you a
presentation controller
can enemy tits chrome in a different
animation block
than that which is used for the view
controller presentation
so we can make that chrome respond just
how you want
by the way this simple code including
call node
is available on the world wide developer
conference website
just look for look inside let's see
how we implemented this totally custom
presentation controller
and switch the presentation controller
we used
for overlay view controller
back in our review controller I show you
setting up our transition delegate
like this we're gonna need to augment
this logic
a little bit to provide our other
presentation controller
first will check a new internal method
that we've called
presentation should be awesome and if
this is true
will use a totally new transition tell
you
this transition delegate will provide
custom animator object
to manage that skill in animation and a
custom presentation controller
to manage the crown the use our earlier
otherwise
if that value is not set to yes will
just use
the other transition go get that you saw
earlier
and then setting this on the view
controller will cause all that machinery
to be put in place
when we go to present
so to summarize what we talk about her
today and there's only two points that
you really need to take home with you
first of three you I presentation
controller you like it
ourselves are eating our own on food and
really improve our own API
for alerts in for pop overs and per
search
no longer do you need to put their views
into your hierarchy if they
could be best served by a presentation
additionally with presentation
controller representing
the last piece in the puzzle for totally
custom presentations
you can now build things that you never
could before
with custom chrome and custom animations
and we encourage you
to go make your own cool mod we can't
wait to see
what types have totally custom
presentations you're going to add
to your application
have you had any more information or
questions Jake barron's the game played
down here is our happened that
frameworks evangelist loves hearing from
you guys because there's documentations
on the Apple Developer forms
more important over the related sessions
this is the last talk on you a view
controller
up with new and you can't rollers and I
was eight so all the sessions were
earlier in the week
highly recommended to take them on the
videos and that's it enjoy the rest a
comment and have a great vacay