he think you
thank you very
much my name is Andy Matuszak I work in
the UI kit framework
and later I'm going to join by my
colleague Colin Barrett
also works on you like it today we're
gonna talk
about advanced I O S architectural
patterns
which is is going to store to be a
continuation
a bill done is talk from this morning
the core I was
application Arctic Tern patterns were
gonna be taking some of those ideas a
little further
and just in case you didn't see that
talk this morning or even if you did
I want to tell a little story explains I
think
how we all got here many start-up by
yourself in the project start small
they're well-intentioned keeping
everything orderly
you're adding features and everything
still good you add more features and
the kinda pile-up been you got momentum
behind you now have all these users and
demanding
yet more developers cuz maybe that'll
help but it doesn't seem to have quite
the impact on your progress but you've
been hoping for
you're making changes faster and faster
and bug thing to be appearing faster and
faster
and things like all you're doing is
spending your time finding bugs
and you think okay well knock you down
in a few more comeback
not adding new features you ads and unit
tests to try to get a handle
on what's going on here somebody stole
you that's gonna help things but through
the open easily and then the button
start
coming back and then you learn actually
your YouTube tough can have bugs to what
we do
people say
software architecture you are a
cool Suffolk texture are
whatsapp architecture researcher on the
internet and you
you know how much a blog airlifting like
home and never do this
stop its gonna make your architecture
bad and it seems like a lot
contradicting opinion from people safe
start small and some people wanted line
everything up front
things like these discussions just keep
coming back to
taste maybe dogma all you really know
maybe is that your taste
is improving a lot faster than your
ability
you can tell that something starting to
get smelly
can tell you got a problem the maybe you
don't know what to do about it
Serena try to help you'd only scratched
the surface today
the ideas to take some time honored
concepts
from computer sciences offerings nearing
an to present them
hopefully less abstractly and in a way
that might make sense to
you and I West developer with your app's
today were
hoping to provide insight not dogma were
not
I'm so glad so glad to hear that
epistemology is important need to know
why you're having architectural problems
not just a bag of tricks that you can
use
when faced with any particular issue
that way
probably have a real objective measure
but you can use to compare approaches
that way when your colleagues disagree
with you can actually talk about
what might be better and what might be
worse and why rather than just
citing a buncha countries alright
so today we're going to talk about 3
brought approaches
that you can use to consider the
complexity your application and evaluate
approaches to dealing with it
first time we have tangled measures
up information that works like this
we're gonna clean them up
by actually designing the information
flow in our application rather than just
letting it grow ad hoc like a weed
and then when are objects start to
become a more pissed blobs
we're going to separate them actually
define what their responsibilities
are and hopefully get each other circles
a little smaller
finally when Pinkberry ground seems to
be shifting out from under you
we're going to take advantage of
immutability and in particular
some new features have swift to really
get a handle on things
for those big concerts from today will
start
but talking about designing information
flow
now much the complexity in a modern
application is really just shuffling
information events around
yet delicate handlers target action
called active completion blocks
ideas and signals and how should
this information and events go through
your application
is our wiring stuff up is that this
object to the delegated this other
object ever hear
you say at Target action and every time
you're doing that
adding a little-known this network
never just getting earlier and i learn
maybe you've drawn networks like this
force a
object ownership in your application
which object owns which other object or
maybe for a workflow but in this section
we're going to
talk about thinking conceptually about
this diagram as it pertains to
information flow in your application
where's information coming from and
where is it going
the first question I'll ask is where is
true my application
in order to do that in order to keep
things hopefully some concrete
we're gonna turn to a demo application
which is having its own problems with
information plump
all rights over here we have an
application it's going to be written in
swift
and thats just because I like swift
quite a lot by the
the topics were discussing in this
particular section really don't
require swept I it's worth the journey
application
right on what's going on in your life
cue track things maybe River him Lincoln
and like any journaling up there's a UI
to add an entry you got the bug report
for user
talking about a bug with the photo
edition you live in your application
so go ahead and start making a journal
entry
we will out a photo
taking this one from Apple dot com hand
there is this Peter here that lets me
show and hide
the photos that I've attached to my
journal entry
everything's looking good so far but
this bug report I got
said that the app seems to break
when I'm playing with this button so
I'll play with the button
so something really which is happening
there and we have a crash
that's no good now we can look at this
back trace but
probably the problem is already happened
and we can see the issuance now this
exclamation point here's
going awry rather than trying to address
this specific crasher I'd like to draw
your attention to the
infrastructural problem which is
underlying the scratcher
let's take a look how exactly this
expanding and collapsing love the photo
drawer features work
here to expand photo drawer and uppers
we say okay do we have authority
if we don't make one
did it all laid out so it'll expand from
0 height but
animated 24 heights and you know update
that but in a little bit a bookkeeping
course then in collapsed orange or if we
only have a corridor which we want to
collapse
we animated shots and when the emissions
done we remove it
things pretty straightforward you know
you might say well this this
option this option seems to be the
problem like you're letting users
interact with your you all the
animations going on
shouldn't do that %uh okay so you could
remove this option
I but you know we we do actually want to
keep things fluid
there's no reason that the world should
up to stop just because this folder is
opening up
and furthermore all we're starting to
get a little them for that taste verses
ability tradeoff we were talking earlier
I mean hopefully your
your you're looking at this year's thing
I well I i dont
exactly see anything wrong so trying to
work around this bug by just disabling
the button doesn't seem like the best
thing to do
what's really going on and even if we
were disable the spine
things get somewhat worse if I rerun
this application of show you there's
sort of a side feature
to say that was the case that you could
not
interact with the show photos button
while the animations going on well
now here's our body and as we start
typing into it
we hide that for it or because we want
to have more space for the keyboard
so it's actually not good enough just to
disable this button
to make this problem go away the problem
will still exist because
we collapse this photo drawer
plan we focus the body about to keep
going on like that it would crash
so there's something more fundamental at
play here some mold growing in the
corner
and I'd like to return to diagrammatic
approach
to examine that mold
now this is boxes and arrows
representation at the information flow
in our application
we've got this this photos or tap action
and we've also got a text new focus
action and they're both doing something
based on a piece of information now
piece of information is
does that follows drawer exist does that
Jordan you exist already
every song the code it doesn't exist
today will make it and if it does exist
will start animation when the
nominations done will throw it out
that's phenomenal what's going on here
this bug is occurring
because we're getting our information
from the wrong place there's another
piece in state
which is in the drawer semantically
expanded
that separate from does the drawer view
exist because the journey wasn't torn
down
until the animation completes if we
start collapsing the drawer
then we want to think about the state of
the system
as the drawer is collapse now just like
to start animating a view to the other
side of the screen
its model value is already at its
destination
the drawer whose existence is more like
the presentation value that you it's
like a proxy
for that underlying truth should the
drawer view
be expanded modulo any emissions that
are going on
so we can deal with this problem by
ratifying that the state
beginning a property say you know is the
door you expanded right now updated
immediately
when we start collapsing the drawer view
and let me start expanding that your
view
and then once we do that we can look at
this diagram and say we're
why are these actions getting their
truth
from whether or not the drawer you
exists what really matters
is whether or not the door supposed to
be expanded or not and when you picked
up in the TextView
you should only really be collapsing the
four drawer
if it is actually expended you don't try
to collapse the photo drawer
if it's in the process a beam collapsed
already
but that drawer view hasn't been removed
yet
now in a stock I'm not actually going to
make the code changes that we're talking
about here because
with a lot material to get there and i
wanna cover quickly but here we've been
able to solve this problem
a conceptual level at least by thinking
about our system
in terms love how information is moving
through it
where we're going data however making
decisions and considering first
where is true who really knows
that state which one place should be
consulted for it
now to help us get all the boxes that we
need in our diagram
don't think on all the boxes we need in
our diagram
on joy attention to the difference
between
that room level truth that one place in
your application that actually knows
where things are supposed to be
and the values which are merely derived
from it
so in order to do that again let's
return to our demo application
and you'll see here that as I continue
typing
the character counter my character
counter there because you might be
extremely
up going extroverted person with your
journal you might want to
take advantage of this feature that we
have which automatically shares
oliver journal entries to put her so we
give you a
character count in order to help you
make sure
that it actually gonna fit when you post
Twitter simple enough
goes up as wheatly and goes down
as we had in characters that's all fine
but if we think about the this photos
feature
that we have
you know when we post to Twitter
we're gonna have to put a URL for that
photo in the body in a tweet so that
means to be included
in the character count and we got a bug
from users saying that
they tried to make a post and
Twitter rejected it even at the Y said
it was okay
so I added this photo you can see it
added to this entry
and we can see that the number remaining
characters is 240
and if I start typing wacho enter one
key
and we jumped on the 118 like
immediately reconsidered
the URL I'm sure you've all seen this
kind of bug quite a lot from things
stale something that was supposed to
happen has not
happened and unfortunately that kind of
problem is really difficult to debug
there's no way to break
so we can we can look at the code and
say okay what's supposed to happen
there is a an update character count
method
here and very simple it just a
just update this character count label
with the result %uh
our Twitter entry encoder to those two
possible problems here
of a problem number one is but we're
entering coder is that Paul
it's returning a wrong value possible
problem number two is this method is
simply not being called
when we add a photo so
we can look to invalidate wannabes
hypotheses we can we can look to sort of
guide to where we should be addressing
are debugging abilities we can
do that by just adding a break point
here
and well going create a new journal
entry here to set this up again
all out photo: we see that the character
count is never called
but 1i anarchy here it is called
sewer problem appears to be at this this
method is just not even getting called
when it should be called in
let's continue to follow this rabbit
hole upwards I guess
and see who calls update your account
not only called in one place
and it's called on text you didn't
change
now Taliban esoteric
facto it about the you like it and after
the eyes is that
if you programmatically set attacks
Piers value the text you does not
emit delegate call backs saying that the
text is by changed
and the same thing is true for basically
anything else the house a delegate call
back if you programmatically set the
value
that its corresponding to that call back
you like it flak jacket will not call
you back
so you can react to this by saying
allergies
got to work around this this weird you
like it behavior
II guess we'll add an extra call to
update character count
when we at a photo which happens
down here somewhere right here you know
we we coulda
we can call it that character count
there but you know what if we added
a audio recording feature you know to go
take a voice note about how your day's
going what if we added a video recording
feature all these things are going to
have to remember to update the character
count
ans I hope anyway that you're starting
to get that
sort ofthis person's ability smell again
something seems amiss here
not exactly clear what it is
so again I propose that the solution is
thinking about the information flows
your application diagrammatic way
here dan is a diagram any information
flow in the application
as a text you enter the character count
both these things
are getting their values from the mall
let things okay
we've got truth the models will intrude
and we're using the right inputs in our
information flow
but we're still not getting the right
behavior reason for that
is that derived values have to be
treated differently
think about what is derived values are
in comparison
to the truth which provides their inputs
now if you have a drive value it doesn't
couple things the commute it computes
some other value like a character count
from some seven parts
that straightforward we saw that the
character count
separately it needs to re computer
that output when one the inputs changes
these requirements are really very much
like a catch
and I propose to you that everywhere in
your program where you have something
like
a character count which seems like a
very straightforward thing it's just
a value derived from another value all
of those things
have many of the same properties all a
cash
which means that they're subject to the
same problems that a cash as well
for instance when your original data
changes you need to make sure to update
the cache data or else you're going to
have
staleness bugs and on the flip side
if the original data haven't changed
than you shouldn't be going about Jerry
adding new
cash representations that information
either else you're going to have a
vision see problems
now our problem here is stilts
and you can see that the same issues
apply for truth versus derived values
as they do for caches and the values
which are being
cash so its focus on the stand on this
issue here
and try to understand what's going on
with our application how to
get here where did we go wrong and how
do we model it with these information
diagrams
surgery in this diagram
we see that the models are you to find
the text you value
I guess they didn't show it to you but
take my word on that the models of the
changes we set the text you value is
very straightforward
we haven't seen any bugs with that at
least not yet anyway so let's go ahead
and assume that this is how it works and
when the models change the text using
validated saw love that is fine
the problem that we're having is with
the character count we've seen the
definition about the character count we
know that
the character count as deriving its
value from the model
but when the model changes the character
count is not invalidated
rather it's when the text you changes
the character count is being invalidated
and the lopsided miss in this diagram
should hopefully indicate something to
you usually they rose is basically doing
have a job
you're splitting up these
responsibilities to different places
and that's really because of our buck
region we can solve our bug
by merging its responsibilities back to
one place because of the stillness
problem by saying okay whenever the
model changes we need to make sure to
update over
values which are derived from that model
it's really easy to do this in swift
because we've got these fancy new
property observers
we have to do is add that up the
character count call to our did set lock
and in general gonna be way better off
if you always keep users merge together
and this is a very pressing reason
not to so that's just one more tool in
your tool bag
for thinking about the complexity in
your application
actually draw out these information
flows what the boxes
where the arrow's teacher those arrows
actually mean
both definition and invalidation because
they need to
Realty might have still has problems
now finally I'd like to turn your
attention to the text you
now he said okay the text he was getting
its value
from the model not part appears to work
but
we know that when the user types in the
text you that model must be getting
updated
after all I can making a journal entry
and
it appears to get saved so there must be
some reverse relationship here too
how we think about that schematically in
the same way
and in particular this looks like an
infinite loop
but it's not we don't have a stack
overflow
so these errors must be asymmetric in
some way
and I propose to you that in thinking
about how new truth
is created need to carefully consider
the asymmetry those relationships in
your application
alright so its return to our app talk
about creating new true
now our application is another feature
I've been told you about that features
that
I can share my journal with a loved one
I can let my fiance see all these
entries i right
at a great feature I'm but it's
complicated somewhat by the fact that
there's this
edit button here you know if I were to
start
editing the century you see our
character count issue on display again
about to start editing the century out
we need this break point anymore
then we don't expect
for my fiance just a reminder phone to
actually see
this at a journal entry at right because
I can hit cancel
I'll be throwing it out presumably the
old entry would still be there
so I said that working with the model
here but we must not be working with
any model must be working with some
other model
that has a relationship to the first
model
because if they were really one model
then there will be no real way a
implement this cancel button and she
would be seeing those changes as soon as
I made them
I'm going to suggest that thinking about
the relationship between this
editing you eyes model and the
underlying model
which it is added a is actually the same
as the relationship between the model
underline the TextView
and the new values that the text use
emitting to the mall
but if we're gonna think about this
effectively we really need
to be able to think about it from
a diagrammatic perspectives so that we
can see where everything is in
how it's going so talk about these
errors
let's talk about what they need
what's that asymmetry we know if we
start with just the text you
that the Texas values defined by the
models value we also know that if we
edit the text you somehow that monica is
getting updated
but the tax-free with deference
to the model value if the mall Delhi
where change
out from under the text you somebody
were to just Sep the body to something
else
but text you would probably just update
immediately to that new value
and if some other piece the program were
wondering what
is the body value up this journal entry
they wouldn't asked the text you or at
least we hope that they went as we saw
earlier instead we hope that they would
ask the model
the model is true and these derived
values
are different too true these new values
they met
as you added are like suggestions
flowing back up the graph to the model
along these dashed arrows
truth new pieces of information facts
these things flow from the model to the
derived values
and suggested new pieces of information
flow back from a taxi to the model
because the course the consolidation the
behavior over application with respect
to the 140 character 20 limit could be
that we just okay
so it could be that that suggested
value: was not applied exactly
in this way this relationship is
asymmetrical
and we can use the same structure is
thinking
to think about the entry viewing
controller
which presented that editing controller
and
the entry editing controller there's
some original model
not so my fiance saying she looks at the
app and that's the one that's gonna
still be there if we hit cancel
and then there's the model that were
edited which
began from a copy at the original model
so the same way as these other
relationships in our crap the model that
we're editing is derived from the
original model
and when we had that done button
are editing controller is suggesting a
new value
for the model to the viewing controller
that is how new truth
is created
I want you to imagine with me because it
isn't on the slide
that there is a dashed arrow coming from
the model
back up to the original model that is
how you can think about this
relationship
just as the model may validate the text
is value is coming out the text you
the original entry view controller maybe
validating the edited entry for instance
if she were able to edit those journal
entries also
there could be a conflict now and so
when the new model value suggested
some you I might be presented to allow
that merged to happen
in the same way the editing controller
its value is derived from the viewing
controller
and the new value was only a suggestion
to the viewing controller
so we work through how these techniques
can help us solve several real-world
application problems
and hopefully they suggest to you ways
that you can solve
the kinds of problems you face in your
everyday use have to actually think
about how information and events are
flowing through application first where
is true who really knows
who is really responsible for those
fundamental pieces States
information events in your application
and then once you start thinking about
how the flow through your application
remember the difference between true and
the values derived from church
remember that values derived from sure
there are many ways like a cash
and needed to be treated as such and
finally remember that when new truth is
created
that relationship asymmetrical by
necessity
in order to avoid some kind of infinite
loop one direction
facts flow and in the other direction
suggested new values flow which may need
to be merged a valid in some way
by thinking systematically about the
information flow in your application
you can really get a handle a complexity
all right now let's move on
I'm going in by calling their it up talk
about the fining
clear responsibilities for your
application
here
thank you any good afternoon everybody
miss next section minute show you
how to identify and tease apart
responsibilities in your application but
start with an example
form validation
we've all at least used form like this
many russians may be implemented one
you know it's not a simple as
just putting from text field on the
screen and a button
their rules about
what values are allowed in a different
text fields before we have here
and how the other interface elements
in this view are enabled
and disabled or shown in hidden
depending on the values the text field
so
what they were implementing this are
this few here where we start
well will need to know when the user
finishes editing a text field
so will implement the text field did and
editing
delegate message
our view controller and in that
delegate message we're gonna need to
consider each text field
and if they're all valid enable the Sign
up button
but we can't exactly consider
all these text field uniformly they all
have different
rules let's look at the rules for the
username
field with this regular expression
that our server engineers came to us we
have to match that against the content
to be using text field
we don't have any if we don't match
we're gonna need it show the user
somehow that they messed up in
when you go back and correct a mistake
now
there's a1 other complication here and
that's if our text fielder empty
if or
text goes empty when we're checking each
field we're gonna wanna leave it alone
but one were considering the state of
the Sign up button
we're gonna want to leave the Sign up
button
disabled so we're gonna wanna leave
unstable because
we don't want the user percy with
partially filled out form so let's go
back to the user name
part-time see what that would look like
an in cult
so yes there's a lot of code
but it's all different sorts of
thanks intermingle we have local
variables the track the state love the
text fields and I've empty text fields
we have a bunch regular expression code
right next to that and in between all
that we have
these two lines which are really the
most important
for what the view controller does which
is to manage
and configure its constituent views so
much like we can diagram
information for application we can also
diagram
responsibilities who does what here
in the diagram that we've been thinking
about so far we we have our view
controller
which manages and configures its
constituent views
and we have our views which display the
data given
work or animation Inc or graphics but
we've identified
a third overlapping responsibility
validation
as may not think
so bad but if we had another view
controller that also have to do some
more validation
know how the same logic into places
a bug in one at 3:15 the other and fence
these are in different places it's
likely that they will diverge overtime
I'm typeof we'll get at it in one place
but not the other cuz not left 30 their
making it even more difficult to change
and
and fix these common issues overtime
so what we want to do is separate their
responsibility out
in one place that can be shared by both
you controllers
so to do that we person identified
what validation actually it's
when thinking about these types of
questions it's useful to think of the
input
and output Ford to put it another way
what information do I need and what
questions
much trying to answer so are they build
through
this a common sense Val explanation what
validation is
I'm gonna fill an the inputs an output
in stable
so validation seems to be that
if you give me an input value I can tell
you if it's valid
and it is not a valid I can tell you why
these pretty directly translate
to fairly simple data types
and we look at what that looks like here
in swept
on forgiveness in fact they're there we
have are output
types were here but we're missing our
input
at because we want to leave this
actually open to interpretation in this
case
because a good technique for dealing
with complicate responsibilities
it to be able to build larger units
are smaller ones so in this case will
build larger Bella there's
at a smaller ones so for those larger
validators
the input will be implicit in the
constituent Valley daters input
this technique is called composition for
composing
a large around later at a smaller ones
and it works
totally fine objective-c to I also
really like swift I
so let's look at what I username object
%um calendar object implements this
validation protocol would look like
wall we have our input here the string
and
this bell date with error function is
where we're going to have our regular
expression code
it's now up isolated it's not air
mingled with
all these this other code we can do
likewise
for password validation
but may be wondering that
dazzling represent the validity of a
single password field
then that's correct we need to represent
that to password fields
match in value in addition to an not
being too short
not being hi mom things like that
so will create a that password valliere
that has
to password validators is a composition
action
its gonna represent in addition to that
the password field
individually are valid that they're also
matching in value
we can also apply this composition
technique to our overall form
we have a username validator set
password bow their
an email address validator
this is also where will handle the
behavior know we talked about earlier
be constituent elders will allow mill
because we don't want the individual
text field to show
a story air state wanna empty that would
be confusing
but this sign up valliere will check
that its constituent validators have non
mil
input and if any of those inputs are no
it'll say it's not valid allowing us to
easily disable
Sign up button so let's return to that
workflow we were looking at earlier
and see what that looks like
now were able to consider each text
field uniformly
because all we do is set the input on
the corresponding validator
were also able to decorate all the text
field uniformly as well
the logic and that responsibility has
been moved elsewhere
we're only talking to an abstract
interface
so let's define clear responsibilities
with
separated out the responsibility a
validation
from the rest of our program
we've use composition to build up
larger pieces from smaller ones let's
move on out to
our third section civil fine with the
mutability
you may have heard on the Internet that
new ability is bad
and you should feel bad for using it
but no one is really told you why
why is it bad I mean it's you use use
said it rate we're working imperative
foreign languages here we have
statements
so to illustrate that let's look at
another diagram
in this diagram
the red box represent immutable object
which doubt
which has a value 5 me is circles here
represent other objects are packing with
new mobile data around
so what a packer this mutable object to
be
be probably doesn't want that object
changing out from under it
so how do we ensure that that happens
well a phil has a reference
to this object so be depends on
a sorry if yes exactly a change that
then BC that change
so be depends on a behaving in a
specific way
they're linked in in this or
responsibility and and
dependency graph now likewise if this
object now get past the see
the other objects could still have
references to it they could still change
it
so see may depend on A&B
but actually it will get worse than that
because
a RBI could be waiting for C you make
some sort range
AB a has a register for KD 0 observation
maybe beers in the deli on this object
is waiting for some for a call back to
happen
the specific timing of that could be
part of these implementation
iffy changes what it calls some Center
that could screw up be so we're seeing
here how mutability
hi all these things together it's one of
the biggest reasons
why you feel that drag that any was
talking about as your application grows
bigger
and it also explains what adding
abstraction often
doesn't help as long as you're passing
around the same mutable data
it doesn't matter how many layers you
happy here in fact just
lashing more mutable layers on
onto the big ball so
let's look at what would happen if the
subject was immutable instead
we couldn't change its value when a
passes it to be
while a size reference to it but can
change it
no one can change it it can never change
it be done to make a change
s to make a copy impact that copy to see
no arrows here there's no dependencies
everything
has a data that they have and that's it
so there is a trade-off here the right
your ability inheritors to think about
locally thing about building up a string
or ray it also wasteful the crate
airmedia copies
one no one else's new tearing our
in when Noel canfield mutations yet
you may be wondering is there a better
way happy to say this was struck
are that better way they have often
utility
be in the mutating keyword this lets you
choose whether or not a struct is
YouTube or or immutable
based on using the let or var keyword to
introduce the binding
to the name when you when you declared
so
Swiss truck offer on the property there
call by value which just means that a
new copy is automatically created from
you
in past that's trucked for one function
to another
you don't pass a reference or pointer
like you do with an objective-c
or swept I object
so let's go back to diagramming see what
that would look like one more time
here we have our Swiss struct happy you
green box
I and when we pass it from a to be
an implicit copy is made and that's with
passerby
he can happen when you take a want
people changes
and again when we pass it
another copy is made and see get its own
copy
so that's one for the mutability
that house was struck can help us be
get a lot of the benefits have any
ability without sacrificing
a programming you the programmability
but there's another kind of in your
ability i wanna talk about we see that
in you I motion effect
not familiar with you emotional fact it
simply adjust properties on views based
on jars coke data
we use this to achieve the parallax
effect on the home screen elsewhere
throughout the OS
motion effects are reusable across many
views
have one type of motion no its crate
wanna fact
motion effects of a very low latency
requirements we don't want to get behind
the Giro data because that was laggy
and its really ruins the magical
effective
para lacks on the home screen and other
places
so
again at work we're going to show how
this is also immutability
once again by considering the inputs
outputs
on the motion of that process
motion a fax take a device pose which is
simply
description love the devices orientation
in space
and return a relative offset for each
keypad
that we want to change
it may be a somewhat surprising describe
emotional factors immutable
it doesn't really have 12 properties not
we're dealing with
you I am terribly much in fact it
feel more like a function but in your
ability is actually a
debe idea and had deep our
because motion affects take an absolute
device pose
return a relative of her they can always
return the same
dictionary for the same input device
parks
in much the same way that if you don't
have a a fetter you always return the
same value for your candor
so to really show that this design is
in is mutable let's look at some
alternative designs
promotion fax what say that we thought
that having
Delta inputs rather than actual absolute
device pose
was a better design well
with Sauber device posed data but it
will be dealt is
and would still be giving back relative
offsets
but the calculators offsets we would
actually need to figure out what
the current orientation the device was
so we would depend
upon all previous poses as an implicit
former them put
now are inputs are not just all possible
device poses
but all possible sequences a device
posed albert's
at a lot bigger input space hearted test
harder to reason about and
it's also not immutable because as our
application changes over time
we're gonna get different answers
likewise if we had absolute offsets
rather than a relative of that we would
have
value-free keypad that we're turning
absolute offset we would
we depend on our particular view that
particular view
would make his motion effect not
something that was reusable across many
different places
and again would make it so that its
value
for a particular device pose would
change overtime
so thats super fun with the mutability
we seem to different forms of
immutability
and how we can leverage those to build
simpler
more easy to reason about portions were
application
be able to reason abstractly about peace
in your application
is critical captain no every nook and
cranny
on the system and wonder if changing one
thing is gonna cost something else to
break
ap just become this big spider web you
can never really escape from
talked about a lot today so let's just
review everything we've gone over
right now first
we talked about how to design
information flow in your application
we learn the difference between truth
and derive value
how new truth is created
we saw how to define clear
responsibilities how to tease apart
different portion the app how to isolate
them
we also saw how to use that isolation to
build things a composition
we also saw to simplify with the
mutability to increase
our ability to abstractly reason about
our application
so what now you heard this talk maybe
hopefully
you're all fired up about these concepts
go back to your apt put someone in
action
when you're designing a feature think
about the information flow
think about the responsibilities share
this talk with your coworkers
tell them about it I'm in your app
specifically your
ap where there was a bug where you are
maybe updating
for cash that you didn't really even
realize what the cash until just now
so we got today for more information
contact a parent's
build gave a talk this morning about
to other type design patterns in in our
frameworks
thank you for listening have a great
afternoon