good afternoon I'm John Kavanagh
and I manage the group that creates the
I'm impatient for all about polls
consumer in pro products
here's some of what we do print pieces
that come in the box
iBooks and PDF's I help topics that
appear in the OS 10 help viewer
we have some highly contextual in app
solutions
and deliverables on the web like these I
O S user guides
or this what's new experience you may
have seen
in OS 10 maverick's now
creating great customer documentation
isn't always seen as one of the most
exciting parts of software development
I realize that as the documentation guy
and it can often be treated as it
an afterthought by developers not the
developers in this room of course the
let's just say some developers
and when that's the case it can often
take the form
a van FAQ for help system
where basically you wait until a person
gets stock
drop them into a comprehensive body of
content
and then have them fend for themselves
to try to get answers
and historically icons like this have
been used to
represent the experience which really
isn't the most flattering image to have
associated
with your ap our game unless of course
it's about rescuing people lost at sea I
don't know
now this
get answers strategy it it does have its
place
in help systems for deeper aP's but as i
OS developers you probably don't even
have to go here
instead
rachel's gonna show you how to
anticipate users needs
in a seamless on boarding experience so
they won't even feel like they're
getting your help
they'll just feel as though they're
experiencing your amazing
after game she's also gonna show you how
to extend this strategy
into an area we like to call inform and
inspire
and that gives you the opportunity
to delight users by showing them what's
possible
now as I said there's great ways to do
this
and not so great ways and that so
rachel's gonna show you now
Rachel hi everyone
my name is Rachel Roth and I'm wanna
Apple's
user experience for fans of so
today we're gonna talk about onboarding
and welcoming people now term onboarding
you may have heard it called
the new user experience for that first
youth experience or
I what happens in a tutorial for game
I'm really on morning for a term that
traditionally associated with
what happens with employees when they
first started a company
how people acquire the knowledge and the
skill
behaviors to become successful their job
now when it comes to an hour our game
people are gonna go for a similar sort
of experience
they need to figure out you know how the
UI work
how the gameplay the staff really gonna
be right for me
and that's prime you want to welcome
them
it's so important that their first
experience
is a good one because otherwise it's
gonna be their last six grams you've got
a million other competitors in the App
Store literally
for people are gonna stick around if if
the first experience for them
really great now when you step into a
store there's like in at like a physical
store in real life
earth there's a number things are gonna
influence whether or not you stick
around
already turn around and walk out you
know if the
layup by the store intimidating her or
is inviting
here's the staff rude as the staff
really aggressively percy
those things could turn you off to make
you walk away
but if the staff is inviting and the
environment comfortable
well you might the crown explore the
merchandise
so the best approach with after game
is that you want to get people and using
them as quickly as possible
you just wanna jack but people jump
right in and sometimes that's not always
possible now
her number recent for having onboarding
and having
a confusing or poorly executed you I
is not one of them for you wanna make
sure if your UI is an intuitive
an easy to use spend time are finding
that why
not building an onboarding sequence okay
now if you have registration required to
use your application
that's a different story
or where should game
you might need to explain the back story
or the rule you know how
how games are played or if your UI
heavily reliant on gestures that might
warrant a little bit of information in
order to get started
so let's stop beef briefly but if you're
too require registration
sometimes that is absolutely necessary
to see anything
banking application or source on that
were
for bill pay anything that have personal
information
then you're gonna need to to let people
now what's going on
but before
if there's any way possible you wanted
to lay that registration and took
absolutely necessary
now that I can store is a great example
Beth you can browse and look at all the
books in the music and the movies that
you want
and it's only when you go to buy
something
you need to authenticate or register
this means there's nothing standing in
the way of finding something you love
requiring people to register before they
can see anything put forth
unnecessary obstacle in their way
they have to trust that it's going to be
worth their while to go through that
obstacle
here is a better way this is Duque at
the concert finding out
they've got a great design that will
help you find concert fair
local to you tailored to your case they
were even find someone to go to the
concert with you
now not only do they have a very short
onboarding sequence
but you they will let you browse without
registering
at all you just cap that skip this
for now text at the bottom and you can
go right inside and explore what the app
is all about
you can look at the concert listings
read about band
and it's only when you express interest
in something are you want a parking
ticket
well that's when they have you ask you
to find out
and that's great this approach lets you
see what happens all about
you can explore everything all the
concert in your area
and you only have to register when
you're ready to take action on something
people are going to be much more
motivated and quite frankly comfortable
going through that registration process
if they're confident and the quality and
the utility
what your app is offering them
now wanna time to have people go through
that registration
you wanna explain why you're asking them
to register
so think about it this way let's say a
stranger walked up to you in front of
Moscone and fed hay
can I have your email address and phone
number you
%um give a damn right it's just creepy
and you've no idea what's going to
happen
with that data now that's exactly
what you're doing if you ask people to
register but you're not telling them why
and they don't know anything about you
it's especially important in cases where
you have to register in order to use an
app
because your description in the App
Store or word-of-mouth
or brand awareness isn't enough to make
people feel comfortable giving you all
of their personal information
you need to make it really clear what
you're gonna do with that
so this is jelly and they crowd fourth
answer three questions from your social
network
so they have a real challenge take it
there really is nothing they can show
you what are you registering and finding
an
so that's why they've given you this
brief explanation
what the service is about and explain
why they need your information
and very importantly they let you know
that they're not gonna post anything
automatic way and this is very important
because when you're dealing with people
personal information you want to make
sure that they're comfortable
giving it to you they wanna know that
you're gonna protect their privacy thing
and transparency around privacy is
particularly important
if you're dealing with social network
integration if I'm sure we've all had
that
friends that you've got some after going
crazy on their time line you're thinking
of what a new
you know nobody checkers that aims they
didn't know what they were doing
and nowhere is this more the case when
you're dealing with dating application
because I would be a nightmare of an all
your friends your family and from people
the Econo from worker
met some time at a bar kit fee very
alike
and he didn't like nobody wants fat
so tender here very popular dating
application and they're very
worth it they are never gonna post
anything
to face back on your behalf and this is
hugely important because the way that
tender works is there asking year
if you like people based on their
picture
so if you have any doubts at all are you
feeling a little have the 10
you can tap that I but and they spell it
out in more detail
they take your primary privacy very
seriously
they're never gonna post on Facebook for
you they're not going to give away your
location
for people can feel reassured more
comfortable
and nowhere is this privacy gonna be
more important than with your social
integration
now I'm just giving you a whole lot of
advice about things to tell people
before they register
but I want to encourage you that when
you're telling them I love the thing
be for Frank be out for things as
possible
we all know that people don't like to
read long passes
passages attacks on a nap 8 tap tap
tapping it going
now whoever does a great job with this
if you haven't experienced
over yet in San Francisco it is a a
it's a car service for the %ah come pick
you up I like a taxi
and you might think well why do I have
to give them a email address and phone
number
just in order to get a ride from A to B
and at they explain here very briefly
they're gonna offend you notifications
about when the car coming
an email about the confirmation for that
makes you feel better
fell being for things will keep your
registration process or
and it will help encourage people
actually read the taxpayers so carefully
crafted
for that spring now another way that you
can make the process shortest
only collect what you need right now
don't be tempted to ask for a lot of
information could you have this great
featured you're probably gonna do it
someday or
maybe you're thinking about doing that
so let's get data birth and life after
gender and
you only wanna take what it is that
you're going to use
and what you've told the users that
you're gonna do with it so that people
feel comfortable
giving it to you other wire
people are going to be suspicious and
that could prevent them from actually
going through the registration process
fell if you do you need people to
register in order to use your ass
keep these things in mind follow these
guidelines on everyone's gonna feel
really comfortable and motivated
to give you their information
alright for now let's get into the
onboarding best practices
as I said earlier the bath
experience it's gonna be a just jump in
and start using that app
right away for you one after South
what people need to know in order to get
started with my app
and if the answer is nothing fantastic
dope any onboarding and your great just
let a man and let them get going
now if there are something like the rule
for game
or like a gesture that they might need
to know
you want to tell them just enough to get
started and then get out of the way
quickly
so think about if you went into a
restaurant
and before you sat down at the table the
host that okay welcomes the rough trot
I'm gonna tell you everything off and on
the menu right now
in great detail and by the way here are
the things that I think you should order
I would be ridiculous right so pretty
really just wanna come and get federal
to your table peruse the menu at your
leisure
acting experience for your after right
so that's where you need to recreate in
your app
for your game you wanna do that ok well
and I've leading people into their table
tell maybe you're gonna tell them the
specials in a restaurant
and then let them explore on their own
when people launch an app or game
they're expecting for part if the pay
they're not expecting a long lecture
so a match then matching you launch
calculator app and you saw something
like that
followed by this
followed by this oh my gosh now I'm not
gonna make you guys sector of seven
apiece but
you can he how frustrating that would be
if you're faced with a long list of
marketing messages about an hour
before you even got to you that I mean
it's calculator right
they're really resist the temptation
to strings together a whole lot along
with SIV features and marketing and hey
make sure you check this thing out
people want to get in and get going
there is no need for instruction
if the user interface is intuitive two
years
and the functionality is obvious and if
it isn't
I should just that spend time reworking
the divine
not thinking about tomorrow morning
screens on their
if you need to give a few I fared you
wanna do it quickly and get out of the
way but otherwise
avoid those long marketing methods is OK
now you always want to start with the
basics
and this is especially important for
games which are most often the place we
need a little information to get going
like with video games with our app for
game you might want the backstory
so you know you know what's the
objective of the game are the back story
makes for more fun
right but think about a card game that
you sit down to play with friends
first usually go over okay what are the
rule how to play progress how do you win
abt important one and then you might
even try
a couple tips on strategy all before you
start playing
so just like a card game you start with
the basics
and then you build up the complexity
from there
because you're not be prepared to learn
about strategies for weighing if you
don't understand how the game is played
in first place
but forget a great example of this is
dot
doctor the puzzle game any just a little
bit upon boarding to explain how the
game works
and they've also touched on the
inspiration up for the game they've got
this quote here
smart man one fat everything offense
like act mmm
okay for the first thank you got
connect them got it
now a couple more got
now different colors the top wall
wall wall you'll
pretty basic but they're building up the
compact see if you go
and they're reinforcing everything was
found in animation
positive reassurance that you're going
through so it is completely interactive
for that that's a great way to get
started
and now I know that the seems like a
pretty simple
example but really almost anyhow game
benefit from that builders role playing
games arcade games all that
but take a look at him and go now at him
and go have eliminated on morning
altogether it doesn't put you in the
game right away
a great experience but to fat people a
person
six path the very basic level of
start the first level that you play
start with very basic accent
so what's the first thing you need to
know in order to play this game
what how to move and and how to win
right okay we got a straight line I only
have one choice
are one more choice
her a fix have I mean it was very easy
it's a no-lose situation
but that teaching you what's the
objective I want to get that big dark
circle at the end of the screen right
how do I move along the path
next phase introduce you obstacle
again got one path and I'm a hit man
and this guys back up towards me thou
here is a pretty easy target I
again if I can't leave level but I'm
playing the game and I'm learning as I
go
so it's fun it's not morning I'm playing
a game here
now at the level for graph a get more
difficult you get toys in your path and
now you're obstacle here facing years
that's going to be a little trickier
and trust me get much much harder get
different kinds of obstacles
more them trapped or things like that
when you first start playing all you
have to do its complete the level
get to that dark circle of the an
but the more you play more challenges
you have for now I'm not just
completing Level and you collect the
brief K
I gonna do it 12 move for last last
getting more complex missus giving me
more QE
more challenges and it's encouraging
repeat gameplay flop
recovery view to start on this level Hui
I think that would last all about
30 FAC and from the night be off to find
another game
now starting them play and building up
the complexity is called scaffolding
and that's how you can set up new
players have an enjoyable experience
gonna keep them coming back to your game
but this approach also worked her ass as
well
you want to teach the basic thing how to
navigate and the general purpose
function
before even Confederate trying to teach
people
about more advanced operations
now this is Yahoo News tight ass since
one of this year's Apple Design Award
winner
now they've got a fantastic you I have
might have gas
by their ward its intuitive two years so
not appear on boarding at covering you
are
now the way that that's news works is
that it's a daily digest
twice a day and this is an entirely new
paradigm for Yahoo News
had quite an established audience that
was really important for fat people
expectations about the content that they
were going to be seen
otherwise people might be confused
throughout the purpose of the app
so by putting together just three short
screams with a supportive illustration
and then getting the right answer the
news they're setting you up for success
in a different kind away and this
approach is not appropriate for all
kinds of after games
it's really when you're breaking into a
new market or the earth abducting from
sort a new paradigm
that you might need to communicate just
a little bit about your pork on Feb
and that's going to help people
understand the product and quite frankly
appreciate it right
for just three short screams and then
getting at you enter the news cuz
they're gonna get out the way quickly
so think about the basic basic things
that people would need for now
in order to start playing your game are
using your app and think about
if any of them really need explaining
because again if you don't
if they don't don't do any onboarding
right but if you do
can consider the way that you can start
based
with the basics and bill that the
complexity with games it's going to be
had a mere
what the object at howdy when in fact
that
and when you're teaching me thing make
sure you're only teaching one
thing at a time it is so much harder to
our never doubt whether
financial construction that Juan orbit a
freshly
its related to something unfamiliar
right okay I'm gonna give all the guy
from instruction
after their I want to leave Mosconi
make you left turn better write down the
alleyway
go to the coffee shop on the corner
order to lock a
1d cast one low-fat
but three sugars in the decathlon and
one sugar in the low fat one and bring
them back to me here
got it and if anyone got that i'm
looking for to my locker after that
but but you can see how difficult that
is I'm sure you guys all turned out on
Feb 3
people are going to be much more able to
follow those instructions if they're
parceled out one at a time
self I fed go item of going make to have
turned and then
when you get to the corner of how you
what to do and that of a go to the
coffee shop
and then when you get to the register i
text you hey here's the coffee
but I want you to order you this would
be so much easier
see you want to give instructions one at
a time and give people a chance to apply
those instructions before you start
teaching anything else
so this is Leo 4chan another one of our
Apple Design Award winners
from the fear it up really fun platform
adventure game
that in these really gorgeous
environment and
their tutorial eva is fantastic they
first start explain the game with a
little bit a backstory they introduce
you to Leopold
they let you know if losses 4chan and
you're gonna help him reclaim it
so this translates into you get the gold
coins
now you got your objective right next
Sat if just
about how to hold your device they're
getting used to this idea that the last
fire screen
and the right phone screen are gonna do
something different
but they haven't told you what that is
yet just put your thumbs and this
position and that gets you holding the
device eg
in the bath way now once you press your
company
or call then they're talking about
movement what do you do with your life
span
well first we're just gonna go forwards
and backwards
very basic fact and then you get a
chance to play without a little bit you
gonna collect from car and go there some
other cool environment
and then a flight obstacle now
there's a little chop trying to help you
out or some words on the right that lets
you know
now it's time you can use your right
time here we go
get up over that lives and then
a chance to play they give you things to
jump over
thanks to jump on fair and next up
some more obstacles here it's about
using that up gesture for something out
so they're building up the complexity
while teaching one thing at a time
pushing up on that lever is going to
release the drawbridge
and then you can continue on your way
then you learn about pushing down and
what that that for you
earlier fourth-and-1 scale other time
which is so mad small
and have fun because you're playing so
it's a great example of scaffolding
along with him mango
and several other examples
so the first thing you do you if you are
in the objective collectors gold coins
next thing you're gonna learn about if
optimal ham possession right for their
building up the complexity with the
scaffolding
and the next thing that you learn about
as really basic movement
how to go forward what are you doing
with your left hand
next up is obstacle which you conquer
using your right hand in various
gestures
and then further in the game they start
selling your advanced obstacles are part
of
you can see how the complexity built up
that way
now like I said the same thing applies
to ap stats not just games
you can teach people by doing you don't
wanna show them a lot of screens that
front
now penned for a the first entrapped and
they onboarding just for specific
feature
so they have a new Guided Search feature
and
they needed to teach people near the
Afghan also returning user
how do you how to go about using it may
do a great job apart going out this
information one step at a time
for the first time you go to the search
tab after the feature was introduced to
get a little bit of information
and a given you some sample of and the
fam both are all things that I'm pretty
interested and
so they've done a great job in making
this a really valuable exercise
for me now I happen to like nail art
and Sonax I tap they explain to me how
to refine that starts
even further
and then 15 down for find that they talk
about even more advanced for five at
free typing an because you're getting
this information one step at a time
it's much easier to understand what to
do and they're letting you execute on
these instructions
so you're really learning you're taking
it all in
you're much more likely to remember this
later next time you get a first for
something
with all of these examples it was an
overwhelming right
and you're actually able to use what
you've learned because you're playing
the game are using an app
because people learn better i doing
than they do by reading or listening
when it comes to App Store games
dot hit man go leo's fortune they all
reinforce what they're teaching you
replay
and Pinterest letting you actually first
for things they want and i cant
experienced those were real thirst terms
with real refinement
so even though this is there really
super easy can't lease level
on him and go
it's a lot more fun then this would be
right
now benjamin Franklin have a great quote
about this
tell me and I forget teach me and I
remember
involve me and i learn that's where you
want to avoid
screenshot from low to display anything
it's gonna take you out a contact to
prevent you from
actually using the app or game isn't
going to be effective
again what if this was the experience
with calculator
it would be terrible right first evolved
you are so damn you can barely feel
about
at all secondly you don't need to faye
tap here tap here tap here all over a
catch
interface its attach interface you tap
my biggest pet peeve is when I see click
here
on it on touch devices for that really
gets me
now again if your buttons don't look
obviously interactive
redesign your butt don't pick from Notre
way letting you know that you can tap
places
so if you do need onboarding make sure
that your experience let people protest
Bay
and you can use animation to do a lot of
teaching at it's a really powerful tool
there's a lot of great information about
the craft of animation
and Q se designing intuitive interfaces
sessions if you don't
fear fashion check out the video it's
available
for today I would just like to talk
specifically about something that I've
seen games
all the time its giant
bouncing a row
now I'm first this does seem like an
effective way to get people through
tutorial level
great but then know what
starts to show people where to look
eventually become
distracting when there's more
information on the screen you're not
looking at the information
you're just looking at the Aero and word
attack and thinking I want to play the
game I don't want to read the tutorial
fair looking at this button and federal
looking at what the different characters
are gonna do for you
wire picking them the strategy the game
or how much it's going to cost you what
the reward is gonna be
for pretty fair your game have gone from
you know happy ice cream fun time or
whatever
to cap a row no one wants to play tap
the arrow
up our fun game tafero gets old
so quickly another way kinda thing
coveted I don't know how many view
had but if you've ever tried to point
something out to a dog or cat
they often just want help looking at
your finger right here
I so this is exactly what you're doing
with tap the arrow
people are going to be looking at what
you're pointing toward for gonna be
looking at the Aero
fell rather than pointing try
suggestive animation one that's gonna
help you read people fight for the right
part of the screen
or let them know what they should dare
really basic example but it's a good one
with hit mango you don't need in a row
or
a graph a record some other kinda about
the air afsane to let you know that this
is a button
in addition to being the name that whole
thing animation draws me to you it makes
you wanna tap it right
may could have had an arrow pointing cap
here to have here
but you don't need to do that
about putting me about using animation
thoughtful way
I hope I look forward to seeing far
fewer bouncing errors in the future
now if you do need your on boarding
another thing
and to keep be wary at is there is no
need to point out
any platform convention you only point
out the unconventional
because everybody knows there's another
screen app icons available on the folder
the paging got take care of that for you
you don't you want me to put a narrower
syntax says slide to the side to see
more icon
be ridiculous similar way
you don't have to tell people that tab
bar and toolbar
our interactive they instinctively look
that way
or that you can swipe for more content
because the content waiting off the edge
doubt that job for you and that's really
one of the greatest advance says:
everything platform convention
people just instinctively know how to
interact with them
you won't need any onboarding for these
type of thing
you only want to point out anything that
def Teenz
and unique an unfamiliar to your
audience
now another thing to be wary a is
forcing people to go down a secondary
path that they may not wanna take
so think about a photo application
I don't want to be forced to crop it a
match if I don't think it needs to be
crops
I don't want to apply a photo filter 24
to a photo
I shouldn't have to you this is my happy
I want to do what I want that
similarly with music application it's
great to show people how to make a play
with
earth station but don't make the market
a favorite if if not a favorite
it's just frustrating
know when it comes to tax like I said
before sorter is always better
we know that people are not inclined to
read really long passages
must have the book fell make sure your
language is short
and career avoid jargon and
Akron am or in fighter language that may
not make sense for someone who's near
your apt okay
this is my favorite example I've Duque
and they're talking about their
notification
it so fun a mixtape from a stalker I'm
excited
yeah I mean this this Texas clear
its friendly its entertaining as well as
being educational
so here's some things you can think
about when it comes to writing your tax
after southeast question could detect
three shorter
could be clear will the tax make sense
to someone who is new to the application
because you look at your apt all day and
all night
every day for you really need fresh
perspective and
and what what someone unfamiliar with
your app thank
if the methods to complicate if it is
you can make it simpler or maybe you
need to change your approach altogether
or would images were better than tax
there's our prayer a picture's worth
1000 words
sometimes it's just easier to do it with
a dry like with me a fortune
but little chart dry if my heart it's a
quick read
you can't hop up and go on your way as
opposed to paying
okay when you get here left your thumb
up for that Leo will hop over the lads
would be ridiculous
and make sure that feels like an
extension to your brand
because onboarding it's going to be the
first experienced that somebody had to
be there after game
kinda like a wedding invitation our
party invitation
affect the tone for the entire
experience
so make sure feel exactly like your
brand
like the personality where at
and birth is a very important one
always give people an option to get
alway the father lunchtime fashion
yesterday Natalia talks about
the dark days of the interwebs with the
big crazy flash intro
and all people wanted with skip intro
skip intro
and that's exactly what we're talking
about here you don't know if someone has
use your app on another day by if they
watched
their friend use your app her friend
paper just impatient and want to get
going
if people want to watch her on boarding
no matter how of a midair
don't make them and finally
learning should be an enjoyable
experience
it's going to be Plaza again it's your
first impression
up I've after the game for you want to
make sure that
it's a good one let's take a look at
flights
which I think they have a really great
on boarding experience
back close button up fares are optional
gap
you I have faith going on gestures and
so that's why they wanted to give them
just a very brief onboarding explanation
attacked invoke that joy travel
just a few short screen visual design
matches every other aspect of the app
and when you're all done tap ready to
fly
and you get a nice little animation fun
right
enjoyable sure InPrivate
so make sure if you need to provide
onboarding but you're doing in a way
that fun
nobody likes a long boring lecture
so these are the things they need to
thrive for if you need onboarding
if you need on morning
now whether I have an app or game one
thing that's always a challenge is
at how to teach people about gesture
search I risk open handsome and
anything that doesn't have some sort of
visual representation
in the UI so let me give you a few tips
about how to make the invisible visible
and the first one is using animation cue
now I know not if you're gonna make a
big brown fear 0
but there's a lot of things that you can
do to convey the interactivity
or the gesture in a very elegant way
your key people focus on the UI not on
on the kieres and visit jet fighter
it's an app that specializes in luxury
hotels and resorts
they've got tons of amazing photography
which is one thing
that's not part from their competitors
this gentle giraffe love the photo lets
you know
at interactive but you can't touch it
and explore different aspects
have stunning kitchen
invites you to touch it
now the wedding how Tracker app uses
horizontal movement to show that the
screens are swipe the ball
so bad and if you don't quite fit it'll
auto advance
got a nice rewind page what type of
animation at the end for that you know
you've had the last I am
and then you can flip through for
anything you might have missed
and those are just some other way for
you can use animation to really help in
Courage people are
plane gestures are other of factor Buri
and again there were a lot of tips on
the stand Tuesday fashion
so make sure to check it out if you
didn't already seen it
see a now another factor teaching tool
is
temporary him just really quick tips
about jesters
the physiognomy is tight ass again as i
showed earlier there on boarding is all
about the core concept
so instead once you get into the UI they
don't need to tell you about that
but have time but they give you just a
couple animation cue
and temporary can't for tapping on
article headline
has a horizontal animation and then that
short message about
swiping so if the horrifying animation
didn't do it for you this method which
only appears for two seconds
makes it abundantly clear you can swipe
from article article
and you'll note if they didn't force you
to swipe
because I might be interested in reading
this article I just wanna make sure you
know how to navigate
lightly has a different approach the
photo editing application
and the first time you use it they give
you hints about gestures with short tips
so here are just selected argyll filter
and so what comes up as a message about
adjusting
the Attensity now I just want to point
out they don't
actually force you to adjust the
intensity
any other player anyplace the tap with
the Smith at hand
whether it's adjusting the 10-city
picking another filter from the bottom
or using any the other control
for an addition to the plane temporary
head
you can also think about providing
controls for people to turn them on
and this is what we do in garage fan on
I laugh
now this is something that's more
appropriate for deeper application
not every at warrants bath and you can
come and just start playing the drums
and going not
without any assistance at all but if you
want to know more
get a deeper knowledge about drumming
because it's sort of a specialty
K-fifty want to become a better musician
and you think that question mark button
up in the up in the corner
turned bomb even on modal kept
see you can keep playing the drums
while you're reading more about them and
without those non-motor
without these tipsy might not realize
that you can get different found out the
hi-hat
a fun word is that you're tapping at
or that a single tap will play the crash
cymbal and the bass drum together
but a two finger tap is what results in
just the crash cymbal
or you would know that the fear the
drummer Pete is determined by the
distance between your two finger
all really useful so if you think you
have an audience that wants a deeper
knowledge
or needs actor Guy 10:05 specialized
subject
this could be a good method and
and it's really important but you can
continue to use the app for that you can
learn by doing
you can put it into practice right on
the spot
because all of these approaches work
passive they're shown in contact
it's important that when you're
demonstrating gestures you wanna do it
right now moment when people can
experiment with them
so that they're learning by doing so now
I would like to address
a dirty word an IRFU I define
help help
nobody nobody wants to think they need
help or nobody wants to ask for help
and as a designer I certainly hope bad
every abstract have my you live
intuitive to use
to every person in every scenario no
matter what their names
sometimes mister hard to achieve
I mean people have different experiences
different backgrounds
they come from different culture they
may have a lot of experience with Apple
platform
but not without I'll ask for specialty
nah lives
like I can navigate around just about
any after on the Apple platform
but I'm not a good photographer so
although filter
on Photofact I don't know what to do
with them
I don't know what I should do you find
how they're gonna make my pictures
better
and not for how can be very handy
but it's not for us to feel like a
lecture from a mean teacher
or boring nobody wants for
we're moving away from that large
reference manual right
at a few more like that just making
things a little bit easier on people
or maybe like support from a friend or
family member just giving you a couple
tips
because I'm definitely not suggesting
that you had a huge reference
documents Tirath there are a lot of ways
but you can provide help
without people even realizing that they
got any
what are the easier things that you can
do is to put instructions in your empty
containers
rather than just saying no results for
third store
at an iffy here you wanna keep in Mt
view from being at that
if at all possible let people know what
to expect here or how to get out of this
dead-end situation
so an ivory for I left there's a theater
view
were you complete a project go through
you can view them
now before you create any project
there's nothing to show here
so the message lets you know exactly
what you're going to find here in the
future
and then they tell you how to get
started making a product project
for that you can have a movie here
really quick way and it's worth pointing
out that both the math fares
and the icon in the navigation our
interactive
seeking get going quickly while you're
learning the UI
and the same approach can work for empty
input field
to you playful or text can be super
informant at
the third up to you which is at counter
app
you can of course manager on a point man
for one of the things that's cool about
up to you is that you can also subscribe
to other people counter
and the other people can be your friends
or can be Barack Obama
may have time for counters available on
here so you can browse to find the ones
you want
you can offer starts and that first text
is very suggested in terms of the types
of things that you might want to put in
there
now I got the impression from the
graphic that I could search for sports
teams but
I didn't realize I can just type in San
Francisco I'm see
all the listings for San Francisco
it's very helpful
and it didn't feel like hell right I
didn't even realize I needed any help
but yeah I've learned something now
you can also think about showing
supporting information
right and mine and we do this with
batting
now not of adding because they don't on
the year
game time is a pretty universal comp
that there's nothing else to say here
butt dial a fifth well some people might
have some questions about what baghdad
so there's just a little bit more
information right in that moment
again it didn't feel like hell
and with games we are fortune that chalk
drawing is giving you that little hints
and they don't just do this and the
tutorial level it's throughout the game
in fact showing information in mind
often a great alternative to onboarding
altogether
you don't have to tell everything up
front just put the axe from
information in line so it's fair right
in that moment that people need it
now another great approaches to watch
for indications that people are
stack now when it comes to games though
you have to be wary about over helping
people
because it's a game nobody enjoys having
the puzzle fault for them
that's not fun gonna give people a
chance to play all
all on their own and then watch for
clues they might be stack
and that's when you offer how
with Rio 4chan if you try and number of
times to get over this very basic
obstacle on you don't make it
they give you the option on screen
control
again they only do this if it looks like
you're struggling with that first job
the room to offer have a great approach
now if you haven't played it at the
mystery poverty have our game your
second through many follow crew after
clear after crew to make your escape
now if you've been struggling for a long
time we still have managed to accomplish
the next thing
a give you this question mark back
and this is great because it's giving
you the option
upper hand because it's true I might be
stock or I may have been distracted
my dog might have started barking or
someone needed something and walked into
the room
so that's really good cuz they're not
they're not solving the puzzle forming
however if I am Relief Act and I'm at
the point walking away it's an uptick
keeping gays to keep me moving for
and fed up giving way the answer biggie
clears
CR to feel guilty doesn't have to be
like cheating
you have to feel bad about it right and
it doesn't devalue year
peachy man for people who can use the
cliff we're all gonna get something and
some of us are gonna get there faster
but this works out really well everyone
can feel really good
when they finished the game and the sky
hands can be helpful
with ap to you the first guy guy
another 1i have this year's Apple Design
Award winner
you can pan all around the sky and see
the consolation
planet comment all sorts of star
and they were Honda information
about almost anything in the night sky
now you might think that tapping on a
star the way to get that information
but I would make it a little too easy to
navigate into the details here
you be going on accident you getting
frustrated
so instead the right way to get to get
to that information
is by flooding a star and then tapping
that I button on the right side of the
screen
and if you tap its are gone to try and
select it
or get more information you get a
pulsing animation and that glow
called attention to itself they're using
animation to attract your attention
and it's really elegant because if you
double tap it start thinking
are maybe I can tap hard enough for
maybe I need tapped wife
a powerful every time you tack to get
your attention
so they're keeping an eye out for you
that your stock and trying to pull you
in the right direction
get you back on track
and all the steps that I found you are
really just about anticipating people's
needs
telling people what they need to know
and the moment that they need to know it
think about but the restaurant again and
I talked about earlier
you wanna see the dessert menu before
you've been seeded or while you're
eating your appetizer
you want when you finished your mail
and when you have good service at a
restaurant means the wait staff is there
when you need them
and they're not there when you doubt and
that's exactly the pro
approach you wanna take if you got help
and fire your application
and figure is really one of the best
examples but I've seen out there
it's an anonymous social networking app
so what this means is that you see poets
from your friends but you don't know who
they are because everything's anonymous
at the rowing interesting way to
interact with people
now the first time your feet won't their
explaining in the moment exactly the
information they need
now so here I'm scrolling through my
feed and
I don't know anyone in the UK now
traveled across creme seeking a friend
where are my friends now
I don't have my phone number yet shoot
and what for star me and I wonder %ah
popular one
when you go to comment
they explain why they are all these
icons here they're just letting you know
about commenting
because that's where you are in apt
they're not telling you about navigation
or what is the star me and things like
that their focus on commenting
it's worth noting that they're just
giving one piece of information I retire
after all
and if you're the first to comment
they've populated their empty
the Mt view with information you know
the common for gonna be there
for general-purpose to be the first one
and I just love that the placeholder tax
encourages you to say something
hines great
think about what people need to know
based on where they are here after game
how long they've been using it and
anticipating people for me
it's just another way that you're going
to be able to provide help without it
feeling
like hell
and be sure to take the opportunity to
inspire people
like secret that we face some think I
now a lot of people use very defect
reminder Pentax search exports course
things like that
I remember when you found out that
theory would answer questions like this
mean all the fun this convenience
features the source of entertainment as
well
unexpected and fun and now theories more
valuable to me
because she's not just the utility
anymore she comedy
she's flattery it's great
people might come cheer up with a
certain expectation
about getting one thing done but when
they discover that your app can do more
for them
well then the app becomes even more
valuable
it's gonna feel like a bonus prize
and that's why we fear we give you a lot
of suggestions of things that you can
ask her
you just tap that question mark button
you're gonna get along left
afsane recast phiri and you may have
known that you can use very 10 ish a
call for
have her make an appointment on your
calendar but did you know that she also
will book restaurant for you
or Italian movie times I mean if work
goes on and on
on path does it with some other
onboarding
and their private social network so they
really need you to register because
everything is orange around your
personal information
but before registering they're giving
your theory screen
that covers both the features that the
apt but also
how you might want to use them a lot of
people go to pass thinking they're going
to use it for work but now they're gonna
be thinking about
how they can use them in their personal
life to you
or with Pinterest got Mr probz
I mean maybe you can depend for after
they were interested in nail art or
wanting referee for dinner party but now
you're off thinking about
gardening and many think about what else
interest can be used for
first step away from that traditional
idea of how
reference manual and think about how you
can anticipate people ask me
putting instructions an empty containers
n sewing Supporting Information Line
it's about telling people what they need
snow in that moment
but they need to know it like the
perfect for
at a restaurant there when you need them
an invisible
when you down when you're doing all that
don't forget to take the opportunity to
inspire people
that increased now I've increase you
tell me about your app
it's getting increased I am
fellow if you only take a few things
away from the talk today
in summary ollie
require people to register when it's
absolutely necessary
after South if you really need
onboarding at all
if they don't need any information
before getting started and Jeff but I'm
get started
otherwise tell them what they need to
know and I get out of the way quickly
teach your accent because people are
gonna learn better by doing
anticipate people's me and don't forget
to take the opportunity to inspire
now I hope that you leave today with a
new impression about how
and how can work in your app for game
and at that I hope that I've inspired
you all with how to make a great first
impression
so this is my email and I what it
genuinely like to hear about changes
that you make your app
and how that change the overall
experience we've got a lot more
information about this I'm
at the a bit developer doubt Apple dot
com
and if you didn't see either BT fashions
on Tuesday the video
are available got the ingredients for a
great game versus about making
a great game and then designing
intuitive user experiences with all
those animation test
thanks so much