hi welcome to the advanced class
shin
thank you arm
my name's Jacob Vargas I'm a software
engineer at Apple and one of the
designers at the Clark API
and my colleagues and I put a lot of
hard work into the club kid API
and I'm really excited talk to guys
about it today so let's jump right into
it
so Clark it is
this thing that we've built on top over
I cloud servers
we build a lot of my cloud services and
what we're doing with Clark it is
exposing those database servers
that we use at Apple to all love you
developers
I so we're actually using this this is
something that we use in the new i cud
photos and i cud right feature that
we're introducing
and we're building all that on topic
like it if all this is
unfamiliar to you might want to go back
and check out the introducing crockett
session
I was given on Tuesday and there should
be videos online
so we're gonna jump right into this I
what we're gonna learn today we're gonna
go over the clark et private database
which is a way for you to store private
user information
in my class we're gonna talk about
modeling your data in cloud kit
I we're gonna talk about Advance record
manipulation in different ways of saving
records to the server
we're gonna go over how to handle
notifications reliably
I a few miss a push what to do and
finally we're gonna go over the Eichler
dashboard which is a web-based interface
for managing a club kid application
so let's start off by looking at the
clock API really quick
we designed the clerk API to be highly a
synchronous
everything has a call back on nothing is
and we did this because all these
requests are going out over the network
I when you get the network involved
anything can happen you know the server
might not be responding quickly there
might be a bad network connection
I we don't want to block the UI and
cause a better user experience
and to help do this we've used and its
operation almost everywhere in our API
I I say almost everywhere because if you
went to the introductory session you
remember seen what I we called the
convenience API
and the convenience API is our way of
helping you get
started with Clark it really quickly and
simply are all these APIs are
you know single calls at work on are one
record at the time so in this case were
fetching one record
and its a synchronous we get that one
record back in our completion handler
but as he's clock it more you might find
that you need some additional
functionality
and that's where the NS operation based
API comes in
so what we've got here is the CK fetch
records operation
and this is an NS operation that does
the equipment at their convenience API
we just saw
we give you a lot more functionality
when you use the
Ennis operation base API so you can see
here that
are initializer takes a array record
ID's
you can fetch a whole batch records all
at once we also give your feedback on
what's happening we've got a completion
block for each record and we also give
you progress as we download those
records from the server
and finally these operations give you
more
knobs and levers to tweak what what is
returned in what the operation does
on this case we've got a desired keys
property the lets you specify what he
should come back on the records if you
catch
so since all this is built on and its
operation let's do a quick overview of
what the
and its operation class looks like are
what we got in and its operation is a
completion block Anne
cancel call so that you can manage the
life cycle your operation
we've got a couple variables that tell
you some state about the operation
and and its operations have dependencies
seek and linked to Anna separations
together what you have in its operation
you're going to want to start that
operation and you do that by
adding it to A&S operation cue when you
have an ass operation cue you can also
manage
the life cycle that operation cue you
can suspended and resume it
and you can cancel the operations and so
if you go to look at her and its
operation base API you might just see
this big list I have a bunch a different
operations it's kinda overwhelming and
confusing
are the best way to think about this API
is to think about the
objects that you want to deal with I
remember from the introductory talk
I clarke its base objects are records
and zones and subscriptions
and you'll see that up here we have a
factional modify operation for all those
items
one other really cool things about and
its operation is that has dependencies
I so you can set a dependency between
two operations
and the second operation won't fire
until the first operation is completed
%uh this is really handy with cloud kid
if you want to do something like fetch a
record
at a property to it and say that record
back to the server
you can make the fetch records operation
make the Modify operation at the same
time
set up a dependency and when the feds
completes you can put that date in the
Modify operation and it'll start
automatically
these dependencies also work between
cues so even though Clark it has its own
internal operation cue
that you can use run operations your
welcome to to create your own and its
operation cue
and you can then manage its life cycle
you can stop operations are spending
more cancel them
I want one tip with using them and its
operation though is that the
and its operation base class has a
completion block on it
this completion block ends a fire in a
synchronously with dependencies
30 setup dependencies n you using the
and its operations completion block
they might happen at the same time and
that data you're trying to funnel into
the next operation won't get there in
time
you know that operation is already
started so what we've done with the
crowd get a PI
is we have clout get specific completion
box
and if we look at are what we had for
that fetch records
operation we have a fat records
completion block
are you'll see this pattern on all over
and its operations and these completion
blocks hand back
all the information you need to know
about the operation it just ran
in this case we've got the heirs for
that operation and we've also got the
records that were fetched
and finally and its operations can have
their own priorities so you can set
background operations and have a
runnable
really low priority and keep your UI
responsive
so when we were designing cloud kid
wanna things we noticed is that there's
two general classes applications
there's one class application that
stores a whole buncha data up on the
server
and when you use the application it's
just presenting a viewer that data it
downloaded on demand
displayed to the user and then you know
tosses it out because it's the real
copies on the server
but there's another class application
that has just a little bit data
but you want that same data on all the
clients
so if you remember from the introductory
talk we talked about that what we call
Big Data little fun
that's the case where we have a lot to
date on the server it's not all gonna
fit on one phone
and you downloaded and viewed on demand
so you can see these
clients are downloading records feeling
I'm and
the truth lives up on the server
however there's another class
application where
it's a small amount of data it lives on
one client but you wanted on all your
clients
i an example this is an application that
manages the receipts
so I every time you buy something you
take pictures 3 seed
and you want that information on your
phone in your iPad and your Mac
and you want them all to be up to date
with the same receipts
so what we've done to help you solve
that is we've got something in car kit
that does a
a if you remember we have every
application its container
in every container is a public and
private database
and just a as a refresher that private
databases
actually one private database for every
user
insiders the bases we then subdivided
down into zones
so both the public and the private
database have a default on them
but we've also given you what we call
customs and these custom zones allow us
to give me some extra features that we
can't provide
in the default I'll you can create these
custom zones and
use the new features I let's go over
couple
%uh the first feature is atomic commits
so Clark it has relationships between
records and if you start using cloud kid
and using these relationships are gonna
build up an object
object graph and you're gonna realize
you want consistency
in your data I if you know you might
have an object graph that you want to
commit all at once
and if some other things don't get
committed the date on the server doesn't
make sense
on the public database we can guarantee
that because there might be thousands or
millions of users hidden same database
so there's no way to lock the database
while we you know commit your very
special records
but in the private database you only
have one user its
the current user's account and in that
case we can provide you things like
atomic commits
so with atomic commits these batch
operations in the end its operation API
will succeed or fail as a whole so if
any record had a problem you will get
back
a CK air partial failure
inside that partial failure air you're
gonna see a user the user info
dictionary is gonna have this
seek a partial errors by item id:
and that's going to be a dictionary
record ID's to
errors for each of those records and
some of those areas are going to be
the real failures that you care about
these are the reasons that the atomic
commit failed
but you know the rest of the records
fail because it was atomic commit
and we need to let you know that they
failed see also gonna CCK air bats
request failed
that's just the way of saying that
something else in this batch failed and
you know this wasn't the real problem
it was that other record in here
another great feature that we give you
with custom zones our Delta downloads
so Delta downloads our way for that
second class application
to be possible in Crockett I you can
download
only the changes that were made in that
zone and you can catch them all locally
so what does that look like well we've
got our Mac here
we've got a iphone and we've got a
customs up
so let's step through a delta download
really quick we got
in orange record in a green record over
on the Mac here and we want them on the
phone as well
so we're gonna first upload those both
in the car kit in our customs own
and then are iPhone is gonna perform a
delta download to get up-to-date
cities doctor downloads are based on
what we call change tokens
and a change took it as a way of
tracking the state the server the last
time you talked to it
so this phone has never talk to the
server and
what it's going to do is send up a new
change token and that's the way of
saying I'm never talk to you to send me
all the records in the cell
so the service going to take that no
change token send down and/or the orange
record in green record
the phone is gonna save them into its
local database and then the servers
gonna send out a new change token
on this case it's changed okay and that
means that
you know the records you have are all
from state a
if the phone came back again with change
taking a the server will go well I don't
have anything for you
is good enough there's nothing to
download
but let's say the Mac comes along and it
creates that purple record
and it deletes the green record and it
upload those changes to the server
the servers go to track the changes so
it'll note that that green record was
deleted
it'll note that there's a new purple
record and now when the iPhone comes
back with change take a
the server goes alright well we're it be
now
that's farther than a here's a deleted
the green record and here's a new purple
record that happened while
you know since the last time we talk
then it sends back then you change token
and everyone is up to date
seeking use this Dell to download to
implement an offline caching your
application
if you want to do that there's a couple
steps you up should take this is kinda
outlined above basic state machine for
every time you talk to the server and
you want to do it all to download
the first thing you're going to want to
do in your apt is to track the local
changes
you're gonna wanna make a change table
and every time the user makes an edit in
your application you want to write that
down
I you're gonna wanna do this because you
might be offline when the user makes
changes and you're gonna need a replay
all those changes back to the server
when you can talk to
then you're gonna need to send all those
changes up to the server you want to do
that before you fetch the changes
because
someone else might have changed the
record in the meantime and you need to
resolve these conflicts
so we'll go over conflict handling in
just a little bit but just keep in mind
that that's an important step in this
process here
finally ready to do the Delta download
this is the point we're gonna call seek
a pet record changes operation
the server is going to send you back I
updates and deletes and modifies and
adds up records
and you're gonna say those in your local
database
finally the service can send you back in
New change took in and that's the change
took in you want to save so that the
next time you talk to the server
you can get only the records that have
changed and not everything
so what are the other features we give
you with custom zones and Delta
downloads our zone subscriptions
i in the case of that state machine I
just talked about I
you could poll every you know ten
minutes or five minutes or whatever and
hope that their changes up there
but wouldn't it be great if the server
just told you have got changes it's time
for Delta download
well we give you that we give you what
we call zone subscriptions
these look like weary subscriptions but
they're a little bit different
what they do is every time something
changes in a custom zone
you get a push notification when you see
that push notification you know you
should go do a delta download with
server
and you'll get new records
so a couple notes on designing custom
zones and when you should use them
these custom zones are meant to
compartmentalize your data
are because it that there's a couple
restrictions on the the first is that
you can't move records between zones
you can pick these records up in copy
and make a new copy in a new zone
but you can't move 'em are you also
can't make any cross the zone
delete self relationships so you have to
think in these zones as
as self-contained if you have records
that need to go across town he might
want to rethink your model
and finally the zones determine the
level of updates
to using his own subscription you're
going to get a push every single time
something has changed in that cell
I if you have a lot of data on the
server and you only care about getting
updates for one party that day to you
might wanna make
that as own so that you can ignore the
you know really busy stuff going on over
here and just download
things you care about
so let's talk about some advance record
operations
when you're using seek a record any
changes you make to seek a record object
locally
get tracked and then when we talk to the
server
we're only gonna send the changes that
you may do that seek a record
this is the default behavior and it
works great most the time but
you might want some additional control
over what we're sending to the server
and we give you that with save policies
so the same policies we have three in on
their seek a record say the server
unchanged
we have CK record save change keys
and we have CK record save all keys
so let's look at the differences between
this
are the biggest difference is what they
did determined for
a what I'm gonna call a locked save and
a lock save as a way of making sure that
you don't overwrite data on the server
that someone else has re-written
when you perform a locked save it says
that I
if the record has changed since the on
the server since the tiny fetched it
the server I'll give you an error saying
your record is out-of-date
you need to resolve this conflict and
try again
so the only thing that performs a locked
safe here is see Carey
CK record save policy save its server
unchanged
the other two actually force these
changes to the servers so save change
keys and save all keys
always over at the values on the server
these policies also determine how much
data were sent into the server
in the case have save its server
unchanged and save change keys
we're only gonna chill send up the wreck
third we're only gonna send up the
values on the record
that have changed in the case have save
all keys were gonna send the entire
record all the values whether you change
them or not
so back to locked updates we've got this
a thing called locking and if you don't
use it
here's what could go wrong with an
unlocked update I'll right now we've got
this Contact Card
we've got same name first name last name
picture
on to clients and the nine class
everything's good right now
but let's say the iPhone changes that
contact completely certain modifies the
picture it modifies
first name and it modifies the last name
well it's gonna perform a save change
keys to the server
which is gonna send up the things that
that have changed and that's gonna
over right whatever is on the server
next before the Mac it's a chance to
download that record the user edited the
first name
that record and just changed it and that
Mac
then sends does a safe change keys with
the server
and it sent up just the property that
was modified and now we've got a problem
here
apps we've got a problem this contact
record
isn't what either the client's meant to
have so to work around this
we have locked updates and locked
updates are we r
making sure that the server knows that
you're updating the same values that are
already on the server
and we do this with the chainstay so the
change takes the property on the record
that necessarily changes anytime a value
in the record changes
in this case we got changed a gay both
on the server and locally
and so we know that they both have the
same values
if we go in we add a new property on the
local record
when we say that to the server using the
default say policy
it's gonna send up both the change take
and the property the changed
the servers then before does anything
it's gonna check the to change takes
and 30 quill will apply the change that
you made
if on the other hand we have another
client dead
up for and then the server is going to
send back a new change take because we
did change a property
we return this new record to you with
the updated change take
in the completion book so if you take
the record that we give you at the end
of a save
and you do all your subsequent put
modifications on that
you'll be using the updated change token
and you shouldn't have an
any conflicts with the server
now let's say we have another client
that you know hadn't seen that change in
he was still a virgin a
and he decides to add a different
property record
well he's gonna save it to the server
he's gonna send up the change tag
and modify property and the server is
going to realize that
hey those two values at the same and the
client's gonna get back
an air sane you know you have a conflict
so how do we handle these conflicts
well if you run into this case a bar
locks a failing
you gonna get an error that CK your
server record changed
and because you guys all went to the
introductory talk and you learned about
how great air handling is and how
important it is
are you got some fantastic air handling
here and its gonna check for C Care
Survey record changed
when you see that you know they your
out-of-date you're gonna need to get the
new record from the server
you're gonna need to take your local
changes apply them to that record and
try the same again
and we've already anticipated that so
what we're gonna do is help you out a
little bit
and we're going to return those records
to you already because we know
that's the next logical thing to do so
inside the user in for a dictionary of
despair
you're gonna find three copies of the
record
you can find the record that you
attempted to save to the server
the one that encountered the air
you can find the original copy at the
local record which is
the copy we downloaded from the server
it before you made any changes
and finally we're gonna give you the
server record back this is the copy the
record with the most up-to-date change
take
you're gonna want to figure out what
makes sense
out of all those copies values and keys
you can apply them all to the server
version for the record
and then you're going to retry that safe
see might be wondering at this point you
know what type I love save
policy should use and the simple answer
to that is that you should just
always you seek a record save unchanged
and it's the default it's a default for
a reason and that's because it's the
safest
I if you remember that example have an
unlocked uptake on bad
you could end up with really mixed up
corrupt data on the server if you're not
using block
however there is always a time and place
for using unlocked updates
and the biggest case for this are highly
contentious updates
if you're doing anything in the public
database you might have hundreds or
thousands or millions of clients
accessing at the same time
and if every one of those clients is
trying to save
say the same record and you're locking
on that
most those clients are gonna be hitting
locking there's a gonna hit complex
and they're gonna be retrained really
frequently City know this is going to be
a really contentious update
you can structure your client to do
unlocked updates as long as you know
you're always ready inconsistent
properties
on the cases that unlocked update the
failed you know you could make sure you
always read both the first and last name
and you know it'll be consistent
the other reason to use a unlocked
update in the case they've saved
save all keys would be if you wanna for
something to the server
the client might say you know the copy
on the server is bad but I know I have a
good copy the record here
I wanna just forced at all on top of the
servers copy
there are some catches to use in favour
keys
and one of the problems is that any
property on the server
that doesn't exist in the local record
that you're trying to save
isn't gonna get removed in less you
explicitly remove that record their
property on the record
on all those words are really confusing
and it's really hard to explain so
instead I'm gonna try and explain that
with the picture here
so we've got our our contact record
again what we're gonna do is add a
couple properties were gonna change
first name we're going to add a new
property and we're gonna delete the
hobby
we're now going to do a save all keys to
the server
what that's going to do is send-up all
these properties
even the ones we didn't change locally
and they're gonna update the values on
the server but what you'll notice here
is that the server had an additional
property that we didn't have an original
copy the record
this home town property wasn't removed
we do this to help you with version if
your app are you might
releases aversion to have your apt that
ads hometowns but version one didn't
ever know about the hometown
and if version one was using save all
keys its gonna over right these
properties on the server that it never
knew about
and and that's kind of a bad thing you
can't have a backwards compatible code
easily that way
so what we do instead is we still allow
you to remove that but you need to
explicitly tell us that you want that
property to lead on the server
so even though there's no hometown
property on this record
we can still call seek a record set
value for keno
or we can call remove object for key
we're going to remove the hometown and
now when we save it up to the server
that delete will also go up with the
save
finally one other really neat things
about a seek a record is that we allow
you to have personal records
so you might have a really big record on
the server and you only care about one
or two properties that
well with the desired keys property we
allow you to fetch
just a certain subset the properties
that are on the server
and we expose this desire keys property
on any
operation that fetches a record so you
can see it on CK fetch records operation
I seek a query operation and seek a
fence record changes operation
and there really anything about this is
you can then take these partial records
and save them back up to the server
you don't need to work with entirely
full records
you can you know if you want to update
just one value on a record
such that one value from the record
update it and do is save a
just that record that has that one value
I you doing this with
locking enabled you know it's safe
because if
the record is change some server since
then you're gonna get a conflict
so now let's talk a little bit about
modeling your data for cloud
if we go back to that example the
receipts ap
let's say we have a shoe box that holds
over receipts
and that's going to be one object in in
the cloud
and we're gonna have an object for each
one of our receipts
and the initial way you might design
this is you create a receipt array
inside a shoe box
and every time you add in the receipt
you're going and add new entry to that
array
and that entry is going to be a
reference to the record is created
I we call these forward references these
are references from a parent
to its child and the prom with these is
that you end up getting bottlenecked on
that receipt sorry
of this was a public database you might
have hundreds of clients trying to say
this record at White's
and every time a a client tries to add a
new record
they need to update that array on the
shoebox and even though the clients
might be adding different records
are different receipts they're all gonna
run into are
conflicts on the shoe box at on the
shoebox record
so we recommend that you try and avoid
forward references
in your design and instead I use what we
call back references
so instead of having the shoebox point
at the receipt that senate
have the receipt point at the shoe box
it's in
the great thing about this is its very
scaleable
you can have millions of clients adding
receipts all at once
and there's no bottleneck they can
create their receipt pointed who owns
them
and none of them are going to run into
conflicts
when you need to go get everything
that's in a shoe box rather than
fetching that shoe box getting the array
records in it and fetching all those
records you can instead just use a query
not clear is gonna select all the
records that have that shoe box as an
owner
one other neat feature we give you with
relationships are cascading deletes
so cascading deletes our way for you to
make your object graph
get cleaned up automatically and you do
this by
marking your references with they seek a
wreck Prince action
delete self and that means that when the
for record the references deleted you
will also be deleted
in this case the green record has that
reference action poignant in orange
record
when the orange record gets deleted the
green records gonna get automatically
deleted by the server
these elites also cascade so if we had a
whole trio objects hung up for that one
orange record those two liter get a
cascade all the way down
and clean up artkraft for us
but one thing to keep in mind with these
delete self references
is that they're not reference counted
that means that if you have
multiple references coming out one
record the first one of those records
it's deleted will cause you to get
deleted
and finally these delete self references
give you one additional feature if you
doing a batch save and you've got a
jumble records in this graph and they
have to lead self references between and
clock it is gonna do an automatic top a
logical sort for you
we're gonna upload the records in order
so that all the records that are
referenced will be up there by the time
the record reference in them is upload
I this is really great and the public
database where you don't have
atomic commits but you still want to be
able to upload data that looks
consistent
at any point when a client downloads
so while developing Clark it internally
we've had a couple of our clients ask us
you know why do I need to use these
reference object rafted
no Alec and met and it's so much work
arm you know I
to get a record id: why can't I just put
in a string input at my record
are you can't say you know you come up
with this clever little record id: the
string
but then you look at the record I D
class and you realize it's actually
two properties and you can't just store
the description on the record on server
I see get a little smarter in the story
the record id:
and the their name in the zone ID I'm
but then you look its own ID and that's
also composite a we need to know what
where zone is and and whose account is
so you get a little more clever and you
make this record I did a string in zone
I did a string
I am in now you call that everywhere
the problem is now you're not for its
compatible if anything ever gets added
to references
all the records on the server are going
to have this hard coded format
and you can have to go through a lot of
work when you query records
instead just use references its gonna
make you could really clean
I mean that she box could be a record
id: that shoe box could be a record
itself
it could be a reference all those are
just work as long as you use to seek a
reference
a couple last notes on modeling data Inc
like it
I wanna vom is that clock it as a
transport mechanism
I what we've tried to do here is give
you an easy way to
access the clock its servers but we're
not meant to be a local persistence
layer
we want that to be up to you and you
need to figure out the best way to store
your objects
and to that extent we recommend that you
don't some class CK items
you should take those items when you
receive them from the server
and translate them in here on model
objects
and you can do that on the way out as
well when you need to save on your model
objects
translated into a CK record and upload
all that to the server
so if you remember from the introductory
talk we have these things that we call
subscriptions
their processing queries that run on the
server
and every time something changes that
matches that query
you're going to get a push notification
and these push notifications are sent
via the Apple Push Notification Service
just the same way that it would work if
you build your own server
but there are some drawbacks with Apple
Push Notification Service
are one of them is that they can't make
any guarantees on delivery of these
pushers
other kinda meant to be these at them a
little you know here's a push use a push
if one of them gets dropped because I'm
a bad network or
anything else going on I there's no
guarantee
so in practice there really good about
delivering these pushes
I and one other reasons is because the
server will store pushes for you
if you're offline so if you put your
phone in airplane mode and you get push
as soon as you come back out of airplane
mode the server will have that saved and
still deliver the pusher
but the problem with this is the server
only stores1 push per client
so if you received a buncha pushes while
you're offline you're only gonna get the
most recent one
what does that look like well we've got
our Clark its server we've got the
APS server and we've got the iPhone
appear and we send a push
and we're online everything goes through
we get our badge everyone's happy
but then we get on an airplane I our
phones in airplane mode we have no
network connection
and when they push get sent the APS
server helpfully stores it for us
if we were going to come back online
right now we would get her subscription
push
and we'd be happy by this is a long
plane flight
and while we're on the plane that we got
his own update push that new eyes on
subscription that I was talking about
when that gets to the APS server its
gonna drop their previous subscription
push
and now when your phone comes back
online all you're gonna receive this is
an update
the problem with this is that you never
heard about that subscription fire
so how do we solve this well ok we've
created a notification collection in
Clark it
every time the server sends a push to
the APS server
it also makes a copy of that push in the
notification collection
see can see we have that same problem
where we're in airplane mode we drop a
subscription push
are from comes online tickets the push
and
because this is a well behaved client it
knows every time they receive the push
it should go check notification
collection to find out about anything it
might have missed
so how does that work well this
notification collection is a lot like
the Delta downloads I talked about
earlier
it's all change token based you had to
change talking to the server
and the server Hans Backe all the
notifications that have changed since
then
along with an update to change token
so since is our first time talking the
notification collection we're gonna send
up a new change token
we're gonna get back both for those
pushes are one of them which we missed
and then we're also gonna get and
updated change token for the current
state
one thing with serbs subscriptions is
the
you might want to use those to change
some UI in your application
for example in our receipts ap we might
wanna subscription for
any receipt that was over a hundred
dollars if that happens
we want to arm marked every seat in a
different color
so were gonna get this push for a
subscription
and now the receipts blue because it was
a big expensive receipt
but you know this is gonna happen on all
your clients so you can have your iPad
showing that receipt in blue you can
have your Mac show in every seat in blue
and once the user acknowledges it you
want that you I state to go away on all
your clients
well the way we do that is we let you
mark a subscription
certainly let you mark a notification as
bread
and when you do that you're going to get
a push for the updated
subscription updated notification on
every client
so in this case we mark a receipt we're
gonna go mark that subscription is right
on the server
and now there's a new entry and if we
switch over to our Mac which is still
showing it in blue
it's going to get a push its gonna check
the notification collection
it's going to get that subscription
subscription notification and it can
tear down its UI
and now all your clients are in the same
state
so with the notification collection keep
in mind every time you get a push
you should check notification collection
are you never know what you might have
missed
and this isn't just for airplane motor
bad networks
this can happen if you get multiple
pushes in a row
I there's a lot of changes that happen
all at once the cloud kitserver Michael
SM
or the push server my coalesce this
pushes
and of course because a lot of these are
mobile devices their iPhones
they're going to be moving in and out of
network states they might be on my fire
they might be on a
a bad cell network you never know what
your network is like
just assume that there might have been
more pushes that you didn't hear about
so now we're gonna go over the i cud
dashboard and the Eichler dashboard is
our web-based interface
for managing your application in
Crockett
the I car dashboard lets you view your
data
i lets you manage the schema that were
trading for you
it lets you control what's indexed and
it
help to moving from development to
production I can explain dollars in
detail in a bit
I let's start with viewing data
so if you remember the a
view of our containers appear we've got
a public database and a private data
rates
and when you're viewing your data in the
I car dashboard
all that data in the public databases
have course public
so in the dashboard you'll be able to
see every record in your public database
but if you remember the private
databases again one database
for each individual user and in this
case were only logged in as one user
reluctance our developer account so all
we're gonna see on the icon dashboard
is the data in the private database for
our developer account
%uh this is really important you know
you might use a different account for
testing in a different account for
viewing data in the Ikelite dashboard
if you do that you won't be able to view
your private data in the dashboard
so what is the Dutch word look like well
we log in
and the first thing we're gonna see here
are different record types
so you can see we've we were using the
party app we've got parties
and over here we see the different
schema for those
values that's being created
when you're developing the clock
application you're talking to the
development environment
and the server in the development
environment creates a just in time
schema for you
so we did this because we wanted you to
be able to develop as rapidly as
possible we didn't want you have to go
to a
this dashboard and planned out what your
gonna do in your application and
choose all the data types that's not as
much fun as just
writing some code so we let you dive
right in
you write some code and the things that
you upload to cloak it as you upload em
those values get locked down into a
scheme
so you can see here that we've got a a
couple different values and we've got
there
couple different keys in their values I
but we notice that we made a mistake
when we're developing this app
we uploaded a date value heard a key
but we use the string value and what we
really want there is a deep valley
the I car dashboard is gonna let us fix
that up so we can go to this
and we can deleted we can remove it from
my schema
and now we can recompile a wrap use a
date value
upload that record again and when the
Service is at record
it'll create a new scheme entry for the
date value
using a actual date inservice training
so next up you can view all the records
in your
public database using the I could ask
for see can see here we are you have a
couple different parties in the public
database
what you can also do is create records
in the public database
so you can tap on this plus button and
fill out a new entry
we're gonna make a new party for coffee
on Friday
and we can say that and you'll see that
that actually got saved into the public
database
I any clients that are fetching records
are gonna see that
that change in the public database
we can also search for records are this
is just like CK queries so we can
click on that magnifying glass and we
can type in string
and we can filter down to any party that
mentions WWDC
additionally this gives us all the
functionality that we have in CK query
we can build compound queries right on
the dashboard
so if you click on the plus button I
let's choose location
and much filter down to everything
that's within 5 kilometers
Mosconi Center I happen to have those
memorized
so that filtered everything down just to
the two parties that are in this area
are finally in the public database by
default
every record can be read by every user
and it can be created by any user I want
to create a record
that record can only be updated or
deleted by the user that created
but we understand that that doesn't
provide all the functionality that you
might need to make an application in the
public database
so what we've given you are what we call
roles these roles let you choose
sets abusers that have different
permissions for record types in the
public database
so one example that might be there I
want to
restricted so that only I can create
parties in the public database
so what I'm gonna do in order to do that
is create a new role
I'm gonna call this you know party admin
and in that I need to choose a record
type: and give it
special permissions so I'm gonna choose
parties
and I'm gonna give it create read and
write permissions for those parties
now what I need to do is go to the
record type in restricted so that no one
else can create a party
so I'm gonna find my party I by party
record type:
and you can see up there that parties
can be created by anyone who is
authenticated
we don't want that we want only party
admins to create this record so we're
gonna
unchecked that value
now we need to assign people to that
role so that there's actually users out
there that can do this
if we go to the user records we can see
everyone who's use this app so far
if they have marked themselves is
discoverable you're gonna be able to see
their first and last name
if they having you're just gonna see
that record id: up there
so I'm gonna click on my user and then
I'm going to
at myself as a party at nine
and now I'm the only user in the public
database that can create a party
so are one of the last things the icon
dashboard helps you do is move from
print development into production
so as I talked about earlier we wanted
the development environment to be as
quick and easy to use as possible
we wanted you to hit the ground running
we wanted you to just open up Xcode
start typing some code say view record
to the server and see immediate results
and that all works great because the
server does just in time schemers
but that's not very efficient if we're
working in a public database that might
have millions of users
we need to prepare some things before we
go into the environment that all over
customers are gonna hit
so the way this works is we've got our
records we're developing our app right
now
and we just created a record for the
very first time and we uploaded it in
the development environment
the servers can see that and since is
the first time it's in a party it's
gonna
automatically create a new party record
type:
and then for each of these keys and
values it's going to create an entry in
the schema
and its gonna creating index on every
one of those values
this index is what lets you query for
any value in a record
so while you're in development you can
just run a query and search on
any value for any he in a record
and let's say we're gonna head were
developing this app and we decide we
want to add
an additional properties so we decide we
want to I have a background property for
the color of the party
so this party's backgrounds blue all we
have to do is upload that record
its gonna send all those other
properties to the index
and the server is gonna notice our
there's a new property in here
going to create a new scheme entry build
a new index an index of property
when you're ready to release your app
you can wanna make sure you've run
everything in development first so that
you've built up This Just In Time scheme
here then getting UCI car dashboard to
move that schema from development
into production and you're gonna wanna
check all these fields make sure that
they're the right values
make sure that every key that your Apple
ever use exists in that scheme
and when you do that you're gonna move
it into production and lock that schema
in
additionally all these indexes take up a
decent amount of space because the
tested
make it so that you can query those
records I if you know you're never gonna
creep
a value like we know we're never gonna
query for records with just a blue
background
you can drop it index and this'll help
free up some space
in your aP's database or in your users
database
us to finally a couple kid tips and
tricks
so we already went over this in the
entry talk but air handling
on please handle your heirs Inc like it
this is really important
I am i kno air handling is hard and it's
not fun to do
but cloud kid is all based on network
communication
and when you're talking over the network
any thinking a rock I'm
you know that the network and it dropped
because we have other people talking to
the server we can get conflicts we can
get errors
all kinds of things can happen and as as
possible the first talk this is the
difference between a
working ap and then not working now it's
not the difference between a
good app in a great I if you don't
handle areas here
your ap just isn't going to work right
arm
in Clark it also we've tried to avoid
any sort of magic
we we don't want to try and handle these
errors for you and figure out what might
be best
we want to just tell you what happened
we want you to be able to
figure out what you need to do next and
we want to give you all the information
to do that
so keep in mind when you're handling
your heirs hear that your operations can
have partial airs
these personal errors when you're using
the and its operation API
you might be sending up abacha records
and if you're saving in the public
database
it could be the case that just one of
those records had a conflict but the
rest saved just fine
if that happens you're going to get a
partial tear an insider that you're
gonna find one air for the record that
failed
I this was in a custom zone you might
see that as a
atomic update airs so you might see that
one of those records failed and the rest
got the batch
air I error in there
and finally we want you to make sure
that you retry any server busy years
I it could be the case that the you know
I'm buncha people are going to service
at the same time in service can't handle
it and I need clients to back off
I could also be that your client is
misbehaving and and hitting the server
too frequently in the service and/or its
slow down buddy
are this is our way of saying you know
we need a little more time this request
was okay but please try to get
and anytime we give your server busy air
we're gonna hang back AC care
retry after key this is the number of
seconds that we'd like you to wait
and retry request
so are limits in the keynote it was
mentioned that cloud kate is free with
limits
I how those limits worked well anything
stored in the public database
is counted against your app score we
give every app
a quota and that's just for the public
database
anything you put in the private
databases count against the user's
account
so every I caught a cab gets 5 gigabytes
of free storage
by users might have bought more or they
might have filled up all that space with
the emails are backups or photos
I so every users can have a different
man storage in there
and because this is kinda the user space
and it's shared space we want you to
know
remember to be nice to your users it's
technically free space for you because
it's theirs I but you know don't fill it
up with unnecessary stuff
are so again with the limits on how much
do you get free app container
well what we're concerned with here is
customers having a great experience
and these limits that we've specified
here are really to try and prevent abuse
we don't want to prevent legitimate use
we just don't want anyone abusing
market and the numbers that we give you
here also scale with the number users
who have
IP going developer not able to calm you
can get the full breakdown I love the
different values but
as an example I if you had 10 million
users have your hap
we're gonna give you a petabyte in I've
asset storage 10 terabytes a database
storage
has some pretty high transfer limits and
this is all for your public database
in your application
so finally a note on efficiency arm
one thing about cloud kid is again it's
a transport mechanism
we are only there to talk to the I cloud
servers for you
where not store in any records were not
cashing records
anytime we give you back a record it's
something that we got from the server
we're trying to be as transparent about
that as possible and not do any
I cashing shenanigans here we're always
just giving you what the server gave us
I in terms of efficiency though you
might remember from the same policies
that were only gonna save the values
that have changed on record
so we try and be smart about what we
send over the wire
I when word sending up assets those can
be potentially really big blow up the
data
and that data is transferred efficiently
so if the server already has a copy of a
file
we don't reupload it if we are to have
their file locally we don't need to
redownload
are so in summary I we're really excited
about Clark it here
I we built a lot really great features
and it's something that we actually use
that Apple we've built
I Cloud Drive rebuild I clarke photos on
top at this
and we want you guys to start using the
same technology that we're using
at Apple I'm really excited to see
what's going to happen
I can't wait to see some maps in his
pocket and
good luck with you think like it
so I'm if you need any if you need to
contact anyone Dave the long as our
evangelista is the guy with the boat I'm
I few documentation its on developing a
double dot com
are we had a introducing Cloud kit
session earlier in the week
there's a couple more related sessions
thank you