so good afternoon everybody my name is
Jeff Watkins
I'm in Iowa saw
near I'm on the iTunes team and I have
pleasure talking to a little bit about
advanced user interfaces with collection
view
recently we got some brand new designs
for iTunes Connect and
these were welcome new designs for
I was 7 look and feel and
they were really fantastic they were
brand new fresh clean
I look and feel and they gave us
a great opportunity because we haven't
making
decisions for our code since I west to
and as you can imagine
the decisions that we made. back and I
was too we're really not the same
decisions
that we would be making today so this
was an ideal opportunity for us
to take some time and pay off some
technical debt
now we all know that that's fancy speak
for
throw away the old code and write some
shiny new code
but the reality is we really wanted to
build
really great modern architecture
that would take us forward a few more
releases you know
everybody thinks that they're gonna
build this shiny
glittering drool architecture that's
gonna last for ever
but the reality is you get to maybe
three releases
have anything to build and then it's
time to rethink things
but this was our opportunity so
I'm really excited to announce that we
have some sample code that goes along
with this
talk but what makes the sample code
even more interesting is this sample
code is distilled
down from the actual source code
Abidjan's connect
I have my manager and his chain
management to thank for this
because this is kind of unusual normally
sample code is something that you
just sort of work together after your
talk
and it covers the aspects that you're
talking about
but it you know it becomes the bear
minimum
this actually is full rich
data sources full rich
you I collection delay I'll I and
there's actually way more in there that
we're going to talk about today
close
I'm sure there are bugs I
but more importantly we'll be building
on it
and improving as time goes on so look
for all sorts of additions to this
a simple code as time goes on so we had
some requirements
just like you all probably get
requirements with your applications and
I'd like to go through those
one by one and take a look at them and
give you a little bit
are a sense up where we were coming from
and you a little bit a sense that the
tear
that I felt I'll when I took a look at
them
so first the ball we had really complex
data
we started off with iTunes Connect
to supporting aP's and books and that
was great
but now we're gonna support all the
content types
the store that the store supports so we
were gonna add
music God music
as well as movies and TV seasons
now that
was going to pose a significant
challenge for us
because each one of these content types
as you can see has multiple sections
multiple different I'm
tabs within their we're talking about an
awful lot of data that's going to be
a real difficult time to manage on top
of that
really want to have a single loading
indicator
one of the things i think is really
tremendously important
is that users no when the content is
available
and ready for interaction I really don't
like it
one application has a spinner here
spinner their
I don't really know if it's ready for me
someone to make iTunes Connect really
clear
that when the speaker was gone we're
ready for you
so we're not have our spinner
their spinners gonna go away and there
was the content
now most of our designs looked like you
I tableview
and this was easy we could have done
this in our sleep
but it got more interesting on ipad
because we have needed to support
multiple columns
now we could have packed together a
solution for iPad
but that didn't feel right right here
we're trying to create
a future looking modern architecture
we should consider consider hacks
so we really needed to do something more
sophisticated
for iPad and that's when I started
thinking let's take a look at collection
you
well if you know collection view
you know there's some limitations with
the standard flow layout
specifically it doesn't really support
global hatter's
like you haven't able to: right and we
needed to support global hatter's we
needed people have this one header
that stuck around as you tapped through
your content
so that made me start thinking me we
have to do something here
and I might wind up having to write my
own layout
in addition we also needed to support
pin headers so as we're schooling
through our content
it was really important that we able
we'd be able to get
at those segment two controls so that we
could get
to the different sections of our content
so we needed people support pin headers
and flow layout also doesn't
really support that either so
that kinda put the mail in the coffin of
I've using flow layout for us
and that man we're gonna have to do I'll
I'll a collection be layout which I
gotta admit was pretty exciting
I also wanted to add swipe to at
this was a new feature in Iowa 7 I
thought it would be a great addition to
iTunes Connect
because it gives it that modern I
interactive feel
and users can swipe to the tax code from
their loss to favorites
and
Nevada
also you know if you've got a list the
favorites
you're gonna want to be able to edit
those so we want to support batch
editing
and likewise into the tax code
now favorites wouldn't be any good right
if you couldn't
manipulate them if you couldn't re water
your favorites because
because I have a drag if you got a lot
of favorites and
they're in the wrong order so want to
sport drag reordering as well
and we need to support that with a
custom layout and I was going to be a
bit of a challenge
but I feel like I've been slacking on
Xcode summer put it back at the top
other
the list favorites because they really
have
it at a park
tomorrow I'm
K
with with swift and all the other stuff
they've been doing
those guys so so those were our
requirements
and those those kinda law
I mean on top of all the other stuff
that the rest of the guys had to do on
but i wanna talk about the first one
first because without
data right iTunes Connect is nothing
it would just be some pretty pictures /a
I've your caps and everything else
which are nice but nobody's gonna want
to look at
that you know lines and and
pretty pictures so getting the data
right is the most important thing
and quite frankly was the thing that I
was really really calm convoluted Lee
freaked out about because 5d a types and
all these different sections and whole
my goodness so
I really needed come up with some way to
minimize the complexity of all that data
and the way I took
a look at this as I took all the designs
that rahi guys and gals in fact mostly
Italian
to come up with and we laid them out I
kinda squinted 'em
adamantly about side by side and I
realized
that there were some real similarities
here right
diffuse if you squint that these you
realize that we've got some
key-value stuff going on here and
that in particular showed up all
throughout the application we've also
got this
status section that shows up frequently
we've got lots of sections in our
layouts
that seem to reappear all over the place
I thought to myself gosh
this is really something that we need to
take advantage of you really need to be
able to reuse
this kind of code but the problem is
if you've been doing collection view
controllers in the past you know that
there's really
challengers with code reuse when it
comes to
data sources the traditional approach
to a collection a few data source has
you putting
everything in the view controller and as
a result
you wind up with one of two things first
you can wind up with a gigantic view
controller and
I'm sure you've all seen this not on
your projects but you want to put the
view controller that's like
five thousand lines of code and it does
everything I'm including things that you
don't do anymore
i deleted all that code and
so wouldn't want that especially nothing
we're starting fresh right we wouldn't
want that
the other option is we could have had
one view controller
for each content-type: and that seems
like it's a better approach
but it's really not because there's
really a lot of things that
the view controller just does innately
and the way you wind up with
sharing common code is you want to push
it down to a common base class
which ones being the same thing is
having one gigantic you control it
because
you pushed all database class so sure
you kinda hidden it a little bit but now
it's down there
and you're just not looking at it on and
it doesn't
all solve the problem code reuse across
screens
so we wanted a better solution now
fortunately
I had the pleasure working on the Game
Center team during the Iowa 7 redesign
and they came up with a solution to this
exact problem
it's called aggregate data sources now
they're
data was a little bit less complex than
ours by just
a smidge I but they hit upon the right
answer
which was building up data sources from
smaller data sources
there's nothing that says that
a UI collection you datasource has to be
implemented on your view controller
in fact I would encourage you not
to implement that data source on your
view controller in fact
I go so far as to say never ever again
implemented under the
you can I mean unless you really want to
but what we do here
is we implemented as a general and its
object
and then we build those together to
build a much more sophisticated data
source
and this goes a long way to enabling
code reuse
because as you can imagine we've got
these little classes
up data sources that we cobbled together
we reuse them all over the place
and as a result we wound up with a
single view controller for our product
detail screen
that is only 14 methods now six of those
methods before you get all upset
that F fourteen methods 60 those methods
five other building 25 content types of
data sources
one of them's building the overall the
source and then the rest the number some
action methods the public or responder
chain
I think there's some you know delegate
methods in there
and what not so I mean we do go a little
overboard
I probably could cut it down I'll but
you know
we're getting there so let's take a look
at
the four intrinsic aggregate data source
classes that you'll see in the sample
code
the first and most important one were
all the action is is APL datasource
that's the base data source that's where
we implement the UI collection view
datasource protocol as well as a host of
other good stuff that will talk about
in a little bit on top of that with
layered the
AAPL segment to datasource
and that can have multiple children but
only one of them's active at a time
think I love a UI segment to control in
fact
there's a good reason to think that it
will bend out a header
with you i segment to control as part of
its
base behavior then there's the APL
composed datasource and that will take a
number of children
they're all active at once and it
manages the mapping between the external
index pouts and the internal child
and ex-pats and then there's this
AAPL basic data source how many times
have you had
just the list things and you just wanna
shoulder
well that's what the basic data sources
for it takes I'll
an array of items it manages insertions
deletions reordering
all that nasty stuff it sends out the
right notifications
it only allows you to have one section
because there's countless times
well that's all you need and we wind up
using it
all over the place so let's take a look
and how we use these four classes to
build
up our product details datasource
so first of all the product details
datasource
is a segment to datasource and it has
four segments: no surprise one for
details
one for episodes one for reviews and one
for trends
those correspond exactly to the UI
segmented
control in the headers that you I
segment two controllers actually created
by the segment a datasource
now the details
child datasource is composed
datasource and it has children
for the Status section
information and description
each one of those is its own data source
the information was one of those key
value data sources
the description here's a special textual
datasource and all these appalling
information outpolled
the product object
now episodes is just one of those basic
data sources
because we've just got a list of
episodes but this is where it gets
interesting
because as you can see episodes have
show date now we could take
the date and we could pass stop to the
cell and we could have the cell
created an estate format or we could
read written
do that but we've been told countless
times that
thats really the wrong thing to do right
so this is what data sources allow us to
do is we can encapsulate
task-specific logic presentation
specific logic so in
my episodes datasource that's where I
have a big formatter
that specific to the to the episodes and
I do that conversion
up the estate that in each episode
into a string before I jamming into the
cell
and that way I get the best performance
rather than allowing that to happen each
cell
then reviews is another compose
datasource
probably getting tired us but it's great
let me let me tell you
I and the composed a source for reviews
has one for ratings
and another one for the actual reviews
and will actually come back to the
reviews datasource
when we look at how things loading in
the and coming up slides
and then trends is a custom data source
it arrives directly from
the base data source because we go out
we fetch the trend data
and then we actually render it in two
separate sections one for the graph
and then another for the historical data
so that's how we build up a product
details datasource
from all these little aggregate data
sources
and that has an additional benefit
because remember I told you that we
wanted to have
a single loading indicator
right well we originally tried
to make are single point the truth
for whether we're loading be the view
controller
that's kinda tough because the view
really doesn't know what all is being
loaded
right we've got five different content
types multiple sections
with subsections within them each one
load its own content
how's it going and I'll what turns out
we have 1k
that knows about everything and that's
the product details datasource
so the answer to the whole problem
up who knows what's loading
is the datasource the data source is
responsible for loading its content
and when you think about it it actually
makes total sense
and if you make the data source is
responsible
they know just the data they need to
load
they know exactly how to load it and
their already responsible for their own
past specific
logic so they can format it do whatever
they need to do
and make it ready for presentation so
now the view controller kicks off the
whole process
in view will appear by sending a low
data
to the datasource which in turn
propagates that message
to its children as appropriate so for
example a segment to datasource
or only send it to the selected its
source
but I composed datasource will send all
of its children
and because we're good computer
scientists just like all of you
we as a state machine keep track of
everything
you work right let's take a look at
section
so the obviously named
aglo doubles content state machine
um got a few states it's not as nasty as
as it could be all data sources
start of the initial state until they
receive a load content
message once they perceive the load
content message
then the transition into the loading
content state that's when we display the
spinner
that's the only time we ever display
this banner and if you notice
you can't ever get back their
so when they get content where they get
an error or the
receive no content from there respective
sources
they'll transition into no content
content loaded warned her state will
display
the appropriate a view
and we'll take a look at exactly how
that works
so let's see how this all works from a a
datasource loading date of the network
and from the UI standpoint so here we
are
in the end initial state we've got my
check list
datasource this is from a from the
sample application because I am
Kat Krazy and
yes I was heartbroken when we switch to
California landmarks
the yeah
I thought the Ocelot was finally gonna
get its chance
I'm so we're starting off in the initial
state and we get the load content
message
and we transition into loading content
when the datasource
in this case it's gonna request out to
its server
get me some caps the server eventually
comes back and says
here you go now depending on what the
responses
then it's gonna make a transition to the
right place and let's take a look
what the you why does in this case so
here we are loading content
showing the spinner and
let's imagine we get back some cats
so here we're gonna display the cats
like I said this is that simple
application
I'm assuming everything works well with
you compile and run exactly as
as planned on your apt on your machines
and we'll see our list the big cats
right there on our
devices however
if you know anything about cats there
never where you expect them to be
so more than likely you're gonna
try to load the cats any gonna be told
there are no cats here
will the great thing about this is I had
to do no work
here which is great cuz cats
do a lot of work for you on so
in this case all I set up was the No
content message in the new content title
on my datasource
and behind the scenes the machinery to
care everything else
why transition into the new content
state the layout
and the data sources take care
presenting the placeholder for me
really takes a lot of the burden off my
shoulders
now sometimes things go wrong
and then we go from the loading content
state
into the air state and similarly to no
content
if we configured an error message and
inherit title
will get a placeholder telling the user
what's gone wrong
so this is a really great way
to that we found to get are
consistent you why but it's a little bit
more than that
because in most cases
we're not just loading one thing right
I mentioned would come back to the
ratings and reviews
we load and information separately
would fetch the ratings and we fetch the
reviews
well we can't update if we've got a
single loading indicator
we can update the collection view but
the ratings
and then the reviews that wouldn't look
right
so we gotta update everything all at
once
and in order to do that we needed a
solution that was elegant
because anything less would be just
wrong
so the solution that we came up with
relies on the fact that we have
a parent-child relationship to our data
sources so let's take a look at that
all over data sources start of in the
initial state
they get the load content message and
then he all transition into loading
content state
at which point the ratings and the
reviews data sources
send out their requests to the server
now we all know that the servers not
gonna respond
simultaneously to both requests that's
fantasyland so what happens is one other
responses comes back
first that data source will process the
response
but not update itself what it does is
accused of a block
that actually will do the update and it
sends it up
apparent change and that Michael
disorder hang up there for a bit
then the next datasource will get its
response
it does the same thing it transitions
into content loaded
shoe's upper an update block
and then the parent will discover I'll
look
all of my children are loaded it's okay
for me to try and say
transition into contact loaded and now
I can call perform batch updates on the
collection view
and schedule all those update blocks
safely
insider perform backup update block
the good thing about all this is we
don't get exceptions because our timing
in
and be consistencies and I don't know
about you but I don't like exceptions
my boss kits for the corruption so to
recap
aggregate data sources were a great way
for us to reduce our view controller
complexity
our view controller only does do you
control a rethinks
it no longer involved in the datasource
other than setting up
and went a long way to promoting code
reviews
so now our code is scattered in these
aggregate data sources that we use
all over the place and isolates
task-specific logic
that we use for setting up our cells
into the data sources where they're
appropriate
and we got that single loading indicator
that we were looking for
so that was our first two requirements
so let's take a look at the next four
which necessitated
a custom you I collection view layout
now have a confession to make on
the first time I built the layout
I was very unhappy it worked
they weren't actually really well but I
am
mean actually put this hard to please
and if didn't work as well as I wanted
and the reason is I didn't collect all
the information that I should have
I tried to to be done
and just move on to other things so the
message I want you to take away from all
this and I'm
I'm for skipping had to the summary
before leaving start
is who your bookkeeping get
all the information you can and at the
very end run instruments
to make sure that you have enough memory
and your not using
too much resources and then prune
back the information keeping but cheap
at all
a prime so let's take a look at the
information I kept
if Michelle didn't keep and what I
should have kept
so first what I need to keep
and where did belong
so obviously we got these great designs
from hiii
and there's pictures right
we need to interpret that and figure out
what did we need from that
to actually lay out cells and headers
and and footers and
supplementary views and decoration views
the whole nine yards
and then kinda as a footnote where does
it all go
one address that first get it out the
way
in sources band visual information
defend views design metrics official
information
I put them in the datasource partly
because
the data sources are hierarchical and
they've got
fault metrics into got section base
metrics it just made sense
to put it there I could put it now
parallel structure
and had parallel structures never been
too crazy
so there in the data sources that's
where you'll find so let's take a look
at the section metrics so we've got some
big cats
and naturally we're gonna wanna know the
row height
we also one another background-color:
right are a lot of our sections
can be crazy summer white number garish
colors
obviously we have some that have
separators and separator insets
but not all of our sections have
separators
so we need to be able set them on a per
section basis
we also need to be able set a selected
background-color:
the way we determine whether or not a
cell appears
selectable is by the selected
background-color:
whether actually a selectable is in code
now remember we also support multiple
columns
so we needed to know based on the
section how many columns should support
and whether or not it should show a
column separator
for the headers and footers we similarly
needed to know
the height for the most the time we set
this to 0 which means
figured out yourself thanks to on a
layup
we also want to know the background
color
but most the time we set this to nell
which means inherited from the section
and we also
want to specify a paddock because one of
the things that we saw in our designs a
lot
was exactly the same header
but with a little bit more space between
this instance the header
not instant to the header and yeah
we could find a subclass to give us a
little extra space
or we could just have another metric
that says
0 here we're gonna have 10 points
spacing there we have 20
so we added padding actually wanna
beings
hugely helpful when it won when we
needed to line things
horizontally as well so this gave us
all the information we needed to lay
things out
in our actual layout
but some %uh this information needed to
be passed along to the cells in the
headers
and to do that we had some custom
attributes
I'm sure you all know that you can
create some classes the layout
attributes
so what exactly what we did and we
wonder with 4
a few more I cut custom attributes
first law background color and style
select a background color
and padding but also can header
at one point we thought that we wanted
our headers
to respond to being penned for example
if we'd had a
I'm a navigation bar that was blue
would make perfect sense for the header
to reach the top pin
and change to be blue and
it would need to know that was pinned in
order to do that
so those with a custom attributes we
decide decided
fine for headers and footers and
ourselves
now remember we also needed to support
global headers to do that
I'm gonna let you in on what I thought
was a secret turns out it's not
arm we're all familiar with and it's an
expat normally having two indices
one for section one for item
will it seems that you can also create
an innocent XPath with one index
and when you do that you're creating
a global supplement review
index path or a global decoration human
expert
it makes no sense to create these for
items so don't try
but this is how we separated are global
headers
from everything else when we initially
tried this
I tried to lump them in the section 0
not just made no sense
so now I'm able to distinguish them from
everything else
and we treat global headers differently
when you look at the sample code
you'll notice that the global headers
actually never go off screen
they a pin just underneath the
navigation bar
the treated as what will call special
attributes:
and they get updated as you scroll so
that they stay in place they do all
sorts of funny
fancy things now the code needs to be a
little bit smart
so that you checked the length view
index path so that you don't
accidentally call section and item
for these global index baths but other
than that
you're good now
building a layout earlier today
you might have heard olivier mention
that
I if you want to be really careful
about using invalidation or wanna be
really careful
to use invalidation I should say and
that's exactly the case
you might be tempted to build the most
perfect
single-pass layout and
docked because which will wind up with
is absolute efficiency
the first time and then someone will
come in and the look close you'll come
in and say
hey the cell has changed
and you have to relate to everything or
origin has changed because you scrolled
and you have to lay out everything
and you're just drop your performance
will die so let's take a look
at the pseudocode so to speak for for
the layout
that we came up with and then we're
gonna show you
a little bit of how we snapshot the
metrics
for one of our sections and I think
you'll get a good sense why
breaking this up into sections is really
important
so first of all if the data sources
changed
significantly like it's totally
different one or the total number
sections change
we just throw everything away and the
reason for this is
it's probably more efficient for us
to just three computer everything that
it would be to compute the deltas
because our data sources are actually
pretty small
if you've seen iTunes Connect you know
that the actual content
isn't that big so
yell I could probably come up with a
clever way to computer deltas and
everything else
but this wound up being just easier in
the long run
getting it done sometimes just as
important
next if the collection views with has
changed
or obviously if I threw everything away
then I need to regenerate
all the layout actually it's as well as
collect all the special layout
attributes so all those global hatter's
and any pin headers that might have been
defined within the content
so I make that single pass and I lay out
everything
and then if the origin has changed
because we strolled
I update the position have any special
layout acts now when I go back
and I update all this code to support I
was 8 I'm gonna fix this
because I use the new invalidation
contacts in the slot be different
but this is how we do it today so let's
take a look
at how we snapshot the metrics
so we have this hierarchical structure
data sources
and on you're right
is the product details three
so we start with section 0
which is status and we begin our
snapshot
at the barre least specific data source
which is the segment the datasource now
in this case
these are actually the default metrics
for the entire
product details and that row height
equals 44
background-color: it was like great that
means
everything is relied was forty four
background-color: it's like crack so
that's what we start with
next we move to the next most specific
data source which is the composed
datasource
for details it just so happens
but it doesn't define any metrics
whatsoever not eat
the fault metrics not sexually metrics
so then we can move on to the status
data source
which has section based metrics
specifically for that section
row hi people sixty and select the
background color
medium grey because remember we do the
selection based on the actual color
cell we have these overrides for row
height
and we have a new attribute for the
selected background-color:
so you can imagine if we had to go
through this
every time we move the origin the
collection to you
we get terrible free
so it's really important that we only do
this when it's
absolutely necessary so we only do it
when the collection to changes
but then we go through and we updater
attributes 1
when we actually scroll so I spoke
earlier
about optional layup methods and this is
where
my whole confession comes in I did these
out of order
I'm i knows but the summit you in the
lab earlier I give you some
specific details I started
with initial layout attributes and
finally attributes
and I realize that oh my goodness in
order to do
initial layout attributes and finally
attributes I need
the update information so let me
implement prepare for click to view
updates
and I'll just grab the arrestee updates
well just on the stash that's over here
because I meet them
and each time I would got called for
initial a ride to protect what the array
and I try to figure out what was going
on
and quickly my head exploded because it
was just too hard
and and I i admit
I deleted all the code I went on to
other things
and it was weeks before I was willing to
come back to it
arm and fortunately in those weeks I
talk to a lot of people
I read a lot of the documentation and I
finally figured out what I was doing
wrong
and what I was doing wrong wasn't doing
my bookkeeping
I was in collecting the information that
I need
and so let's talk about that information
and more importantly let's talk about
the information
in the right water so this it turns out
is the right order
prepare for a layup you probably already
implement this if you're doing a layout
but there's some information that we
need to capture here not just
building layout and then prepare for
collection few updates
followed by target content offset for
propose come to an upset
which is quite a mouthful an initial
eight attributes and finally
attributes something to talk about pair
layout
and prepare for collection you updates
together because they
do sort of pair up
first prepare layout so here's my mail
very colorful and when I get
prepare layout what I do as I take a
snapshot
up the current layout I keep as my old
laptop
in the process a building my layout I
have a lookup table
between all the Indus index pounds
to items all the index pads to
supplement reviews
all the index pounds decoration views
number I said keep everything well
when I get called to prepare layout i
duplicate everything
and I I stashed as the all layout
then in prepare for collection you
updates
I create a lookup table for deletions
insertions
and everything that was reloaded I run
through
the array of updates and every all the
deletions get tracked
and all the insertions also contract
so now I know everything that's going on
in my life
and then before I'm done with prepare
for collection the updates
I calculate the cheek the Delta in the
height
up the two layouts as well as
the change in we're the car the offset
up the
start my content should be because I've
got content that spanned
and possibly sprawl of the screen it
gets a little bit tricky
and for the sake of the examples were
gonna ignore all that
but that all gets done right here before
I return from
prepare for collection updates
cell let's take a look at wanna the
other methods I didn't implement
and later wished I had the target
content of that method
now the documentation says that this
adjust the scroll upset
and I didn't understand this really how
important this one's
until I saw in action so I have
animations are gonna show you
just how important this is I its use by
my layout actually to calculate
the pinning offset and the Delta that I
used to prevent
unwanted motion and the trick is
I get this calculation correct which
took a little while
but then I use it in so many places so
let's take a look at a
exactly how that works before I
implemented this
Europe got my old content and its 320 by
1000 I'm scroll all the way to the
bottom
and I put in some new content which is
considerably shorter
and collections you remember does a lot
of work for us
and it says K that's not valid I'll help
you out
all adjuster content offset 20 165
I'll admit everything down for all
member
I'm not easy to please and I don't want
their
I wanna be we'll see the new content
beginning at the new content
that's kinda why I put it there so
that means to me that I need to change
my content offset
soul after implementing
target content offset propose content
upset
cry pair got my old content
again with the original content of 70
432 and this time I propose
I had give a new content of 700
and notice Bush everything slides down
and I can see my content at the correct
position
I'm still not happy because my content
shouldn't be moving
if you've seen sample app what you've
seen iTunes Connect
what we've seen Game Center you actually
know that I wanted my content
not just to come in I want my content to
slide in from the side
because frankly that's cool and
if I get content that slides out from
the top and slide in from the side
I use as you can get seasick heineman
American one-star reviews for that
soul the solution
is initial and final layout accurate
that function I tried to do first
is the final 1i need to implement and
just a reminder
initially attack tributes is called if
the view will be on the screen after the
update
finally on attributes is called if the
view was on the screen before the update
and they're both gonna be called for
view that remains on screen
and I know you're not gonna believe this
until you see the code
but actually really simple once the all
the information has been processed
cell let's look at your admissions
before I like to see the code
on the left here we see what's happening
to the viewport
on the right is what the user actually
sees
K without initial attributes the blue
content
is stock where really is
and the viewport slides up to meet
and that makes that unwanted animation
however after I've
implemented initial layout attributes
you'll notice
that the new content is synced up with
the viewport
and as the viewport transitions to its
new location
the new content and meets with it and
appears
to stand still now
everything's moving but nothing appears
like it's moving
and that's what's important cell let's
take a look at the actual code I promise
you
it's actually really some cell
this is the for staff we start off by
getting section
then we get a copy the layout actually
it's
and obviously need to copy because we
can modify them possibly
and we don't modify the real attributes
because then will be able to find the
real attributes
and then ourselves will be hard I'm
so then we just termine whether or not
this particular item was inserted
or reloaded remember I said we did we
did all this calculation
you prepare for collection you updates
and now that means we've only got
these two lines of code
then it was inserted would change the
Alpha
to be 0 so it's gonna paid in
if it was reloaded and didn't exist
in the old layout remember IQ created a
snapshot of the old layout
so if there is no item at that index
bout
in the old lamp when it was reloaded we
want
Badian it's perfectly OK if there was an
item there
the previous time that's just gonna
change I'm okay with that
and then finally we want to offset the
origin
up the item by the Delta up to
content offset and that way everything's
gonna stay
exactly in place
so to recap bookkeeping is critical
to making your layout work if you don't
have the information you need
is no way you can make these methods
work
and then the optional methods really
make a huge difference
there's a difference between a L a layup
that technically works
and a layup it's just great so
middle for requirements think we did a
pretty good job at that
the last three I fought we're just gonna
be
you know a little something extra that
we'd add to the application
and they changed from being a little
something actually started
take a little but I'm arm so let's take
a look at them
in order to add swiped at it obviously
we need actions
to ourselves and there's any number ways
we could about actions
but in this case we had them directly to
the cells
and here we are because we use this as
an example
we're adding to actions to a cell
make favorite and swipe to delete cell
you can see that each action has a title
and
a selector those selectors when they get
when the action is invoked bubble up the
responder chain
and our view controller catches them
now force white editing batch editing in
and the whole nine yards
we needed some additional custom
attributes
we needed the column index
editing state and whether or not cell
was movable
I think those will become apparent why
we needed them in just a moment
cell slight edit with one column this
works exactly as you would expect
right spiked over you get the two
buttons
tap on a button action goes up the
responder chain
you controller catches it array all's
good
now in the case that the Delete action
that's all handled by the base view
controller
for two columns it's a little bit more
complicated
because just like Game Center we wanted
it to appear
that are cell was sliding underneath
the other content and in order to do
that
we needed to have the column index
as an attribute on the cell so when the
column index is not zero
we display a little gradient and
therefore everything looks like it's
like underneath
so for batch editing we have an
attribute for
weather setting and when that changes to
know
we animate out our editing controls and
movable is yes then we also display the
gripper
and movable is actually determined based
on
a query to your datasource or Rd source
really
and as you would expect you tap on the
twisty thing and outcome the editing
controls
and because I am much addicted
to state machines it is
all controlled by another state she arm
this manages all over gesture
recognizers the UI pen just a recognizer
the UI long press just recognizer and
the states were somewhat complex
the diagram gives you an indication the
reason for that is that
we have to respond to external stimulus
so for example if you have a toolbar
that has a
edit Anna done button the toggles
if you're editing and the user taps done
at any given moment we have to shut it
all down
and transition back into than idle state
and so that means that things are a bit
more complex
I'd love to revisit this and see if i
cant
you know simple fire but works
and that's you know the key criteria
it only works with our layout in our
cells
I I tried at some length to generalize
it a little bit more
by it works
and that's a great feature so drag to
reorder
it required some layout changes in order
to make everything work correctly
weaves add a layout gap
so as you're dragging this cell around
we needed the split apart the existing
cells
and we also needed to take the cell that
you were dragging
and market is hidden and
we also need to make sure that our layup
calculation
was fast enough I'm not gonna pretend
that it's
as fast as gonna get because I'm not
done yet
but it was fast enough it feels
reasonably fluid
it's good enough for the first release
now it does require data source apart so
by default
the datasource normally answers nope
can't move that one
nope can edit that so on so forth so
in order to actually implement drag
reordering in your code
you're gonna wanna say oh yes you can
move those things you can drag those
things
on and so there are some methods on the
data source that
need to have the right responses
but he really was and incremental change
Doral Ale
and incremental change your data sources
its cell that's the last three
requirements and
they were a little bit of a challenge
but they were just
you know a little bit extra so in
summary
the aggregate data sources went a long
way to simplifying
are complex designs when I first saw the
designs that a try
gave us I was a little bit terrified
there's a lot there we had a very short
time
and I'm glad that we found a way to make
it
easier and for you I collection view
bookkeeping bookkeeping bookkeeping keep
all
the data don't let it out your site
at the very end when you're concerned
that you using too much memory
fire instruments let instruments tell
you if you using too much memory
and then finally swiped at a track
reordering they're just incremental
things
you can do it and their simple kept
pull up pull it outta there and make a
party on so
for more information talk to the
incomparable J parents
I'm told he has great shoes
documentation take a look at the I was
documentation online
and the DEP forms there's great material
there
we've been known to hang out there as
well there were
related sessions this morning I'm sure
they'll be online this evening
so thank you so much for coming I hope
you enjoyed
the sea