good morning everyone my name is
Elizabeth read it I'm an engineer on the
I work
team and I'm here today with one of my
coworkers to talk to you about
how to share code between I less an OS
10 so
you know what we're gonna do today is
first talk about what code it's possible
for us share
what we probably don't wanna share and
then how we can share
more code or have a easier to Richard
code using some frameworks
anata specifically also good examples
insured rendering code
and then we're going to talk about file
formats and how you can optimize and
build those for a better
a multi-platform experience and finally
my coworker chris is gonna talk to you
about how to set up your Xcode project
to compile cross-platform last fall
I work add a release where we took our
eye West applications on our modern code
base
and we took that could base and brought
it over to compile for a West End
so now we have all over applications for
I O S 80 S 10
compiling from a single code base and
that was a really big deal for us we
really wanted to how
a a single pot up location for all over
features
have better user experience and and
better engineering experience to the
everyone's happier
and so we're gonna talk to you about
that specific transform from
I West Co 200 West 10 but the concepts
and examples were gonna give you
are meant to be you know examples are
not specific
directives on what you should do and so
the ideas and concepts
should apply if you're going in the
other direction taking an OS 10
application in bringing a title s
or even if you're building both at the
same time is or just you know
principles rather than a obvious I West
only
2000 s10 only and we have a lot of
different examples because
I work as a really big 32 applications
we have well over a million lines of
code
and over 10,000 unique class an obvious
10,000 unique
classes over 75 percent of them are
shared between I O S
and OS test now not this number is not
nearly a hundred percent its a large
chunk of code more a lot of the code but
not all over the court within hours
intentional on our part we we want to
choose which could we wanted to share
and which code is really meant to be
only one on one platform
or the other and that gives us are
really good common experience for our
users in our applications
well still targeting embracing the
strength each device were running on
and that was really you know helpful way
to keep to build the best applications
possibly could
so where do we start we started with
Rius applications
we have Rd had I work running on iPad
and iPhone
and we had a team really you know
excited and passionate
developers who wanted to take this code
and bring it to our
to our Mac platform and have everything
running from one location
and our code was set up something like
this rough estimate
hopefully you guys are familiar with his
pattern but just a review the
model-view-controller design pattern is
is where the model is that the data off
your application it's the contents
made your son of the wire sitting on
desk the viewers what your users looking
out or interacting with
and you don't really want those to ever
to talk directly to each other
if you're your model changes and you
don't want your view to change
if they're tied directly to each other
that's you have to change both sides
or vice versa and so instead we have
controllers them use as a translator
to negotiate between the two of them so
you don't need to worry about
having a model in your view too tightly
intertwined sorry
look at each section of this we started
with the model and we
want to figure out if we could share a
model code and for us that was part in
one of the major points above this
particular rewrite
we really wanted our our files to be the
same everywhere
and and most in a very important part of
that is having our model code:
talk to our files also be the same
everywhere and center model code:
isn't talking to the view code have our
controllers in between we should be able
to share our model code:
all talk a bit more later about the
actual content of the model
but for now we're gonna say that the
model code we're gonna share women
shared in this context
next we looked the at the Vue code
can we share our view code we want to
share a few Kobe really want our
applications have
the same content for users you know
files when we open and display them on
screen
we want those look the same everywhere
because our car users
carefully crafted their their document
took exactly how they want
but there some problems with Sharon view
code first ball
there's actual interaction per platform
on OS 10 the way that users interact
with your applications over the mouth
and keyboard hotkeys you know that
they're using the cursor which is a very
precise
single pointer where is on I left you
have
multi-touch you have 10 very
a wonderful but less precise fingers
Human Interface Guidelines says
anti-western major buttons to be at
least 44 by 44 points
just make sure that your users are able
to tap them and that's you know
less precise than your OS 10
interactions
and so that's you know one thing we're
gonna have to take into account with our
view code
another thing we need to consider is the
fact that the actual display size
between the different devices
is going to be different the kinds of
content we can show the space we have
for controls
is going to vary based on platform it
even more extreme on iphone verses map
and so we want to take advantage of all
the space we have available to us
when it is available and handle the fact
that sometimes that space will be
available
on smaller devices and we're gonna
happen to craft our code
for each platform a little bit in that
do space
also on i OS your user is looking
directly at your content
your application and nothing else that's
that's how I was devices work
and on OS 10 you can have multiple
windows mobile applications are doing
multiple things the same time
and you really need to take into account
that there's gonna be other things
happening on your OS 10
platforms and you need to build your
view accordingly you don't get to use
all over the room all of the time
by more technical note you literally
can't compile new code cross-platform
if you take a class that inherits from
you live you and you try to compile it
on OS 10 actor will look something like
this and it kinda mad at you
and so you there's that technical hurdle
as well
now someone you may be looking at this
and saying I I know how to handle this
I can fix this problem and you might be
thinking of something that looks like
this
we called a shinning and I work it's
also known as conditional compilation
and it's where you had your subclass
inheriting from
either you live you on I less were an
issue
on a West 10 and it that changes made at
compile-time
and here at the same code and has a
different superclass
on each platform now you know this will
compile
absolutely and it does work but there
are some problems with shinning
now views how think they are you live
you in an issue
have many similarities they serve the
same basic purpose in your code
they're there to head all user
interaction events and put content on
screen
but there are a number of differences
between them as well
they have different API the sport
different features and there's some
subtle differences in their
common behavior as well and so if you
build for example driving drop sport
on your OS 10 application with your view
annual compiled on I less
those API's don't exist and your code
will compile
and so fucin you're gonna break the
build fairly often
because of the differences and API's
between platforms
also it's very very hard to target your
fix
shoot a platform that your trying to fix
so if you have
a particular issue or change wanna make
or only on OS 10
what your code is compiled in both
places you now
gonna have trouble getting that code to
only 60 at 10
and not ISL s and so you could do more
conditional compilation absolutely that
you have in your code
that makes you could really hard to read
and also really hard to maintain
so overtime more and more problems may
arise
as you reach the edge cases have your
behavior
also if you build a view hierarchy on I
less
and looks great on your iPad or your
iPhone
a new shit to bring it over to West End
and you get everything that can compile
compiling you put it on screen
your UI is going to look like it's built
for I less remember how r buttons are
supposed to be larger for the fingers to
tap some
then you would use for your cursor you
if you build the same do code in both
places that new code is going to look
like it was designed
wherever you built in the first place
and will look a little unnatural
for the platform where it wasn't
intentionally designs
and you really want to have the best
experience possible and embrace the
Human Interface Guidelines and
lifestyles
over the platform on what you're running
so in general we think that
shinning is something that if not you
know it's helpful in Flex cases it's not
definitely the wrong thing to do all the
time
you know its it has its moments but just
be aware of some of the problems that
may arise
if you're using shining in your own code
if nothing else you're pushing all the
complexity understanding what the
platform differences are
aunt your clients in a way that isn't
necessarily obvious from the beginning
rather than keeping it all into in a
single location we could handle all the
details yourself
and let everybody else not worry about
it also note about swift
if you literally translate how you would
shame with objective-c
this one are compiling swept there are
ways to
Shin your code in swift you get more
complicated than your basic
conditional compilation that we can use
objective-c just a side note about swift
so for now we're gonna say that our view
code needs to be platform-specific
so that we don't run into these problems
next up is the controller code can we
share our controllers
we found that it really depends on the
kind of control or that we're dealing
with
some things that are called controllers
like view controllers you I view
controller and and ask you control or
are really tightly coupled with the
views themselves and like to view
themselves they won't cross compile
and and so controllers that are meant to
be used for get a platform specific
behaviors user interaction events hot
she's not handling multi-touch gestures
all those are very platform-specific
controllers
we probably don't wanna share those for
the same reasons we don't want to share
these themselves
however a lot over controllers are happy
do contain more shared logic there
talking to the
model more directly rather than dealing
with the intricacies
up the view itself and so we'll we would
like to share those controllers if we
possibly can because that's where a lot
of the CoreLogic
other applications live sorus eighty per
share some controllers
but not all hopefully you're gonna share
more controllers the non it really
depends on
on higher code is set up to to give you
an example what this might look like if
u
with your controller code in and I work
we had
a file was called canvas new controller
it
inherited from you I view controller and
it had a lot have stuff in it
it'd I did a lot of different things for
us and we realize that
your the split up the code in that file
with kinda
similar ratio here where some other code
with absolutely platform-specific it was
part of its job GUID controller it was
controlling the view as specified
but a lot of stuff we had in there was
more shareable logic it was about
they're managing states in handling some
renderings Dauphin
and you know scrolling and zooming some
earnings that we can handle any more
shared way
and so we really wanted to keep that
code and use it on both platforms
to solve this problem we split it in
half now we have
the IRS can issue controller that's
really in charge
actual you control your behavior road
and you could pick you control behavior
plus some other stuff and then we have a
shared canvas controller whose job it is
to actually control our share tender
subject which will talk to them
bit more about later and then we created
a counterpart
on the last 10 the OS tent embassy
controller tell the platform-specific
you control your needs on that side as
well and here we have a very clear
separation of concerns
so we know exactly what you'd object job
is and you can put the code in the right
place
based on what its its real purposes how
it should be use
a real-life example this a you know with
actual pictures and so forth
is rotation in in I work there are a few
different ways you can rotate objects
and also really depends on the platform
you're using
on I once you put two fingers down and
you rotate them relative to each other
any object will rotate on OS 10 hold on
the command hotkey
you click on the handle and you drag it
and the object will rotate
and those are really different
interaction paradigm really did you both
of them are very much
using the platform specific interactions
you can't do any other platform
but the underlying model changes are in
fact exactly the same
it's just an angle that we're applying
to an object and all map it goes along
with it
so we wanted to share as much about code
is possible because there are some
you know exciting math in there well
keeping the platform-specific logic
separate
so reset are cut up like this we have a
shared rotation controller
that does all the you note the the real
math and and state management
and it talks were model object when
appropriate and we have a
platform-specific gesture recognizer on
iowa's
that handles the multi-touch and
translate that into an angle their
rotation controller can understand
and we have a platform-specific mouse
and keyboard handler on OS 10
that handles both are hot key and
clicking interactions to tell us that
you know again translate that into an
angle for rotation control
so that are in pretty helpful we have
shared coherent have platform specific
logic
but there's actually more ways for us to
rotate in our I work applications
on OS 10 we have inspectors and you can
actually just typing angle directly into
a text field
hit enter I will rotate the object and
so
we also have had or that calls into the
exact same rotation code that you would
call
if you're doing it with your mouth or if
you're doing it
with your fingers on my last and
everything is exactly the same except
thing that translates
the user interaction into an angle for
our rotation control
also new in OS 10 yosemite we have NS
gesture recognizer API
that they have a lot like I left you I
gesture recognizer
and we could also theoretically plugged
the same thing in to our rotation logic
and have yes
third way for our user to you interact
and rotate our objects so if you look at
just the bottom half of this diagram
you know sharing code between platforms
aside this is a really powerful
abstraction for us
we have three completely different ways
to rotate an object
but most have our logic is still share
and we can also plug this in for things
like
testing if you want to just test our
rotation Monjack we get a fourth pass
I'm just a tester that as I would like
your attended by 10 degrees
and all the rest the code is the same so
our actual testing
our logic and not just our interface we
could also use disorders abstraction for
quick look for plugins
there's a lot of different ways you can
apply this attraction
in your own code to now we have
share model code: not sure I'm not sure
did you code and some controller shared
and some not
and we want to share more code and now
so we looked at the founding that the
framework supplied
it supplied by Apple and we noticed that
most to them
are the same on both platforms they have
the same APIs to have the same behaviors
and so we could use them in both places
if you're if you read some core data
code
10 from the same on both sides there are
some very much the however that aren't
the same on both sides
if you're using Qt kit now will compile
and I less it's just not supported we
recommend you try it eighty foundation
and and not an important thing to note
is that acted and you like it
well they serve the same purpose in your
code are not the same framework
have many similar API you can use them
in many similar ways
but you should treat them as separate
objects in your own architecture
and handle them accordingly we'll to
this list
we we thought that we could use
coronation core graphics to have
more shared rendering code not right now
we have non rendering coach shared
and it really like to have some comic
code their
coronation as useful because it has
these things called CA layers
CA layers are used to put content on
screen and make them
and they behave exactly the same on both
platforms and that's really helpful for
us
core graphics is is good for more dense
graphics operations you can build
content with core graphics that you
can't build
coronation alone take that content and
put it into corn mission there
to get it on screen animated there are
some caveats
core graphics contact I in you I've used
in
an excuse our foot relative to each
other in the y axis
the origin for you I views on the upper
left and for an issues on the lower left
and you know that makes our math more
complicated but you can fix this
by overriding is flipped on an issue
and that makes are origins in the same
location in both places
and this is really helpful for us not to
share our views but instead to have
shared rendering code
it doesn't need to worry about that
extra flip while we're calculating
where things should appear on screen
and the Wii U score animation core
graphics to build
are layer tree elaire tree for our the
eye which campus
the I work and this is this part here
it's the its actual user content that
they interact with on screen
and the code that renders that can this
is exactly the same on
I'm on both platforms we his coronation
call graphics
have the same rendering code in both
places so we can make sure that the
user's content will look the same
now because coronation core graphics
our platform specific for are not
platform-specific rather
we're losing a platform-specific support
that we could get using
views so you know on i OS if you have
your content you have a charge that's in
its own view
you could put a gesture on that if you
directly to turn it to interact with
just that
that chart however that charted in just
a layer
you can't directly target gesture to a
layer
you have to add an extra layer up
support to handle the platform specific
aspect
that rendering system so there are some
downsides to this but we found it was
very helpful for us and I work
so now we have a little better shared
new code but that you could was very
carefully crafted to have
a stronger user experience and and more
unified rendering situation
but there's one last ep we that we
needed before we can actually get that
picture
100 logic to compile
we ship we're under a lot of images and
you have NSA wrench
on August 10 and UI image on I'll ass
and they're both really fantastic and
really helpful objects do some
really powerful things trust to help you
know memory management and caching they
get
information on your bundle and we don't
really want to reproduce that logic
ourselves
but we also don't want our shared
rendering go to have to care which one
is talking to you
for us all we really wanted from our
images was the ability to get a CG image
out for me image order under that image
directly into a core graphics context
and because those behaviors are pretty
simple we bill will be calling image rap
an image rappers away for the calling
code not care about the platform
specific issues are the rent or the
implementation details
you you define a sieve a simple API and
implemented
twice 14 each subclass thats
private internal for class costs or so
we have a
my image superclass thats abstract
superclass
and a platform specific implementation
that talks either directly to an NS
image
or directly to our you eye image and
translator API
based on how he did that work and this
is really helpful because we're not
losing the power
%uh NS imagine you I image all their
great features were still got to use
for our shared code doesn't have to
worry about which one is actually
getting use
when it's calling the code
now not hear that we're gonna have to
translate your API calls directly
ourselves in our upper layer and that
means that
you know rappers are really useful for
simpler objects like images
but it harder to wrap things like new
controllers which are very complicated
and powerful
and behave a little you know there's
enough different behaviors
that trying to translate them all
yourself would be rather difficult so we
can rappers are
most useful for simple objects
so now we have our application compiling
and running on both platforms
we have shared rendering systems or are
our content should look the same in both
places
and one other designers made a a Dec and
they put this image in
and they open on the Mac looks like this
but then they opened it on the iPad and
the image
looked funny it the colors were off and
sent
we really wanted our content look the
same that was part the point of having
assured rendering system
me you know scratch our heads and but
for a while
and we realize that the problem was that
the image that that we had use
had a CMYK color profile for those of
you unfamiliar with car models
CMYK cyan magenta yellow black
which are it's designed to best use for
printers at those are the
the standard printer ink colors and so
computers don't you know your pixels
your pixels on your screen rather than
than Inc and so a lot of RU our content
on computers as
is made with the RGB or red green blue
collar model
and there are other color models out in
the world and so you know there's a lot
of different ways you can specify colors
in the universe
but I left devices do the best job
rendering
sRGB content which is particular kind of
RGB
and so we found that you know any image
that was it sRGB was probably look a
little bit different
when you open on an eyelash device I
wouldn't want that to happen
so what we did it which all over content
that what already sRGB
and converted sRGB when the user
inserted it into our documents
and so that was ok and that way R are
content to look the same on both
platforms
so this is you know if you wanna learn
more about core management in general
there's a a session you can you can see
on mine best practices for color
management
there's also a lab right after the stop
downstairs at 10:15
so now we have arm itches looking the
same on both platforms
so now we can opener our documents milk
the same for real this time on both
platforms
on but we built a large document with
lost images we're testing out this
behavior
I me notice that it took a while to open
the documents when they got there gonna
and and we figured you know OS 10
devices have
a lot of resources available to us we
should be able to to make this a better
user experience in
and be faster sore what are the
different resources we have available to
us
well there's personal between I lesson
OS 10
there are different chips that are
actually reading your hardware and
that's gonna you know those
those will affect how the hardware
behave other performance will be
slightly different
things are can be faster on one platform
or the other
also the memory bandwidth available to
use different based on the device upon
which running
the total ran you have available has
also been a very and
and the exact media that support will be
different again based on the chips
and so this you know the combination of
these factors would have slightly
different performance profiled
depending on both platform running on
also the specific hardware
and so we want optimize you know various
parts of our applications
per platform in the case have opening
the document
slowly and we want to get quickly we
mail easily loaded model
different parts of our our documents you
each slide in Keynote
is a self-contained unit it doesn't need
to reference things on other sides
immediately when you open them
and so far have a three hundred 5.2 Dec
animal looking at the first 10 slides on
my screen I don't need to read the third
300 slide from desk
so we're only gonna read the parts of
the model the user's
actually looking at and what they
actually need interact with
and also we can load each of those in
parallel
because again they are referencing each
other and these things combine will give
us a faster
experience opening a document because
real estate a and we're doing your bit
at the same time
and again this was an optimization for
you know multi-core
male the more cores we have the more
parallel reading would help us
and to this was kinda targeted for a
West End specifically we also had other
optimizations and I less
but you know this is just to give you an
example of the kind of things you want
to do
while building your applications for
each platform
so now we have you know our documents we
have a model that we had became played
begin loading Lisa Ling and in parallel
what actually
in our model what's in our documents
one thing to keep in mind is that your
users not going to update
all your applications at exactly the
same time they're gonna be running
different versions
on different devices at the same time
and your own fortune just you know this
is a fact of life know how to deal with
this
and so you note the most fundamental
first step if this is you need to
version your data
you know for a fact what version of your
application actually built this document
so that if you change how your motto is
written to disk you can handle that
appropriately set the first important
step
however you can't do something a little
bit more interesting than that
just inside a bit version it purely on
the application version:
you can version based on the features in
the document
so if I have a version of keynote that
has some great features and and kind of
things we write
to disk and we Updater application mad
a chart feature so that our chart model
will be different but everything else is
exactly the same
if I have a document in my new keynote
and I sent it to somebody who's using
the older version keynote or open it on
but on my own device that during an old
version of keynote and my document
doesn't have a chart in it
that should open ideally you know if
you're not using a new feature
you should still be able to open your
document and that way you have
you're more likely to have your users
have a positive experience if they could
open their documents
as much as possible one real life
example this that you might be more
familiar with
rx coded you can actually say visited
there's two different formats and you
can choose the format based on the
features you actually want to use
an expert will handle that
another thing to keep in mind when
you're building your on disk model
and also help translating into your
memory in memory model
is that you know the way that you store
your application data in memory
if you rearrange that that doesn't
necessarily mean you're going to change
on disk representation they don't need
to look exactly the same
as long as the overall data that you're
stating on this key is the same
and you can translate from one to the
other and this way even if you update
how you are in fact handling things in
your application to make your life
easier
trying to change the actual document
model much absolutely hafter
finally if you're working with a
doctrine based application
we recommend you check out the creating
docket based ap session
which is probably online now Friday
so just to summarize what we've been
talking about
when you're trying to share code between
I lesson OS 10 first look at how the
code is actually
use is it used in a way that should be
shared or is it
handling something that should be
platform-specific in which case you
don't necessarily want to share it
also really recognize and embrace that
the platforms do have differences in the
way that users should use them in a way
that you're you I should book
should be different based on the
platform upon which a running
also consider using shared frameworks
when possible which will make your life
easier and
and make it to that allotted your code
doesn't need to be rewritten
her platform and investigate the design
patterns among all new controller
and wraps and again keep in mind that
we're not saying that these examples I'm
giving you are absolutely going to apply
for you in your applications
and what works for us won't necessarily
work for you but these are meant to be
more like universal concept that we're
giving you examples of
rather than universal solution and now
I'm gonna hand it over to Chris
and he's gonna talk about how to set
your Xcode project thank you
thanks Elizabeth so now that we've
learned patterns and technologies
that made sure in code easier for us I'd
love to walk you through how we made
this transition
from Xcode configuration perspective so
as elizabeth was saying earlier
we had 3i wesat that we were very proud
of and we wanted to bring
each back to the Mac I work is a large
code base
so all the things I want to share with
you may not impact you now
and in the event that they do not today
will be all the more prepared
sugar at ever evolved in a direction
similar hours
and since the techniques I'll be sharing
with you
trend for the two all over aP's I'm
going to focus just on what we did with
keynote
because the same overarching principles
applied to both pages
and numbers as well the first
small yet pivotal step to moving keynote
to the Mac
was to create a new Mac target for the
half so
what the target a target contains
instructions for building a single
product
the most common type a target as an
application target which builds perhaps
for this also unit test targets among
many others
targets also organized everything that
gets passed into Xcode built
which is Xcode build system and lastly
targets
our part a project it's pretty easy to
add the Mac target to the current IRS
project
all we need to do is click on the
project in the navigator on the left
hand side
and click on the plus button on the
bottom then
we select the Cocoa application template
from the West End category
we give it with the name something
profound in this case
keynote for Mac and we press Finish
and what we've accomplished the first
fundamental step we now have two
application targets
one for the keynote for IRS and one for
the Mac
so right now it doesn't do anything too
fancy
we press building run we see something
that looks like this
and this is a course a far cry from the
keynote experience
the reason for this because we haven't
added any functionality to our Mac
target yet
so let's take a look what functionality
there is available to add
luckily for us with a fair number up
subsystems
ever want to take advantage of for Mac
application one example
is the I work and this which is
Elizabeth for sharing with us earlier
being able to use the scene Candice and
oliver aP's
is incredibly important to us because we
want all over documents
to look the same across all the devices
that we support
we also want to make sure that our file
format and model is the same for both I
with Kanye West End versions are perhaps
so we would want to point our common
persistence framework as well
we also want to bring over all of our
common utilities
these utilities include mechanisms for
blogging convenience methods common data
types
and many other classes whose
functionality span across our entire
suite
these elements we separated into
libraries
so what the library simply put
it's a bottle collection of coke more
specifically
they are targets in Xcode but they are
not execute a ble
they just exist as a way for you to
share code primarily across projects
to that end we found it didn't make
sense to break code into libraries
unless it was going to be shared by
multiple projects otherwise
we can just add the shared code to both
the IRS and Mac targets for our app
and it's important to note that if you
have a single project
ap this may be all you need to do and
that is absolutely fine
again we feel it's sharing libraries
make sense
as a means to share code across projects
and not necessarily
inside projects and lastly
libraries can be either static for
dynamic so
what does that mean all static libraries
are built with the project whenever any
other targets reference them
and there included as part of the final
ap
that you build think ima libraries can
be external to the project
and this makes unfavorable for a few
reasons first
once you build them you don't need to
build them again until you change them
and second they can be put in a shared
location and not rolled into the final
application you build
which makes your application smaller
a concrete example a dynamic library as
a framework
simply put they're packaged up and
precompiled
dynamic library remarks have just been
brought to Iowa State
if you'd like to learn more about how to
make modern frameworks I encourage you
to look at that building modern
frameworks talk video
available on Apple developer website
so we currently have a free market cap
sending functionality shared across
I'll I work for I was aP's and let's see
what happens
may try to extend are shared app
framework to work with OS 10
as well as Iowa
so here's the I work shared Xcode
project are going to add a new framework
target
just like we did earlier by pressing the
plus button on the bottom
we slept Cocoa framework we click Next
again we give it a name the press Finish
and again we have a new target the first
part of the battle
as one let's roll up our sleeves
break out the sledgehammer and create a
new common group
an Xcode let's talk about what sort of
things we might want to put
in this common group we currently have a
class and i OS that represent the
document
and its platform specific because it
extends you I document
you a document does not exist in our 10
so we'll need to introduce a new Mac
document
extend something else as a basis for a
document functionality
luckily for us and this document as
everything we need to read
update and savor documents
that said we'd like all callers are a
model to be as agnostic as the platform
as possible
don't want to expose a common interface
between both documents
and this we can express and shared
interface called I work document
this interface to convey clear comment
behavior shared across both
I West and the Mac let's take a look
and what I work document might look like
here's the shared I work document
interface declares methods for treating
saving and updating objects in a
document
and then we can create a Mac and its
document subclass
and the clear conformance to the shared
interface we just created
and then we implement the required
methods as declared in the interface
now let's dive into the project itself
bear with me
I know this is going to be a little
tedious which is actually part of our
point
I'll show you how to leader make this
easier to manage we wanna show you
what's happening under the hood
fourth so what there's one thing we need
to do to I work shared project before we
move on to the Keno project
and very important that we do so but
click on
I were captured Mac target in the middle
sidebar and double-click on the public
headers folder path option
a popover appears but to move within
their already
and give it a name this name is the
first part that goes
after our import exploration and before
the flash in class is that import logic
from this remark
okay now we're ready to go back to keno
and use this new
Mac document object
so open up my document window controller
in the header for the keynote for Mac
project
at the import exploration i press build
and it fails what happened
I thought I just to clear the I work
sugar I were shared her former pastor
well we still need to tell the Mac
target to look at the place we just said
we're going to deposit the headers to
navigate to the header search path
section
the Mac build settings we double click
on the item
a popover appears we type dollar sign
parenthesis
configuration builder and for intensive
and then we hit enter this stealth tax
code that when we're building keynote
for the Mac
they should look in the headers
directory where things are built
which in this case is the location and
the shared framework
then we dismiss the popover and now the
keynote Mac target knows how to look for
the shared Mac library headers
so I start putting my implementation and
then
try to build it again and get a bunch of
linker errors
thanks so what happened here is that I
didn't link the Mac
ap target with the library nor they list
the library is a dependency
so that's why it failed but fix that
so go back to the keynote for Mac
targeting the keynote project I click on
the bill faces tab
expanded disclosure triangle next to
target dependencies
a click the plus button reflect our
library
i press add note that if you're not
seeing the library is an option
you'll need to drag in the project
owning a library into your containing ap
project
are shared library now shows up as a
dependency this means that before we
build the keynote for Mac target
exco to make sure the library is built
first
next we need to link at binary with the
framework
to do this we click on the disclosure
triangle next to the each link binary
with library section
and click on the plus
reflector framework we press add and
then it shows up
then when we try to build and run it
works
for now keynote for Mac is building on
top of the shared Mac remark
and it's not too hard too extreme and
extending the same process
to other frameworks and libraries used
by keynote as well
to combine with extending our shared
framework to be Mac friendly
we also need to create max this abuse in
view controllers
that use the three marks to produce the
keynote experience on the Mac
with a bit I'm elbow grease a hand
weaving a wonderful thing happened
we have a fully functioning Mac ap
so at a high level one can now imagine a
project looking something like this
we have Xcode project for pages Numbers
and Keynote
and each project has a Mac and I went to
Target
these targets build on top of at
specific libraries
which in turn bill on top of the
cross-platform canvas
persistence and shared core utilities
frameworks
wow this is great or not quite out of
the woods yet
one big problem as I build settings are
somewhat disorganized
remember how we manually set the header
search for and Aquino Mac target
and the same thing with the public
header search path
so present each targeted own build
things associated with it
while this works everyone should change
the building somewhere
we need to change it for every target in
the project and only did
to trust myself to make that change
everywhere consistently
how we fix this as a Xcode config files
and they look like this they simply
contain a title
and a value each line control something
specific about your build process
you can customize every aspect of your
build here
some common examples the properties you
can set our header search paths
which dictate the directories in the
filesystem Xcode should use for finding
public headers
compiler warnings or what sorts a
potential bugs in the code you'd like
exco to tell you about
architecture which defines the type that
CPU your target can build
St case which define a platform and
version at the STK
the target you should you'd like to use
and employment targets
which declared the minimum version I
West End I O S
a user needs to have in order to build
and run your app
these are a few examples a popular
properties than many other remain
and for the fullest you can look at for
configuring exco configuration files
please refer to the Xcode build settings
reference
available on Apple's developer website
the real advantage exco config files is
that you can use inheritance
in other words you can create a common
Xcode config file for II West and Mac
and then have an extent a common one
and a common file would place build
settings that apply to your whole
project
and a platform specific configuration
files you would add directives that are
specific to be there I West
or the Mac an under-strength affects
could convict files
is that they can be reused across
projects in other words
you can read it I was configured file
for numbers pages and Keynote
and then have all other I was aP's use
the same
II West config so let's create an Xcode
config file for Mac target
and implement it together to create an
ex-convict file
we select File new from the Xcode main
menu
with like the configuration settings
file and press Next
we give a name in this case Mac
and for starters with associate it with
the keynote Mac target
you click Finish and now we have a exco
configs file for the Mac
but this conflict file does not know but
the common configuration is building on
top at the
to accomplish this we simply add pound
include to this child
in Fig followed by the name XE can fix
file we'd like to extend
and of course we later at any Mac
specific settings that we care about
once we've done that we can associate or
target with these configurations using
the project editor
will still need to set this up for each
target in each project
after we set this up we never may never
need to touch build things
each target ever again so let's try for
the keynote project
we can do this by expanding the
configurations disclosure triangle
and then for every configuration setting
the appropriate can fix file
and we can verify the defending the
American think files propagated to the
target
we take a closer look at their bill
thanks
and here's what's provided by the Mac
Xcode config file
for example we can see here that we're
building against the latest
West End STK as opposed to the current
STK
we can also see the configs file had an
impact and the supported platforms
and ballot architectures at the Mac
target as well
so now we have a sustainable highly
customizable
bill process and a great native Kenya
experience
running on the Mac and as such our work
is done here
so take a step back and review we
accomplish together this morning
meet a target for each platform that we
wanted to support
me broke some other functionality across
multiple projects and platforms into
reusable frameworks
we told at Target Harry use the shared
frameworks
and we streamlined our bill
configuration across every one of our
targets
using Xcode config files
so while there's no silver bullet as
elizabeth mentioned earlier
we found the design principles and Xcode
project configuration we shared with you
this morning
to be incredibly helpful to us and we
can only hope
the find the ideas we shared with you as
hell useful to you as they were too of
also we compiled a simple project called
photo memories
which exercises and up a cross-platform
concept and exco configurations
mentioned in this talk
the sample code is available on Apple's
developer website
and explains how to implement similar
patterns and practices week
talk about today in even deeper detail
if you're interested in learning more
about cross-platform applications
there is no shortage other sessions per
ticket deep died
and a similar topics we touched on this
morning and if you're interested
all the session presentation videos and
demo materials will be available
Apple's developer website and finally
if you have any questions about what you
for today please don't hesitate to
contact check their hands
or deep too long or consult the
developer forms
at their forums Apple dot com
and with that we wish you the best of
luck in your cross-platform application
adventures
and enjoy the rest your time in San
Francisco thank you very much