thank you
I my cats I'm a software engineer on the
I was absent frameworks team
I'm here with you have a sport min to
talk to you about building great cloud
documents based applications
so area made from Port important changed
I club
first the I clarke david has been
completely rewritten on top quark it
work all year I Cloud Drive if you're
interested in
warning more about clark et I encourage
you to attend their sessions in labs
second we've added Windows support I
cloud now users with Windows devices
can access and modify it their documents
on their windows devices
third we've got and I cloud folder in
the Finder
now users can add whatever documents
they want into their iPod folder in
Finder
and organize them however they see fit
for
we've added access to the I card folder
from within your I Lesseps will get into
this one or more later
were really cover here today we're gonna
start by talking about some the best
practices
%uh access your documents mccloud then
we're gonna move on to talking about how
to discover enlist your documents
mccloud
next year to talk about displaying
thumbnails near you I when your listing
your documents in the cloud
every talk about accessing documents
from outside if you're out container
such as the shared iPod folder
and finally we're gonna talk about
providing document storage to other
applications from within your app
so what is a document anyways word and
find a document here
as a single stand-alone entity and its
understood by the user as a single
stand-alone entity
are you might want to modify it or give
a name that's meaningful to them
or send it via email 21 their friends or
colleagues
there some documents which we all sorta
under standard documents
Aquino document or numbers document or
Pages document
are clearly documents but we're also
going to consider something like
a chess game to be a document for this
presentation
a user might want to save the current
state of their chess game
and e-mail alert when their friends they
can pick up where they left off
again some hard AI level so we consider
a chess game to be a document now talk
about dealing with your document from
the cloud
so it's important when you're dealing
with your doctor to the cloud to use
file coordination
there are several reasons for this but
when the main ones
is to avoid data loss you may have the
simplest single-threaded applications in
the world
but and you may think that you're the
only one reading from
or writing to your documents but once
you add the icon David into the mix
that's no longer the case so use file
coordination
let's take a quick example this say
you're a
is doing proper file coordination you're
right you're changes to this
the I Cloud Drive Damon will pick up
those changes
and push them up to the cloud and out to
all the other users devices
everything's working properly here
that's what you want to have happen
now it's a you're not using proper file
coordination
you may be right in your changes to desk
but I Cloud Drive may also be riding
changes at the same time
for that same document this could result
in a corrupt document
which the I car drive David will again
push up to the cloud
and down to the other users devices
which results and data loss
everywhere so use file coordination is
very important there's good news though
you I document makes things simple you I
document
and and this document on OS 10 does all
the heavy lifting for you
it takes care of I'll coordination it
also uses background cues to prevent the
power cord nation
from blocking your app's you are and UI
docket provide you with several
high-level API
for whatever use case you might have
let's take a quick example
like really a document from this with
you I document
so the highest level you I document does
all about coordination for you
and in addition Rieger document from
this if you document is a file
you can and its data object which is the
contents of your file on disk
at the document the package you can and
its file wrapper object which represents
your package on disk
you just have to override the load from
cart into tight method
and then display the content to the
document to your users
at a slightly lower level
you I documents on this all about
coordination for you
but this time you wouldn't NS URL back
which is the location of your document
on desk
you then just have to you read the
document and displayed to users
at the lowest level we've been option
that's really provided only for hooking
if you override the open with completion
handler method
you should really invoke super and admit
when the other two methods
you can override this method though if
you want some custom application
behavior when you I document
would be doing the park ordination to
read the document from this
new and I would say
we have some a synchronous file
coordination API's
so the existing power cord nation API's
were completely synchronous that means
you have to do your own background
queuing to
prevent you Powercore nation from
blocking your a
I can be a little bit tricky to do so we
have some new Pop Warner
coordinator API for a synchronous file
coordination
which is the court may access with
intense method
we also have a new course pond in class
which is the s file access in 10 test
file
accident and class which essentially
just contains
a URL and some options for your intent
coordination
you pass these in an array to the corny
axis
with intense method to do your part
formation operations
let's take a quick look at that and some
simple code so this code
might be if I want to copy a document
from one location to another
as you can see I allocate
a source in 10 to read the document
where it currently
exist on desk and then allocate a
destination in 10
for the location that I want to copy the
document to
I pass these to the
popcorn and a method of corny access
with intense
and at some point in the future my
access for block
will be called on the Q I provide I then
just have to do my operation in my
access to block
now it's important when you do your
operation in your access for block
to use the URL Center attached to the
end its file
access intense because they may have
changed
while you're waiting for your
coordination now let's move on to
discovering enlisting your documents
mccloud
the way to discover unless your
documents in the cloud
is there the existing and its many data
query API's
now in previous version of the OS
and its meta data query has been slow to
pick up
your local changes like creates deletes
and remains think a quick look at this
let's say you have your app
you pick up a document in your apt
container you also have a couple and its
minute items
from your and its mandate a query which
correspond to those documents on desk
now let's say you're up create a new
document on disk
there might be a longer way before
and its mandate inquiry updates and
gives you a new and its mandate item
corresponding to that newly created
local document new and I would say
s meta data query is easier to use
directly with stitching
let's take a look at that now it's a
your app creates this new document on
disk and is using proper file
coordination this only works
if you create a document using proper
power cord nation we actually have a
hook
in your file coordination access which
will
update the end it's men today the query
quickly and automatically
to create and new and expanded item to
update your app
that means that you no longer need to
data sources
to show your app's you I want from local
changes in 14
for cloud changes you just need and this
man did a degree
like
also and its mandate a query Canwest
non-local documents you may want to
display some file system attributes
about those documents though
to display in your UI when your listing
your documents
we have a new an issue early P API for
you
which will let you get file system
attributes about those documents which
may or may not have their content
available locally
the way to do this as with the MSU are
all method get promised item resource
value for key
if you want more than one but also to
match be we also have a book method
which is the problem
item resource values for key for Keith
you don't need to be under File
coordination
when using these methods for listing
your documents
I'll also week if you are under par
coordination
we had some new popcorn maker flag for
dealing with me today to
the key difference with these methods is
that the content with these
plaques the past your popcorn enter is
that the content of the documents does
not need to be available locally
when you're doing file coordination
using these plaques
now let's move on to document thumbnail
so we think the best user experience
when your listing your documents in your
app
is to show document previews this can
sure user more context
so that they can quickly identify which
document is meaningful to them
at that point in time as you can see
in this page is ap we have document
previews
which let your user quickly identify
which documents which
now is possible to show doctor previous
previously
but it required a custom implementation
new and I would say we have some new
file system attributes
keys for you to display thumbnails and
you're a
the main way to do this is with the MSU
RL thumbnail dictionary key
if you call this are on your document
using the Get promised I'd resource
value for key method
you'll get a dictionary which contains
your thumbnails
which you can display in Europe you I
the only key in this dictionary right
now
is the NS thumbnail 1024 by 1024 size
key
which corresponds to the UI and edge or
NS image
which you can then just displaying your
UI
now on to saving document that males so
the easiest way to save time else
is for you I document if you override
the file attributes the right URL per se
but operation method
and have it generate a you I am age
which is your time now and return it you
I document will automatically
right the thumbnail to disk for you then
the I car drive Damon will go ahead and
pick up those changes
and push them up to the cloud
alternatively
if you're not using you I document you
can save your thumbnails manually
using the existing and its you're all
set resource value for key method
but you should really be under File
coordination when you invoke this method
on OS 10 thumbnail for actually
generated for you automatically
however if you have a custom document
format
you'll need to let quick work know how
to
display thumbnails for you document
still need a quick look plugin
to generate your time else
now let's move on to discovering
documents outside your app's container
now in previous person US it's been
difficult for users to access documents
outside if your app's container from
within your app
take a look at how they might do this
previously
let's say if your app you have direct
access to all the documents you're out
scant
container there's no problem there but
let's say
your user wants to open say document 3
from within your app how might they go
about doing this
or one where they might do this as they
would have to watch
the other app then using the UI document
interaction controller
make a copy of the document from the
other apps container
into your app's local container only
then
could they read the document from within
your app
we think a better user experience is if
you're out can just
access those documents from the other
apps container directly
so prob rap again if you just open those
documents directly
the users happy so we think that's a
better user experience
knew it I was a there's a way to do this
with the UI document picker view
controller
this allows your users to discover
documents outside your apt sandbox
and let your users grants your app
permission to access and modify
the documents that they have chosen
now to have your to have your app's
container show up
in the document picker you have to often
by marking your container with a and its
ubiquitous container is documents go
public
to be yes in your info pls
I have a great New York I with great new
UI here
which you can display in your apt 3
users to choose documents
and like to show you that now with a
quick demo aka
go ahead and launch Maya them yeah at
Harvard it's a simple text editing at
so as you can see I'm using an ass man
idk wat u less
only one document my container right now
but I'm you see as many
inquiry without power cord nation to
list my documents and display a
quick simple preview of the documents
now let's go ahead and launch up the
docking picker
so this is our new doctrine picker you I
as you see there several containers
listed here and also have
a document which lives in the shared
icon folder
which is listed alongside my containers
now i cant switch to list view here
there's much stuff I can do
sort by name tags state X enter a
and what now let's go ahead and might
roll down this text edit container
and select a document ecstatic container
I had so now I am open the document
which actually lives
in the text in a container I have not
made a copy of this document
stock it still exists in the Tech Center
container but now that
I it's the user granted my app access to
it I can
and a and access it in the Tech Center
container
let's go ahead and X out in this as you
can see
now that I'm granted my app access to
this document
it is now as now updated in the end its
mandate a query
and I have I can list it alongside the
other documents
in my app I've also annotated a if you
can see with a text editor name just to
tell my user that lives
in the text edit container let's take a
quick look at this
encode
so this is basically all the code I had
to write to
display the doc can pick your all app to
do
is allocate the document menu view
controller
and pass it an array of the document
types than interested in
I'm a simple text editing app so I only
pass the plaintext UTI
as the documents at my apt can access
I then just present the view controller
and then implement these two simple
delegate methods
and finally when the document when the
user pics a document given URL
I just loaded and displayed to users
it's super simple
now if you noticed my app did not
actually show up
in the document picker that's because I
haven't set
my my eye container to be a public
container yet
a second just a quick look at how to do
that
so if I open up my in populist here
job and into this as you can see applied
document scope is set to be not public
all I have to do is set this TS
and then bomb the bundled version so
that
so that the doctor picker knows that I
have made a change to my info key west
and then my app will be will be
displayed in the document picker
so that other Afghan get access to my
documents
arts quick summary wish I knew how
easy it is to display that document
picker
inside your apt and how easy it is for
users to
Greg chura access to documents and other
APs containers
such as the shared I cardholder
we also show you how it is to make your
container show up in the UI docking
picker
just by sending your flag to be yes and
then bumping your bundle version
with that I would like to welcome you
had a sport men to the stage
was going to talk to you about from the
key principles
behind the document picker please
welcome you and it's the stage
thank you Mike hymie honors from the you
like a team
and I would like to talk to you about
I'm some of the
main I differences I have between at
external documents and documents that
may live in your container
as you know replication right now
has I access to its own container only
so your you're able to read and write
the documents inside your own container
and as you have seen in Mike's
demonstration I'm not for other
documents
what we do is at once the user has
chosen this document
I we save a so-called document reference
into your container stock and reference
well then go and point to your I'm
external document to ease this
this new concept in to your application
we provide
few new features and attributes on the N
is made it a query
you are using probably using the
animated aquarium with the ubiquitous
documents cope right now
to list the documents that are inside
your container locally
and even if the user has granted your
application access to a document
at outside of your container even if if
he has granted to your application
access to
document outside of of your container
will still continue to
million this documents that our local to
your container as long as you don't pass
a new skull
which is the ubiquitous external
documents go
the ubiquitous external documents cobe
ensures that you get an animated item
that corresponds to the hi references
that that
his res extended to at your application
container
now these new and admitted items are
effectively just like the old ones they
also have an animated items URL key
and this and admitted items you're out
he well
point to om
this animated items you are a key
wellpoint to
the and you're out that your document is
actually located at
that means that if your app is using the
animated item iraqi right now
to access a file directly that will
still work even with the document
reference
the you can pack past the return value
of getting this key
directly to for example a UI document
and
huge that as your I'll to directly
access to
at external document now of course
sometimes that is not actually what you
want to do sometimes that you're
interested in is not the
actual document backing this this a
reference
but rather the reference itself
for example you may want to display the
reference inside a folder in your
applications container and your UI
aren't you might even want to allow the
user to move these references around
inside their folder
on for that we provide Nucci and this
one is
actually knew nice at a on the
ubiquitous item your own local container
this key points the actual reference
inside your applications contain
such you can use this the file that is
at this location
to move it around now
there are few other keys it may be
useful for you to know whether a file
at that has been returned by Ginn
admitted a query is actually external to
replication or not
at sorry to your applications contain a
and for that
you provide is external document key
which will return ol for local documents
and
yes for external documents and if you've
seen at Mikes demo
he showed a little bad shore that text
label 2i in from the user that the
document that he's shown that
popped in there was actually from not
from the local content over other front
exit
and to enable you to do that we have to
contain a display name she
attend container display name he's a
localized key that
I'm is fit for display das and
up for example would in if you if you
extended
a document front exit it would show
takes its name
alright so we've got these document
references spot
why did he even ET's so
the main reason is for security
om we do not generally allow any app
to access any other APs container
on the document pickers they can do that
the document pickers running out of
process so this
its it's not on I it is able
that has the sufficient title man's to
be able to list all of the
document containers and the only way to
get a
document inside of your application St
Houston
document picture had to that
for that purpose we return a so-called
security school Purell
and he fused sandboxing mechanism on
August 10
you may already know this concept of a
security Scott URL
on you get you an issue row which has a
tiny bit of information attached to it
that informs the kernel and of course
the the owning ap
that arm in fact the owning ap is
allowed to access this document and is
allowed to
for example my hiatus while on
now importantly arm if you
naively which if it were to save this
URL
for example you would see realize it
into a string and thence DC realize it
into out of the strain you would lose
dis
security skull and that is not something
you wanted happen
because of course security Scopus what
you use to access this URL
of course you need a way to get back to
this cock your row
and arm that document references feature
is providing one of the ways to get back
to the issue or else
if you get your Ennis & Ennis URL from
but he document reference
this and if you're already has the
security scope attached
you can't use it with you i document or
with
started testing and stop accessing
secure disk ok resource
methods on an issue row but I strongly
suggest that you use your document
because that does it every
that does all of this for you I'm to
for example of the contents of
file backed by this year
now sometimes enumerating your document
is not actually what you want to get
back to the documents
for example at one thing you might be
using estate restoration
and its state restoration of course what
you want to do is pop the user back
into the UI that they saw before so
you instead of enumerating files that
the year at she access previously
what you want to do is access have very
specific file
arm we offer a mechanism to do that for
you
I'm which is a bookmark the bookmarks
also possibly known to you if you've
used it
on with the sandbox a nice tan I'm
and the bookmark encodes the security
scope alongside the URL
so he can use the bookmark to get back
to the Securities cultural
I am we offer
API which already exists I'm
add to bookmark data with options
API is used for by huge on an issue or
Allen stands to create it bookmark that
you can then see
it's an basically an opaque in a state a
blob I'm that you can then save into a
state restoration archive for example
and of course the comp its counterpart
is a class method on
an issue RL that you're all by resolving
bookmarked it out which we
week and then Hughes to resolve this
bookmark into an issue I'll that has the
scope attached
all right om now
Mike showed you the enjoy da can pick
your view controller in
the so-called open now and I'm
at an open mold what we will do is
indeed
trade a bookmark and a corresponding
security Scott URL
hand you back the Securities Co Purell
and of course place the bookmark ref are
the reference document inside Europe's
container
now sometimes that is not what you want
to do you actually on for example you
may have an application that does not
instead of opening specific documents
may also
I'm aggregate documents keynote for
example would be one of these
applications
I in which hugh for example might want
to open in image from an application to
inserted into your presentation you
don't want to maintain a persistent
references that image but instead you
want to copy this
image into your presentation as
as one piece and we also support a mod
for that it's the so-called
important note: import mode will not
create a bookmark
but instead I'm will copy the file
to a temporary location you of course
still be granted access to this
temporary location
but on the file is not persistently
reference by replication
after the application terminates for any
reason I'm
we will clean out the temporary location
and you will no longer have access
soul you have to make a copy soon after
a decade and I get called back to
actually hang on to the document
alright this is reading documents and
that is
of course a very important part but
equally as important as a possible
writing documents in treating you
documents
now as i've mentioned you will not have
general access to containers
outside of at your app's own container
I but of course you can ride into that
container so
or possibly in Tampa into a temporary
location so to create in your document
that is exactly and sorry and you
document a
on disk at that is exactly what you want
to do
I'm you can then shoes a special
document picture mode
to move that document outside of
Europe's container but again the user
chooses where to move the document
I let's have a quick look at how that
works he would
at of course you already have a document
top three in this case
and use the unit with you are all method
on your document picker
with your the URL of your existing
document
to allow the user to choose I'll new
location
these are now choosing the location and
remove the file
into the new location we really try n
document reference to you so you still
maintain
access to the document and this URL
is effectively exactly like one that has
been returned to you by
the opening mechanism so I'm you can
I enumerate this new document reference
in your animated
query now of course sometimes
that is exactly not what you want you
don't want the reference
I'm so we also have a an export mode
which allows you to forgo the entire
reference thing
and that case you will make a copy of
your document I'm
into another apt container and
that is basically it k to me
give a quick summary of how to use
document management here
I'm the scene that you can choose Add
the document reference mechanism to
enumerate documents
that have been previously I used by our
are granted access by the user we've
also seen that you can use bookmarks a
state restoration
and we've also yeah I shown you I
quickly how to use the import open an ex
parte and move mouse
and all of these of course I'm play
together
to enable your user success all of their
I thought documents not merely does that
are inside your folder
but you notice I said all of your iPod
documents here
and of course I jazz users
may have at different locations for
storing their documents
for example you may be are part of an
enterprise that has their own storage
management system
and of course it would be grand if you
could tag ranchers users access to
those documents as well and for that we
are introducing a new feature
the so-called document provider
extensions
now what is a document provider
extension
document provider extension is an
alternate way for
you are a third party to provide
document storage
from the host applications perspective
this works exactly the same way as the
pre-existing I
health storage location and here is able
to
I select one of the searched locations
from the document picker
and they could use these storage
locations
in the Dec same old story they can open
documents
and I'm move out documents to the
storage locations
on we implement these using to I
different
separate extensions first of which
is the so-called I'm document picker
extension which provides the you a few
controls have class
that is effectively free-form that the
user can at
to use to choose a document from your
storage location
are from of course from someone at the
search locations this year document
picker subclass
is displayed as part of the docking
picker view controller
so it effectively contained inside one
of the few controllers just like
at the I cloud baker s there's also a
separate second extension
which is the so-called high provider
extension the 500's tension
is in on you I extension which deals
with
actually providing the files that would
be a
the usually use cases where you want to
provide files
is I'm would be arm for example ensuring
that a pile on disk is
I current uploading a file that has been
changed by the user
or arm enabling us to identify a file
so the user can savor are the use this
app can take a bookmark prostate
restoration
I'm the hi provider extension is access
to the proper hair extensions modulated
through falcone nation
which means that all access this that go
through FY coronation will automatically
do the right thing
with regards to providing access to the
file this another
important case where you absolutely must
use eye coordination are everything else
everything will just not work
alright let's have a quick look at how
at the dataflow works with
a five-car I dare extension specifically
when reading a file from desk but say
you have a whole stack
and its host at is used by the user who
is trying to to actually open a document
in this case
so the whole stabbed through some July
action is
are calling the interest document types
and not method
on the UI document picker you control or
and now that document picker om what the
user inside the document picker
select a third party
document picker extension yours
I we instantiate you're you're talking
picture extension
and send it to prepare for presentation
and mold call
now this method is called with the mold
that the euro is actually selected
and at this point %eh you want to probe
the
display a view controller that
corresponds to the mod that the user has
chosen for example for the open mode
you would want to display a view
controller and allows the user to
at pick a specific document and of
course for the
move out mode you want to display a view
controller that allows them to select a
location instead of
document all right
I'm the year now goes ahead and Jesus
your UI
to select a document at which point
after these s confront their intentions
and you have to would determine
which for the their location in at the
fight system
you want you saw this document in I'm
can then call the dismissed grant axis
at the granting access to your route map
it on self
what that is jury that document picker
you control a top-class and
I'm I thereby II
in from of about your intention to
actually allow the user to access this
URL
at the document picco will then call the
document picture depict document at URL
method on its delegate to in from the
his rap that their use rest just picked
this document
now with the his rep is probably wanting
to do is to read the document at this
location
it will use the and its high coordinator
methods for example
I'm corn and reading I to mature out and
and from and if I could answer that it
should ensure that the document is
actually present
and s5 accordion her will call out to
your fav provider extension that's your
tiny
on you I extension I with the start
providing I can assure our method
this method takes completion call back
which you can call once
your sure that their item at
this specific location is actually
current
so once you call the completion a call
back on
I II at sorry I want to call the
completion call back
the half I crater 10 that it is now able
to unlock the file
and idk itself can call it successor
rock
and now insider access for block the
user application can use this your
document like it sees fit
for example using data with contents of
your L to
be able to I read the file
let's take a quick look at how as
security and
at persistent had access works for I'm
document providers I'm unlike
the eyecup document provider which saves
the special document reference
inside and I call container the document
provides extensions don't take part in
the document reference mechanism
this is because of course in this
let's say we're in an enterprise setting
our enterprise administration has
decided that
they do not want to use I clout but of
course we still want this
adduction provider extension mechanism
to still work because our enterprise has
grant
has given us an application that I
can be used to access the files on the
enterprises fighter
so it's no good to use I clout in this
case
of course to get back to you document
references
but of course at the bookmark mechanism
will still work
on to that end the fat provider I is
able
or has to be able to resolve are I'm
at resolve and identify our into a file
URL and the other way around
now for security purposes I'm we have
and
isolation layer that saves the state
information about
which application has been granted
access to which
identify robot inside which I provider
and this is also something that out we
use these identifiers for
that some quick look how a bookmark is
created and resolved by
a document provider extension but say we
have at our host ap
and host app is for some reason I'm I
going into the background and us wants
to save its state
it will call the bookmark data options
method on surr
an issue I L will call the process that
and I did firefighter mature our method
on Jeff I provide extension which can
then return
a process that and fire this might be a
database key
or it might be something much simpler:
it depends on the actual
I way that your at
type providers actually accessing files
now at some point it will return the
person that if I would just just just a
free phone and a string
to the NS you're all and an issue I'll
will package that op
and I return it as a the opaque data
blocked that is the book market
this point are his rap can go and saved
its says save
state and for example get terminated in
some way for example the user i reboot
steady fights
now at some point later we the user is
open the opening their app
you doing at his rapid city state
restoration and
in the process of doing this is calling
the URL by resolving bookmark data
on an issue or out we hand yet into fire
back to your fav provider
which can that in in the jar of our item
with process that entire method
and it can then I at resolve this
identifiers into an ass you're out on
this
now soon after we call the provide place
holder at your out method
which you can use to provide a small
place holder
that can be used and I I
correspondence with the at previously
discussed
baguette promised item resource value by
the user app
to really get mad at it out on this file
but what can also do is at this point
legally download the file
I'm we will at least ensure that you
were
are providing a placeholder now
you pass the an issue of the file I that
on this comeback
the an issue of methods can now return
this an issue row
and the host apk and used to get
promised item resource value
to merely meta-data or use five
coordinator API on their
an issue or I'll to access the file
if you're I well no matter what you have
chosen that we will at least call you
to ensure if if the user uses high
coronation this case a lot that the
actual data from this document
to ensure that the file on disk is
current
alright we see how everything works and
how getting back to documents works
let's have a quick look at how writing
files works
in this case at his religious using are
the whole steps using
at pack a nation API to actually read at
right sorry right
I'm data to disk so
I'm it what to iraq coordinated right
to the file inside your story japs
folder the file is now changed inside
just arent chaps folder
at some point very soon after but
importantly to note
not and blocking way so the fact our
nation will have succeeded by this point
we will call the I can change that URL
on your fav provider
at this point your heart provider can go
on for example initiate an opt-out of
this file
or at the very least market as being
dirty and meeting at a lot so you don't
accidentally overwrite it at a later
point
alright arm let's have a quick look at
how that works
what I've done is I've filter very small
sample project
using the template that comes with Xcode
very nice because it provides you with
on
almost everything you need start
used to you target here and you stay
application to extension
template for the document picker and
basically choose a name here and it'll
setup that too with different extensions
inside my project I that's half the two
different extensions
one folder here for the the actual
picker
I'm doing a text snippet picker to go
with at
text display at that Mike showed and
inside this I have a whole bunch of
files
which are basically I law classes to to
display
some sort of picking you lie but the
important part is
my subclass of your document pic
extensions you control here
and insight this subclass important
parts are
the I'm prepare for presentation mode
method
I me make this big so you can see this
and in this presentation mode method
what I want to do is basically display a
arm specific I in this case I'm 90
I'm using a collection to control it to
display a list of documents
and I'm displaying this and
I ins all of my picking actually is not
handled by my
abduction pick up the controller by a
top-class
scorsese's delegates a pattern to to get
back
to my at main class once the his rest
picked up command
the call this this method here
and inside this method all I have to do
is call their dismiss granting access to
your I'll
with the file you're all that I've I
previously written out
now the that document by provider here
is very simple in this case
the interesting method here for for this
demo is the struck providing I can
assure our method
which I implemented to ensure that the
snippet at this URL
its current and call completion handler
let's have a quick look at how that
looks on sheen
alright I've got my my my at Des Moines
appeal which is
basically you since I started from the
template just an empty apt
and said I'm going to pop up the
document picker
and you notice I don't even have any
documents maxluger.com
on pot when I pop up this
document picker menu here I see List
including
at the I called up from picker and my
separate picker
and if I pop up the snippet picker what
if displayed is my snap a pic of U
controller
and I can use that to pic any of these
documents are snippets in here
so when I bikinis with the exact same
sample app that Mike showed you
I'm able to I access these snippets from
my my little touch and perhaps now
when you I shoes the seed one to
I try this out not that this snippet
that the document the key will create
will not show up by default
so you can use though new locations
button and
I'm navigation bar of the iPod docking
picker
has a lot more pop out we can enable the
set the picture
all right switch back to slides
cool summarize the demo we've got an
exco template to get you started at the
document picker
mechanism I'm deduction picker
RR a document provider will
show up right next to the actual picture
if the user installs them
and I we have
also I have sample code available on
the I session home page at that
will enables you to quickly test this
out
the sample code is basically a a little
test app that two-year-old
to be able to display each of the
docking picture modes
cool so that's
document providers and I
that almost complete cessation but I
have a little
bit of information for you to I that
from you how I since we have this new
clout drive mechanism I how that
migration story is how that
I'm on I was 8 users can
either choose to once its once it comes
out
choose to a use the old I thought
auctions mechanism
or to migrate to I thought drive on ice
10 yosemite
we do not provide backwards
compatibility
for be all i cud documents mechanism so
the user has to either choose to migrate
to cloud drive
or date will never at will no longer
receive the updates
across the devices because they can
choose to migrate at a later point at
which point guard upgrades
him after after an account is migrated
to like our drive
on the the devices that are actually
using I call try
will propagate changes between each
other for us. developers
I this iz I important to know because I
even though the I current
she built that you have in your hands
right now arm
is automatically using I car drive I'm
the actual new features and us that you
can
easily te sol says out the new features
that we presented in this
today's presentation way only be
available if user is using my cock dry
so you have to be aware of this
possibility
in case they have not actually chosen to
migrate
alright arm
to summarize arm if you're
just taking one thing away from today
session
it would be that he should use 500
nation for document access
a without using faculty nation that none
of these mechanisms can work
and you will probably the
be at some point experiencing
experiencing data loss
on the machine to view user's which of
course is extremely bad
we've seen how to discover and display
files not only in your own container but
also using the UN document picker
which allows you to access files outside
of your
applications containers and was given a
quick overview
how to use doctrine provide extensions
to
I'm be able to integrate your
on companies storage system into
the whole document access mechanism for
more information
arm I would I liked a guy cue to Dave
too long our
app framework evangelist and also check
barons who is the
like it specific F rembert evangelist
we have some need documentation out
there's a at brand new icon for
developers guide
and we also have guides for the document
picker
and of course also guides for the
extensions
mechanisms wealth at the Apple Developer
farms where
I our developers hang out and will
answer questions
I related sessions
that there was a very nice session on
introducing Cloud kit
if you're interested in the technology
behind
and you like hard drive mechanism the
powers of this
the session is of course not and how the
necessary if you really want to story
documents
because the car kit mechanism is
entirely transparent
from that document storage perspective
we also have s had sessions on creating
extensions for iris a nice 10
and with that com thank you for your
time
and I wish you address of the week and a
nice bash