thanks for coming out this morning and
welcome to another
installment a the US Proview session
here today we talked a few times in
previous years about things related to
event handling in UIScrollView
but we wanna take a little bit more time
to go deeper into
some other details about handling on i
OS how it interacts with you I
ScrollView
how US will you use it and how you can
do interesting things want to know more
about it
in your own aP's so before we get too
much into that
want to take a brief walk down the
history of touch handling in
UIScrollView
so will start out by going all the way
back to the beginning of time
in 2008 with the introduction
up iPhone OS 2.0 and the first public
STK
where US groovy was built entirely on
top of the UI touch API
with touches began moved and didn't
cancelled about
and it was bill in the same way that you
would have written any other bit of code
using
those you i touch API's and had a few
limitations that
all the books were trying to work around
by subclassing UIScrollView an
overriding those such methods
and with difficult to do some of these
things because you didn't necessarily
know how the internals
up the US will be worth of work and
further attempts to add things like
nested soap scrub the support
putting one scroll view inside another
and this was much harder than it
probably should have been
so a year later in 2009
we had a big update to you I ScrollView
that changed
pretty much everything about how it I
look that touches and and use those
touches
and right out of the box it added
support for nesting one scroll view
inside another
so you didn't have to do any of that
work or subclassing I understand the
internals in order to make that happen
and then later that year
we introduce the UN gesture recognizer
API which
really expose the internals of how you I
ScrollView had started doing these
things
and let you add that kind of support and
two other views in your own maps
than in 2010 with
I was 4.0 there's another fairly big up
day with the release of the iPhone 4 and
retina displays
now the interesting thing that happened
here is that because
each dimension up the screen doubled and
pixel density
it meant that there was more per session
that you could get one positioning
elements
now for most things you still position
things on point boundaries
so that you could run across different I
was devices that were either 1x or 2x
but US Grove you added support for
strolling at half-point boundaries
so they could scroll to individual pixel
granularity which give a much much
smoother scrolling experience
year later with IRS 5 we added support
for
exposing those gesture recognizers that
we had previously updated and used
to add these more advanced growing
techniques and a UIScrollView
and what these gestures were exposed it
made it a lot easier to interact with a
ScrollView
in your own aP's so you could do things
like get the pan gesture recognizer and
set up their requirements against it
or do all kinds of things like that and
if you go back to previous year sessions
you can see a number of places where we
talk about how you can do that sort of
thing
so a lot of interesting things became
possible what you had access to the
gesture recognizers themselves
but in 2012 but I was six
there was another fairly large a control
update to you I ScrollView
the added support for resting touches
and so what I mean by this
is that in previous years prior to I O S
six
if you put a finger down on the yuan a
UIScrollView that was the finger this
role he was going to track for scrolling
so he did something like grab an iPad
around the edge in your farm happened to
land on a ScrollView
you would try and throw with another
finger and nothing would happen because
it was tracking that first finger
now with OSX we started looking at all
at the touch is that we're anywhere in
the scroll view
and only paying attention to the ones
that were actually moving at any given
time
so even if you had a touch sitting there
resting and not going anywhere
it didn't prevent you from scrolling and
you could still I interact with other
fingers
so that was a really big and interesting
update and we'll see some way that we
are gonna take advantage about later
today
and finally last year with Iowa seven we
added support for dismissing the
keyboard using UIScrollView
and there's a new property that you may
have noticed was added last year that
lets you
decide whether or not scrolling a
ScrollView and having a finger
intersects the keyboard
will push it down off the screen so over
the years the US ScrollView API has
remained fairly stable
there haven't been a lot of changes in
the API but under the covers
there been a lot of internal touch
handling changes they have added all
sorts of new things that you can do
what you know about how some of these
internals a ScrollView in touch and leon
i less work
so we're gonna take a look at three
areas a touch channeling today
and they're gonna talk about three
things that you can do once you know
about these bits have
touch channeling information so three
techniques
based on three areas a touch handling
knows
takes a touch handling things will talk
about well first off we're going to
start with hit testing
has hit testing is the most fundamental
part handling touches on iowa's
when a finger comes down on the screen
what got hit and what element are you
trying to interact with
to look a little bit more deeply at how
it works and ways that you can
adjust things during head testing to get
interesting behaviors
that will spend some time talking about
you I gesture recognizer lead to
something we talked about many times in
the past in various different sessions
but we have some new interesting ways
that you can use gesture recognizers
along with your scroll views
I will give you some ideas about things
you can do in your app's so we get to
that later today
and then we're going to talk about touch
delivery so the way that touches flow
through the system get delivered to
views interact with gesture recognizers
and how you can take advantage of that
information and other interesting ways
once we get to our three techniques so
how about those three techniques
we're gonna talk about transparent
overlays putting content on top of your
other content
making sure you can still interact with
everything and things don't end up
behaving strangely
we'll talk about dragging while
scrolling with a something that I
actually find pretty exciting and and
because the really cool thing you can do
with really is
so you can have content in your school
view that you interact with
say something that you wanna pick up in
drag around but
often you might wanna vent be able to
continue scrolling with another finger
and I mentioned before that we had this
resting touch support and ideas about
how you can interact with multiple
fingers on a ScrollView so we'll look at
how you can use that information
to add support for dragging content
while also scrolling this role you
and then finally will and by talking
about highlighting objects which
may not seem at first like a really key
part but it
part of the reason it doesn't seem so
key an interesting is because it just
often does the right thing and you don't
think about it and so in places where a
dozen
you end up seeing some jarring effects
and we'll talk about how that happens
and how we can go about fixing it
and look at some internal implementation
ideas that house call the US taken
gesture recognizers
to do interesting things with highlights
so three areas a touch and Ling and
three techniques
book it started with transparent
overlays of course if we're gonna put
things on top of things that's probably
going to involve some sort of
information about the testing
so we'll get into that but before we do
i just want to give you a quick idea of
the kind of thing that I'm talking about
and where we use this sort of technique
and I was ourselves so let's take a look
at the home screen
where we added spotlight and I i seven
up at the top of the screen
you can drag your finger down and pull
spotlight down in from the top of the
screen
believe it or not this is actually done
using a UIScrollView down
its really more of a transparent overlay
ScrollView it doesn't really draw
anything itself
but it's an interesting technique and
we'll take a look at how we can use this
in our own aP's
so before I get too much into the
details of how it works are taking three
slides or anything which could have
elisa come up
and do a demo to show you what we're
gonna build
hi iight
got a little at here that I've started
building and doesn't do very much yet
drive a bunch of dot in a canvas and
and soon we're gonna add support for
dragging them around but for now
the dots highlight I hope you can see
that
in that touches began and the on
highlight in touch is ended and touch is
cancelled
so the first thing that I wanna do here
is added a drawer that you can pull down
over the top by penning anywhere in the
canvas
and and so in order to do that we're
going to need to
add a ScrollView that covers the entire
add
canvas so I'm gonna switch over to the
code
and you can see this is pretty much it
I got a little dot you class that I that
I'm can make a random dot you that the
random color
and I gotta candace you that has 25 got
added to it and there
arranged randomly interview so the first
thing that i'm gonna do
is added a ScrollView and I'm also gonna
how to draw review and what we're gonna
do is take advantage of the new
I API that without an Iowa 8 I you I
visual effects view which allows you to
create blurry content
in your applications and doesn't this
droid gonna cover part of the screen
will get offensive that by making it
blurry so
go ahead and make these guys
so are ScrollView get added to the view
the drawer view is going to be a you a
visual effect view
initialized within a fact and the effect
I want is a dark blur
so I'm going to ask for you I blur
effect affect with style
blur effect I'll dark I need to choose a
frame for my drive you
I'm gonna make it the the with the
screen and 650 points
tall because that looked good when I
tried it out and
I'm gonna add it to this review is the
subjective okay
one more thing we need to do is tell
this groove you how big
its content is so I'm gonna make
a content size which is the the whip the
I
screen but the high I have my bounds
plus the drug use freemen that will get
giveth enough room to scroll that drove
you entirely off the screen
at the top and finally I'm gonna
that starting content of that to make
that up launch
with the drug is called off the screen
so go ahead and run it
rights we've got our dot
and that now if I scroll I get a blurry
drawer cool unfortunately I've broken
touch handling
I'm so if I now scroll that drove away
and I try to tap
on these got and i'm having nothing
happening
so the reason for that might be a parent
if you think about it
I've taken at big screen size US really
wanna come to town on top
so of course it's blocking touch
delivery to the content underneath
I'm touches are going to this role you
not with allowing me to pan
right to fix it what can we do
one thing you might consider doing is
turning of user interaction on this
cruelty that's generally
a pretty good way of getting touches to
pass through a user interface element
that you got in
I'm so let's try that and
ScrollView that you turn action enabled
no run it again
and now excellent touches are now going
to
I dot as they were before but if I try
to scroll
a course nothing happened at so why not
well obviously I'm
disable user interaction on this will be
so it can't scroll
I'm right so that's no good so
the way we can actually fix this at
least the way we're gonna start to pick
that
is to use a technique that Josh tonight
introduced in a session
two years ago I'm on Open GL content and
it works here as well
you can take the scroll use hand gesture
which is exposed as a property that you
can access
and you can move it onto another view
I'm in order to restore panning in a
situation where the screw view isn't
suitable to be being the view that
getting the patches
so we're gonna use that technique here
and we're gonna actually move
the just the pet the scroll use pen just
recognizer
onto the my view controller's view
so on to the school you super view I'm
this way
the scroll you can can continue to have
its user interaction disabled
but the panning will be restored
so it got touches going to the dot
and now I also have pending working so
now kinda starting to look like we've
got this overlay behavior the way we
want it
and let me go ahead and add some
additional dots in a drawer
and cuz need something in the drawer
so I'm gonna say add twenty dots to the
drawer view
noticed that when I do this I ask for
the drive use content view
and this is because drew the drawer view
is a US visual effects you and you a
visual effects view
at views how are doing a lot of work in
order to make up blur happen
and in order to avoid it interfering
with it you add any
additional content into this content
view that they expose
and then in order to differentiate the
drawer from the
candidates I'm gonna arrange the dots
neatly I in the drive you
right so can run it for the drawdown
got my neatly arranged ot I can interact
with
the dots in the canvas but i cant
interact
with the dot in the drawer and in fact
moreover if you look
through the drawer at this like orange
and blue guy here you can see that I can
interact with the dots that are behind
the dryer still
right to know why is that happening
well I disable user user interaction on
this review and the drawer view it and
thoughts are
in the scroll you so touches are passing
rate through
this role you the drive you the dot to
the content behind it which is not what
we want
so in this case disabling
user interaction was kinda too big a
hammer it got most of the behavior that
we wanted but now it now as soon as we
want to interact with something
in that you hierarchy we can't summit
turn it back over to Josh
to explain a finer grain technique that
we can use
to get the behavior that we want here
alright so we're getting closer but
as ELISA was mentioning we've just gone
a little bit too far with this disabling
a music
user interaction on ScrollView pick up
part of what we wanted but it went
beyond and a little bit too much
so to start figuring out how we can be a
little bit more precise and what we're
trying to do
we have to take a look at how he testing
works and that is going to be using the
method hit test with a bat
hit us with event is the method that you
used when a new touch comes down on
screen to figure out what
we should deliver the touch to and what
gesture recognizers should end up being
involved in looking at that touch
so before we look at how we're going to
use it
let's talk a little bit more
specifically about what exactly it does
I wanna do that by going through and
writing a little bit of pseudo code to
just show you the
order things it does and how it goes
about doing it so here I've got a swift
version I have
hit us with event down this is our
of course function syntax right there so
the first thing a test with event does
is it checks to see whether or not the
point being passed in that you're trying
to hit test
is actually within the viewer not and it
does that by checking to see
is this point within my views bounce so
if it is that we're going to do some
other stuff if it's not we just returned
mail
so if the view finds that the point is
being asked about is it and it bounced
every turns nail to indicate that it's
not interested in this view
that story in this touch that point so
then the next thing it has to do
is return itself if it actually was in
the bounce
so by default if it within the bounds we
at least had the view itself
and that's where we're running into
trouble with that transparent part
right at the beginning even though we
weren't getting any sub is a ScrollView
in there was no content there
as long as the touch was within this
role these bounds the scroll view was we
got going to return itself as the thing
I got hit
now of course you can also hit test into
some views above you
so once we decided that it's actually
within our bounds we're gonna
iterate through all of our sub views and
see if it's in any of them
so we're gonna go through and had an
inner loop where we walk over all a
farce abuse
importantly here we're going to do this
from back to front because if you think
about how rendering works
we render the first sub you in on the
next one and the next one
all the way through to the end of the
list of sub use and so whenever one
rendered last is visually on top
so we want to perform the hit test in
reverse order so that we owe it would
help the one on top first
sorry enter it backwards through the sub
US and ask each of our sub use
whether or not it got hit. so we call
hit us with the bat recur simply
on the sub use now one of them does
return something other than Dale
we're just gonna return whatever it
returns and then that'll break the
recursion
so the first sub you that were to hit
something it would
end up being returned as the thing that
got hit that's pretty much all there is
to it it's pretty straightforward
I've also got a version here in
objective-c case at that big difference
was too big a difference
but in so now let's take a look at our
sample app
and figure out exactly how we can use
this information
to get the behavior that were looking
for the first love we're gonna go in re
enable
on user interaction on this role you
because we decided that that was just
not
a the right approach it was too big a
hammer so everything we're gonna talk
about right now we're going to assume
that we've turned user interaction back
on
and go back to Mac so let's start by
looking at our view hierarchy
we've got that you a view controller's
view it's the reviewer hierarchy
an end to that elisa added a dot view a
container view that has all the dots
in it so we've got a direct sub you have
the view controller that has all the
dots
that view has a sibling another sub you
are bad view controller
and that the UIScrollView so those are
siblings but the US role he was the
second in a sub the order
so as we just talked about a hit test
that's the one that I get had tested
first
and then we have a sub you with a
ScrollView which is a drawer view that
inside the scroll view
so now let's take a look at how touches
flow-through during that had tested
between all these different views
and to do so it'll be a little easier if
we can see them all at once so I'm just
gonna split it out so we can take a look
at it as a touch comes down and see what
happens
now first falling into remove that dot
view
because we already mentioned as were hit
testing we're going from back to front
and whichever one gets hit first then
return something will end up
I ending the rigors and we won't iterate
through the other sub you so
as it starts we're never gonna even get
touches going to that dot you at all
so I forgot about that first
now it's a touch comes down in the
drawer area
see what happens so it all comes down to
their we start out at the root view the
view controller's view
and then we work our way through its
abuse and we find that the scroll view
was gonna hit something and it works
through its abuse
and we find that the drawer view is
gonna hit something and then there's
probably a dot in there are maybe not to
but we're at least going to end up
returning the drawer view
maybe the .be so that part already
worked that was easy
there is no problem there so now the
issue came up when we were in that
transparent area the scroll view that
was farther down
so Touch comes down down there
we start with the view controller looks
through its abuse finds the scroll view
and even though there's no content
visually there it's in the bounce so it
returns itself
and so that the place where we have to
do something to fix this and
perfect actually is pretty similar to
what I just said there every turns
itself
that's the only place where this role he
was gonna return itself from hit us with
that
in the other case where things were
working it was returning one of its
abuse
so we can do something we're taking
advantage of only the case
wheres Ravi is returning itself and
instead of returning itself we want a
return nil
which will cause that's super you they
view controller's view to move on and
look through the other views
that are some things I've itself and
that would allow us to instead of
heading a ScrollView
hit either the dot view or 12 the dots
later in the dot view
instead so what we can do is we can
subclass UIScrollView
and over I'd hit us with the back
course what we've overridden it we just
actually most at the time want the
default behavior
so we'll call super and hang onto the
result that we get there
if the thing that the superclass
implementation returned was
a ScrollView itself that means that
we're in a transparent area
so in that case will return nil which
will cause that you are you controlling
the outer
view to continue through this abuse and
find the dots and hit something and
they're
so pretty straightforward fax lies is
gonna come up now and make a chain strap
and see how you're doing
right so I've started to add this class
here
new subclass if US role you have called
it relay throw you
let's go ahead and add that to the
project
I'm first thing I'm gonna do is just get
rid of the implementation that was
provided
so we want to do here is
a as judge said override hit test with
it then this is really the only point of
this
a UIScrollView sunglasses to not return
it fell
from a testing so we're going to
call super hit us with a 10 and for in
the most
most of the cases will return the view
that was that was returned from the
super implementation
but if the super implementation returned
the scroll you
that means that we were that the cuts
came down in an area this really that
didn't have any other contact
and in that case we want to allow the
touch to pass through this role you
and go on to the other siblings have
this girl use this review
so will return nil in that case and
that's pretty much
it so we need to go back to the view
controller
and import that file
and then here where I'm creating my
scroll view instead of creating a
UIScrollView
I'm gonna just create an release review
and and
I need to remember to stock disabling
user interaction because
we no longer need to to big hammer to
get the fact that we want
so I can run is and
even though user interaction is disabled
is now re enable rather
I can still touch these dots to that the
effective
returning nil from hit us with an I'm
and I can still pull down the drawer
and now I can actually touch the dots
that are in the drawer
and I can no longer touch through the
drawer to the dots behind so
right that we finally pretty much have
this working the way that we want
one thing to note
I'm still adding the school use pen
gesture recognizer
to the Super view I need to do that
even though every enabled user
interaction because
I'm the transparent part of the scroll
view is no longer hit testing
and this will use pan will not get any
touches
that don't hit test to the view that
it's on so
in order to allow scrolling in the
transparent region i still actually need
to use this technique
moving the pen gesture onto the Super
you otherwise you'd be able to scroll in
the drawer
I'm which is getting hit test but you
wouldn't be able to scroll the other
parts of the scroll you
right to with that all done I mean it
change gears and let add
dragging to this to this application so
we're gonna make it so that these dot
can be picked up using a long pressed
just recognize her and dragged around
so here where I add the dots to the view
for every dot that I had
I'm I'm gonna make are you a long press
gesture recognizer
I'm going to initialize it with myself
as the target and the collector had a
long press with allen went in just a
moment
L add that just recognizer to the dots
I'm gonna end up with a lot long press
test recognizers 1 per dot
and here's my hand along Press method
so before you can view anything in
response to these long presses I wanna
show you a bug but I just introduced
by adding the long press at all
so if I run this and I touchdown on a
dot
and leave my finger down the dot on
highlight after a brief moment
even though I didn't actually lift my
finger in this case so
the reason that that is happening is
that by default
you a gesture recognizers cancel touches
in their view once they've recognized at
the default behavior evaluate just
recognize her and it often
what you want I'm in this case it's not
what we want because we actually want
the dots to stay highlighted while
they're being dragged around so I can
fix that here by telling
each one press custard that it does not
cancel touches an atty
right now let's go ahead and implement
this handle on press method
we're gonna get the dot that was pressed
by asking the gesture for its view
now we're gonna do what may be a
familiar switch statement that you tend
to do in
you I just recognizer delegate our
target map
methods I'm we're gonna switch all the
different possible state
that this gesture can be n and we're
gonna do we're gonna grab the dot if the
gestured
just began if the Jester change we're
gonna move the dot
and if it ended or was cancelled we're
gonna drop the dot so
I'll go ahead and implement I love those
methods now
right so and
from a year is as a springboard engineer
I know that when you wanna make
something look grabbed
you that scale transform on it to make
it look a little bit bigger
and you lower Salford to make it look a
little bit transparent
I'm that way it actually appears to have
changed when it starts getting grabbed
and when you wanna make it stop looking
grabbed you do the same thing in reverse
transform back to identity of a back to
one I'm
so the other thing that you wanna do
when
grabbing an element is put to the front
everything
so that as the user drags it around it
passes over all the rest of the content
so these dots may have been got out of
the drawer or they may have been got off
the canvas
we're gonna do is re parent the one that
was grabbed I'm
and moving into the view controller's
view I
at the end of the summer US so that it
passes over all the other content
so I'm going to actually do that before
grabbing it
I mean added as a subview a my view
now anytime that you repair interview
you need to watch out for the
possibility that the origin have the new
view is not the same as the origin of
the old view and so its position
it the center that it had in the old
view may not
result in the same position on the
screen as the center in the new view
so we need to do a little bit of point
conversion here to make sure that the
dot doesn't appear to change locations
when it was repainted
by setting it center to the result of
converting
its all Center from it's super views
were gonna convert that point to
might to the view and then we're going
at it as a sub view
above you alright and then when the dot
moos
also there it's actually pretty simple
what we want to do is keep the dot under
the user's finger
we know that the dot is in my view that
super view so we can simply
that its center to be the jesters
location and that he
right now there's one little caveat here
if you star from one of our sessions
from a couple years ago
your your maybe remember that we we've
done
a technique like this where you pick
something up in drag it around and it
has the potential bug
that I when you start moving the
element that was grabbed jumped a little
bit and that's because
if you see what I'm doing here I'm
adding the
I'm moving the dot so that it center is
under the touch
every day every frame as the user moves
the finger and putting the center the
dot
under their finger however the user may
have picked that up from the edge
they may not have picked it up from the
center so the first time that they move
their finger
it will jump under their finger I'm so
in order to prevent that kind of jarring
John what I'm gonna do in this case
which is a little different for how we
solve this in the past
I'm I'm just gonna actually call moved
out with jester
in that grab animation so that the first
time that the user grabs
and the dot gets picked up it also just
animates
so that its center is under their finger
and that way we won't have a jarring a
fact when they start to move their
finger
finally when the dot gets dropped
we need to figure out are we gonna put
it down in the drawer we gonna put it
down on the canvas
so I'm going to find out from the Jester
what is the location in the drawer view
and and if the drug use bounds contains
that location that means that
the dot has been dragged to the over the
drawer
and I will at that point add the dot to
the drug use content view
otherwise I'll add it at the Puma
Candice
and I need to do that same point
conversion in reverse
movies the dot centered so that it's the
result of converting
from and my view that within 24
to its new super view so it will appear
to stay in the same location
and and now we should be good to go so
I can pick one up these guys up at your
side animated nicely under
underwear my my mouse was pointing I get
around
I'm I can do the same in the drawer
pick it up right around put it down pick
one up here
so I can movie that all around it seems
to be working
I'm the drawers getting a little messy
this offends me
lately so I'm gonna fix it by and just
asking the dots to arrange themselves
neatly with nifty animation
in the drawer at the moment that they
get picked up and I'm an idiot
same thing when we put them down and
so now when I pick one up they do that
who and good
cases it's pretty much working as we
want and but it would be cool if you
could pick
I dot up with one finger and then scroll
the drawer
to either bring it down or put it back
up again with another finger I'm gonna
switch over to an actual
iPad here where got this running
so that we can do a multi-touch thing
to hear that anything out and running on
an iPad the one difference is that I've
modified it so that you can see where
the users touch come down to that little
white dot
that moving around is where my fingers
and so
you can see that I can pick up a dot I'm
and I can actually even pick up more
than one dot
the you get for free just because we've
got a bunch of
long press just recognize that I can
move the ball around at the same time
but if I put down another
finger an attempt to scroll the scroll
view nothing happens
I'm so let's try to fix that we want to
be able to
simultaneously be dragging one of these
dots around and growing a ScrollView
with another finger right so why isn't
that working
so I could have
fingers on the different ones are the
dots and interact with those at the same
time
because those views are siblings and so
they're just recognizers don't interact
with one another
however the dots are some view of the
view that has the pen just recognizer so
the long press testers and the pen just
recognize our do interact
and by default the behaviour gesture
recognizers that interact
is to be mutually exclusive so 15
already picked up a dot
I can no longer make that hand gesture
recognizer but we can easily
tell these gestures that they can
recognize simultaneously in the way we
do that
is by becoming the long pressed gesture
recognizers
delegate so will I'll
say that we conform to you I just
recognizer delegate and when we
added the long presses will make
ourselves the delegate to follow them
and then will implement a single
delegate method gesture recognizers
should recognize
simultaneously with a gesture recognizer
and and in this case just as a shortcut
I'm gonna return yes
I can do that safely here because this
is a pretty small app and I know that
the only just her that I'm gonna be
asked this question about is the school
you can just ur
in your own applications you should be
much more specific here because
it would be a and easy for some bugs to
this return yes willy nilly to any
gesture recognizer that that you're
after bout on
so once we're done that I can I'm not
gonna build it because I've actually got
an already built copy over here
I'm so this is the result
a having made exactly those changes and
let me
its were right
so now and
I can scroll well
one of these guys is I grabbed but it
but you can see there's actually a
pretty bad but here
if I try to and scroll this down I can
but I can also screw it using the very
same touch that's dragging one of the
dots which is clearly not here that I
want at all
right to know why is it happening well I
would act
can depend Esther recognized
simultaneously with the long press
tester and I said yes
so they're recognizing simultaneously
I'm the very thing touch
is having the effect have recognizing
with both gestures
so a that we do not want to do and I'm
gonna bring
Josh back on stage to talk about how we
can fix that last little problem here
alright well we're getting pretty close
a we can almost do what I really want to
be able to drag these dots around while
also scrolling mister on and off on
so let's figure out that last little bit
how we can make sure that these gestures
recognize using the touch is that we
actually expect them to
down what first began at the view
hierarchy and where all the stuff is set
up just to make sure that we're all on
the same page about Alice's
currently interacting so we've got that
matter view and we've got our ScrollView
gonna drive you here now of course the
the long press is that are on the dots
look at the ones first that are up on
the drawer view there on sub to use up
the drive you actually there each
attached to the individual dots
and then we've got the pan gesture
recognizer from the scroll view
had we not done anything else that would
have been on the scroll you
we took a and we moved it up and put it
on that outer
containing you like you can't relieve
you so without their
said I wanna touch comes down inside
that drawer it's gonna be seen by both
it'll be seen by any other long press
gestures that its interacting with soft
on a dot will be seen by the long press
on that dot
and it will also be seen by the outer
you right hand gesture recognizer
from the US robie now that's where we're
getting this budget analyzer was talking
about
so how do we fix this we need them both
to be able to recognize at the same time
because we want one touch in a dot to be
able to move it while another touch
outside other
and we already know that those gestures
are going to interact with one another
so we definitely need to allow them to
recognize simultaneously
so we can change that we wanted do
something when
the pan won the long press starts to
prevent the pan
for recognizing with that touch we want
to allow the the long press the Continue
so we can drag the dot
we just wanna stop the pain
we don't to stop it from pending at all
just for pending with that touch
so we can actually take advantage a the
fact
that is that special side behavior up
disabling a gesture recognizer
which cause it to stop looking at any
touch is that it was currently looking
at
so wanna pay and when the long press
recognizes we can just get the pan
gesture
and sat at the table state the false by
setting up the false it's going to tell
it to stop looking at any touches it was
currently considering
and reset itself basically so it will no
longer consider that touch
the long press will still be able to
continue considering it because we
didn't disable the long press
just the plan but of course we did that
then you wouldn't be able to pan with
another touch
because we disable the pan we can
actually just go right
around and turn it right back on and it
will still have stopped looking at the
touch that it was looking at but it will
now be able to look at new touches that
come down
actually turns out this is going to be
really really easy to fix analyzes gonna
come back and do it quickly and see
where that leaves us
right so this is gonna be the fastest
demo and history all I need to do
is at the moment when I'm grabbing the
dot and
I just need to disable and re-enable
the scroll use pen duster so disabling
it will cause it to just stop talking
all the touches it was tracking
including the long press
and re enabling it will allow it to be
ready to
attract new touches that might start so
I will switch back over here and
launched the third version of this I'm
so
the third version year we can now pick
up a dot
we can simultaneously scroll the scroll
view I
but the dot itself
no longer scrolls the scroll used to now
I can do all the things I wanted to do I
can
grab several docked at once put them in
this role you grab several them
outta there pull them over here so
this is pretty much working exactly as
we wanted now there's a will there's a
few elements have
polish that have to do with the way that
these dots highlight
themselves and i wanna try to draw your
attention to
a little problem at that may not be
immediately apparent
so I'm going to put my finger down to
start
a pan in that blue dot near the top
did you see that it momentarily
highlighted an answer have blinked back
off again
do it on another one the orange one year
just to I'm
so pans that starred in the dot cause it
to momentarily receive touches began
which causes it to be highlighted
other than as the pan recognizes it
cancel touches in in its view
and so had to cancel gets delivered to
the dot and so you see this momentary
flash
have highlighted as you start screwing
but I noticed that the same thing does
not happen
with the dots they're in the drawer so
when I start panting
I'm here I don't get that flash
have I'm actually woman
I get them doing it too slowly vacay let
me a the media little bit faster to
to the affected very subtle but for the
most part pans don't
result don't cause that flash
highlighting in the drawer you
and if you're really delivered about it
I guess you can get them to do it
I'm so the reason for the difference
is that the I is that these dots here in
the drawer
are in a ScrollView and by the and by
default
school you actually had behavior that
delays the delivery approaches
to its abuse I'm while it's checking
whether a pen is starting
and the you can really see the effective
this if you use you a table views
in Iowa you'll see that if you basically
starts rolling pretty quickly in a you a
table view
you don't see a flash highlight on the
cell that you happen to touch
and and so you avoid this kind have
experience have
flashing happening as he starts rolling
so
I'm gonna bring Josh back on stage to
explain how that
accomplished in UIScrollView and how we
can get the very same effect
a for these dots that are not in this
role you
alright I promise that the beginning
that we were going to talk about some
polish
and look at them internal implementation
ideas of how you a ScrollView
accomplishes the sort of behavior
so let's go do that but before we do I
just wanna
get a quick video fertilizer mention
their when you're scrolling in the UI
cable view
so I don't scroll this a this view here
you're gonna find that
we don't end up seeing flashes as she
said we wouldn't a
its rolls smoothly there's no flash in
any South highlighting no matter where I
put my finger down
as long as I starts rolling pretty
quickly now if I
put my finger down and leave it there
for a little while then we're gonna go
and highly whatever cell
you put your finger so that's exactly
the same kind of thing that we're
talking about here in these dots
but applied really everywhere that you
see you I table be so
this behavior as ELISA mentioned is
accomplished using a property on
UIScrollView
so if you're in a scroll you're getting
this automatically a property is called
delays content touches
you can turn this off if you wanted it
for some reason in your ScrollView you
wanna make
touches go through immediately with no
delay but by default you get a short
delay before they're delivered to any
view in this girl he
now in the case that we're looking at
here at these dots
we don't actually have all the dots in a
ScrollView so we're not getting their
behavior on the ones that are
to understand how the school he is
getting this helps the look
at although the gesture recognizers that
are attached to this girl D
so the school he has a pen gesture
recognizer we know that
we already took it and you that this
that the session in order to move it out
onto the interview
of course it also has a pinch gesture
recognizer so if you're using zooming in
your UI ScrollView
there will be a UI pics gesture
recognizer on this review as well
but there's actually a third one the you
may not know about it's actually bear if
you look at the
the gesture recognizer rayon a
ScrollView but it's not particularly
useful
to at know about in most cases other
than to understand how these things work
and the third one is a touch delay
gesture recognizer
so this gesture recognizer sole purpose
in life
is to sit around and fail a so
I feel so bad for it but it's there on
it never recognizes
it they're just too as a way to delay
touch delivery to the views in this role
you
and when it does that is by taking
advantage a property that exist on you I
gesture recognizer
called the lace touches began and this
is no by default because when he said it
yes they can introduce big delays in
touch delivery writer aP
so most gesture recognizers do not want
this property set to yes
because what it does is delays delivery
are touches began
the entire cup sequence actually the
began and all subsequent
events a until that gesture recognizer
either recognizes or fails
so we can use it to delay delivery of
the entire touch sequence
to some view that attach to whatever
view the gesture recognizers attached so
if you look at
a time line up how this works that we
can see why this make sense and how does
what it does
so wanna touch comes down the touch gets
it's gonna be again comes down don't
forget what happens to the pan gesture
the touch still a gesture and the view
that it's that the touch with
had tested to so at this point the touch
delay jesters gonna start a timer
its pretty short timer because we don't
I had big delays the delivery at the
touch
I would say 15 seconds just as a number
that I would like to get out
on now if you leave your finger down for
some period of time
until that timer fires then
the delay gesture is going to fail it'll
said its data failed
and what it does because it was the only
thing delaying that touch
the UI you at that point that it was hit
us to do we'll see touch it began with
the band and it had to be delivered
now things at progress in the user
decides to move their finger a little
bit
maybe the pan Chester starts to
recognize and at that point
the view is gonna get touches capital
for the back so that's where the highly
will get removed
the delay jester has already failed so
nothing new is happening there
so that's the case where you leave your
finger down long enough
but the interesting cases when you
scroll really quickly so let's look at
what happened in that case
again we put the these are put their
finger down the delay jester starts a
short timer
and if you still haven't seen anything
because that the late yesterday
cysts and has the latest such as beget
now these are at this point start
scrolling
and the pen just a recognizes then the
pen just her would have cancelled that
touch
but because we never delivered it yet it
was still being delayed by that delay
gesture
we don't ever actually delivered to the
view at all as far as the view is
concerned the touch never happened
the pen just a recognizes the touch
would've been cancelled but we never
delivered began so he kinda silly to
deliver began cancelled
on so we just don't deliver it and that
causes that the never highlight
and never flash a highlight and get
exactly the behavior that were looking
for
now there's nothing particularly magical
about this touch delay just a recognizer
and we can write when ourselves that
does
pretty much the exact same thing that
the one on US Grove you does so that we
can use that in situations where we're
not using a UIScrollView
course there are no situations where you
should not use the US role you but
lets the match in that there might be on
so we can do that by subclassing you I
gesture recognizer
and over I think over reading at
designated initializer it with target
action
and of course what we do in there is set
delays touches began to yes because I
mention that no by default
so that most gesture recognizers aren't
doing that
then as with all you like just a
recognizer sunglasses were going to
override to the touch methods
so we'll do touch it began and didn't
cancel in this case
because for this gesture recognizer we
don't actually care if that ever moved
anywhere
we're not trying to deal with that we
just care when it comes down when it
comes up
so well over itouch began and start a
timer
we mention there's gonna be that short
timer Soulstar that their and then in
touch is ended and touch is cancelled
we wanna centers they to fail now the
reason we want to do that is because if
the user taps quickly
we want that touch to get delivered
immediately when the Touch comes up
we don't want to wait until this time
has expired in order to deliver the
toucher you introduce extra delay that
you don't mean to when it's not
necessary
so if the at the touch ends or get
cancelled we're gonna set the state the
failed
and that'll allow that touch to go
through and get delivered to the view
now of course we said we're setting a
timer so we have to implement some time
a method
but say that we've got some function
like it's called what we're gonna do in
there
is also centers that failed if the timer
passes
this gesture fails that allow the touch
to get delivered
and then finally the last thing that
gesture recognizers should do is
override
the reset method which is where you go
about putting herself back in shape to
be
ready for another instanceof trying to
recognize and so in there were just
gonna clear the timer reset it and get
everything back into a good state to
start over again
so pretty small gesture recognizer it
never gonna try and recognize which is
kind of unique
there's not a lot of gesture recognizers
that never try to recognize anything
but I get this an interesting effect
analyzes gonna come back up and build it
for us
right to I'm adding another class here
touch delay just recognize there which
is going to be a subclass
have you I gesture recognizer and
so we're going to it could have a really
simple implementation like just
described
and the first thing we need to do apps
is import
the the glass but we show that night
police
and and then we're going to overriding
it with target action
I'm call super and then do one thing it
which is to use that touches but delays
touches began to yes as Josh mentioned
the only purpose for this thing is to
delay touches to its view
us so we need the delays patches began
flag on
and then it I'm back Terry
went to bed myself we need a timer in
the
and as anti-virus this guy and then
we're going to set that timer in touch
it again
so will schedule it given interval love
point 15 seconds
and when the tire fires were gonna just
called us fail method that I'm about to
right and in the fail method I'm
we will simply set our state to you I
just recognize our state failed
in touch ended and touch is cancelled
were also just gonna fail
and finally when we're told to reset
we're going to just get rid of that time
are cleared out and be ready to go again
the next time a text comes down
so I'm going to go back over to the view
controller no
and we're going to import this file
and then I'm I'm just gonna make one of
these guys
and I'm gonna add it to the canvas
view now notice that I'm passing it a
nil target and no action
with an unusual thing to see you when
you make a gesture recognizer
but this thing never recognizes so
there's no point in giving it a target
or an action if I did then they would
never be invoked
so it's really just the existence of
this thing and the fact that it's
attached to a view
that's gonna have the effect that we
want so I'm gonna add it to my cam is he
said that the dot
in the canvas get the theme behavior as
the dots
in this role you I'm so go ahead and run
this
and now if I start a pen
in what have you got to do it slowly
enough then you'll then you can see
a highlight technique that one up but if
you do it fast enough you see that
there's no longer
a flash as I starts growing
who I'm and to getting back into the
behavior that we have in this role you
so I'm we're gonna show you one more
thing
a another sort of small element of
Polish
that we can add to this application and
I want to show you the problem first
news that somebody's got here are
extremely small
I'm in fact I've I think I've I'm
generating their radius is randomly but
they're
as small as a a ready if the 10 which
makes the whole thing on the 20 points
wide
in general it's pretty difficult to hit
a view with your finger if it's less
than forty four points
wide or tall and so although its put
very easy for me to pick the things up
in the simulator using my mouth
it would be quite difficult to hit them
if I were using my finger
and we want to show you a technique that
we can use
to make very small user interface
elements
hittable and for me to bring Josh back
up on stage to explain how we can
accomplish that
alright so we promised three sections
and three techniques but we've got a
little bonus extra bit here at the end
so
a work we're going to talk about his
testing though
so still within the three areas a touch
handling I promise we haven't
straight that far from my original
statement on
as ELISA mention what we're trying to do
here is in force a minimum hit target
size
that you mention 44 in through that
number out the reason that
she mentioned that is because it the
common number they are fine throughout
you like it
if you look at the default bar Heights
for things like
tow bars or the default row heights for
table B cells
44 is a common number they're gonna find
come up it's a good rule about not
something that
if you start getting smaller than this
it's hard to hit this thing so
to figure out how we're going to go in
and resolve this situation we're gonna
go back and look at his test for the
banned again
now there's a couple ways you can do it
you could make your view bigger
that would obviously make it hannibal
but in the case a what allies is looking
at
in our sample app right now if we made
the view bigger that would actually make
the circle draw bigger because she's
drying it based on the size above you
so if we were gonna fix the hit testing
problem by changing the view side then
we have to go refactor about other stuff
and change the way we draw the view to
account for that
and I could end up making things more
complex and a bigger change that we
really mean
let's go back and look at our hit us
with event method again
and see if there's anything in here that
might help us but we focus in on this
part I mentioned at the beginning
we've got one check right off the bat
that says is the point insider bounce
now I wrote this in some pseudo code
here so it's
that not exactly clear what that means
so what expanded out to what it really
does
to go and call a method called coincide
with the van
on the view that being asked to help
test itself and the reason that that's
interesting to know is because it means
there's another override point where you
can change the behavior
a test with the band without changing
hit test itself so we can actually go in
override that method independently a
test for the banned
and change what it means for a point to
be with insider view
so by the fall as I mention what it's
going to do is just check its own bounds
and see if the point is within sight it
so we'll call
see direct contains point bounds and the
point that we were checking on
but we can make this do whatever we want
so if we want to view to behave as if
it's bigger without actually changing
its bounds and making it bigger
we can subclass an override coincide
with the van and change the check to do
anything we think is right for our
you that were interested in so another
short section but allies is gonna come
right back up and go ahead and fix that
last but for us
right
so Here I am in my dot view subclass
so it I mention that I'd written this
class pretty much all I do here is
make he's got give them a bunch of
random properties that their corner
radius so that they look like
circles I'm and what I'm gonna do now
below this code that deals with patches
beginning ending in being canceled and
is I'm gonna
override point inside with event and I'm
gonna have to
I'm gonna figure out whether this dot is
a dot that should get an expanded
touch region so the first thing to do is
and is the minicomputer what I want to
consider my bounds to be for the Sikh
have touch and lick so the touchdowns by
default will to start out with our real
bounds
but if this dot is one whose radius
is small enough and I'm gonna Nicolas
this
44 points wide I'm idea
so if the radius is less than 22 then
I'm I'm going to calculate an expansion
a amount by which I mean expand my
bounds for the sake
apec handling at the different to get it
for that every dot
get act as if it's at least 44 points
wide
when touched and then I'm going to use
this handy
CG wrecked in fact method to expand
the touch bounds I'm notice that I'm
passing negative the expansion
that because see direct inset take the
rectangle and move the edges
in in this case we want to move the
edges out so I'm gonna
do it by negative that the amount that
we that we computed
and then finally I'll a
just return whether my newly computed
touchdowns contains
that point so this will have no effect
on large dots but it will expand the
country denmark for small ones
so gonna go ahead and run this again and
now
and right to got my mouth here and I'm
gonna touch outside have this big dot
and you can see nothing happens
they got highlights only when you
actually catch in its bounds
but for this tiny dot over here a.m.
but the above it appear for this tiny
dot I can touch outside a bit sounds
and highlights so this looks a little
strange on the simulator because you
have a
a high precision pointing device but on
a device
you actually really don't notice I'm
that anything is weird it just feels
like
you can pick these guys up so and
that point inside overriding the bounds
that comfortable and select pretty much
else turn it back over to Josh's
to conclude
alright well thanks for coming out again
as you know jack barons over there in
the front
and then I've had today he's a ready to
answer all of your questions if you have
anything else you wanna know after this
there is one other related session left
today that I
obviously encourage you to come to you
cuz I'll be right back here in about 15
minutes
for building interruptible and
responsive interactions with any
Matuszak
so I stick around and we've got a great
session for you coming right up
thanks again enjoy their remaining hours
at the show