RA good good morning still right um
here a little while ago what time it is
around welcome to building
interruptible and responsive
interactions so
handy and I wanna spend some time
talking about
how you can build the interactions and
he raps that are really fluid
and make the user interaction with the
content in your app really smooth and
natural
and avoid any sorta jarring changes
as you transition between things and
if you were just here for this review
session on a start out with something
that probably won't be too surprising
and show you a ScrollView
I just to give you an idea the kind of
things that we're talking about here
they have got a nice bird that's a in a
UIScrollView
and I've zooming and scrolling and stuff
the
thing I want to draw your attention to
is the transitions between the user
dragging around in a ScrollView and let
it go and how animation start
and then grabbing again as the
animations are in progress so
I can zoom in on this burden I can drag
it down and about to get the edge
but if I keep grabbing it there's never
a time where I can't start scrolling
it always works I can scroll around and
it's all a very smooth transition
anatoly wanna talk about this morning
is transitions so what kinds of
transitions
well three transitions in particular
number one transitioning from jesters
into animations and how to do that
really really smoothly
number two transitioning from animation
to other animations and I'm sure you
were to guess what number three is
transitioning from animations back into
gesture control
so the key to making all these
interactions really smooth is just
making sure that the transitions between
these different states
are a seamless as possible I thought
start out by talking about transitioning
from your jesters
into your animations so it's often the
case that you're doing something like
dragging content around using a pan
gesture recognizer
and you may be having a track your
finger directly because that
a really great way on a multi touch
device to optimize
jester interactions but that when you
left you might want to start some
animation
something like what a ScrollView does to
do a deceleration or or something of
that nature
and you want that transition point to be
a smooth as you can for take a look at
two different possible ways to do this
got this on loop some to believe it up
here for like 15 minutes and we can just
stare at it for the rest of the day
around the bottom one is looking a lot
smoother than that %ah point
we've got two fingers that are dragging
these boxes the one comes off with the
wanna finger left with the same velocity
and it comes to rest nice it smoothly
the top one as soon as I left my finger
it snaps with what a stop and then
slowly start up and then comes to rest
so we want to figure out a way that we
can make oliver transitions from jesters
the animations behave like that bottom
box
and the first part to making this happen
is to figure out what velocity we want
to start our animation act so
number one concern compute blah city now
if you're using
some other standard UI gesture
recognizers this is really easy to do
because it's actually already done for
you
so for using a UI hand gesture
recognizer you got this velocity and new
method
and you can just pass interviewing you
get back to velocity the panning was
happening at
and whatever coordinate space you need
at to start your animation so that's
really easy
if you're using a pinch or a rotation
gesture recognizer
you get the exact same kind of thing I'm
just bored whatever it is that your
computing in the case a pen Chester
recognize are you getting supplies to
give the scale
and for the retention you're getting
angular velocity for that rotation
computing is really easy if you're using
one of the standard gesture recognizers
if you're not competing velocity is
still a pretty straightforward thing to
do
velocities just distance over time so if
you just keep accumulating adjusting
your times that keeping track at that
you can compete the velocity they should
start
yourself for whatever action you're
interested in so that was pretty
straightforward
the interesting part is how do we start
our animation at that blah City
so take a look at the standard you like
animation
we've got animate with the racin delay
options
animations completion so there's no
velocity and their
on so that's not going to be obviously a
an easy way to go about doing this
but happily last year when I was 7 we
introduce the new more expressive
version of this method
that had to new brand parameters and it
we got using spring with damping
an initial spring velocity so that is
looking a little more promising
let's focus on the initial spring
velocity this is the thing that is gonna
let us pass a velocity at a bar gesture
recognizer wherever we computed it
and start an animation that feels like
it's coming off a finger really really
smoothly
so how do we compute this initial spring
colossally we just take that velocity
that we had and pass it in
obviously if the answer was yes I
wouldn't really be talking about this so
we're probably gonna have to do
something else
let's take a look at an example assuming
that we were pending some objects and we
want to start having at the celery
just along the x-axis for simplicity
sake and see what we do
so we've got a box we are pending at
around at that point fifty right now
export it fifty and we're going to have
an animate over to the right side there
to export it 150
now let's assume that we calculated that
are horizontal velocity was about 50
points per second so that's what we want
to start this animation
to figure out what velocity wanna pass
into the initial spring colossally we
actually have to compute
a normalized velocity the cord its base
that this method is expecting to get the
velocity is in
is a normalized coordinate space and we
want to normalize it based on the total
distance
that this object is going to travel
during the animation
so first rate to calculate that distance
we've got our destination value that's
150 we went to subtract from that the
a starting point so we subtract of fifty
and we get a total distance traveled a
hundred points
so that it to figure out the velocity to
pass then we just normalize the velocity
we want by dividing by that total
distance
so we take our 50 points per second
divided by the total distance traveled a
hundred
and we get an initial velocity a .5
that point five we just pass in the end
to the method that we just take a look
at
as our initial spring la city so you
argue enemy with duration
we can give it a time at how long it's
gonna take delays all those other things
you normally do
and just passin that additional velocity
parameter and will get a really nice
affect
so that if we take a look at what that's
going to end up doing we can see that if
we drag this box around
we get it coming up our finger really
smoothly and additionally
we got a nice little bounce there at the
end as it comes to rest
that bounce was the other parameter we
saw a and you can
tweet that to get a different kinda feel
whatever feels good in your app's
you get nice springy animation that they
come to rest
with its with velocity coming off your
finger so
that we can do with a standard you I do
animations
but there's other options as well so
what they may be wanted to do something
a little more advanced
and have more types of interactions with
other views on screen
or more complicated the celebrations
than just the spring
so also in I'll I seven we introduce the
class called you a dynamic animator
and this is another great way to go
about getting animations that feel like
I come up your finger at the exact
velocity that you were interacting with
flick but forget how would set that up
into you I Q controller
in order to get some animations going
with a dynamic animator
so first off we would create you a
dynamic animator I'm doing this in sweat
so is a couple interesting things we can
talk about what we go through this
here I'm assuming this is a property on
our view controller a
and I typed it as a UI dynamic animator
question mark and I actually just made
that an equal sign it should be a corn
I literally change this on the stage
before I got occurs I thought it was
wrong and I just realized line up here
I'd change to the wrong thing
so don't write code in Keynote it's a
bad idea a
I'm trying to declare a dynamic animator
uptight
you again and again later optional and
optional then again later because we're
going to go in initialize with later
the reason that this one needs to be
optional here is because you edit you I
dynamic animator when you create one
take for you I view at creation time and
you don't have a UI view a creation time
love you like you can't really because
you want to control is to love their
views lisa Lee
so we want to start out with this being
mill and then initialize it later
so a week we've declared a property for
it will go in set up a lil bit later
now we've got art dynamic item behavior
which is a class that participate in
this %um accept them
and this is where we're going to attach
views that one we want to have dynamics
associated with so create a UN and I
kinda behavior and
we can initialize this here as a
constant because
we don't need to provide any views at
the time we created it let us add or
remove use over time
so created at a time great are you a
dynamic and behavior
and now over i'd give you did load
method because when a view controller
goes the low to view
gonna load up all the view bets and then
there's a good place to go and
add additional initialization after the
views loaded in
a you did load so-called super just make
sure that I get the chance to do any
work it was gonna do
and then we can go and set up the rest
about it dynamic system so we have that
optional you a dynamic animator this is
a great place to initialize that is now
we know we have a view
so we can create are you a dynamic
animator we have our view now so we can
pass it
we also want to set a couple properties
on that on the dynamic animator just so
that as we said blah cities and get some
deceleration animations things will come
to rest smoothly
so we're gonna set our resistance and
angular resistance
to evaluate just picked randomly of
three you can pick different values and
get different fields
and then finally we're going to add that
behavior we created a dynamic
item behavior earlier we're going to
associate it now with the dynamic
animator now that we have it
and so that's pretty much all urs for
setting up the system so that we have to
figure out how to transfer velocity into
this dynamic system
from our testers cuz that's really what
this is all about so take a look at how
we do that
a the first thing we want to do is find
out what view we're going to be
associating
I this velocity Inc in so we we've got
up and just a recognizable to assume
that it's attached to some view that
were dragging around
will get the target view now this is
what
you would often do you and I you I just
a recognizer target action method so I'm
assuming I we're doing out here
so what do the normal switch statement
that you would see within a target
action method for a gesture recognizer
so it depends us to recognize our state
and switch on that there right now we're
just talking about transitioning
from the Jester to an animation so we
don't worry about any state other than
ended because that's when you perform
this transition
so it's going deal with the ended case
that we have to get the velocity that we
were moving today into the dynamic
system
so alaska hand gesture recognizer for
the velocity and the view usually that
you'll be doing here if we're dragging
around the view is attached to you
we want to get the velocity and that you
super view because that's the coordinate
space that the views
I geometry is gonna be in so we'll get
the velocity and that
target is super views coordinate space
and I would just ask the dynamic item
behavior
to add some linear velocity adding
linear velocity will just
increase the velocity in the dynamic
system up the object by whatever the
current a
velocity was that we were dragging it
around by so we can add that
into the system and then it'll smoothly
decelerate from
whatever the Jester is doing so again
now take a look at some boxes and US
we can see that as we drag the things
around eight decelerate smoothly
but because the dynamics they can also
interact with one another
so I think allied they're gonna start
doing other interesting things so this
is a great way to get more advanced
a behaviors while still preserving these
really smooth transitions
so we talk about two ways to go about
doing this we've got
enemy duration: now there's def a
reasonable you might choose one or the
other
there's no one right answer for all
situations enemy with the rationing one
of the nice
properties are doing this is that it
creates server-side animations
now what that means is that the
animations that are created using the
spring velocities that we talked about
at the beginning
those are actually going to execute
another process added the context of
your application
so even if you end up doing some working
application that may be blocked your
main thread for a little while
the other render servers running at a
higher priority so it's going to be
optimized to make sure that we trying
not to drop frames on that animation
even if your app has a lot of heavy work
going on in the main thread
so it becomes easier to maintain smooth
animations a few
just off loaded onto the render server
by using IMAP duration: method
now of course the other option we talked
about is you like a dynamic so you a
dynamic animator
now that one of the big benefit to this
is that you get even more advanced
interactions
and it will see a little bit later when
we talk about more transitions
some other transitions can be easier
when you're using a UN dynamic animator
then when you're using the server-side
animations because with you I dynamic
animator everything is happening in your
process in your address space
now the downside to that is that it
means that going to rely on your main
thread turning often enough that the
dynamic an American update the dynamic
system
and get everything committed to for the
next frame so if your app
happens to do a bunch of work or you
know is taking more time to get
something done it
easier to drop frames if you're not
being careful so your dynamic animator
is a very powerful way to do it
you have to be a little bit more careful
to make sure that your optimizing your
apt to avoid dropping any frames
and there are Arthur options that are a
little bit more advanced
and in fact the thing that your dynamic
animators built on is CA DisplayLink
now see a display like as a class the
call you back once every frame
so frame is gonna get rendered you get
called back to go update your
happened whatever we want now that'll
give you 60 Hertz call backs
and so you can try and update your
animations at 60 Hertz at exactly how
dynamic animator does it
so if you have some really custom thing
that you can't accomplish with one of
these other technologies you could build
your own animations
to do things yourself now of course this
is a even more advanced thing we're not
gonna go and exactly how you go about
writing arbitrary animations if you have
an idea of something you might wanna do
you probably I can go build it yourself
but so be that are out there
may be thinking well waiting on is
another option why are we talking about
and this timer a this was a common thing
before see a display existed just
created and ice timer set it to call
back at 60 Hertz
and drive animations of that well
understand why we're not going to talk
about that is a really viable option
lets take a look at a time line
showing what happens over time for an
astronomer CA DisplayLink
and all of the display frames that are
coming on screen so have gotten vertical
bars is one of those represents a
display frame
now let's take a look at what NS CA
DisplayLink does
a within each of those gaps so because
we're running at 60 Hertz on I'll ass
its gap there represents about 60
milliseconds up a little bit more than
that but that's roughly right
so that's how much time you have in
between any two frames
now see a display like I said is gonna
call you back once per frame
and a place where cause you back is
gonna try and beat as tight as possible
to where the frames are happening
so you're gonna get these green dot says
call back times letter
associated roughly with where the the
frames happen
so what happens when a timer while it
depends
and it's time for you might get in there
maybe I'll get them at the beginning
maybe I'll get them closer to the and
but what's really getting in the middle
you actually are really sure where
you're going to get them because when
you get them depends on when you happen
to set up the NS
timer and a timer is in synchronized
with this plan anyway so when you get
the call backs will depend exactly on
when you set up the timer
obese if you set it up for 60 Hertz able
to be sixty 60 milliseconds
from whatever you set it up depending on
where in the brain that what's
could be anywhere it's hard to know now
why that a problem
well looking at how much time we have
now we had 16 milliseconds
for this whole frame with Dennis timer
that we've got about 80 seconds from the
time that
it got called into the neck sprain
assuming that happen to be set up right
in the middle
even then you may not see why exactly
that's a problem I mean
so it's a millisecond you can really get
done in less than eight or if you can't
then all right here within the next
spring
well the trouble comes into places where
maybe your art always either in the
current frame for the next spring
so what say that it actually takes you
about 8 milliseconds to set up your
frame and get it committed to the render
service
so if we look at our second frame here
at a piece that I have listed
let's say that the first time we get it
done in a millisecond but that happens
to miss
being rendered to the screen for this
frame so it goes over an adult
come in you know another 16 millisecond
later so we missed that brain
and the trouble is that maybe the next
time we happen to get things done a
little bit faster and do make that print
what that effectively gonna end up
meaning is that the frame where we
missed
will really just never displayed to the
user it'll be as if it just disappeared
and not gonna end up looking like a drop
frame so we're entering a
within eight milliseconds only taking as
a and we have sixteen to get things done
so it seems like we should never drop a
frame
as worried well under the tall frame
time we just dropped a frame because
you're right on the border
with CA DisplayLink it was taking as a
millisecond cuz we started close the
beginning
we still have that actually no second
buffer time every time so there's no way
we're gonna miss that frame
now if you do take 60 milliseconds you
might get back into that same situation
but it's taking 16 milliseconds to
prepare frame you're basically never
gonna hit 60 Hertz anyway
so at that point back to you have to
optimize your app but if you're finding
they are optimizing things they are
using an ass timer and you got it as
fast as you can and you're still
dropping frames
it's probably because you're using a
timer and is heading this variability
and you should switch to using SEO
DisplayLink so honest I was never really
the right solution for doing client-side
animations
so that's the story free transitioning
from adjuster to animation
to give you an idea I've now had a
transition from animations other
animations
and he's gonna come up on stage in talk
a little bit about that
thanks Josh seek God animation going
you wanna change directions
and if you've probably seen this issue
before you know this purple certainly
say go to the other side
and in the middle %uh its animation it's
a weight now go back the other way
because maybe the user press the button
and then what happens
is the circle jumps all the way to the
right side
animates from there the web is a pretty
common bug
that we see in applications and is one
the reasons why people will for instance
disable user interaction
on their animations to get around issues
like this
now there's always been you I view
animation
option they can help deal with these
scenarios
called you I view animation option begin
from current state
and this is what it looks like by
contrast there's no jumping position
and that's great but
there's a job in velocity
if you look at this animation it can
only get hit a brick wall
and it starts going back the other
direction there's a more fluid option
but I'm going to talk about now I'm
gonna introduce you to its called
additive animations
take a look at how this looks the circle
on the bottom movies
and it preserves both position and
velocity
when it changes direction both love
those are smooth but see that one more
time
can see begin from current state kinda
like it hit the wall
additive animations the velocity
component this MOU
so absolute animations have been the
default
on Iowa us I'm so far but but
starting now with I was 8 additive
animations are actually going
to be the default behavior for all you
like a free minute
most likely create animation we'll talk
a little bit more later about
exactly when this is going to work and
when it's not
botch going to write about is that
if you have this code typical animation
thing
you are going to get that desired
behavior
so I do want you to actually understand
what's going on behind the scenes here
I think that's really important taking
advantage of this new feature let's walk
through
how could such actually manages
animations in the system what's
happening behind the scenes to make this
happen
to get the circle you tell it go to the
other side say
animate that exposition to 500
so if you were to up the circle
for its under Zacks value immediately
after making that call it would return
same thing to go not means the circle
should draw all the way on the right
side
but it doesn't the first frame that the
circle is rendered its
still gonna be at the road because it's
going to animate from 0 to 500
and the reason that that happens is the
distinction between
presentation layers and presentation
layers values
and model wears values so if you're
unfamiliar with that distinction I think
just watching
the talk in just 19 2011 called
understanding you like it rendering
I'm mostly going to assume that you
understand the distinction already
the point is that where the layers value
is
sorry the layers current value was not
necessarily where it's going to drop
was a presentation value that's used for
rendering so right now the presentation
earlier this layer 0
the reason that 0 is that there is this
CA animation object
which you like it has created and
attached to the lair
incomplete a few pieces of information
you look at it has
if from value set now from value was
read
out at the model value of the where
model though you're the layer 100 so the
from tell you this animation 00
you know that there is no to tell you
and that's because the way this works
is that every frame but to tell you
is going to be the current model value
the lair so if we were to read this
animation
in in natural tax we would say okay this
is an animation it's going to animate
from
00 to the current model value of the
where
which happens currently to be 500 over
one second starting from a thousand by
one
so this animation omits a value of $0 $0
four-time a thousand .1
and that's why the presentation value is
an extremely render emits a slightly
greater time
that is the value that we use for the
presentation layer not how we move
across cream
now if we were to start reversing
direction part way through this
animation
say we set the center the circle back to
zero
and just as before the model wears value
jumped immediately back to zero
but it's not good draw and zero
immediately
sometimes we fear animations the the
next thing that happens
is just going to be that we destroy
the currency animation
and that's gonna be why you see that
John we create a new theory animation
replace it
and just like before we get that new CA
animations from value
from the current layers what about you
which was five hundred
in this case now we didn't make it all
the way to the 500 but the model though
he was five hundred
so that's an emissions from value is
five hundred and that means if we were
to read this unnatural text that
we're gonna be interpolating from 500 to
zero over a second
and Dean the next spring we render the
animation at a value $500 on the go
ahead and use that
to render the circles position and
that's why we have that job
so why I meet from five hundred back to
zero across the screen
and so we finally get his era
begin from current status a little
difference like you understand how that
works as well
so say that we're at this point we're
part way through the animation and then
we met the code to reverse direction
so we say and meet again this time begin
from current state
well again we're gonna destroy
the animation that was pre-existing and
create a new animation
but the this time we're going to create
a new animation with the from value
derived from the presentation layers
value
rather than from the model wears value
now the time is animation was created
the presentation I was 150 and so we
make an animation
which is going to animate from 150 20
instead of from 500 20
and therefore the next frame with
rendered the animation with a value
150 and so we don't have that positional
jump
so things like everything's good for
animating back towards the origin
but we still have the kind a brick wall
feeling
as we look at these three circles
earlier like you understand why that is
now as well say they were gonna be
animating the circle from lesser the
screen to the right side of the screen
just taking snapshots at a regular
interval as it goes
snapshot might look something like this:
now if part way through that animation
we were to stop and
try reversing direction at the circle
again and then
if we were to take snapshots at the same
interval we we get snapshot that looked
a little bit like this
so the first thing we notice is
that we are animating a smaller distance
over the same out I'm
and that's going to create a problem
because we can see that the slopes at
these two lines are not the same
that's not gonna be smeared but maps
not the whole problem you might think
okay we could just that are Asian
we can get around this I think about
using
if you were doing either any doubt this
might be with us not just look like
and then if we were to stop part way
through reverse direction that problem
will be exacerbated
looking at a plot this is the situation
we have
really the issue we have is that the
velocity components move
was that kink in the middle of the graph
and i cant is exactly what I did
animations are gonna help us all
so I'd like you to understand how added
animation actually work
under the hood returning this example
here
what they we try to animate across the
screen
as before we're gonna creating you see
animation and we're gonna have this
added to flag that yes this is the
property that already existed on the
animation
you can use that in previous versions of
IRS it's just that you like it is
configuring the spore you now by default
the from value is a little different the
two values now presents let's talk about
this
the familiar with the to tell you are
interpreted relatively
to the model value every frame with an
additive
animation that's basically the purpose
about animations
so we create from value by subtracting
be
the previous value from the destination
die basically two months from
and we create the true value by just
signing 20 so that's gonna do with that
every frame
not animation is going to amid a
contribution
here -0500 which when added to the mall
value
currently 500 real form the presentation
0 so 500 plus -0500
is zero and that's why the first frame
is that circle all the way on the left
as it starts moving towards the right
the animations contribution decreases
its always getting closer to zero
so -0500 -4 50 -0400
and the Sun is getting closer to zero
now part way through if we
reverse direction again the model value
jumps
over the left side but this time we're
not gonna destroy that animation
we're gonna make a second animation
added on top
so now we're gonna use both on those
animations values
0 plus native 300 plus 500
is 200 and you'll see even though we've
got in this animation reverse direction
we overshot a little bit we didn't
reverse direction instantly and that's
because we can't do that
without making a jump in the loss to the
component so here we overshot a little
bit
but now the second animations can
overtake the first animation
all the way until we get back to the
origin so the stack
Raja like so we get back to the origin
they both have a zero value everything's
happy
we have this crap and now we have this
crap
cac-40 so I promise that I would tell
you
I a little more detail about when this
is going to work and when it's not going
to work
so there are a set of keys on which this
behavior supported
basically they're your geometric keys so
this kinda stuff is
is all they work fine for moving objects
on the screen scaling them returning
them
it's all going to be fine there are
certain behind the rotation flow which
work in other ones which don't so
this really briefly if you were to
actually try to animate the layers
transform property
I you're only going to get this additive
behavior for
a fine transformations the definition of
an alpine transformation
is that it keeps parallel lines smooth
after the transformations applied so the
bird on the left
we've rooted in about the axis mister
lines
I'm sorry power lines are not smoothest
a parallel caroline's
pre transformation remain parallel after
the transformation
that is now fine transform September
left Caroline still parallel
burn the right pro lines no longer
parallel so a
rotation animation that is like the
bottom left
will use additive animations rotation
animation fly to burn the right one
month is a few the compatibility
requirements as well
this feature will not work with keeper
many nations at the time being
and it also will not work if there are
pre-existing repeating animations
because we that can get you to a place
for you have an unlimited number of
animation stacking forever
it's not good for the system finally
will also not work
if you've gone behind you like its
backing created pre-existing absolute
animations on that later
but these are these are perhaps not
common
situations now I said that
not all keys are supported for instance
alpha is not supported and you really
know what setting the circles to color
is going to do you know that that's an
enemy to property but
you really know what that means um
and so you can it be defensive about
whether property support additive
animations or not
by continuing to use begin from current
state so
for centered on tax for that animation
we're not going to use the old begin
from current state behavior behind the
scenes we are still gonna make that how
to defend a mission
but for the other two properties for
alpine for the text color
that at least to get position preserving
transitions
so you can go ahead and eat use begin
from current state
centered on tax will be additive the
others
will use the presentation value in the
reverse directions the other thing
that's interesting about this transition
it's worth a side effect
you know you like it doesn't actually
have a way for you to cancel inflate
animations right now there's no way to
do that
so some people do it like this make a
new animation
with their duration and you just set the
value something else
now that will sort of stopping played
animations just because the behavior if
you like it and emissions has always
been that
when you make a new animation we throw
out the old one replace it with a new
one in this new ones gonna be
0 2nd block but as we just saw
we don't throw out those animations
anymore so this is not going to stop any
implied animations instead you just have
to drop down
the sea animation API directly do your
work
when we think keep in mind is behaviour
completion and others
intermission stack so before
if you on a mission completion handler
you started reversing direction
as I thought we were going to remove
that animation
so when we remove an animation we call
your completion handler the argument is
finished and so when we call your
completion and where we call it with a
value
balls because the animation didn't
finish and
then we'll create the new emission and
that when complete will call that
completion and over well
in the additive animations world if you
have a
I would have been a mission with
completion handler and then you reverse
directions
then remember we don't throw out that
animation we make
a new animation and so
we
don't have a completion analytical right
now variations to go
it's only when we actually get to the
end the animation
we call the completion handler and we
come we call the completion handler
with the finished argument if true
because the first animation
didn't finish it's just another
animation was added on top
so this could be surprising potentially
and what I'm telling you is do not be
surprised I
sup informer transition will be smooth
about a fault
this is a great thing however
their arse some kind renovations that I
have supported the system and so
you should do is begin from current
state if you're not sure about whether
you're animating
supported she supported scenario or not
that's fine will do
the best thing we can do and finally
do keep in mind that those completion
handlers may stack because that does
actually represent
a-changin' when we are calling me back
so we've talked about
a transition from animation to animation
now that you've got these animations and
flight you do still want to be able to
interact
with your application for josh is gonna
come back up talk about transitioning
from
animations to jesters alright thanks
Andy
we're getting close we've got one
transition point last
that we're still finding we've got some
issues with and by default probably are
noticing that in this transition point
going from your animation back to your
gesture
you're actually by the fall actually
able to even start and interaction
so before we can even talk about making
its move that we have to talk about
how to allowed gestures and touch events
and interactions to begin
while you're in the middle %uh wannabes
animations so it's going to take a look
at why this is the case and what we can
do about it
so here we got some big view and I put a
sub you in that eye color:blue just to
make it
standout a and we're gonna say that
we're taking that deliver animating it
over to the right
into this position on the right side of
the screen a
with some standard you like an animation
using the you live you enemy with
duration
API and let's say it happily through and
a half way through
we want to start interacting with it so
let's say that
touch comes down on the screen and it
comes down on top where that is
visually in the presentation layer and
the default thing that you get if you
just do you live you animate with the
racin
is that animation better in progress as
a result of that do not allow user
interaction
during the animation so that he was
gonna get hit tested
and the touch will be attached to that
view
but because the interaction is disabled
by default
what you'll find is that the touch
actually doesn't get delivered anywhere
and just get swallowed
it just disappears it's as if it didn't
even happen so
obviously we want to fix that and the
way we can go about doing it
is by using an animation option called
you I view animation option allows user
interaction
not too surprising the name and you can
pass this into the UI do animation
and iteration API's and this will enable
interaction during these animations
now what you've opted into allowing user
interaction
you're basically saying I got this I i'm
in advance
developer here and I know what I'm doing
and I'm gonna take care making sure that
the right thing happens
so I you know but upon you like it is
making it safe
so that you don't have weird things
going on but what you up two and you're
saying that you're going to deal with it
and you know how to do the right thing
so we'll talk about what the right thing
is so again let's look at what happens
if a touch comes down in that view
now this part is probably going to be a
little surprising at first if you've
tried it
what actually happens is that you'll
find that the touch gets his that had
tested
to that big you in the back which
probably wasn't what we meant because we
touch with visually on what was there
in fact if you go and put a touchdown
where we're moving the at the view to
where it's going to animate to
you find that the thing that we had
tested the thing that's currently
animating over today
on understanding what happens goes back
to what any was saying about the
difference between model and
presentation values
was even able user interaction you're
saying that you're going to take control
this whole system then you're gonna
decide the right place to go do it
and do a test because we don't actually
know if the thing you're animating is
something that you intend to interact
with
or just something that is interactive
animating in a system but you're
actually trying to interact with that
thing behind it
so really were hit testing the model
values that all these layers
but if you want to interact with the
thing at animating you really wanna be
had testing a presentation values
so if you go talk about how we can make
a presentation layer hit test instead of
a default model value
test and you do to do that
we can override the head test with that
method on our you eye view that
animating
to make it so that it's gonna hit test
its presentation value estimate model
value
now by default the method is going to
take a point
it's the point in the view that is being
hit tested
and that's the view are the point that
you like it thinks that you've touched
but as I mentioned it done that in model
space so we have to convert it back
to presentation layer space to see if
it's currently inside where we are as
were animated
so we can take that point that passed in
a converted back into our super view
so a convert point to view are super
view
what they've got in the Super views
coordinate space then we can convert it
back into our presentation layer space
so we convert out using model space and
then back in using presentation space
so we can see where it is inside of
where we are currently given
that we have an animation in progress so
we can do that by getting our
presentation layer
and using that to do the conversion back
into our court in space
once we got that converted into the
right space then we can just call super
and what it do what i was gonna do so
return super it ask
passing in the converted point now
increasing patient space and everything
else can just move on as it had before
so what we've done that we can talk go
pick take a look at what's going on
again
now we've been able to user interaction
we touch down and other right view is
gonna get hit
given what we're trying to accomplish
now keep in mind that other API's
like touch location and view are also
assuming model space convergence
all the UI kit behaviors by default are
converting using model space
so if you now enable hit testing into
something at animating and here
in the progress up doing the animation
and you want to start handling touches
in the view
if you ask for that touch location and
view it's going to be back in model
space
so you would have to be careful to go
and make sure that you know which space
here at your
interacting in so really the reason that
the default is to disable is because
once you enable interactions you have to
start knowing more about what's going on
and being careful to be using the
correct word its basis
but most of the time this is actually
probably not gonna be a problem
because usually appear enabling user
interaction on something that animating
you're probably trying to grab the thing
and stop animation
so really what we're gonna talk about
now is how we stop the animation that
the key part that were interested in
right now we got hit testing working
once were touching down how do we stop
animation I then he mentioned
there is no direct API on you like it to
stop in animation
they were going to use the Seattle area
guide to do that but there's another
interesting component that we have to
keep in mind
because editors Randy through the whole
story of how things go when they're
animations on a layer
and part of that is that the model by
was already at its final location
so if we just remove the %uh the the
animation from the layer
that was the thing that was keeping it
in the center of the screen visually
right now so would snap to the end
so we would touchdown on the object or a
movie animation it would snap out from
under a finger in mind however it was
going
so we don't want that we have to go get
the presentation values up where it
currently is on screen
and sent those to be the new model
values so that there's no jump
now let's assume that they were doing
was animating just its position its
location on screen
on I'll give you an example how that
would look in that case of course if
you're animating something else like its
bounds or some other property you have
to do the same thing for whatever
property you're animating
so in this case we're just doing the
center so let's get them view get its
liar
get the layers presentation layer which
is going to be where it is on screen
right now
and in this case I'm asking for its
position because that's where it's its
location on screen so we'll throw that
away here
and we just want to send that to be a
new model values that once we remove the
animation it doesn't jump it's going to
end up right here
now presentation I i sorry at
you i'd use property for this is called
senator CA layers is called
position they're actually the same thing
so you can just assign one to the other
and not really worry about it they are
the same property that is have a
different name and you like it
and coronation I so want to set that now
the model value is putting it where we
thought it should be visually cuz that
the presentation value so we can just
going to a movie animation
now in this case I'm taking the shortcut
and just removing all animations
now you prolly wanna be a little more
careful than that when you're doing it
yourself to make sure your removing only
the animations really mean to be
removing you
have to be cognizant of whether or not
there are others there but that the key
to it is just removing the right
animations
so I mention the things we're gonna be a
little easier
when we were talking about you a dynamic
animator earlier in the talk
now this is the place where things get
easier when you're using a dynamic
animator
because dynamic animator doesn't have
presentation and model space
we don't have the same complication of
having to figure out where it is on
screen compared to where the model is or
anything like that
then again it's all just wherever it is
and it's happening in your process
and the model value is the correct
position on screen right now
so stopping this for a dynamic animators
a lot simpler
we'll take a look at the code that we
wrote earlier and are just to recognize
our method where we are handling the end
it case
now of course we're trying to do with
new touch is coming down so we want to
handle the began case on our gesture
recognizer
so next space for that and my suggestion
for what you would do here
there's a couple things you could do but
the the 1 I'm going to suggest as a good
option
it actually just remove the thing that
was animating from the dynamic item
behavior
because what he removed it no longer
going to interact with any of the other
views its gonna lose any
a the law said it may have had because
he just took it out a bit
dynamic system and now you'll be able to
manipulate it and move it around
yourself
so we can take a dynamic and behavior
and remove the thing that we're trying
to interact with our target view
now of course once we removed it it's no
longer gonna have any new velocity when
we try and add velocity later so we have
to put it back in when the jesters done
so I'll take that dynamical behavior and
added back at the end
and there's other things you could do
instead if you really wanted to leave it
in the dynamic system you could subtract
of the current velocity so it would just
come to a rest
but personal the easiest thing to do is
to remove it and it's also probably what
you mean a lot of cases
because it'll stop it from smacking
against other abusing here
system as you drag it around
so now we've really dealt with most of
the
the transitions I want to talk about we
got our just heard animation going
we got animation animation going we r
animation back to gestures working
so it seems like everything's good like
we all visually everything looks great
so we should be done but we got fifteen
minutes left so
what's what's going on well
there's some complications that really
start to come into things want to do
this in a real application
so far everything we've been talking
about is pretty theoretical its if
you're just doing animations are pretty
easy
but if you in any real application you
have other state
transient animation state that exists
only during transitions are animations
maybe when you start some transition you
create a bunch mixed reviews to use
during that animation and when the
animation is done you destroy them
you have to know what the right times
are to create and destroy these things
and if you're stacking animations with
additive animations and we're figuring
out that we're starting at removing
things in the middle by
allowing interaction adjusters it's no
longer immediately obvious where the
right places are
to make some of these changes the view
hierarchy to set up and tear down your
transition animation state
so we're gonna go through too much
insight about this actually
what we're going to do is just do a demo
shown you how you can make this happen
in a real app
so it is gonna come back up and write an
app for you that does all that
thank you very much I am extremely
excited about this for the talk
I don't think we've ever talked about
this topic publicly and we've been
confronting a great deal ourselves as we
think about
how to effectively deal with these kinds
of problems
we want everything to be fluid as much
as possible in our system
and that means wrestling with these
problems there's a superstructure
upstate
around your animations which you need to
deal with but you can't forget
so I have a very important application
here it's been a it's been a key thing
for us
bruising is a a test ground for for this
experimentation
it's called hubbell bird sometimes
you to Burke so
great features press the button Gilbert
sometimes you don't a bird you press the
button broke a sweat may not have bernie
more
that's great but
someone here in a site that if they okay
well into this burden don't know I don't
actually want the bird
I i was i was overeager with the bird
put the burned away Galway bird
but you can't because the buttons
disabled
and that's frustrating you know really
want the feeling
where and animations in progress and so
the world must stop
until the animation is done so we can
look at our code we can say okay well I
I see a couple up
pretty big red flags here looks like
we're disabling re enabling the bird
toggle button
when i when this animations and flight
so all those going coming up echoed that
everything will be cool
you know that but it's not the same
anymore looks good
fourth once walked through this but what
is method together
because I I think it actually all strata
lot a common problems that people have
when trying to make this kind of thing
work
so this is just the center for the bird
expanded property which you'll see if
that's just a property
I'm and the property which is an
immutable
which means I'm designed it so that it
is that this property inside an
animation walk then they will be
animated
I think that's a nice top we do that by
inheriting
the parents animation context by making
a you I D animation block
as a zero length rations he'll see here
there's a title bird method
that sets the bird expanded property
inside on a mission like that so that
part works let's let's walk to the rest
a bit together
is a better state we keep track of is
the bird expanded
and if that the bird is supposed to be
expanded
a new we make a merger or view set it up
we want to animate from you know being
all with but 0 height
so we do a little late out initially so
this is kinda like a preamble
you know we're making some stuff that we
need unit set up
and then we actually do the animation
this is the part that is now active
that's great you know where we're just
changing as constraints constant
tell you fill out this item in animation
block that will soon decide the correct
abounds in position animations actually
get things moving
and I only have something a post stamp
when animations completed
if the bird is no longer supposed to be
expanded
we clean this up because the bird is
being drawn
with some very novel an expensive
rendering technologies
and we don't wanna waste system
resources on that you know
gotta be good samaritans so this is the
entire you what's going on here
and the problem arises
when we remove these enabled centers
because we can run through this method
multiple times while the animation thing
flight
this completion block as I said earlier
is going to run
even if there are new animations related
to the bird also running
so we really have a more complex state
machine
going on then it seems at first
so I'm just gonna jump right to the
solution here
only a few lines change first let me
prove that I have solved are burned
toggling problems
was very nice we can be indecisive about
the bird safely
and hearing the code I've only changed a
few lines
I got a new I've are now I'm always
gonna be tracking
how me active transitions we have
so at the bottom every time the bird
expand property changes we increment
that
and every time a bird expansion or
contraction animation completes
we documented so we're just keeping
track in the number up inflate state
transitions currently
and then we change our preamble and post
ample to consider that counter
we say okay well only do this preamble
if
we're transitioning from not having any
animations to
having some animations similarly
only to our post ample if we're
transitioning from
having animations to no longer having
any animations at all
and that alone solves this problem
I do wanna show you what this would look
like
with I was seven style ambitions
note that the bird jumps to the finished
value
when I try to make it reversed direction
so even if I were to use the beginning
from current state option
to try to use presentation values you
see that when I reverse direction
it's kinda like the bird hit a brick
wall
now we much prefer
the additive animation solution much
smoother
so that's great I wanna she quickly
I was gonna comment this a little more
in order to make clear how general the
structure of creative
almost everything I've written here
doesn't have to do with birds or
toggling
that is the key point because you might
be riding up front idler
you know I'm no I don't want to be
creative
sup with a few seconds into the preamble
section in the preamble section
you can deal with all the possible
states we only have a preamble for the
bird becoming expanded
you could have a preamble the other way
similarly discounter
that's not about birds are talking
that's just about transitioning between
states
and the post ample we don't oppose table
for the bird being expanded
we could we proposed a bill for the
burden contracted or point out that
we're checking the state at the time
the completion handler being called
rather than the argument being passed
into this method
because again is complete members can
stack and the state might no longer be
what you thought I what's
the one last thing I want to point out
is that this is the solution for two
states
but if you had three states that you can
move between you can handle that this
way to
you just need a counter for each up the
state's
not cover with track how many
transitions to or from that state or in
flight
right now we only have one counter
because the number of transitions to or
from
each other states in our by stable
system is always the same
so this is a solution which generalizes
and which doesn't have anything to do
with birds are talking
alright with a doctor slides to wrap up
thank you
as I said earlier we don't stop the
world will animations are in flight they
might be beautiful but your users trying
to do things
we also want to keep things fluid so
use that just a velocity translated
in the animated actions which result
make the interface which feels more
responsive
once you've got an emissions in flight
make sure that a smoothly transition
any new animations which might replace
those first at the den emissions
finally as I was saying a moment ago
don't stop the world
try to make animations interruptible as
much as possible it is more work
but we've talked through some techniques
for dealing with it
and finally keep in mind that there may
be additional Associated State
on top of these animations
that is often what makes it more
difficult to enable user interaction
while animations are in flight but we've
just talked through one technique which
i think is quite general
for dealing with that finally
if you have more questions I encourage
you to ask Jake we have a coronation
programming guide which
actually does talk about many of these
topics and is it will perform where you
can
ask your peers questions I hope you've
had a fantastic conference
I can't wait to see what you make