hello
thank you very much for coming today and
if you're watching later on video thanks
so much for watching i'm can cash and a
and their session is called strategy
for a great work so think we all try to
do great work I certainly
always try to do great work regardless
if the result in the outcome
certainly the effort is directed towards
doing something great
I think that probably the same for all
love you that's why you're here at the
conference today
that may be why you're watching later on
video houses subject thats
very important to me I I like talking
about like thinking about it and I was
left on stage in 2012 with a
I talk all bleak basics plus habits I
talked with him
some tactical concern some real soon not
in both think about how to setup project
and then had run projects once you have
them going in this is very
tactical served any details things like
code review
when you know working with fewer other
people that you might have on a team
so today you know it different I i would
like to
in this session talk about from higher
level ideas kinda move it up to
the level of strategy rather than
tactics
and so I went out and got a helpful
quotation
from Wikipedia to a started thinking
about what the difference between
strategy and tactics
is into tactics to the actual means used
to gain an objective
what strategy the overall campaign plan.
which may involve complex operational
patterns activity in decision-making
that lead to tactical execution
certainly the a complex operational
pattern sounds like programming to me
right I
definitely so you know I think that
really
30 strategy yes you have been a big idea
what you might want to do
and that really should hopefully be
driving what you actually do to
accomplish the goal
right so today I'd like to talk about
some of these ideas and high-level ideas
that inspire and inform
my every day work but really
this session is not you know sir how to
make a great project in 21 days
try two minutes it's not going to be
it's never that simple right every time
you see something like that axe
experience as a 21-day
its never ever ever that simple so
for simple kinda media need a plan for
kinda
attacking the problem here and so today
how many do that is I tell you some of
my stories
project that I've been involved in um
but you know there's kinda like a note
of caution when you hear stories
and maybe try to apply it to your own
life and I have an example here like
failure in Las Vegas
and you see somebody go by was carrying
a big pile of chips already get them
cashed in
you stop the person said we what did you
do to get that big pile of chips
and their to come I put it all on 14
K so
its true but not so useful to you
right you go over and put it on 14 you
may or may not get the same result most
likely not
so hopefully the stories will be
interesting to you
but the real goal before during and
after the story
rates particularly after is to extract
out the lessons from the stories
because I think the lessons if you take
them in the aggregate starts stringing
together some russians
serve points toward the strategy it
certainly does for me
today eight stories
eleven lessons take all those lessons
put them together and
really that that is what informs my work
and again of course I'm always trying to
do great work so hopefully this will
this will all come together a nice pics
ok with the end
soap to begin with stories
number one stories like a crystal ball
in the election
is no a good idea when you see it so
I joined Apple in June of 2001 and if
you
you think back to that time on Mac OS
10 version 10 dotto was released
about three months before now
it's come a long time ago we think about
it the browser on the platform
was Microsoft Internet Explorer it
that's the browser that shipped
with the operating system from Apple
now we've had there was no framework
to load and render web content
right so we've just had a nap but no
framework so my job
long with someone else going Don we
joined same day our job became
make apple a web browser and in
objective-c framework
to again loading render rate web content
and make that available for the PI to
you all to bed developers
so
we start looking at my options were what
were the options available to time in
you see
through the leading candidates there
some of these where
our commercial products Apapa high
option
some of them were open source project
out there in the world going on
arm we could you know go and meet
perhaps adopt that source code for
procter we can also start from scratch
we considered it
um absolutely so my job
you know to begin to do some technical
investigation up in a particularly the
open-source
I options I am
and can i download Mozilla their toes 11
story II took
per week I remember to try to just get
Mozilla to build on the Mac
and I remember at one point I am I
wanted the steps in this long recipe if
steps that need to get done to get
muscle to build
I need to rebuild the the Metro works
the library
was one of the steps so this was not a
straightforward thing but he eventually
got a building in you know
okay um but this disc process went on
for weeks
you know when I i went you know and and
got these you know the server these
programs the commercial prop products
you know that what he did for that was
you know got them running in
30 doing some performance analysis and
say you know unico compatibility in
and so to between the commercial
products though those test results in
the open source project
some sort if I reckoning okay how much
source code was their
how easy it would be to adapted and so
forth her
you know to test results showing I
printed out on paper
but I couldn't have a demo
no damn just test results
to write about that time getting new
engineer at our team the winning Richard
and so I showed him you know described
to him basically a to describe to you
you know what I've been doing
I showed him the test result in he said
really what have you been to a
six weeks in this is all you have so
you know if I quote yeah I just gonna
shrugged and said that I have
for he just didn't think very much of
that and so he went away and two days
later
he had a demo he took one of those
options KHTML
which is the the the web rendering
engine what that was parted the key D E
desktop environment for Linux heat
ground
that source code got it running on a Mac
just did whatever kind of hack said he
needed to do to get it running
and had Conqueror Akii browser
running on a Mac in the next window
this was amazing
absolutely amazing just standing there
in like looking
at a browser running on the matter fi
can we say to what it was like
a crystal ball whose absolutely amazing
and we saw all the people who are
involved in you know not only are on the
project but the decision makers at the
company
saw that KHTML was our future this
this was just like you opened up this
tunnel to
like the future it was absolutely
amazing
and so the lesson from this experience
know a good idea when you see it really
for me I kinda felt like an bumbling
idiot
there I was for six weeks you know
trying to do you figure out what to do
and really had nothing and someone new
came in and in two days
he had the future right there
that we could use now sooted
lesson for this again is really what
does this mean you no good he when you
see it is even if some
something to like this happens to you
when you're made to look like an idiot
don't
doesn't matter I didn't care it
shouldn't matter to you either
because there's actually some a couple
of good things about this experience
number one I had a great new team member
who I was gonna be
now involved it's going to be helping me
to come to make this
project happen an he's really proved in
two days here's a really good
I am and so is just like what it was in
Houston next day well we
kinda know what to do right we're gonna
start you make in the future real
and so
that's kinda the story it like a crystal
ball but you know there's a bonus
lesson here too not only know a good
idea when you see it
but Canada extra leptin up make
demos and prototypes if you're starting
a new idea
don't him test results her at all well
and good
but you should also at the same time
make something
that you can actually begin to use
like you want to use the real thing that
you're gonna be making ultimately in the
future
get that open up your own travel to the
right get something in front view and
working
as soon as you can that's like a crystal
ball
no good idea when you see it and make
demos and prototypes
so the next
story number two is the black
abolished and the lesson is don't try to
solve every problem might want
so continuing right on from the end of
that last arc HTML
fantastic we group good looking the more
we look at the code
the more we are confident that this was
really the
the way for us to go but really what do
we do now
rate me when we to right and so you
imagine open source we
going you know party the Katy desktop so
we went
and we downloaded all Katie but the
thing is we only want idk HTML only
each email a rendering engine
and we also want to KJs the JavaScript
engine so
the job became to serb draw a line
around
just third key HTML part have this whole
desktop environment
so that we could just extract that use
it has turned out to be about a hundred
source files seems tractable
so the next step was to bring those
files or the Mac
after compiling them one at a time right
critic didn't compile because we just
took the source code expected this whole
other desktop environment around it
and now we just heard for the whole rug
out from under it
so you know it didn't compile we had a
whole bunch of missing things and so we
just began
stabbing them in stopping in missing
functions one at a time
and these were very very light that
these were only stops in header files
right to it only wanted to it surged
define the problem in terms of all the
missing things
that we needed to ed this was very very
slow work
it took about another six weeks six
weeks is kinda magical number
for this this project this took about
six weeks it just
compiling II it would be like
channel 11 hours of compiling a every
single day
I am so it was pretty I'm
pretty painstaking and then even at this
that nothing link because it makes these
are only header files
through her only running we were tight I
made a custom make faster don't even try
to run the linker just just like you try
to
show us what we were missing I'm
so after we were done with that right we
had another six weeks
weeks to get everything to link actually
going in and
finishing out so did the header file
actually putting in
you know some stub implementation for
everything and the even
then we had lots of crashes because in a
lot of functions that return strings we
returned empty strings and you know it
obviously there to lower not really what
a lot of the code was expecting so
we also added a whole lotta blog
statements to our implementation saying
yeah this is not implemented at all i
mean it returns a value but edgy you
know
should not implement it all partially
implemented yea we think we're pretty
close n
implement that we had a whole bunch a
blog statements that
we which fee will a whole bunch lawyer
message is getting written to the log in
to track to try to use the program
and after this whole process many many
weeks
we eventually wound up with the Mac
program to used
cage email and then one day
the lights came on so my coworker
richard was actually off on vacation he
was really kinda doing this you know
certain leading up the effort to
get things to link in that crash so much
and then I came in and took over the
process
and actually got the first
being to draw on the screen I looted
a URL in this case WWW dot yahoo dot com
and euros reams and reams and reams and
log messages go by
in the program didn't crash then there
was a short pause
and it drew
a black obelisk
so this is the first if the first thing
that WebKit you know
a Safari ever ever you know what became
Safari ever rendered
now to see it little bit of a secret is
actually turned out if
that this was reversed so that the
publisher been on the others are decided
to scream but you know that
we we fix that took a little geometry
problem very soon after
but you can imagine did you know that
once I got this going at Sky Go Go
infection everybody who was disclosed in
the project were all sitting around for
like 2001
face Odyssey with this black obelisk
going who
so that was a a very happy happy moment
now the lesson from this experience
is don't try to solve every problem it
won't
at this point we had almost no knowledge
of how the innards have Keech Gmail
worked
this was simply a mechanical process
of making the compiler happy making the
linker happy
making it so the program didn't crash in
we try to do something with it
it was all very very mechanical the
compiler says
there's something missing go where that
thing so that it no longer missing
right now it turns out of course a a web
rendering engine is a very very
complicated piece of software
an but we just could we didn't have the
band with
to think about it at this point as we
were trying to just get those lights to
come on
that began to happen as soon as we had a
program that would no longer crash right
don't care if you guys trying to attack
in New big problem you've got this big
problem space particularly
if that problem space is new to you to
try to figure out what the most
important thing is to do first
and do that don't think about the whole
prom or try to
operate on the whole solving the whole
problem
at one time right don't
try to solve every problem at once and
that's the plank
so the next story number three is
the hardest problem and the lesson is
find
smart friends and listen to them so
fast-forward to the fall of 2003 in my
job became too ed
editing to WebKit so we wanted to use
WebKit edit HDMI male
in mailed out a app on back with 10 we
want to make
editing in WebKit lookin work like text
editor
K to the problem it is kinda been unit
printed
problem that we try to solve is somewhat
obvious right a lot of
other platforms in particular I window
sends
you know HTML mail from Outlook and we
wanted to
not only render it which we could now
that we had WebKit but we also wanted to
edited because if you think about it
before it WebKit had editing
the web content which open your mail
message as an attachment in RTF talking
with big
breaking insertion point after you
discovered delete the whole thing with
one
to eat an entire web page with one one
backspace
so that's not what we wanted we want to
be able to get in to the details of the
web content to get it right
so now the hardest problem
I have ever ever worked on in my well
many
many years of programming is arrow
navigation
through web content now what do I mean
by that so
picture a a a wet tiny little web
document like this
and what you do then is you hit the
arrow key the right number of times
and the insertion point wind up at the
end that's it
disco character by character have the
insertion point chopin the right place
each time you press the arrow key and
then similarly
press the R key to go back the other way
in San the insertion point back to the
start
that was it this was turned out to be
very very difficult know why is this
because
you know on white thing RTF document
which is just too
series of characters in indexes into
basically nureyev characters
what content is a is a tree structure so
if you see on the top where the
insertion point is
at the n and then if you look at the the
model
the web document the insertion point
would we get the in
if in the web document insertion point
was
their or their or their
or their right so what I had he was a
complex model the relationship with the
model changed
but the view didn't change me
senator begin thinking about this I used
the DOM the the web don the Document
Object Model that the API for dressing
web content
and to use positions in the web
content to try to understand where to
make the insertion point blank
and so i think is illustrated I came up
with this notion have an equivalent
Dom positions compositions
that would make different compositions
but that would make the insertion point
blank in the same spot
K so I started writing some code for
simple right al
arrow algorithm here get the insertion
point position
in a DOM position then fine dysfunction
in use this function
equivalent downstream position to find
the DOM position
that which still make the insertion
point blank in the same spot but was
closer to the end of the document
and then go to the next position and
then set the insertion point there now
that seems reasonable but kinda focus in
on these two
important functions here right will
naturally it's a program right image if
you wanted to
perfect results the functions need to
work perfectly in the problem with that
was the equivalent downstream position
was implemented in terms of get next
composition
sometimes are have this feedback
process going were bizarre things happen
because above wouldn't feed into itself
right and cost something that was very
very difficult to understand and
diagnose
simply by looking at the result in the
view
does complicated right to get right and
then
other issues come up as well what if
you're already at the
ended the document visual and if the
document as you know if you've ever
probably viewed source in an HTML
document there's
of in many many things at the very least
the cassava closing /body tag closing
each email tech water times their script
content there might be
you know time I P style content after
there could be any sorts
sort of information that not visible
after the visible and if the document
and by Tom position it would it would
you know if you just kind of fended off
to position it o'Mara we go there
and there won't be a place for the
insertion point to point to this is a
problem as well
and then what if you wanna move by word
because the ultimate goal was to make a
text editor
right to hold down the option key an
arrow in the new move word by word not
character by character
and so I was in know where I was stock
working on this
for it sir was just three thank you very
good say six weekly
magical number
but for many weeks without really
feeling like I was making progress
so I asked for help and fortunately I
had some very smart people on my team
which course the
two other stories have already
illustrated explain the problem
to them much as I adjusted to you and
their solution came back
very very clear the DOM positions were
too low level
house trying to build a very a complex
edifice but I was using
to you fundamental an abstraction
to get the job done when you do more
powerful attraction so they came up with
when they gave me what they call it
visible position
and all this was this is super sport
coat is a Supersport class
that represented our place in a document
where the insertion point and blink
30 and then secondarily at library
called visible units
they could take a visible position and
moved by words lines and documents
okay so they gave me this design now the
point is
that I still had the hard work of
figuring everything out
but now I had a complete
outline all the code that I needed
everyplace word by word well I knew now
there was actually a place in the
document is a stub function
that was weird the move word by word
code should go where that should live
and so this dist really the set have
abstractions really helped me to just
organize the work and figure out where
the solution should live
it also made a easier to think about the
prom so that I went up with fewer
these kind of functions that fed back on
each other producing
bizarre results so
when you're blocked don't be blocked
find smart friends and listen to them in
this case they said visible position
visible units I said okay
I will do that and it worked
absolutely work I certainly went back
and got some more they're helping
details but this was the big big help
find smart friends and listen to them
particularly when you're stuck
to not stay blocked and this is how I
got through
my hardest programming problem
and so the next story number four is
quality and the left in his work
should explain itself
so fast-forward to 2005 now
and I joined the iPhone development
project pretty
early on and initially I join to work on
WebKit
because it seems like a a good match for
my skills and experience
at Apple but I soon transition to work
on keyboards
so now if you think about it right this
is kind of what we had when we started
with the iPhone
I we had a screen and we had this
notion at the keyboard will be on the
bottom the app content would be on the
top
annie cruz the big question was well
what should the keyboard
do how should it work watched it look
like
and if you have seen you know even from
the very beginning that the
you know that the Steve Jobs
announcement have the iPhone your you
know the original announcement in 2007
he pointed at very very clearly this
virtue of the iPhone that
it didn't have those placed the keys on
the bottom we could draw the keyboard
and make it look like whatever we want
it
some doubt jumping back to the giving up
that story because
even stages the end of that story right
we didn't have placed the key so we need
to experiment what we're gonna do
right how we gonna replace those plastic
keys with software
and we came up with many many ideas
for how we would do this now there are a
lot of challenges
a particularly at the beginning when we
were only with dealing with
touchscreen keypad particularly a i
touch screens
a in general and touchscreen keyboard
specifically
to the one in the challenges that this
small target too hard to tap its
pretty logical I'm sure you you even
experience that now the small the tower
at Target get the more difficult they
are to tap
and not only not only that but as you as
you go for a target as you get close to
it your finger
covers up the thing that you're looking
for so the smaller than it is
the more difficult it is to you know do
sumfin green a judgment as you get close
for these were we we as in our
experiments we we were ex- seeing their
result this was very challenging to make
a keyboard that worked at all
and so in the beginning we we were
pretty clear we will do this we thought
we were clear
the bigger keys would be the solution
this would solve both problems
so I have an example something in the
spirit
apps wanna the experiments we tried not
an exact
example but something very very much in
the spirit of what we try to call it the
keyboard keyboard
but if you think about you know about
other things in the world are you know
accept a lot of touch input right was a
piano keyboard right
so could maybe conceive a keyboard that
looks like this
so how does this work well I'm gonna try
to protect the Tiki and so
how do you get a key well you look on
all the keys
and you do make a chord multi multi
touch motion
to find all the keys are heavy on it
okay so there you go he H age is
actually got to the same keys
he by age is only on all those two keys
and and and Daiichi
she can see how this would work ray
according keyboard
this is good got the keys are back
you can even really think I'd like you
know it's just like home keys are you
just gonna keep your five fingers right
on top of the key is in you
you know you can use the keyboard like
that at it easy to press the correct key
for that good but it's bad because
there's a learning curve right
the first time experience is a mystery
you see this alphabet soup on this thing
that you click piano keyboard how do I
use this
right and so we were thinking that well
the solution would be we have a tutorial
to teach the people how to use the
keyboard not actually in a different you
know not
this is an ideal actually how some
history
may not happen because the original Mac
ship to the tutorial
to teach people how to use the mouse
since that was new
me so we figure we come up with a
tutorial in the interim you think about
it
is that even if we you know we didn't
have that
keyboard keyboard are you mad enough
that we did we could maybe even come up
with a keyboard that use music to try to
keep people that you could baby play
tonight
so it wasn't the craziest idea in the
world but after each of these
experiments
and each the times we thought through
how to make a tutorial
um we always came back to quality
because your already know how to use it
there's no need for tutorial right you
see the thing
and instead of cash what is this
how do I use it right instead of that
you have
this for you look at it and okay it's
different because it's a touch screen
its
small but where weird sir hauling on and
invoking
write a lot have these kind of these
familiar notions that your already
very very comfortable with so that's why
we wound up with this
and ultimately right we have this today
because we thought was more important
that the work should explain itself
right
you already know how to use quality we
don't need a tutorial
and so this was really the key to that
decision
key a schizophrenic funny word but it's
the here are the key keyboard
but the I'm it's the real reason why we
chose to go with QWERTY
because again we thought that work
explain itself
so the next story number five every word
on every keystroke and to the left is
choose the simplest
thing which might work
to continuing on the development of the
iPhone keyboard
became my job to do the work iniquity
possible
right we had this challenge have
smokey's
difficult to type now into course you
all
care about my problems you just wanna
type quickly
right so the software was gonna need to
help
and so the eventual solution for that
was so auto correction
which Chris what you meant and not what
you did
taking what you didn't figure that what
you meant from it
and of course there's I you know quite a
bit have I
your smart people have thought about the
I
you know text processing and in a text
you note extradition prediction sure
your summer the
to terms that are you know in the state
of the art you know then as now
basin statistics and stochastic
programming conditional random field
know a lot of these involve large
statistical models
to make them work that they rely on
language models
and these were not going to be possible
given to
you note the hardware and software
environment to the original iPhone
not only that I less studied math in the
11th grade
which was in the eighties and it was in
the early eighties
so I'm him so I screws can I was looking
at you know so generous to Catholic
programming okay well you know so
really worried if I was I needed
something simple because
math is hard right
and sell here
it's a little bit have an idea little
little better how how the or a
correction
works right certainly in the you know
who you know way back then in the first
time that I try to get this
get this idea together so you typing a
letter RI well
since the keys are small maybe you meant
those keys
as well so I was highlighted but maybe
you missed
in maybe you meant one of the keys
around RI okay
and then you type the key and walked
similarly maybe you meant one of those
letters around it so even just with two
characters
you can see that there are a number of
possibilities
right and so in it one column are words
that are real words inner
going to be in English Dictionary arm
and the other column there are just
those
words that are in there there letter
combinations but they're not words
you know we have words that I'm at the
one column has
words data in the dictionary and the
other column has just letter
combinations that aren't words
as we do with this is now raw material
right and so
or a correction really ultimately view
too big part of it is just speculation
did you mean this one did you mean that
when did you mean the other one did you
mean this one did you mean this one
and this involved in many many many
dictionary lookups
to just check are these water
combinations are these words in the
dictionary that
is in a selected by the by the user so I
needed something that work really really
fast
and a you know so that the idea was was
offer to me that well you know you could
maybe in as user is typing just kinda
send that dictionary lookup stuff on a
background thread
an you know sorry post the results back
when it's done in Crosby been back then
we didn't have GPD
and so it you know DP threats would have
been the solution and it's like I'm
scared a multi-threaded coat it's hard
it's hard to get right at a secret to
say she's like
there's actually I did have one little
bit of multi-threaded code
in the keyboard in the beginning to do
some initialization and that was as
largest source a bug's a tiny little
piece of code
and that was his largest source a bug
dealing with app startup in
this is launching happenin suspended
Williams said huge source a box
even if just a little bit of code and I
want to keep multi-threading
out %uh or a correction which was much
more complex right
because I wanted to keep thing simple
because I can understand simple
multi-threading is hard I can even like
making a good breakfast in the morning
right to make the egg
make coffee then make the a keeper
single-threaded rate
otherwise it went up with the message
kitchen okay to keep it simple
so here actually a little algorithm for
searching a dictionary
word list on one side
and a little algorithm on the other side
and this is actually thought up by the
same fellow who did the caged emailed Mr
and so he came up with a good idea and
as part of some of our other experiments
and i'd
why I I saw that good idea and I used it
to what you do you have a
Lister words in the dictionary a memory
map it eatery
the list wants to find the line endings
you store those addresses in a pointer
array
you can then binary search in you can
find whether word is in the dictionary
really really fast really really fast
and so next after that I wrote a custom
c plus plus train crash that
could wrap any string in that memory
mapped area
are each of those strings are not
terminated in the end so you could just
kinda going to wrap
and an address and you have a string as
long as realign start
I and so this turned out to be really
really fast like a check dictionary
membership in microseconds
even on the original iPhone hardware
so this was when I really really fast
and to what this
did was it made speculation really
really
cheap and that in turn made auto
correction
possible to go from
this and take all love those
permutations even for as long word as
you might find
in a language and actually go and figure
out
whether that word is going to be in the
dictionary or not
and whether similar options would be as
well mister to be so fast
I stored no state for the current word I
didn't store previous results all I did
was
at restore the string for the users
piping if we think think think back here
all I've had stories I T what if you
typed
the actual characters that were lit up
right not the neighboring ones
only thing stored was the characters
that were lit up
K only such store that string so it
actually
career in the entire algorithm on every
keystroke
from scratch which means of course that
search the whole dictionary seventy
thousand plus words
on every keystroke because to me
this was the simplest thing as I was
thinking about it was the simplest thing
which might work
and by coming up with sufficiently fast
implementations
up this it turned out that with the
simplest thing
didn't work simple is
often speedy and
Voice simple something I could
understand and when they're about record
understand where those bugs might have
been
and everywhere and every keystroke
choose the simplest thing which might
work and again if you're kinda looking
from the beginning a project trying to
think
to the endeavor project and you know
what you might have when you're all done
at White term this way choose the
simplest thing which might work
if you did actually have a crystal ball
you could tell whether maybe your idea
would work
I think the even from the beginning cunt
finger
the simplest thing which could possibly
just give you what you need
go with that first not a good idea
and so the next story number six
is we only need one of these right and
the lesson is only
show your best work
and so fast for it if 2009 I joined
efforts to develop the iPad and at the
iPad Mini Keyboard
and authors by this point I had to sign
quote pasted onto my back want to kick
me
and the other one said because keyboards
so I it was to
a here sir if something that seemed to
be
in my my area and so I noticed that in
landscape returned an iPad 2 landscape
that
the a number of key said you could fit
across the top was close to the size of
a full-size desktop keyboard
and so here it is a representation have
and their is the size of the keys that
we could fit
on an iPad ABC for overlay one on top in
the other
it's pretty close not exact the iPad is
smaller
but it's close and so I'm thinking that
it's okay but you know it's not the
exactly the same size but
auto correction could maybe help you to
type comfortably
right from here big keys across the park
that seem
like a good idea but then we also had to
quit
you know the the question in our minds
what if you wanted more keys we now have
space for them
allocating the space in the original
iPhone keyboard was the place tortuous
because
you know we couldn't even fit you know
that period character in the first
you know in the first you know keyboard
that that you saw we had to put that on
to a secondary key point
and so we didn't have that problem that
we could have more keys we had the room
for them
and so you can imagine that we can get a
start getting some more key issue in
this case I put in shifting caps lock in
10 happen
couple character characters of the site
and then taking a direct your attention
to this year so we would have a switch
that would allow you to go very very
quickly between
come
the one with the keys and in the one
with the more keys and tourists are
similar to what we have where you change
to
numbers and punctuation but this was
really keeping the letters the same
and he's bringing in more keys and so
you know a bunch of us who are working
on this we thought this was
the best of both worlds score
so hi demo this first the
which is as a gulp and so I am
so bringing the iPad you know you can
have the demo reel 'em
and go in there and then there to keep
him there and then you could OKC
put the iPad in front of him and I and
fortunately the work
explained itself to the description was
a short at
we're looking at iPad keyboard options
today here two options press the switch
key
done so he did
he looked at the first keyboard
depressed switch key
the animation he looked at the second
keyboard
the press to switch Keegan he saw the
first one come back
a third time presses switch key fees the
second one come in
and he looks at this for a moment and he
looks up at me and that's really what
are these right
and he's looking at me I
and so I got through a couple times and
so I and he says well which one do you
think
we should use and I said well
you know I think we should use the one
with the bigger keys
because it's just easier to type it
close to the size full-size keyboard
he said okay we'll go with that one
and that was it really a record and
really really was it was it was quick is
that it so that's why we
went up with this and then ultimately
today this
and course the you know the lesson is
only sure your best work
perhaps more than anyone else Steve
understood this
go out and think I've all the ideas that
you can
and get now we just pick up the ideas
but get them and make them and use them
in live with them
and think about them and then try to
figure out which is the best one
so it was interesting to me about that
story is that even though I was under a
lot of pressure
when he asked me which 1i thought was
better I knew
but they didn't have the courage to just
go in there and show him
the one that I thought was really the
best the first time
it needed his extra product that little
bit have
extra investigation libitum extra poking
per se
we women it right which is the best one
which is the second best one with not
show the second best one
right only show your best work
you have to go through all the effort
Chenery lot of ideas to come up with one
that really worth it
and that we only need one of these right
homie show
your best work
okay story number seven is let's tried 2
percent darker
and the lesson is iterating quickly lead
to better work
and so 2012 I
jointed effort to develop Iowa 7 and
course as you know
that one of the big goals for Iowa 7 I
was a whole new look and you have to
question how do you make
all of these choices you know in a lot
of times you know coming up with these
new design ideas
it felt like a game of whack-a-mole
because every decision
affect every other decision that you
make you change one thing
and you had the things over there the
kinda family well with the thing the way
it was before and now it doesn't seem
like that now it seems that the thing
that you just changed dozen really work
well with everything else
and so this required a tremendous amana
tuning
iterating iterating iterating you know
version after version
effort after effort try to get things so
that they all look
like they belong together and so if you
can't cut a break that down here from
you know the process of actually trying
to do that work one design iteration
most the time looks like this K
guy like me will bring a demo to the
designer
the designer will have feedback a Pik
notes
how then go away to make those changes
that the designers requested and we
schedule the next demo
we have that next time we go back to
beginning
fell this process can take hours are
baby
because people are busy right and
sometimes you know it's just it's just
hard to get together
and so we wanted a way to go faster
can we go faster and so Am I very very
smart friend to get smart friends
the real key when I might very smartest
friend came up with this idea
upsetting and water settings while
settings are tunable values
are you take all the settings that you
might want to tune
and put them interested object to choose
to submit a backup properties
news Kb 0 so that when you change when
those properties
the the part to the system they're
interested in those values changing
can know about it she also came up this
way save and restore these options
have and then there was also a way that
you have settings which own
settings which on setting so you could
have a tree have settings
and also came up with an editing you I
and if the editing you I wanna show you
so here's just a very simple example
very simple ap
that I let you manipulate you metric
shapes so I've got not one blue circle
and you can go and with the settings you
are I
you can bring up to hide right in the
app
to look up or sliders in change from one
blue triangle 23
red triangles great and then similarly
we can know this other one that actually
support those nested
settings that would use to iPhone style
site to site navigation to show you the
different levels
settings and so if I take the red
triangles and move it back to the
settings for the
the to circle you have this and so what
did this to you
did something very important this
reduced iteration time because once you
had the right settings surfaced
in the apt he gets it with the designer
engineer could sit with the tire in
trying many many
many options and so we got to the point
where
you know you kinda trying to figure out
what control center could look like in
the design a good thing
well what if we meet two percent darker
even know if you can see that up on the
big screen it's the point a bit
is that we were trying to get tuning to
this level
2 percent darker 2 percent darker on
your left
then on your right wanna
that level of polish inattention to
every single value
in the US so when we had a tuning
session like this it was great because
I could do is go back but back to my
desk now copy that
you know that the default that got saved
from the tuning session
copy those to the new for them commit
scrape
and this made cheap and easy to tune we
could just do
over and over and over and over again
this was the way that we went with just
a handful blur styles for Iowa 7 that
are used consistently everywhere
very very difficult to come up with
those with that settler styles
and this is how we did it by just
hearing iterating in making
into reading easy and cheap the lesson
really
rightish iterating quickly leads to
better work I think
my experience from I was seven was there
was a direct correlation
between how easy we made it try out new
things
and what the quality the final work
product wise
that's what strike two percent darker
lesson is iterating quickly
reach the better work
okay three-member 8
three lessons from making this session
and so this is not the original session
I wrote an entirely different set of
lights
and not only that I did three full
rehearsals with them I like to hurt a
lot before I mean it's important that
that this session goes well for you are
y'all came here and if I'm gonna make
sure they give you a good product image
so
put a tremendous man effort into
preparing the fighting rehearsing
arm and so with another set of slides I
used up a big portion of my time
rehearsing that certified I feud good
thing was
done way ahead of time
it was great it felt good to just be
like when preparing for WBC can be
really points just always seems like
everything is down to the wire
down to the wire in this year plan I was
really ahead of time but had one more
review for the content I had in my
flights just go over the material the
content particular because i'm talking
about.
some past Apple work and it turns out
you know that version just got shot n
you can you can show that they're just
issues that could be resolved the
details aren't important
but there's kinda the one big detail
which is I don't have affection anymore
three weeks ago I had something that was
rehearsed and two weeks ago
I didn't know if I was going to be here
today I am
I need to rewrite
I'm and their or three important lessons
they took away
from that and the first was
during this review session where the
person
who I was submitting my flight for
review
to said you can show that
he didn't raise his voice thank you can
show that
here's why many reasons it's very calm
and even after I mean it was clear it
was bad news to me
and even he found me later initially
made sure that I was okay
with this decision that was a very hard
one to cheer with me
and to the Russian from mississippi kind
to people
but be honest about the work
right there's no reason to like be
shouting
into reading people who work try hard
and doing their best
if you have ever found me in a lab or
you know maybe even to
with what little time we have left in
the conference before 10 if you find me
in a lab today
I am I hope I'll do my utmost to be kind
to you
personally because I'm so glad that
you're here it's a pledge contributing
to our platform
and i wanna see you do great work too
but if you show me peace work to be
honest when I think about it
and those things just need to be kept
separate the personal kindness
and honesty about the work
and secondly it's kind of like a you
know through the def did you know
difference I did the same conifer I
didn't peak is feedback personally
in russian history separate yourself
from your work
now in I always invest a tremendous
amount
have care and emotion into my work its
my nature I can help
after I'm done making something
and bring it to the stage the 3d demo
if they just turn it into force myself
from
that thing that I just
sweated over making because
I that's not me that thing that I just
made
right I am ready to accept whatever
feedback anybody had
and ready to go into the next thing
actually need to kind of divorce
yourself when you get feedback
people hopefully are not giving you the
feedback to giving the you the feedback
about the work
separate yourself from the work
regardless of how much time and effort
how much investment you have in it
the third lesson is well obviously I
need to get back to work if I wanted to
have
show right at all I needed to
figure out how to make a set of flights
that would work
and the lesson here is that you never
done for seems like a
you know some you know some sort if you
know nightmare you know if you think
about it one way
you know that you're never done really
but you think about it no one ever done
we all loved the first version
have the iPhone when we shipped it and
then we went right back in we made
version to an earlier this week we
showed I always stayed in Yosemite and a
whole bunch of other great things
you are never done if you're committed
to
you working in this industry working in
high-tech
are you are never done the world keeps
moving you gotta try to keep moving
weather
to do the best that you can do at any
one time basically you're we should
bring your latest demo if you think
about it that way
that these demos get to be very very
polished polish to the point where
you're gonna actually
actually share it with the rest of the
world me
so still on this this idea this is a
quotation that
actually up on the wall arm
very very large in Cupertino a quote
from Steve jobs
and he said if you do something it
turned out pretty good
then you should go do something else
wonderful not dwell on it too long
just figure out watch next
I think this is true only when you do
something that turns out well
but it even has been case for me for the
session I did for me it didn't turn out
so well
I needed to figure out what was next
give up I could try again and I tried
again
I'm very glad that I did a very happy to
be here today and so
the year kind of the Big Sur have joined
up
lesson from the section is that I
stories and lessons never and I thought
this was going to be a central just
about stories in washington had no idea
that I'd started a process that would
teach me more lessons
and so those are my
stories and there they are
again and I think
you know I hope at least that you found
them entertaining
but really I think the important part is
the the lessons you can take out from
them
because you never gonna find yourself in
exactly the same situations that I did
I but I think that you find yourself in
situations where
you can apply some of these ideas useful
E
and productively work and those are my
story
and so now I ask you heard you
to go out in you make your own stories
tell your own story
extract wasn't out from them right and
then figure out how are you going to use
that
experience to go and do some more great
work up your own
thank you very much