alright good morning everyone welcome to
this morning session
name is Mark Miller I'm in iTunes
engineering manager
on the store and we're going to talking
about a foot tools for app developers
now
just in case anybody is a new to the
program or unfamiliar with what it's for
we're gonna go over a quick overview
love how it works
what its purpose is and how you can use
it a
it's also been a couple years since
we've last a presented here
so we'll talk about what's new in the
program in a what
to but new things you can do with it and
finally there's going to be a deep dive
on tools and services that you can use
to
interact with the program so first off
we kinda need a castle characters
who's involved with the affiliate
program and how they interact with each
other
as you might guess their the customer
yours
and the iTunes stores and they are
talking to you and talking to the iTunes
Store but one might not be so obvious
is behind-the-scenes there's an
affiliate network
and the affiliate network mediates the
interaction
between you and the store an affiliate
network is where you go
to sign up set up payments manage
and track your campaign I performance
and go to check on any support issues
you have
so what's it for
a the key thing they're trying to do
with nuclear program
is to drive customers
to your apps and other content so
you might have a game and perhaps you've
released a sequel to it
you want to promote that app and you can
do that using the affiliate program
similarly you might already have a
website use to promote your app's
and you can affiliate those links and
start getting the benefits before a
program that way
but it doesn't have to be euro naps
that you're promoting you can promote
other after Belper zaps
and other content and this is pretty
much all the content on a music store
excuse me on the store on so that's
music movies TV shows books
podcast anything you can think I've is
supported by the by the program
and the use case here is
I am that there's pretty much
if there's a wide use case for what you
can do with it on
you might have a
soundtrack its related to your game and
you can promote that
or if your productivity app and there's
a similar app that
a works well with it you can
promote that from within the app on your
website most the ball
you're trying to connect your users with
content but they're going to want to
download
a their you're interrupting their
workflow a little bit
to send them to the store summit
recounts make sure that link
is are relevant to what they're
interested in and something that they're
going to want to buy
now
to keep the program is that
all your links need a little bit have
data on them
to to function correctly to you ever
been affiliated to an existing iTunes
Store link
and that's it you're ready to go with
the affiliate program
in return for
marketing and promoting that the iTunes
App Store's you earn a commission on
sales are
are generated from that referral for you
you get the benefit love tracking the
effectiveness of their marketing
with our tools and
a small this works on both web and in
your app
so there's no reason to limit the
usage up your affiliate program to the
web you can also do it from within your
app
now
under the covers those links are going
to be
clicked on our top done in iowa's and
the data from the URL is going to be
copied into a cookie
cookie lives for 24 hours on the user's
device
in a supporting but you realize that the
data is tracked in a cookie
and not somewhere on the server this
means that if the user
click on one of your links and then
moves to
her iPhone or iPad to continue I
browsing the store that any
purchase made on the device will not
credit to you
so it's same device that the tap
happens on and the purchase
now once the purchase mishap happens the
data is copied into the database and the
database
I is sinks to the affiliate network
and that's how you get paid
now the terms are really great you
aren't 7 kam
percent commission on all sales that
means that if you link
to for example an app and the user want
to buy another app
you get credited if the user actually
leaves the App Store
and goes to buy something on the music
store you also get credited
at seven percent for all sales within 24
hours
now this is kinda important it in it's a
case of last one wins
a you are operating in an ecosystem love
love love
other developers and its whoever is the
most recent
referral gets the credit for the sale
so if some if a user taps on your link
and then
three hours later tops on another link
from another
affiliate that affiliate gets credited
for the next
24 hours worth of sales
now best the ball this is a seamless
experience from the point of view of
your users
a an affiliate link looks and acts just
like a regular iTunes Store link
so here we've got an example have cut
the rope and they're promoting
the sequel to their up cut the rope to
so when the user taps on get it now
an affiliate link everything axe just as
you expect
the store carousels in and bacon
preview by look at reviews look at
screenshots
brother store and again after that click
this
it's not just aP's that are credited to
that affiliate
its music movies TV shows all that
so that's the affiliate program in a
nutshell
let's talk about what's happened in the
past couple years
most importantly we've had a massive
territory expansion this was the state
of the world or at least the
affiliate world in 2012 we were on three
continents
and we had program support in 45
countries
since then we have introduced
ok the affiliate program to a 147
countries
at the 3x expansion and fifty those
countries happen in the lot in 2014
alone
now that's pretty great your
promoting your app's and other content
worldwide with with your program
but best of all
you only need one network to work in the
entire world
if you're familiar with the program from
a couple years ago you had to sign up
with one program
to work in them the Americas a second
program to work in Europe
the third program to work in Australia
New Zealand
nowadays one network gets the worldwide
access to a 147 countries
this is really huge
now it means one sign up one
payment setup all your tax information
all that sort of financial transactions
stuff that you need to
just get started with the program you do
that once
and your working across the globe
even better we have a common link
structure
for the entire world now
this is what a normal unaffiliated
iTunes Store link looks like
you can see that in the US storefront
it's an app called
iMovie and there's the iTunes Store
content ID at the end
used to be that if you wanted to add
affiliated as
this URL you would end up with something
like these two options
and you have to do it in a region
specific manner so
the euro on top was for the Americas the
Euro on the bottom
was for europe these girls are messy
they're confusing there even suspicious
if a user were too
look at the link that you're calling
iTunes link and examine it a little more
closely
they were today 01 this is I'm not sure
when clicking on any more they might be
turned away by that so no more that
nowadays we take an existing
Store link and we are just a small bit
of data
and the host is still the same
itunes.apple.com
so what we're adding here to the base I
URL
is small bit of affiliated a
the first part of that is the eighty
query parameter
the stands for affiliate token and the
value is essentially you're
user ID within the affiliate program
this is how we identified you
and this is how you get credited for
purchases made
after user taps on your link so it's a
very important to get this one right
also in the affiliated as the CT query
parameter and CT sense for campaign
token
and this is an optional qua primary so
you don't have to put it on
but you can do a lot of really important
things with it
if you have a campaign that you want to
track separately from the rest of your
marketing efforts
you can use this campaign and it will
show up differently
in our you eyes so for example
you might have a campaign for your
website you might have a campaign
a separate campaign for the interior
pages on your website
you could have campaigns for each email
blasts the sand out
if you're doing online advertising
you're buying keywords
you can have a campaign for each of
those you can have campaigns for links
within your aP's
a you can do a lot love analysis to find
out what works and what doesn't
with your marketing efforts
now it's important to note one thing
about these URL's
I said that there's one link structure
worldwide
bites content is not necessarily
available
around the world the the situation for
abs is pretty easy
most cops are available in every country
but if you're linking to
music or movies or books the the rights
may not carry over from one store front
to another
so you need to if you're trying to send
your user to a particular piece of
content
I it's best to check if it's available
in their storefront
before you present them with that link
another common mistake that you make one
first interacting with program
is getting your query strings wrong the
URL's
are on fairly simple but it
there's a few gotchas that you need to
be avoid
the first thing to make sure I've is to
identify if there's already querystring
on the URL now the query string started
the querystring
is identified by the question mark and
if there's no question mark
and you blindly append your affiliate
data using ampersand
that URL probably won't even load for
use with their just going to have an
error
so don't do that what you want to do is
checked for the question mark
and if it's not present on the string
add the question mark
and then your affiliate data now
the reverse is also a gotcha and this is
just as important
if there's already a question mark in
the URL
that means that there's an existing
query string you need to use the
ampersand as a delimiter
instead of using another question mark
if you click on if
a user clicks on you're our two question
marks in it it's not gonna parsed
correctly
and you're not going to be credited with
the
referral so the key thing is
look for the question mark and it's
already there is ever sent to attach
your facilitator
now I mentioned
one network where the key benefits of
having one network worldwide
is that you can have a global unified
view
I love how your marketing is going now
this
is a dash for that shows you in real
time
who's cooking and what what links
they're clicking on
she's not who's cooking but the type of
like that they're clicking on
the first thing you notice about this UI
is that you can track clicks overtime
and you can zoom in from a year's worth
of data
all the way down to a day and again
these these
a Grasser updating in near real time so
in this case
we're looking at per month over month
view and our current month is plotted in
orange
against the previous month's performance
so you can see if your graph is trending
down
or if it's a different
compared month-over-month an adjuster
marketing campaign
accordingly also have no
is that the conversion rate is mentioned
here
and you should pay a close pay close
attention
to this value if the conversion rate
starts diving
that might represent a problem with your
marketing efforts
I maybe your URL's are not
are really in exciting users into buying
or maybe there's a problem with your
links
and something needs investigating so
keep an eye on that one
also on the global dashboard
you can zoom in and get a per country
view of things
the if if you're
a operating in more than one country you
can see how well
you doing in the US as opposed to the UK
or in South America her
or wherever also if
you are promoting more than one type of
content so for example
absent books or movies and music you can
slice and dice and get reports on how
each one of those is performing
so there's a lot of rich data here
and furthermore there's more utility
up at the top you can see additional
tools
for interacting with the program you can
get more in-depth reports of what's
going on
can measure payments and other settings
a
sup make sure it's check out all the
options at this provides because it's a
great way to actually see
how you're doing with your marketing
efforts so that's a global dashboard
its a single unified view love
a single network thats operating in 147
countries
I can't tell you how excited I am about
the fact that we have one network that
lets you operate worldwide
it's a huge a simplification what we
used to have to do
so very exciting hopefully this point
you are similarly exciting you wanna you
ready to go
go sign up for the program and you want
to know how how next to
what the next steps are in terms of a
integrating
for that we've got our tools and
services section
we'll start talking about simple tools
to get you started quickly
a these are things that you don't need a
computer science degree
to work with its maybe just a matter I
love
creating a couple drinks and adding them
to an email or to your website
are somewhere in your app these tools a
really great for the
the one offs the manual so to set up
there's also more advanced tools
so if you want to find I what's going on
I really in the now on the store
and promote that sort of content these
tools let you do that we also provide
smart out banners
smart app in iOS allow you to I'm
promote your app from your website
in a very seamless way a
there's a lot of power there and in the
right situation can be very very useful
the stork it product sheet and iTunes
radio I have been recently added to the
program
we'll talk about it how to work with
those how to get the most outta that
and finally will finish with the
collection
feature with that allows you to fully
define dynamic playlists
for the store this can be really useful
for customizing content for users
first start with the simple stuff the
simplest the all
is link maker this is I
a simple search box where you can come
in
and type a search term get results
and get links especially if you click
into link maker from within the
affiliate network
your the URL that you come in with is
going to have all your affiliate did a
pre-populated
so you need to worry about adding the
affiliate data to the URL itself
on you need to worry about question
marks an ampersand and your own coatings
all dramatically easier
so this case we're going to search for
ed Sheeran he's
a UK singer-songwriter with a lot of
awesome
great songs and we can see that his
albums
I are available in the research results
and by tapping on one of the search
results we get
a nice pop up I love HTML that we can
drop right into
a web page not only that this
HTML has a number of different options
for the formatting so this is the
small-format for the badge if you'd
prefer
a large batch we've got its not to do
that
similarly if you just want to have a raw
Texas lack
maybe this is for and its channel email
blasts or something like that
you've got the the raw text available as
well
so that's like maker in a nutshell it's
simple its
all you I oriented its a bitter bitch
two kno you can drop in
om it's a great way if you haven't
started the year only one interested in
linking to a few pieces of content
to find that but maybe
maybe you've already got a website up
and running and you've got
a couple hundred links to various pieces
iTunes content
in that case you might be interested in
auto link maker
auto Inc maker is away to
on the fly attach affiliated to existing
iTunes links
within a web page its mobile java
scripts that you paste into your page
and on load it actually finds all
the links to the iTunes Store and when
they're clicked
the event handler attach is affiliated
to the URL and you get credit for all
the links for your re-signing
to the page so if you don't want to go
in and edits
hundreds or thousands of pages in your
content website
to you know annotate all these things
with the lady at a our link maker can
really help you out there
so that's the simple I study you can do
you might be more interested in the
advanced stuff for finding content
for thats what are the best tools are
the search
and look at API's and this provides
meta-data
access on the web up to up-to-date
and very very
easy to do some
their two main actions the first is
search
this is probably like you expect you can
find content by name
if you know the artist name for the song
name or your user wants type something
in and find specific pieces content
you can do that with the Search API the
lookup API
allows you to cross-reference your
ID's with the iTunes Store so you might
have a self-concept measure interested
in
and you know the iTunes Store content
ID's you can get the latest data about
that content
using lookup ICLEI and all these
responses are in
the Jason format thats JavaScript object
notation
its pretty much the lingua franca for
data transfer on the web
so sick a look at the Search API a
the only thing that's required to get
started with the Search API is the term
way from your in the course is the
search term that you're interested in
but there's a lot of modifiers available
and you can do some really interesting
stuff
to find specific pieces of content hmmm
you can also change the nature of the
content that comes back the language
query parameter
allows you to specify the
localization above the response so let's
say you're searching
in Canada for a piece of content but you
know you want to localize it to French
you can pass in language Eagles fr and
get a result back in French
media is a constraint for the search
itself
if you only want are interested in
movies are only interested in books
you can specify media equals movies are
media equals books
a content back that way but what if your
actually just interested not just
in say music but you're interested in
songs
are you interested specifically in
albums you can use the
entity query parameter to specify a very
specific
Pisa content are collection of content
that way attribute
is another query primary that focuses
the search term
on a specific case so the
the search will only be applied to
specific portion love
the content and this would allow you to
do for example
if you're query is for Madonna you might
be looking for the
the musician Madonna and you could use
attribute equals
artist name and that searches would only
be for artists
whose name contains Madonna on the other
hand if you're looking for the Beatles
popular song
lady Madonna you can specify at a
beautiful song term
and get song results back
to limit query parameters another one
where I
it can come in handy in many situations
by default
you're going to get 50 results back I
for a given query but if you only want
five
there's no reason to spend time parsing
the resulting waiting for the response
for larger datasets you can either
decrease or increase the size of the
response that you get
and finally there's call back call back
is I
very useful for web developers if you
are trying to do
something that operates within the Java
excusing that browser security model
if you're running JavaScript in a
browser you may not have access to
to make a call tonight instead Apple dot
com but you can use the car back where
parameter
to essentially call a function
with the result I love the query
I'm this can be very useful and just
about every
JavaScript libraries like jQuery what
have you supports call back
and all these responses once when you do
a query
all the results are in a digital format
and their dictionaries of content sorted
by relevancy
and relevancy is an important concept
it's not
it's our best guess at what you actually
searching for
so it depends on how appropriate is the
content to the search term
it also depends on other factors like
popularity so that can be
so you your get your search crews are
not necessarily static are not going to
be sent I'm
if another pizza content becomes more
popular it might move from
ranked number three direct number one in
your search results change you know the
creep renders the same
now the lookup API uses a lot of similar
a
group renders to the search API but the
only thing requires a
is an ID and the idea can be
and iTunes Store content ID or can be a
list
comma-separated those same ID's
to look at a few also support other
identify rare
standards so if you have you PCs for
albums
or ISBN is for books or ISRC
or any on number I've other on
standard ID schemes you can pass those
in as well
so we support similar modifiers to the
Search API language
is a as you would expect call back is as
you expect the
results are the exact same content
dictionaries and you can
passing into some function you define a
javascript
entity is slightly different and a look
at API
so you're passing in one or more content
ID's
and you can use the entity ID to
actually navigates
up or down the content re I will go into
how you can use it in a bit
and again the results are Jason
dictionaries so
this exact same content whether using
Search API or look up API
and the responses you get back are very
very rich in data
now I know this is a wall of text but
there's a lot of information here that
you can use
to populate your out your your you eyes
or
to populate your recommendations
there's expected you get the artist's ID
the artist name
the album name the song name apt name
what have you
I but there's also you can get the mall
its most recent version on the store
what are the release notes for that
version
on when was it released what how much is
it what
what's the file size maybe only want to
recommend small files to use
on some sort of constrained device
you can see screenshots I album artwork
what is the user rating: for this
particular content
what is the age rating: for the content
all this can really
be useful if you're trying to populate a
UI
so that said let's go through a couple
examples I am
but say we are developing a music app
and we want to show
the user a search API so that they can
find content on the store
so we might have a search box that they
can type something in
and we would put that content into the
sort if you are I'll
no one highlight that were specifying
the US storefront and we're passing in
the term that we're trying to search for
in the query parameter term in this case
the user is typed in
the ATM see
now this query
alone is going to be
I what you're going to get is basically
1 I've Ed Sheeran's popular songs from
past couple years
which is called the eighteen and that's
going to be very popular
so that's gonna be at the top of the
list following that you're gonna see
something like the 80's movie
which came out couple years ago and
is seconds behind the the song content
and following that you gonna get about
results for the a-team TV show from the
80's
now the a-team show was awesome who
doesn't like the a team that's great
up but we're music app so we might not
be interested
in getting TV show results
now the simple thing to do in this case
would just be attach
a limit we can say oh well I'm only
interested in the music South music
stuff is
breaking highly to all put limit Eagles
won and I only get one result back
that's great but what if another sequel
to The
a team's movie comes out and to me
that's highest
our music app is suddenly for a
showing content for movies that would be
good
so that's one option
the couple other things we could do we
could say well we're only interested in
searching
for the song term the a-team or were
only interested in songs
bet a a real related to the search term
the a team but that's not really that's
going to limit us a little bit
because what if we want to show albums
or what if we wanna search
on albums that are called
the ATM there's probably several does so
for our use case this is probably not
such a great idea
instead we need to find the right thing
to specify the type of content will were
interested in
and here its media equals music where
music app
we want people to be able to search for
artists
albums or songs whatever so we can
specify a mediator
music and we get just results were
looking for so we run this query
and we get the results we want back
which is great
now this is just one piece a result
are one result back I let's say are you
I we
whitten we might have an album focus
rather than on a specific song
and let's say that are you I we want to
know
how how much does the content cost in
the use or front
and furthermore we want to show them all
the songs
on that album in that store front now
I like to say that if you have a problem
if no one else can help
and if your problem related to content
meta-data on the iTunes Store
maybe you can hire to look up a TI
in this case we have figured out that
our user is in great britain
and so we were just changed the country
code in the URL to BGP Great Britain
and we're passing in the ID
up the collection itself now look at a
TI has a very simple model
for content on the store there are
tracks which are
individual indivisible pieces of content
so this would be songs books movies TV
episodes
aP's there are collections
which are albums TV seasons that sort of
thing
and their artists these are musicians
actors app developers that sort of thing
three levels
and you can use the lookup API to
navigate that hierarchy
so we're passing in the
collection ID for the album ID to look
at the PI and we're gonna get
results back to see if it's available
for sale
in Great Britain but we're not going to
see
is what tracks are available on that
URL what we need to do in that case
is attached the entity that were looking
for
and the entity people song will tell
that look at API
okay give me back the result that I ask
for but also give me back the songs
that are on that album and here
we get the of the results back to you
expect so we get the
album name which is plus and the first
track on that album
is the a team and so on the rest the the
songs on night do our on that album you
can also go
navigate up the content hierarchy so if
you've got a song you wanna know the
artist you can pass in
at City Eagles artist in track that that
way
so there's a lot you can do with a look
at API
its on it's all up to date you might
want to know about price changes for
particular things the to look up a TI
allows you to do that
now that said
you might have slightly bigger needs
in terms of data and for that
we have the enterprise partnerships or
UPS as we commonly call them
these are balk
meta-data and it covers virtually all
iTunes Store content and this is very
much I love
for intended for big data needs
and one is a big data its it's a lot I
it's something like if you download the
full data set for this week
it's going to be 10 gigabytes of textual
data compressed
it's not for the faint of heart but I
can be very useful if you're trying to
established I N and understanding of the
entire iTunes universe
within the feeds are
multiple files and the files represent
database tables
in a relational database sense so
there's for example
an artist table representing artists
your musicians at all personal like
there's an application table for a
iPhone apps and Mac App stuff sort of
thing and as you might expect if you're
familiar with
relational databases there's a
relational artist application table
that represents which artists produced
which
aP's so you can in just this data into
a relational database or other data
store for analysis and
on run your cruise that way and again it
aimed at organizations that have really
deep data needs bit there's a lot of
data there's pricing for
all countries that the iTunes Store
supports
oMG and and analyzing that in dealing
with the data
especially on an ongoing basis can be
really a huge
after fortunately we do have an importer
script
a the script is available as
Python up a and its intended
to in just a feed
into a bicycle database but its the
sample code is
is open so if you'd like you can provide
a different back and
and maybe right to Hadoop HDFS
or something like that if your needs go
that way
the first part it's it's it's a great
way to get the whole
content database frightens on you can do
a lot with it but it did it takes some
doing
a slightly simpler is the rss feeds
are these are dynamic feeds for kinda
what's hot in the store
and by that I mean you got a couple
options if you can see
what's most popular for each piece of
content and in each genre
what's but selling really well right now
what's new what's recently added
on whether this is you know the hot new
single from
today's artists or may be abusive an
album
that has been out at the store for for
decades and is just arriving now
that shows up in the new in Risley at it
fits
you can see featured content what's
actually showing up on the store right
now
on what what did you see when they open
iTunes
to the main page in and check that out
funny you can see customer reviews for a
particular piece of content what are
people saying about it
there's I'll if you want to track your
own aP's performance you can see
recent customer reviews using that RSS
feed
our sis is available in I Adam format
thats pretty much the standard for RSS
these days
it's also available in Jason if you
don't wanna parts a bunch XML you can
get
Jason for not return to you and in just
that way
so that the advanced stuff on
there's all this and more is very well
documented on the website
and we'll have a URL for you at the end
of the session
on smart at banners
are away for you too
cross-reference your ap from website
you've probably seen this browsing the
web with mobile Safari
you into a website and this little
better slides down
and allows you to download the app if
you haven't already
or OpenID if you've got it installed I
or dismiss it if you actually not
interested in the app so from the user's
perspective
is really powerful its if you want to
it's bare
and if you don't it gets out of the way
what it does allow you the developer to
do
is to show your content from your
website
in a native customer experience to your
app can provide the mobile Safari maybe
can't
so this is really powerful I if you want
to
show are have people look at the content
on your website
in your custom app
and again if if users not interested a
simple tap
and it goes away and they're not
bothered by it so how to integrate with
that
it's actually fairly simple I you drop a
simple matter tag
into the head of your web page and the
meta tag
has your Apple ID to find in it that's
pretty obvious we got it
know how to find it and when Safat
Mobile Safari sees that
its gonna fetch the content get latest
price
and show it to the user
you can also pass in your affiliate data
so here we've got her through a token
which defines us for the affiliate
program and we're
were saying the campaign so can as smart
banners that we can see
how many people are actually clicking on
the smart banner from our website
now the app argument is actually a
really important piece today to hear
if we're running a news website or music
recommendation website
and we're asking the user to leave
Mobile Safari leave all that context
and launch into this custom app
we don't want to lose we don't want them
to
you have started the homepage oversight
again the app argument
is actually provided to the app on the
command line and
you can see you can see the same content
that the user was looking at
on the store so it's it away you know
its easy easy integration without really
interrupting the flow
things so that smart app better
if you've got a large website it's a
it's a very useful tool
for for
cross referencing your website and wrap
the circuit product sheet is a brand new
feature that we've got
I am and for the affiliate program its
existence iTunes 6
and allows you
to show iTunes Store content without
actually leaving your
the workflow that your user was an so
for example we've got here on Twitter
the user sees a link to the iTunes Store
and taps on the icon
and the store she shows slides up and
allows the user to do all the
expected things that you would do in the
in the store so you can read reviews you
can look at screenshots
on you can by it right then and there
most importantly when they're done they
can dismiss the store
or the store she and the right back back
and the ap on the page that they were
they were in before so there's no double
tap to the home screen going back to
your apt
it's all rights in the same flow
now the store she as I said has existed
in nineteen sex
but only recently have we added it to
the commission structure
so that means a few if you add a
affiliate data to the store she you're
gonna get paid that same seven percent
over 24 hours
that you did before
to go over demo how we can use the
circuit proxy in our ups
I'm inviting a friend Rick Rubin staying
up to shows how to use Xcode in
drop it in thank you much fine
recruitment thing
II right tools and automation for the
iTunes Store and App Store and other
related products and mark at me to put
together a quick app to show how the
circuit product that works
out in the lobby before the session
getting read a little while before that
for me switch over to
I was here
on summer fire up the app today right
now
and then I'll explain how it was built
afterwards
so here we have your typical stick
figure doing a juggling trick ap I'm
sure you all have several these loaded
on your own I was devices
and from the user and I'm mesmerized by
this juggler I made a fate myself now
I would like some sort of a juggling
related game
all look there's a button right here in
this very ap
the will let me get that content from
in this case the App Store so fight up
on that link
it'll bring up the stock hit product she
just as much shown
and in this case the
the circuit Prachi is displaying a
juggling themed pinball ap now the key
thing here is that while it
may look is that if I am in the App
Store right now
on the juggling to adapt is still
running their
in the background so
if I had wanted to when I brought that
up I could have actually
decided to buy this app I'm not going to
do that right now get them cheap
but for an actual custom I might do that
and then you the affiliate would receive
credit for that purchase
on you bring us up one more time now if
I had decided to click on to tap on the
store link in the upper right
then the user would be taken to the App
Store
that seemed content would be displayed
II
and anything at that that user but
within the 24 hour bounty window
you the affiliate would receive a
commission on all those purchases
a summer switch over now and I
show you what actually happened there so
here we have the new affiliate
dashboards and Mark should before
and this is this is live in Safari
I and you can see that there there are
the Eclipse that I made during the demo
the partition up tap that I made on this
bumpy early was when I was rehearsing
before half on answer this shows the in
near real time tracking
I love I love the affiliate
I'm I'm not but this way and bring up
exclude
and
show you exactly how you can go about
putting the stock it product sheet in
your own aP's
it's very simple I'm
so the first thing you need to make sure
you do is
link against the Starkid
framework other to the public from Mark
that is available to any I less
developer
and it lets you interact with the iTunes
Store the App Store
in various ways in this case the ways by
the circuit product she
Syria the header for our main view
controller
I'm and again just shown here that
we are importing the structured
framework but left this
access the circuit prodigy sorry this is
all objective-c I haven't had a chance
to read and swift justice
I so here we have the implementation
for the view controller and this is the
key method right here this is a method
that I have defined on the view
controller class
I project called simply show star sheet
for products
on takes three promoters the iTunes ID
I the affiliates ok in and the campaign
took
now this is the new difference in I O S
I as mark mentioned the started product
sheet itself has been available since I
was six but previously you could not
include
the affiliate data only one primary was
accepted which was the iTunes ID
faster now you can add the affiliate ok
and that's your usual fully a token that
identifies you
and the campaign token which has might
mention can be any string up to 40
characters in length
that you can use to identify your
different campaigns grip your data
how everyone to analyze I'm
so I take these three parameters and I
put them
into a standard in its dictionary
but since it has been on
simple dictionary these are symbolic
constants that are defined in the star
kid from work
on the S case store product promoter
iTunes I demand in a fire
is the iTunes ID that's the song the
past 10
and the two new ones the product primary
affiliate talkin
and the product from her campaign took
I'm those are optional you don't need to
include them
but since you are an affiliate you
probably do want to conclude them
that your commissions I
so the next thing you need to do is
actually
create to the view controller you do
that using a
standard objective-c outlook and that
model which public from there with
I need to send a delegate for it which
will be called back when
sides tend to dismiss the sheep on in
this case were simply setting the
delegates to ourselves
the same Durkan you control or object
that we're using
on so here's the key call right here
we need to load the product into the
controller
so this is the method a on the
struck it view product control on look
product with primers
primers as the dictionary we just
created that contained again the iTunes
ID the Philly talking and campaign took
on it also takes a completion block
which is the standard objective-c block
on which were returned a result
simply yes or no as to whether it
successfully loaded
and in the case that it didn't
successfully load for some reasons they
that you
somehow had to an incorrect piece of
content didn't actually exist
on the store I A there's an error primer
on and in the black we define what we do
in these two cases
in this case if there's an air weird
slogging it normally in an actual app
you would probably want to display some
sort of dialogue or you I to the user
saying that this content for whatever
reason failed to load in the sheet
and if it successfully loaded here we're
simply logging that it loaded
normally wouldn't really need to do
anything in that case gone
so this point you have loaded the
product into the sheet but you haven't
actually displayed sat at this Cali is
here
on some the call on ourself
which is our view controller present be
she controller
on animated namely 1 yes
and that also takes a completion block
and in this case again we aren't doing
anything in particular in the completion
block
just for reference for logging that
we've completed
on one more important
a method here on is product view
controller did finish this is the car
back method
on that gets called whenever the
sheet action is complete either by the
user can cancel clicking outside of the
sheet
or going elsewhere from the sheet I and
this is where you actually dismissed the
sheet to get it to go the way otherwise
it will remain up
the can selection appear to have done
anything
on I and this is simply the
Bibi action Interface Builder action
that we tied
to the button that was in the top the
app and simply in this case preloaded
with
the iTunes ID love that juggling pinball
ap
that I showed and the affiliate talking
and the campaign took
the code for getting the guy to do the
juggling trick is left as an exercise
for the viewer
so that's the circuit product sheet on
very simple to implement its just a
couple calls and that's pretty powerful
in conjunction with the affiliate
program
thank you mark alright thanks very much
like those awesome
fly cassettes were to proceed I you can
do a lot with it
and possible for users its very on
intrusive
so take a look
next up on our listings talk about is
iTunes radio
night in Trader launched recently and
even more recently
we have added it to the affiliate
program
which means that if you link to an
iTunes radio
station you get credited for
that referral and again it's
very easy to do I shoes another example
using our friend Ed Sheeran
and wherein the sound hound ap and
they've got a link
down near the bottom love that links to
iTunes radio when the user taps on that
the radio station is going to be created
been added to their stations
and the song that the radio station
starts with begins to play
so this is a great way to tell your
users
are to recommends a certain set of
content to use
maybe they don't wanna buy it but they
want to listen to music that inspired by
a particular artist or song you can
get them into the iTunes radio I
experience
and listening to music immediately
best serve all this is supported with
the affiliate program
with the same terms and everything else
7 percent over 24 hours
and that applies not just to purchases
made within the iTunes radio app
but any other store on that same device
for the cookie exists
so that means music of course perhaps
books
movies all the rest are all supported
under the affiliate program
now to constructed a link to iTunes
radio
we've added some functionality to the
search and look up API's
so that the concert result that you see
will have links to the radio stations
themselves
so here we're looking for and Sharon and
in the result set that we get back
we're looking for an artist
the jason has a radio station URL and
you can use that special URL
to launch into the iTunes radio
application you would of course have to
add your affiliated to the sea world
we've been discussing
sightings radio I its
great setup music for you it uses to
person to and you get a bonus for any
purchases made after clicking that link
way to end up talking today about
collections
and collections are something you might
be familiar with
from previous talks used to be called
web I mix
but this is a dynamic playlists
that is to find entirely by URL
and here's what it looks like this is a
collection we've defined by creating a
special URL
and we've set the title
we said description now there's a limit
on
what kinda text you can put in the
description but its
fairly broad and finally we can actually
define
the content I love the playlist itself
so here we've got four songs by Ed
Sheeran
on and you can buy you to these
individually
or tap a single click and by the whole
thing
om I want so
how do we do this the to do
to create a collection like you need to
set something up forehand
on which you need in addition to the
normal affiliate sign up
is to I get a special collection
account with us we will tell you
a special web developer I D and a shared
secret
in the shared secret is used to
cryptographically sign these URL's
so that we know who the author is up
that title and description and
the content
collections support Songz albums
movies TV shows music videos you can
have
kind of a wide-ranging set of content
that you're going to have and this could
actually be pretty high value if you
if you know your user is interested and
six different movies
and their they're ready to buy the ready
to go you can put a single link in front
of them
and they can buy six movies with one tap
at back
can mean a lot of money I in terms of
commissions
up to get started with the collection
system you you there's a bunch of
documentation available online
but let's take a look at what these
links actually look like on
the rather intimidating at first but we
can break them down for you
we start with a the prefix which is
has a little bit history you web I'm X
there's the title that we defined of
course the world coated the description
is also in there and the ideas that we
wanted
I your own code again so that the
the link actually works are in there
additionally we've passed in a WD I D
that's the web developer I D
and we've signs we've done a little bit
of cryptography and we've
added a key to the URL and we put that
into the key parameter
and finally we've got our affiliate
soaking up at the top
because we want to get a commission on
this link course
so this is a great way to make things
happen on the fly if your user
has a special set of desires that you
know about
you can put together a single collection
with this on the fly
you don't need to do you need to
register a particular collection
beforehand once you're signed up you can
do this anytime you want
on the other hand maybe you don't wanna
have the difficulty of defining these
URL's programmatically
for that we have collection builder and
this is a really simple
you why to I am
to find a title and description and the
content
and collection builder if you pass in a
WD ID
in a shared secret will create the URL
for you so if you've got
maybe I a game anyone to promote the
soundtrack to the game and maybe you've
got a comic
I book The kinda expands the game's
universe something like that
you can define that %ah very easily via
collection other
once you've got your title inscription
you can start
searching for additional content add
that to
your dynamic playlist and
you hit go and you get a collection URL
that you can paste into your web page
and you're out
on whatever you need sets collection
builder
on there's a lot of a
interesting things you can do with that
it with the right
situation so to summarize
most important thing to take away with
you right today
is that we've got one program that works
worldwide
sign up is trivially easy and once you
do that you're going to be able to
market your content in 147 countries
analyst is growing as well we've got a
simplified link structure
so you don't have to figure out
what one URL looks like to one user and
then present a different URL to it
another user in a different region that
is a huge headache removed
got a unified dashboard so we can see
what's going on
at a glance across the world we can
drill down
into a particular country particular
content-type: really powerful
real time really great
got a great new commission structure 7
percent over 24 hours
Beckham you lots your bottom line
with added iTunes radio and restore kit
product sheet to the Philly programs you
get credit
the same structures everything else by
using that
and of course we've got a lot of tools
in a lot of documentation available
online
so check it out for documentation
we have an a-hole resource site at
affiliate to license apple a calm
highly recommend checking that out as a
sport link available to
and of course there's def forms if you
have any questions you wanna ask your
fellow developers
there's a real in the session happening
tomorrow about using stork its
is called optimizing in app purchases
and on
they'll be covering a bit about the
stork a product sheet there
and you have any questions about the
affiliate program or the store get
product sheet we've got a couple hours
in the next couple days
we're gonna be downstairs at twos %ah at
2 p.m.
so feel free to come by sello ask some
questions will be
glad to help that's it for the
presentation today
they saw for coming and have various
products