good morning
welcome to the new iTunes Connect
I'm Dave and half full Engineering
Manager
here at iTunes Connect we have a lot of
great things to talk about today
to do so I'm gonna hit the clicker over
on the deaths were here
it all starts with the new design
we want to take you over to walk through
some of the features
the we've added the man who follows
seconding app reviews it's a great
chance for you to upload
video fifteen to thirty seconds dynamic
view of what makes you're at magical at
Bundall
you can bundle up to 10 ap together
with an easy setup low and iTunes
Connect
app analytics very excited about the the
best and an interview
love your app with data only Apple can
provide and laugh
has swype beta testing
we're very excited about this give you a
little more
insight and up and a what we have
planned
protest by beta testing restart with the
homepage
by to inspect an all-new design we have
the same sections as today with great
new icon
if you have any news for announcements
for you
like perhaps you have finally this
contract the relief that's gonna go
right there on the top we came here to
work today
so let's jump into my apt and do we have
the first thing you notice is
wall to wall aP's which I give as much
space you can for always outfit more apt
onto the page
at the same time giving
each ap a little more space debris the
full name of the app
the complete iTunes Connect data easier
tell the difference between waiting for
review
an interview also without a little badge
there to show
the difference when Iowa and Matt Capps
became
to my apt page to check on have data
from a nap
see if the hair salon app has been
approved and ready to go
they're the top when i search bar type
in hair salon
and all the hair salon aP's go to the
top I see it all green
green is good my has been approved is
ready for sale
a month ago check and see how it's done
we've also added
some filtering can see there in the
top right hand corner search by
status you can filter the I have 24
different status is
23 are ready for sale I have one prepare
for upload
phone click on one of the status is of
filtering all the other option show
just the app's with this iTunes Connect
status someone you like the ListView
we've improved that as well more APs
on one page the same search
and filtering that we're right on the
icon view also exist on the first few
you can sort by the different column
names change that up and what's great
is if you leave my apps page and come
back with you find out if iTunes Connect
when you come back to my apt will take
you right back to the list
we're gonna go back into the icon view
and jump into an A
we've done here combine the at pages and
the Virgin pages
and 21 because the top we have app-icon
going across
we have different tabs pricing
in a purchases manager Game Center
we take you by default to the version
have
and to the ready for sale version in my
app see the screenshots
right there from mean eliminated as a
goes
what we want to do is create a new
version so click on the upper
right hand corner there's the new
version button amber provided with the
window
to enter in our version number you
notice there's no what's new text
on this window with information still
required but we understand
did you don't always have all the
marketing data ready we want to take
action to create a new version
and in fact we've added this to the new
Apple as well
you create a new app all you need is a
name
a bundle ID and sq this is the new
iTunes Connect right
in come back when you're ready to do
those descriptions those screenshots
and what-have-you arthritic for this new
version
iraq rate a new sub have there with the
one that they rode out to copied over
the screen shots in a previous version
like normal we can see that the what's
new in this version: Tech hasn't been
filled in
I can fill it and now either way I keep
scrolling down and I see the rest of
my version information I can change that
right now easy to edit I can save in
come back later but we came here today
to create iPad versions that make it
universal
somebody click on the iPad tab
and what I need for an iPad is
new screenshots thats really only
merited a difference between iPhones and
iPad
as reach out to great 5 snapshot
what's going on in my app right now but
we also want
to give a more dynamic experience
one uploader app review giving people
more inside what is it about my app that
magical
the make people want to click on
so we're gonna go ahead and upload the a
preview here as well
now we could 2 screenshot 1
than opposed to reach out to and then
upload screenshot 3
and then upload the video but this is
the new iTunes Connect
and was gonna drag and drop all six
files at once
and then they come you can see the a
previous gonna be first followed by the
screenshot moved on a preview is
for to default poster frame the poster
frame
is the image that people see on the App
Store before they click Play
on your video if you don't like this
poster frame
its easy to change the new iTunes
Connect
we have our over the poster frame image
weekly at a poster frame and up pops
the video itself and the poster frame
that we selected
we can press play on the video find a
spot we want we can
drag drop anytime we find a friend we
like we click
supposed to bring up to go I know my
case the friend that I would like to use
that the animal videos I'm just gonna
scrub on through
finest 1i like that's great
i click said his poster frame
that's all there is to it I'm done
wing coop at first with the phone
now I have my new poster frame but my
app review
my screenshots any other changes that I
wanna make and click Save
I'm good to go
this one looks like in the App Store the
same idea we have the poster
frame video right here fall about the
screenshots
we've talked a lot about the app review
its take a look and see what one look
like
think
best old
just
not that there's a really great I'm
excited to see what you come up with
for the enticing people to Dowager up
a few things to mention remember in app
reviews the UI walkthrough
they wanna see your app what is it about
your app that's great
they don't want to be sold to was not an
ad
in capture this be a stray from I with 8
under oath 10 yosemite
app reviews are up to thirty seconds in
length
and we accept both H 264 empro as
content
and this app reviews
now we move on Apple's upon both is a
great feature
to bundle together after the think I'm
guinere customers in q1 maps or just one
choice
answer to many and want to download the
first epic you want to have a nap and
I'll
is what after opening my bundle
so you have all the apt in your head
with iTunes Connect Asia I think about
you got you some other
you can have up to 10 in this case I'm
gonna pick for them
increase happened and this is great and
offers more value
for the people on the App Store it's a
single install to get
all is a great app that once we've
included in this complete my bundle
same feature we give for music ever TV
where somebody's already purchased one
or more the app to your bundle
the No get a discounted price to
purchase the rest your bundle to
encourage them
to get all your caps
so I was step one flicking what abt
go my bundle the next thing we're gonna
want is the meta data showing the iTunes
Store
we're gonna need a bundle name in
description
public in its green shot a preview
that's what categories rating
marketing URL's privacy earl's all these
different pieces as we won't make this a
simple
as possible for you and we realize that
we have a lot to this information
already so start with information that
is
specific to the bundle its bond on its
own name
need a description about the bundle
obviously it has on price
has on skew and
marking your also you can market the
spinal on its own
the rivers information that comes from
the first app
with Becky ap the first after this
bundle
so the first screenshot will come from
that app the first at preview
you see in the App Store come from that
app the categories
your bundle will match that the first
app and after contact information after
the information
all that we pulled from the first app is
well as well as the privacy URL
the rest of the information
from your money will come from all the
absent a bundle
if you have three APs that are four plus
and one app is $12 plus
your bundle will be rated 12+ for if you
want rebuttal to be made for kids
all of the app's and bundle must be made
for kids threat to the screenshot an app
reviews
will come from the other apps your
bundle equal share for every app in your
bundle
and for keywords will take
all the keywords from all the app's in
the bundle and apply those
you don't have to reenter any new
keywords but take a look and see how we
do it on iTunes Connect
we come back to my apt page
we click new app bundle
first thing we want to enter as our
new app on a name talking toy box we
start selecting the app's
at this point I realized K the first app
is important its key
so I know which 41 my app bundle
but I would like to make this one that
primary ap
that's like my apt I can now see
I my screenshot have already been
popular for me
from that first app I can fill in
the app bundle description the marketing
you /url
privacy policy world as already been
done
scroll down further any deflect
priced here need to be a discounted
price tier
left one tear left my family after the
bundle
it is a discount it was given a few and
then the rest information has already
been filled in
categories the rating I'm good to go at
this point I'm done I've created by
Apple
I made it is a minute one thing to
remember with that bundles
is that once they've been submitted the
app store you can change the apt and a
bundle
the immutable wanna make
a bundle with now five after six after
service for than just creating a bundle
meant that to the App Store here's a
look like on the App Store
you can see your app-icon you can see
all the app's and the bundle
that a preview screenshots come down
below
him up to 10 paid aP's
and Apple you have to give that
discounted price
the first preview and screenshot come
from the first
ap really to all the other apt you're
gonna right there
on the App Store and with complete my
bundle people have already purchased one
or more those abs
we discover price purchase the rest your
bundle
get the whole package and that's up on
those with that like to turn the time
over to Tristan
to talk about app analytics thank you
Dave
when a mistress in cuz Minka engineering
manager working on app analytics
really excited today to show you what
we've been up to
before we get into it talk about what it
takes to build a great out
we're all here this week to learn tips
and tricks on building a great app
we know it all starts a great idea every
app it's in the store today that she's
great success
starts with a great idea how do you
capture that and present bad
to your customers you doubt thoughtful
design
pixel perfect design intuitive design
you focus on really
concrete flows that make sense your
customers we write 13 code we all here
right but free code
worked on my device we testing testing
testing more
so we have automated unit test I'm a DUI
tests were gonna talk more about
our beta testing services well this is a
really important part
writing and creating a great app finally
we submit to the store
these are all pieces develop a
responsibility that were familiar with
today
and Apple does a fantastic job
supporting you throughout this process
great schools with Xcode more great
tools and services were talking about
today
but we know that our job is not done as
developers
13 summit to the store there's this
whole new set of responsibilities
we're not all done and
this is after launching this is what app
analytics is all about these new
responsibilities
can influence this chart hopefully if
you have absolute store
this chart is familiar to you you have
your downloads over time
it's increasing and you see point to
acceleration over time as well
let's talk about what it takes to
influence not and why app analytics is
really important so first
our app store presence we can see on
this chart now I have that
orange dot my see that App Store
presence really
canned influence my downloads
abstr present is your name your
description
your keywords we have these albinos now
we also have or App Store previews
these are great ways to get your out to
have more downloads more customers
morton people using your out marketing
once you have a great app you want to
get the word out as developers
we don't just come into the store with
committed to our social networks we send
it to our friends and our family
we create a home page has she seen
newsletters markings are really
important piece
new updates when you're building an
application
and submitted to the store your
customers crave new content
new levels new ways to engage
existing customers in new ways to
attract more customers you're out me
stay fresh and unique and to do that you
go through this constant release
and build cycle
Nexus advertising advertising and
marketing often used in the same
same vocabulary that advertises a little
bit different
as a developer you may choose to pay for
or advertising and that's a big decision
you want to know if it was worth the
advertising investment
you got it nice return on that app
analytics is there to help you
inform those decisions
all these dots all these wines you want
to monitor
measure and see how they're changing
over time
an app analytics is there to provide
those answers and that is why
we use app analytics because Apple X
provides answers
it helps you answer questions like house
map doing
our people returning to my app
our people converting on here in app
purchases
app analytics helps you make good
advertising decisions
and this is what I'm really excited
about app analytics helps you reveal
missed opportunities
without penalty if you can see that your
app store presence is greatly United
States
and a lot of customers are looking at
your apt United States
actually turning into real customers as
opposed to potential customers
the same may not be the case in Germany
with
app analytics we can see that the
potential customers in German Germany
can become actual customers if we focus
on our German house for presence
localization really understanding the
German culture and understanding that
marketing to Germany maybe a completely
different
different animal and we can do that with
our app store presence
now panel X 1.0 those areas
finally after we launch it's all about
building a better route
an app analytics is there to tell us and
point us in the right direction to do
that
that is why Alex's important
so with that how we look at this Apple
how are we looking at ap Analects is a
product or service
for app developers we're focusing on
this concept a
the customer life cycle and this
involves acquisition to engagement we
want US developers to be covered from
the point rapid the store to the pointer
customers are using Yap
let's look at that from the customer's
perspective we start with our first
measure
here is your app store product page we
have trip guider
nap we made up for this presentation the
first thing we see
iOS App Store use really excited for the
first time
Apple's providing you developers with a
view a viewer app store views
all tench active
this is data on the Apple can provide
come straight from the App Store
to you developers next we have
ap units and sales the state here
attract any time potential customer
turns into an actual customer
and touches your buy button inside your
product page you have a stated today and
felt
and trends if you're familiar with
iTunes Connect but this is different
were time this data into a complete
picture with abstract use
the first time you can see your App
Store views and how that drops
for out units
max we've combined app store data
Billings data
and now we have device data we have
installs
a customer purchases your application
but they may install it on multiple
devices
this is why I installed an app units are
two different to differ metrics
want your customer install the
application starts engaging
we have a new world with device measures
we have sessions active devices
we have retention have this concept
stickiness as well
sticking this is great it's a single
measure that you can track over time
to ensure that your both growing and
retaining customers
there's one measure you want to look at
stickiness
finally if your application has been a
purchases we track that as well
the first time you can see the entire
customer lifecycle from the point the
user
became a real customer to when they're
converting on an app purchases
concept about urself to using
any business intelligence today he may
be looking at average revenue per user
this is average sales we provide that
this in combination with sticking asking
so you really powerful story
how he raps doing and how your customers
are performing
such the customers view this let's look
at your view the developer
we have our app store reviews we have
our app unit
active devices retention in app
purchases this final
starts to drop in that make sense
because not every potential customer
becomes an actual customer
was just look like when we start to ask
more questions house
look by platform we start to filter this
data by
iPhone iPad iPod Touch we can see the
composition
a bar after views across all the Apple
platforms
you can also answer that App Store
presence question
should I be localizing for Germany here
I can see my app store reviews in europe
quite high but my app units in Europe a
little lower
and this makes sense as well and there's
an opportunity there this is where
analytics can help you
reveal missed opportunities if we just
localize rap
potentially making it more apt units and
that will help us get
more active devices more retention more
and I purchases
maybe it's that simple and we don't have
to release another version number out to
get
more downloads in Germany
this is great let's talk about what it
actually looks like I'm sure you guys
what we've been working on I think
that's why we're here
app analytics shows up as a new feature
inside the new iTunes Connect
here beside my apt
first few that we see when we click
inside and the latex
is are out west this is the old reviewed
your entire mobile business
here I can see my trip guide a rapid the
top I can see all of my other app
my sweet can see filters
I can see the ability to change my time
my date let's look at these metrics so
here's the key by dole's
for an application going from the left
to the right I see that life cycle again
it's consistent
start with maps reviews on the map units
I see my sessions
and myself
see if they're rising falling in this
period
hover over these I get toward tips
telling me with the previous period was
as well
ecoFLEX one selecting one of these
brings us into the heart this product
which is our metrics page
first thing you'll notice is that great
trend we can see how we're doing
overtime
in this situation we're looking at data
from a I can see
all remain at my application is increase
in App Store views
which is awesome can also change my
interval below I can change is from days
to weeks to months
talk about those measures again here I
have those life cycle metrics I have my
sales
my store data I have my engagement date
on my device data
conflict any ideas and change the chart
let's look at breaking this down by
particular platform as like you buy
now I can see how this actually looks
across all the Apple devices like see my
iPhone
phone my iPad my ipod touch and it looks
like
the trend is about the same on all been
there all perform an equally in this
case it's great
but a customer can't have and iPhone and
iPad
the same time they're not same device
they're two different devices
so we look at that as a stacked area I
got a chart type
as Lex stacked area that I can now see
the composition
a iPhone iPod iPod Touch and some of
these were equal
a hundred percent whatever metric and
looking at there's different chart types
for different scenarios and looking at
App Store views
here yet area what's the best will
choose the sensible default based on the
measure you looking at
what's what to another measure okay App
Store units
here there's no issues here Analytics is
providing an answer that
my conversions from pageviews ap units
hasn't dropped drastically its a little
bit lower
but the trend is the same and on that
both devices the same
so not a lot of opportunity to improve
my iPad
App Store presence because it's
performing the same as my iPhone maybe
I'm prove them all together
go to another measure in app purchases
and this is
where our team decided that on may 15
we would lower the price in app
purchases as a result we got a lot more
app purchases that occurred and we can
see that would happen Alex
see despite their we can see that across
all platforms
performed much better as a result of our
change
we also had intuition that change in our
in our purchases
would help give more customers more
content
and that would result in more engagement
more active devices
so with that we select in app purchases
compared to
reflect active devices and now
we see are active devices one up had
dinner and a person I can see these
layer on top of each other
telling me the story that yes are
changes to in app purchases really did
impact
active devices as well we've got more
revenue from a nap purchases
and we've got more retention more
engagement from our active devices
such metrics and that's the measures
that we provide
there's some questions we haven't
answered yet
and we can answer that was sources what
are sources
sources are all about how people finder
app
as developers you work really hard on
your map your app store presence
and you have no idea right now how
people are getting to your app's per
page
we're excited that sources solves that
problem first two types
we have a website we have campaigns
web sites are really simple with the
link to your App Store page: you're
familiar with these links today
anytime you have a link to your friends
your family market insights
that link is now trapped in for mobile
website as a refer
source and we can see that map analytics
in campaigns on that same link with the
campaign I D
this is a friendly link friendly name
that you supplied to the URL
let's talk about what that looks like
three simple this is the URL that
hopefully you're familiar with
we had a provider ID we get this
provider ID inside iTunes Connect
and then you add your campaign ID
friendly name you want as friendly as
possible because you're going to view
this name
afterwards we'll show you that in a
second inside your sources list
if you're using I add today to advertise
your application
this is automatic you do not have to go
to I add and setup
campaign names for the purposes about
analytics
it will all happen seamlessly any
campaign create Naiad will be
automatically trapped in available
inside app analytics and you can really
see the effectiveness a bad
inside appena lakes without any effort
so what does this look like come here we
select sources
again brought to the source is less here
I see my top web sites
miss I doubt I can see top campaign I
have the same key by Dolce
that I had in my application list as
well we're really trying to
reinforce the story about position to
engagement and keep it consistent for
you guys
and flat top campaign to get brought
over to my talk campaign last
these are a view of all those friendly
names that we set up
zoom in on one of these here I can see
spring email blast that was my family
name
I see maps reviews my units my sales in
my sessions that same
life cycle this is great we select that
and we're into this source details we
think that
if you're marketers you're gonna love
this page are gonna sit on this page and
share with your colleagues
we can see all those key measures and
nice visual we see a broken down over
time as well
every day has a bar on these key
measures we also see additional measures
that you can only get
on them metrics page
you can see this broken down by
different data types as well so
here we're looking at maps were abused
by regen by territory
by platform changing those drop downs I
can change the measure that i'm looking
at
see exactly how this campaign is
performing how this website is
performing
and what exactly the customers are doing
as well
so that sources we think that you're
gonna love sources today
you know that people are downloading
you're out installing the app you don't
know is whether coming from and
were solving that problem so we've
answered the question
how are people doing the app they can
bring on an app purchases
where they coming from we have an answer
in detail
our people returning are they retained
what does that say to life cycle look
like
and we answer that with retention just
do a quick
education on retention why it's
important this is
obvious a hundred percent of your
customers our customers on the purchase
date
it's really simple moving along
45 percent our customers on day two
35 percent on day 7 and 20 percent and
8:30
hopefully these numbers are scary but
there's an opportunity there
you can get them higher in hiring you
focus on this is really important
because if you have no more customers a
day 30 or 90
you're really gonna may have to focus on
the next stop
or improving your contact your marketing
to get more
how we show this new UI we select
retention and I can see
my purchase date on the left May 23rd
I can see my days later on the right
here i'm looking at
day 7 as a little story
so up the active devices the purchase on
May 23rd
18 percent remain active seven days
later
this great single view of how by
retention on May 23rd was doing
as developers as marketers prague
managers
we want to look at this with oliver
purchase States stacked on top of each
other
so that's the view we're providing in
same May 24th
and now we show you the rest this matrix
so may 2013
June 3rd I can see my retention stacked
single quick view of how my desk the
seven retention is
and you don't have to do anything this
is amazing so
we're providing
metrics sources retention your app list
what do you need to do nothing there is
no STK
no third-party code running in your
app's no performance degradation
you don't have to write any new code
this is not a Apple provided library
that you have to
in bed in your app you don't have to
instantiated initialize it
no code is required no app updates
required you do not have to recompile re
sign recently route to the store
you really have to do nothing to take
advantage of this
we're doing this because it's all built
into the App Store and Iowa State
everything from the store metrics to the
sales metrics to the device metrics is
all automatic in the app's when I was
eight
and what we kept in mind while doing
this privacy
app analytics has been every really
highly requested feature and
iTunes Connect we're excited to bring it
to you guys were excited to bring it to
you
with privacy at the forefront we're not
in this business
to sell your data we're not in this
business to rate informative blog posts
about your data Apple is providing app
analytics as a service to developers and
we
lumber customers as much as you do and
we respect your privacy
as much as we know you would like to as
well rest assured that as we're building
this product
as this product rules out the privacy is
at the forefront we're not making any
compromises in this area
we're really excited about that we think
that's a really unique thing
that we're offering filing maybe the
best news
it's free ap Alex pletely free
what's a great views what a great way to
see your data really missed
opportunities
answering questions we think you guys
are gonna love this we think that you
know I love
the setup time nothing love the cost
we're excited about this feature that
like to bring up Daniel
to talk about Test Lite beta testing
thanks Kristin hi my name is Daniel meow
the software engineer and i cant connect
now most have you heard Durrington keen
on Monday that we're announcing
just like this well we're very excited
to have this opportunity today
to bring you more details about this
great feature now
before we get started have your views
Tesla in the past
great well whether you use test flight
or not
I'm sure we can all agree that great
beta testing tools go a long way
we'd all like to see less obvious
and more the so
before you go into the details let's
talk a little bit about the history of
their distribution
in the beginning beer distribution look
a lot like this
whenever you want to test your app on
your device you connect your device to
your computer
transfer your binary over contest from
there at some point
you probably decided may be helpful to
have others
also take a look at your app before you
publish it to the App Store so each time
you want at a tester
you ask the tester for the device UDID
you got the developer portal
data provisioning profiles and then you
would send
your tester your the binary they would
connect their devices to their computer
transfer the binary over and it was star
testing course you have to do this for
every single one of your testers
so what do we do for you during this
period
how did we change your beta distribution
experience well
we went from this to this
we think we can do better with a new
test liberia testing platform
you can distribute your app not one
not a hundred not 500
but up to 1,000 testers either testers
not devices
in fact you to your testers contest on
multiple devices
next
you didn provisioning profile you no
longer need to worry about these
all you need to get a Tesla started is
an email address let's talk a little bit
about the two sides if
the new platform you start out in iTunes
Connect
as you work on your project you upload
your build iTunes Connect
from iTunes connecting amenities build
manage the testers
distribute these builds to your testers
and other testing
can come back to get inside into their
activity know what your testers receive
an invitation
to testify I mean to test your app
they download the test flight
I was at and from here they can manage
what at they want their testing
they can perform one tap installed an
update
and they can send your feedback
so
well we're working on these features we
discover that
building great app requires a flexible
process everything from
interning with your development team to
distribute a wider audience so we came
up with
internal in beta testers no internal
testers
I mean I figure I can connect users beta
tester
as anyone with an email address you can
have up to 25 internal testers
and up to 1000 beta testers
as you upload build
to iTunes Connect your internal testers
will have
access to these bills right away and
better app review will be required
for you to unlock a thousand testers
while you're building review
you continue to upload new build and
your internal testers can contain a test
and you can get you to manage it has and
i cant connect finally
sandbox account as he could be a tester
signs into the EIA what's up
for the first time go on a Mac we have
a sandbox account created for them what
this means is that
you don't need to come and i cant
connect anymore to create account we
want your testers will attest
all aspects of your application
including in app purchases
so let's see what this all looks like
here we are
we're back on the version pager the you
i cant connect
you know it's a pre-release have will be
quick this
will feel mister the bills that we've
upload in Xcode float so you wanna test
bill number 103 in order to do this we
first have to enter meta-data
protesters so they have something to see
when they receive their habitation
we click
into this bill we enter things like a
description
we also tell the tester what we like in
the test
specifically on this bill after we've
had this information
inputted we hit say ever come back to
build
13 on the Billboard we come to the
corner
we could protesting switch turn on
testing
and that build is now available to our
internal testers
what they want upload
another built for internal testers keep
carrying
maybe upload one more
now we're confident that 105 is a bill
that we want distribute more broadly to
our beta testers
in order to do this we click the submit
button
next to the bill and after review
this is now also available for beta
testers
you notice here that there's a
thirty-day 30-day exploration
on this bill so we know exactly when we
need to upload the next bill
protesters now second
take a look at managing beta testers
here we are on a beta testers with
we see everybody that we've added 24
invited
we see what they're doing we can see
that some protesters have installed the
app
and they're already testing some have
accepted the invite but they haven't
installed yet
and some other not even accepted the
invitation via
for the ones who have installed we see
the latest bill that they've installed
everyone to add another tester
we can't hear the top click the plus
button
at a few email addresses it's a minute
and it has a ready to go
so that I can connect sign now let's
take a look at the tester experience
in Iowa here we are on the device
this is the Mail app and this is an
invitation that we received from a
developer
we see the name that app that we're
we've been invited the test
we see it link that says open test
flight what's going to happen
here we are the test light up from here
we can install app
and what we've done that we can just are
testing
few things to note here send feedback
link
you as a tester can tap this to send
feedback to develop providing
there's also the what the test section
which we talked about earlier the
developer telling us
what they like as a test specifically on
the latest bill
now if we tap the test flight link in
the top corner
this will take us back allister app that
we're actively testing
from here we can open any of the zaps we
can take a look at the what it has no
we look at the version that we're
testing
not go back to the home screen for a
minute here we see that that we've
installed and we'll see a bad
and little orange bag next to the name
of the app
that we have just installed this
indicates that this app is currently
being tested
the Beta Beta bill the via
0 for begun a vacation
with a telling us that there's a new
bill develop a protest
so the top that
but take us back into the app and a test
flight
from here we can uppity up
and we're on our way
and that's test flight the EIA what's up
so in summary we have up to a thousand
testers for each other APs
with their testing we no longer need to
manage
you the ID's or provisioning profile
we can perform one tap installs and
updates
sandbox account automatically created
for us to
for testers to build a test in app
purchases
and is on you test flight out for Iowa
and that beta testing
activity
alright thank you Daniel
very few things to wrap up here before
we conclude
every year we ask after view if you had
a few
tips and tricks we can give to
developers at the developer's conference
what would they be
after you did a great job I look right
before I got on stage
ninety-four percent of all updates
review within five days
and here are some suggestions I can help
pitcher up their app review
number one apt name versus keywords
your apt name is not the place to list
all those different words that you want
people to search on so they can find
your app that's what keywords for idea
Bay
if you serve ads ads must be present in
your
the description and screenshots
must match your app and I would add to
this app review will probably on the
fourth next year
when you're ready to commit and a
purchases
for view you need to make sure that all
aspects their purchase work
if you need a service up and running
said other renewables work
danny's re ready now when you to
purchase is life
on the App Store but when you submit it
after view every app get metadata
rejected
and used to meet again without making a
change
for that matter data it will just get
rejected a second time I say that
because they say it happens
just a friendly no as always makes you
have
rights for all the content the keyword
in your app
this would apply to screenshot app
reviews
anything and lastly testing
I'm very happy that this has Lori
Saldana with this year
one thing I've noticed is that
if you're going iPhone app in East also
work
iPad not to be outdone
that mission teams that hey we have some
suggestions want help
give people some things to think about
before they submit the app to app review
IDFA again answer his questions
correctly in iTunes Connect
you serve ads accusing idea pay makes
you
answer those questions right way get her
number about
delivered within I have all the right
icon sure all the required icons
are in your project before you submit
tool chains and bad signature
these kinda invalid binary messages can
all be solved by making sure the you
upload in crate your ap and the
latest version of Xcode and Mac App than
boxing
if you can if not a Mac app to the App
Store makes you check that box in Xcode
before doing so a low note but
iTunes Connect for Iowa how many have
you already gotten the latest update we
released a few weeks ago
this is our first for rare step into the
redesign
updated pages cells and trends take a
look at your
five weeks due to weaker twenty six
weeks information
new page view
I can factor I alaska Palmer and you can
release the latest version live into the
App Store
so today we talked about
the new design for iTunes Connect a
knife
new UI as well as some cleaner flows app
reviews
fifteen to thirty seconds I've dynamic
video
so you can show what makes your at
magical ap bundles
on up to 10% off your caps together
providing
people in the App Store with one
installed to get all the zaps
app analytics the best end in view
a viewer app with data only Apple can
provide
and test by beta testing if you haven't
been
beta testing your app until now you have
no reason not to
like I was a
and within your seventy these features
will be released later this fall
for more information try to imagine with
them at apple.com
there's the Contact Us form in iTunes
Connect this really is the best way to
get your questions answered by the right
person
we take a lot of time to navigate those
emails based off your questions
appropriately this iTunes Connect app
guide
get on developer datacom
as well as the forms want to get
information there
we have some related sessions later
today uprising in a purchases if you
have any questions on how exactly do
that %uh purchases
check that out what's new and I had
workbench
as Tristan mention privacy matters so we
have a session on user privacy and Iowa
and I was 10 tomorrow advanced user
interfaces with question views
this is a great session will talk about
that show how we use did
in creating I can disconnect Iowa
and the social mission earlier creating
great app reviews
again right before the bash tomorrow
encourages check that one out as well
and with that that's all we have today
hope you have a great day of the
conference