then
thanks hype my name's James Wilson
I'm in engineering manager and one other
things that my team works on
is the framework for power the App Store
and the iBookstore no están
which course includes stalking we've run
a stalk it session at WWDC
for the last few years pretty much since
we did with since we debuted stock it
for doing it purchases
but the session has typically been aimed
at beginners and intermediate level
for developers to get a feel for how
they can implement in app purchases
using stalk
we know obviously from the absolutely
massive uptake
have in app purchases that is time to
move on from that
so this year I want to do something
different what we're going to focus on
in the session is hella optimize
Urena purchase implementation the condom
optimization we're looking at is not so
much
using less memory using less memory make
it faster it's a trap what we
specifically looking at is optimizing
your implementation
to be trouble-free reliable smooth and a
great experience for the user
every single time but if you're not
familiar with docket
his the three key things that stock it
does for you course we all know and love
that stalk it allows us to do in app
purchases
in our apt this is for both consumer one
on consumable items
as well as for subscriptions one thing
the stock it does is it has this thing
called the stock at production
which is the way in which you can sell
aP's another content from the iTunes on
the App Store through your app
and lastly it can be used for receipt
renewal
now receipts are really powerful way
that you can enforce your business model
prevent piracy et cetera right within
your app
as well as within your servers and stalk
it involved there as well
before we launch in optimizing
ass in it in a purchases using stock it
I want to cover a few things that a new
this year
the first is that that's talk it product
sheet that I just mentioned before
that allows you to sell content from
other developers or other apso continue
having the store through Europe thats
talk it
production it now supports the feeling a
program this is really great for you as
a developer
we'd a Buddhist the product sheet I
think was last year
but at that time it was simply a means
by which you could market and sell
those other products and content through
your app but now
with the stalker product sheet
supporting the affiliate program if
you're part of that affiliate program
you can get paid for those items that
you are selling through your app
the second you think I want to call out
is the install kit we're introducing a
new transaction state called deferred
and look at that a bit more in a second
but this has come about due to the asked
by feature that was implemented as part
of our family sharing feature
so family sharing allows you to add up
to six members of your family and former
family
and that family kinship purchases in a
payment method
and when you have children as pilot
family that are under 18
you can enable asked by on them so that
they can I ask for permission to buy
things from the store
as well as in app purchases in your app
and then a parent can approve the
purchase remotely from their devices
so when the transaction is in that state
we call it differed
and that's why we introduce this new
transaction state were touching is
briefly now and I mean look at an
example of how to handle it and what
sort of things you should do in your app
later on
but it's called SK payment transaction
state deferred
what this means is when you see a
transaction
into the deferred state it means it's
needed purchased
nor failed yet you will receive a
further update about this in the future
as in the transaction will into that
final stay to be the purchased or failed
in but it will be an indeterminate time
between when the purchase begins
and when enters that final state the
most important message I want to get
across for you as
app developers is that to implement
support for handling this deferred
transaction state
you need engineered in a way that your
app can still be used by the user
washed its in that differed state
but also worth mentioning the you we do
actually support and allow you to
repurchase that item
that is attempt to make subsequent
purchase for that item while the
permission is still pending
awhile transactions and that differed
state
wherever possible though especially in
regards to the differ- transaction state
should let's talk it handled the user
interaction
will handle alone a lot of the messaging
and dialogues that are required
for the use in regards to the asked by
feature
this is how I asked by works so got a
child device he an apparent device
with a child wants to buy something such
as want to ring up purchases
they attempt to make the purchase by
pressing the buy button and I'll be
prompted to ask permission
for that item that causes a message to
be sent
via the App Store to the parents device
in fact all the parents devices
or approve this device is and they
receive a notification that this request
has been made to buy this item
winters that state that's when the
transaction goes into the deferred state
so once the child has tap the button say
yes they want to ask permission
and the notification is sent out to the
previous devices that's when the
transaction becomes deferred
now wants the parent goes ahead and
approves the declines this
purchase request will send a message
back down to the child's device or the
requesters device
and at that point that's when the
transaction will enter the Familia
purchased
of failed states
now let's talk about how optimizer in a
purchase implementation
this next section is work or stock in
sixty Seconds designed to give you a
really brief introduction to the
processes involved
in completing an in app purchase using
stock in the first thing you've got to
do is know what you going to sell
you need to Lodos it does in app
purchase product identifiers
and then once you know what you're going
to sell in terms of those product
identifiers
you need to ask the App Store for the
localized information about those
products
we do that with Sk product request that
gives back a bunch of SK product object
the week and then go and raw are really
beautiful in a purchase you why
was shown a beautiful in a purchased or
you I and we can touch the user to make
the purchase
we proceed on to converting that product
into an escape payment object
and adding that into the payment cue
the payment cue lingers updates about
how that proud transaction is
progressing
and we will need to process the
transaction as it moves to the purchase
of failed state
assuming they purchase the item within
go ahead and make that acid or the
content feature available to the user
and then lastly we finish the
transaction
so that's it it's a pretty simple
process when you string it together like
that
what we've noticed though is the from
all the apps that we see submitted
from all the apt I V is personally from
the feedback we get from developer tech
support as well as from eating a lot of
developers here double-double they say
is we know that there are definitely
some danger zones in here
it is areas have this process where'd
problems can crop up
or there's common pitfalls of gotchas so
the focus on this session
is to look at those and to help you get
over those to really bring your in app
purchase implementation
up to the next level we want to be as
smooth as possible
a great experience every single time
the start of it let's look at the user
interaction and particularly
in the pre sales pace at making a
purchase that is when you're showing
your store you I
remember the first thing we have to do
is know what we wanna sell we need to
load those
in a purchase product identifiers from
somewhere
now these are the product identifies a
you set up in iTunes Connect when you to
find
you're in a purchase saleable items so
those two options for how you can load
this product identifiers up
one is if you've got a very static
catalogo of items that you're selling
that is you might only have hand for
things are selling you know they won't
change throughout the lifetime at the
apt
that might be simple enough you just
bake those identifies directly into the
apt binary
or included as a Payless that spot I V
the after you submit to the store
that's the simplest implementation
for a lot of developers though we know
that that doesn't suit you will know and
oftentimes giving you enough flexibility
and what we see is that a lot of
developers the first thing happens
during the in app purchase flow is they
make a call to you their own servers
to fetch that list product identifiers
that they're going to display to the
user
know if you doing that you need to think
really careful about how you cashing
loading that data
because it's the first step in making an
in app purchase
and that in app purchase process is such
a fleeting moment of trying to transform
a customer's intrigue and interest into
a sale
that's obviously a benefit to you please
also going to help with their enjoyment
and usefulness of the app that they're
using
even more important is the reliability
of those servers that are hosting
your list a product for you going to
sell you've got to make sure that if you
can have them on a server and you can
make an HTTP request to whatever it
might be to load them
that you have a super reliable
fault-tolerant really perform
server platform that is able to issue
those product codes
really really quickly
because that's not the way to start an
in app purchase
so often when a fun playing games or I'm
using an app
and I'm enticed to making a purchase
because I'm not doing very well at it
I tap the button to see what about and
I'm stuck at a spinner
there's no need for that if you have to
make a network request in order to enter
that
in app purchase flow anticipated and
don't have time
for most have you you know when it's
likely that the user is going to be
presented with these in app purchase
offerings
so just ahead of time to those network
requests in aid
and avoid them getting stuck in a spin
like this
so how low the park information you do
that was so once you've got those
identifiers
you've got a load the product
information about them this is when you
transform that simple identify the you
to find iTunes Connect
to getting to localized product
information product price
from the App Store that the user is
signed into
he do that using a escape product
request
you pass into this the set of
identifiers for which you want that
localize product information back
know when you do this as a said just
before always try and anticipate the
presentation
this will be another round trip on the
network there's
always always going to be some delay
their so it's best
if you can anticipate this loaded just
ahead of time
or at a point in time when you know that
you can safely do that without
interrupting the user
so you can present that in a few I
really quickly
now what you get back when you make that
escape product request
is a bunch of escape product objects the
escape product object will contain the
localized title and description
the price and low cal and if you're
hosting in app purchases with us
then you also get back to contents size
inversion
the most important bit in the escape
product
object you get back in terms of making
for a really good in a purchase
experience
is that localized title and the
localized pricing information
you would be amazed at how many
different ways
there are two represent the simple
concept of currency
around the world this is just a very
small subset have examples
this is all different ways to represent
01234 and 56
in currencies around the world a
currency is something that's always near
and dear to people especially when
you're offering them something for sale
so make sure you can present the
currency for what you offering through
an app purchases
in a way that's comfortable and familiar
to that user
it makes for a much much nicer
experience
to make that use a feel like they are a
first-class experience
in your app regardless of wherever they
are around the world
his in the trick for doing that you can
show the you can localize price using
Ennis number formatter
hereof created my anus number formatter
and I set the number style to be in
currency cuz that's what we want to
display
that he is where the magic stops I set
the locale
for that number formatter to the price
locale that I got back from the escape
product object
I don't make any assumptions about how
the device is configured
I don't make any assumptions about where
the user might be based on any other
criteria whatsoever
because we want to show the price that's
correct for the App Store that they are
signed into
and you do that by using the price like
how the you get back from
escape product object now the second
piece to this puzzle
is when you go to create that format
string by calling string for number
you should pass into that the price that
you get from that in
that SK product object you see that
escape product object has
everything you need to present this item
perfectly suited
for the use in a matter what region what
country they're in so use it to make
sure that it's the most comfortable
familiar experience for the user
but really importantly is this
absolutely no need and you definitely
should not
be doing any currency conversion
yourself when you signed into the store
with their account in their region or
country the App Store is automatically
set up to deliver you the pricing
information that is correct
for the region there in don't try and
cover currencies yourself
another thing that often seeger wrong is
how developers handle
I areas especially during this really
important
pre-sales part where you're making a
pitch to the user about what they want
to buy
important message here is that not all
areas equal
I really encourage you to check out
either the in app purchase programming
guide or
probably even better the stock it
framework reference guide
because it will have fairly small and
easily digestible list of
Eric how's that the framework may vent
to you
errors can happen at a lot of different
times
and sometimes there is something you
develop a needs to deal with the message
to the customer
but more often than not it's an error
message to just provide you
feedback at your apt level above what
happened during that transaction
more likely than not we've already told
them what happened weaver to present to
the dialogue to the user wordy trying to
take them through the process a
rectifying whatever might have gone
wrong
so make sure you know what those area
codes are check with the code is
and know for sure what areas you need to
missus the user about
and what you are can rely on stock it
having taken care of for you
and the most popular example that I see
if this and the one that gets me
every single time I use an app that does
this
is when I'm seeing something i wanna buy
in your app tapped by but more excited
about it
Tyler comes up to sign in to the store a
touch I day done that
gonna get the dialogue to confirm I
purchase and maybe forever reason are
going to be cold feet and hit the cancel
button
so many ups I see then follow that up
with the second I like that says
purchase filed
you cancel the transaction
i know i cancel the transaction I
cancelled
okay yes you're up got an NS era back to
told you that they cancel the
transaction
but you really don't need to go on
reinforce the point to the user that
they got cold feet backed out the
transaction
in fact it can be really damaging for
your
you know possibility to keep that
momentum going and make that sale
because if the first time through
purchase I'm not sure about it and I
decide to back out
if my experience there was in grade in
detail what I'm really not convinced
that I should be spending my money on
this app if they can't make a good job
on letting me back at a purchase
for just being aware that the one ever
really good example love
where it's important to know exactly
what these are codes main wherever
possible
just let us let's talk it handle the
transaction follows much as possible
we see an increasing number about
starting to introduce dialogues and
messaging
ahead of the in app purchase flow if
that's something you feel you need to do
that's fine but it strongly encourage
you to come along tomorrow to
session given by Chris Espinosa at 3:15
about absent kids
it has some really good tips there about
how to handle this sort of interaction
now let's move on to making the purchase
you have
done a great job of showing this
glorious in a purchase you I to the user
was perfectly presented to them no rough
edges no silly error messages
they've tapped the buy button and they
want to move forward
so when you gonna make that purchase
this is when you start to really get
into using stalking
storekeeper revolves around and is
centered around
a payment cue and the most important
thing you've got to do with their
payment cue is observed
always the payment cue is where you will
get all information about how
transactions progressing
whether it was purchased a failed
whether it's in progress whether its
deferred
you also get information about restored
transactions et cetera
it should be the center view in app
purchase implementation
and it's the only source of truth for
state about transactions as they occur
there's absolutely no need for you as a
developer to try and integrate some
sorta complicated state machine all
cashing upstate about transactions are
in place
because you can get all that from the
payment cue itself
you can get transactions that are in
progress you can know about the status
of a transaction as it progresses
and if you're hosting in a purchases
with that the Q is where you'll also get
that download status information
I think one the most common reasons I C
developers attempt to track
tack on aside cash have stayed about in
app purchases
rather than just wholly and solely
trusting the Q
is because they feel that in order to
update you on elements
and you know communicate the progressive
the in app purchase flow through the app
that they need to somehow stash that
payment object away or
tryin tax an extra stayed on to it
somehow so that they can keep that
you I up-to-date and and congress
but in fact that's not true and we'll
see in when the examples I'm gonna give
you how you can harness the Q
and trust only the Q and still achieve
all that
but just as you've got to rely on on the
payment cue for all those updates on all
those pic pieces and information
you also need to be aware that any and
all transactions that appear in the
queue
are real and valid just because your app
didn't start a payment or your the
running instance if your app didn't
start a payment
or for whatever reason you don't think
for some reason this transaction is
valid
then you are likely leaving your
customers out from a real monetary
transaction
that has taken place so make sure you
trust the Q completely
any and all transactions that you see in
the any and all updates you see
are real invalid now if you concerned
about how to ensure that they are not an
unauthorized
or a fraudulent transaction that's a
different matter
please come along on now Friday morning
in 10-15 I'm doing session about
preventing unauthorized transactions
using receipts and you'll see that it's
the receipt that holds that source of
truth
about whether something was a real valid
monetary transaction
otherwise for all intents and purposes
we trust the cure
how we do that on launch as soon as
possible
ideally in your application did finish
launching you should be calling
escape a mccue add transaction observer
the object you add in there will be a
object that conforms to the escape a mic
you observe a protocol
and that's your object that forms the
center of your apertures implementation
its gonna receive all the updates about
how payments are progressing in the
queue
and it's how you can handle everything
from dealing with areas to updating UI
et cetera
to walk you through a quick example here
not so much because you need to get this
begin a certain level information but
because I wanna so show you how it leads
into a really bad design patent and why
that's wrong
first pope first thing we gotta do is of
course we make this call making
start to escape Rick request to get
information about the products we want
to sell
now once we've done that and we said
adela getting cold start we're going to
get that product information back we're
gonna get a bunch of escape product
objects
when the user taps the buy button once
to enter their purchase flow we take
that
escape payment I escape product object
we transform it into a payment
by calling us k payment payment with
product one thing to note here
is I've heard from some feedback from
DTS in particular
is that they've seen a lot of developers
try and handcraft their own escape
product objects
to create the payment with that's
totally not the right thing to do
what you need to do is get your
identifies what you wanna sell use
escape product request to get that
localized information and the escape
product objects
in your hand those escape product
objects
into the pack in to escape a min to get
the payment object
don't run craft your own you've got to
use those real-live escape product
objects
so first up was that we call escape a
min Pinewood product
the next step is we take that payment
and we added into our payment cue to
stop that process
very very deliberate that there is no
step 3 here
because at this point in time you are
completely hands-off and you should step
back
and let's talk it handle this
transaction for you
in fact the transaction will take on a
life of its own completely outside your
apt
stock it and its background processes
will handle the actual purchasing
process
the dialogues in the sign in with the
user outside of your apt
that means that payment takes on a life
outside if your app
even if your app crashes even if you
iraqis quit on or other circumstances
that could cause a long delay in that
that payment process transacting it will
continue to happen
even if Europe's not running
so what we need to do is we've got a
handle the events from the queue to know
where these payment is at
the most important escape a min Q
observer
method to implement is payment cue
updated transactions
this is what gets called every time the
payment stars progressing through the
process of becoming
an actual in app purchase that is made
and we can implement this like this so
here it got a full loop de loops over
reach those transactions and receiving
an update for
and for each transaction I set up a
switch statement because I wanna
particularly no
which state this transaction is in then
I can do things like looking for new
for the state old escape payment
transaction Ste purchased
that means the purchase has completed I
can unlock features and content
I can go ahead and check the receipt
make sure it's a real monetary
transaction or fraudulent one that
occurred
and then unlock this features and
content accordingly
but don't do this
don't set up that case statement to look
for the state have purchased
and then try and find a matching payment
in some side cash the you got
of payments that you thought were in
progress
because once you take created that
payment on check and thrown in the pain
cue to start the process
that object should be dead you should
forget about it
you'll get information about those
payments and those transactions through
the Q
so if you did something like this and
tried to fetch that payment of some cash
for you in maintaining
what you thought was in progress and
then even worse
did something like this and said haha I
know this payment
I can order it comes from I was going to
ignore it and skip over it
you will love left the customer out here
K
if something arrives in the queue it's
because someone bought something
even if you don't think originated from
your app or the running instance if
you're up
there's lotsa reasons and why a
transaction can suddenly appear in the
queue
they're always real they're always valid
you should process them
so why not why would we do that because
what if your app crashes
obviously then you lost your cash
information and not only is the user
have to endure a crash in your app
but next time when they launch a few
then ignore the subsequent update you
get about the payment
they not only have they put up with the
crash they've missed out on what
you sold them
it's just as valid always process those
transactions
now came back to what we talked about
for this new state old
the SK payment transaction deferred he's
an example how to handle
that transaction being deferred so
remember in this state
and child that's part of our family
sharing unit has
asked permission to buy something in
your app and the transaction has moved
from SK payment state purchasing
to deferred now when you see that
status come through as SK payment
transaction state deferred
he is what you should do this 3
important things the week really
encourages developers to do in your
handling this situation
the first is allow the user to keep
using the app
it would be an absolute buzz kill for
the kids
if they are sitting there in the app
absolutely delighted about the process
the possibility that mom or dad might
just say yes
to this purchase they've asked for but
all the while have to sit there waiting
spinners are waiting for permission they
gonna
taken it quit they gonna go to another
app you're gonna lose them
K make sure they can keep using the app
in some way
because it may be some time before the
transaction is updated
it could be up to 24 hours before the
approval a decline comes through from
the parents
it's a really don't get them stuck in
that mean modal purchasing state where
they can't do anything with your app
in fact one way to think about it is
you've got a very captive audience at
this point in time
someone want something in your app and
they're waiting for approval for
make use of that time
that at the end love any transaction you
perform with stalk it weather gets
purchased of failed
you always must call finish transaction
when you call finish transaction that
tells the App Store the you're done with
this transaction
you've seen it you've processed it you
don't need to see it again
it removes it from the queue and that
makes sure that we don't keep calling
the updated
transactions method each time on launch
or another points when your app is
running
now this is the most common cause I say
forbad ap behavior on launch
especially things like really slow
launch time or
launch time where launches minutes
hanging there for a while
all westfall when the app launches and
presented with a series dialogue just
don't make sense to me
because in fact what's happening is
because you didn't remove that
transaction from the queue when you're
apple launches
we can you add that transaction cue
observer in
the first thing we do is go and look at
the history a transaction for the
still-pending haven't had transaction
finished called on them
and will go on replay all those updates
through to your apt
so he then stop processing them and have
reason to message something to the user
and still failed to call finish
transaction
means every single time
your app launches its gonna go through
this process
too bad user experience and it's one
that gets worse the more the user uses
your app
always call finish transaction to get
those items out a cure
to tips about the escape a min Q object
itself
one is going back to this notion that
the escape a mic use your single source
of truth
he has a property on a call transactions
and you can call that property
and get the list transactions are
currently in flight
so for example if you want to when you
show your your purchase you I make sure
you correctly represented any
transaction
items that are still purchasing you
could call transactions to get the list
of payments in progress as opposed to
trying to track that state yourself on
the side
the other one is keep in mind that in a
person can be disabled on the device
and it's a really bad experience for the
user if they're enticed
to play your game or use your app enough
to wanna make an app purchase
then only to find that they get some
error message telling them that that's
been disabled
so you can call can make payments on
escape a min Q
to cost method returnable Ian to know
whether or not
in app purchases can actually be made
now will give you a quick demo few
things we've just talked about
okay
I have here have very very simple app
for always tended does an in app
purchase everything I talk about in a
session including this demo applies
equally to Iowa's
and OS 10 stalk it is the same on both
platforms
but in this app few things to call out
in my application did finish launching
first thing I'm doing -ism
adding an object in to observe the Q and
down here you'll see I will have
implemented
my payment cue updated transactions
method
it in here that I start inspecting
and dealing with all those events that
happen as purchases progress
through the Cure I deal with things like
it entering the purchasing statement
things first start when it gets
purchased
went failed or restored so
for the sake of this damn I'm going to
run my really really simple app
all it does is it sells a 99-cent been
on the Viron in app purchase
really exciting go ahead and purchase
that now soon as I hit the purchase
button
for any other user interaction I've
straightaway
my break point was hit that I said in my
pay make you updated transactions method
so that's really important to know
because if you were thinking you had to
track you I state yourself this
demonstrates you don't
as soon as a button was clicked bang
where into the payment cue in observing
an event occurring
and in fact the event where observing is
the fact that this
payment for this transaction has entered
the state purchasing
so this would be a time when I could go
on updated state if i buy buttons
whatever else I need to do to inform the
user that yes
this transaction is underway and take
the breakpoint oxygen get a bit noisy
let let the app continue into what
happens here so I've been prompted to
sign in
now one thing to note is because this is
a test app
I'm using the a App Store test
environment
that is I have my app signed with my
development certificate as we see here
scroll down to the code thing sometimes
it's easy just searching for code
signing
course said it all in combined
see here my code signing
identity is set to Mac Developer this
make sure the my app is development
signed
when it runs that means that when we
start using stalk it
stock it can inspect echoed signature
this the code to get your this app
and you can know that because its
development sign he needs to talk to the
test environment
not the production App Store and that
allows us to test arena purges
implementation before we have anything
on the store
so you go ahead here an end to my
password
cool yup I definitely wanna buy this ban
on
and I've already purchased it on the
stem a few times now
and see here when we get the final thank
you through from
stock in from the App Store where
already back in our apt we've got a
break point fired
in the SK payment transactions state
purchased
this is where we can then go ahead and
inspect what it was it was bought by
looking at the receipt
unlocking features and content named
whatever else we need to do based on
this purchase having occurred
right now
at this point because the breakpoint
notice that I have not yet called
finish transaction I've made a break
point
right at the point when I would normally
on check the receipt to know what they
bought
and unlock those features and content
accordingly
but one if I hit the stop button up here
in my app in Xcode
this is just like what would happen if
my app crashed midway through the in app
purchase
or what would happen if you use a killed
your Apple quit Europe during the
purchase
well maybe something else happen lost
network whatever it might be
the important thing is here let's put
this breakpoint back on
when my apt next launchers and this
applies to I was no están
watch what happens on launch
I was immediately taken again
into payment cue updated transactions
why
because that transaction haven't
finished yet your app crashed midway
through handling that even though the
user had paid
for what they've bought so this is why
it's so important to always observe the
Q and handle any and every transaction
that occurs through here
in a way that doesn't rely on you
tracking any state yourself
so this time gonna let this go through
and that goes through make sure that we
do actually finish that transaction
one thing I did wanna know we mentioned
before about the updating a view I
let's go through this process again and
you're set a breakpoint here on
transaction state purchasing now when I
run this
let's buy a ban on again
just take note of the fact that this
time around
my a break point he was called
on the main thread but you shouldn't
necessarily
make any assumptions about which thread
you will get these call backs on
so she updating UI elements in here such
as setting a button state
grain things out anything you like your
racket make sure you don't make an
assumption that which thread that
message comes in on
and dispatcher two main if you have to
to work safely with that kid knew I
can't
okay let's go back to slides
let's move on to the post sales
experience so we showed a beautiful you
either the user
mean tightened by by process was smooth
and seamless
now you've got to make good on what
they've paid for
in particular you need to process the
transaction through the payment cue
then you need to make that asset or
content feature available in this may
mean
downloading content and then of course
finished transaction now in the
post-sale experience this three key
things you're going to want to do
the first is validate the purchase
verify the receipt from that transaction
you can verify that on device or on a
server the server level if you're
handing out content from services
and that is your way to confirm that it
was a real monetary transaction
this is authentic and trusted and
occurred with the production App Store
again 10-15 Friday come along let me
tell you all about that
the next thing you want to do is give
them what they pay for
and especially if you have to download
content for that feature
obviously is apt become more and more
rich in features they offer
it often makes sense to have a small a
binary for the actual app itself
and then download extra content as those
in app purchases are made
you can host that with us or you could
have self-hosted
and then lastly depending on the type of
transaction there may be a need to
persist state
about the transaction having occurred
all be able to handle the situation
where the user needs to restore
the previous transactions that they have
made
so a quick word on receipt validation we
did on device validation of the receipt
that is confirming it was a real
monetary transaction with the store
you can then go on unlock this features
and content within the app itself
but increasingly like I said we see
developers hosting content
either with us or on the own server
infrastructure that is downloaded
when the purchase takes place if you
have your own servers
to issuing that content out to your
users based on in app purchases
of course you want to make sure that
those servers on the hand that content
out
to real pain customers and in fact you
can do server to server
validation receipts using Apple's online
validation service
and that'll allow you to restrict access
and be sure you only hand others
valuable assets
to people who have paid but we
definitely don't wanna do
is trying use that online validation
service directly from the device
now there was a time a little while ago
when that was kinda okay to do
but when we introduced I was seven we
introduce the grand unified receipt
format
that unify the receipt format that we
use on I O S and the West End
and empowered you as the developer to be
able to validate that receipt
on the device itself that way there was
no need for your apt to be calling out
Apple's validation service
to get back the information about that
receipt to know if it was valid
so should no longer be using that
validation service directly from your
device
it's okay to do a from your servers to
the validation service
but as far as your app running on a
device it should be the Validate the
receipt locally
all past that receipt up to your service
first then your servers
can talk to the Apple server the Apple
validation service to know if the
receipt is valid
and those I was 6 API's they are in fact
deprecated now
so you really need to move away from
those
downloading content especially in terms
of ensuring a very hassle-free
smooth and great in app purchase
experience every time
downloading content is a really
important area to focus on
at this point in time the user has paid
for what you're offering
Ryan they've done their side of the
bargain they've paid you
now it's up to you to deliver what they
paid for as quickly and reliably as
possible
every single time wanna great ways you
can do that
is by using Apple's hosted in app
purchase feature
that allows you to host in app purchase
content with us it's hosted on our
servers
which very scaleable very reliable
we can download the content for you in
the background even when Europe's not
running
so one for purchases made the user can
switch around doing lots of other things
and I'm gonna get back to your apt
contents therein waiting for great
experience for them
and you can have up to 2 gigabytes her
in app purchase a product
that's not too big total para that's too
big
her item you are selling through an app
purchases
nephew using hosted content it's so
simple to use
way back now payment cue updated
transactions method
looping over at transactions were
receiving updates for
if you see a transaction with the
downloads property in that download
property contains one or more downloads
and you wanna start downloading a
content watch this
simple you simply call escape a mic you
stop download and hand those downloads
over to us
stock it now back from process that
takes care of downloading the content
get to the users quickly and seamlessly
as possible
when the download progress is you also
receive updates via
the escape Inc you observe a method
payment cue updated downloads
this will tell you things like progress
in time remaining: as well as state an
era
and when it's finished you will get a
continuity trail where you can locate
where that content has been downloaded
to
now cause there may be many reasons why
you wanna host that in a purchase
content yourself and that's okay
but make sure you use the background
download API's to download that
for all the same reasons if you're using
the standard old Ennis URL connection to
download this content
there's gonna be some serious
limitations you run into
particularly around the fact that you
cannot guarantee the download will start
straight away
depending on network commissions and the
use would have to sit there
in your app while the download happens
to guarantee it completes
that's not good but what you can do
is you can use an issue oral session to
do the background download for your
there's lotsa great documentation
available for this online but here's a
quick run through how this works
you create you an issue oral session
configuration by giving a
and name have called him my background
download my background session
and then we've got a session configured
we create the session itself and we give
a delegate to get updates about how the
downloads going
and a queue on which to receive those
updates thats dispatch care
this will be familiar with anyone that's
worked with an issue a real connection
before
you create an issue I will request in
this case have just created with the URL
that I want to download
10 simple as this: I create the download
task
using that request and the download
session
see what we did there we set up a
session to go and download this force in
the background
we told what we wanted to go and get and
we when created the download task
and now the OS is taking care that force
in the background
you get updates by the delegate method
onto house as to how the damage is
progressing so you can update you on
but because these can continue to happen
while your caps lock running
when you apple launches you need to
reconnect to any sessions that might be
in progress
almighty finished why your app wasn't
running and this is how you do that
your application delegate you should
implement application handle events for
background URL session
that will get called on launch see you
can reestablish a session configuration
get the session itself set you delegate
again and then get those same progress
updates about how the download is going
but no matter how you download the
content with you downloaded
yourself with you downloaded via host in
app purchases
you must always call finish transaction
of course but you must do that
once you've completely downloaded the
asset and made available to the user
one thing that can go horribly wrong
from the user's perspective
is if you call finish transaction
earlier
before the download is done and then
something happens during the download
they may have no way to get back or get
to that purchase they've just made
so you called finish transaction once
the contents download it and you've made
available
that way only then is a go at a cue and
only then will you not receive further
updates about it
now restoring transactions this is
something you have to offer
excuse me this is something you have to
offer if you are selling non consumable
all items ordering your subscription
non consumable items there things like
it game levels all maps
or one of purchases the designed to be
used across multiple devices
order annual subscriptions they like to
periodicals
where you are setting up a subscription
payment for ongoing delivery of new
content
if you offering either of those you have
to make sure you can offer the ability
to restore previous transactions that is
allow the user to get back what they've
bought before 30 rap
especially if they buy a new device or
otherwise need to get back what they've
already paid for
but if you offering consumers a non
renewing subscriptions so a consumable
might be something like gas in a race
car track
I gems and coins or currency generally
in item that's purchased
then used up and ideally purchased again
and again and again
if you offering those sorts of I am
through in a purchase
then it's up to you the developer to
persist that state
you can't restore those and this comes
back to what I was just saying before
about making sure you call finish
transaction at the right point in time
because you get one shot at a consumable
and non renewing subscription
you have to make sure you're up handle
the transaction probably
makes it available to the user and only
then calls finish transaction because
you can't restore this
but for the content types you can
restore you call escape a mic you
default queue
restore completed transactions now what
happens here
is a course you need to observe the Q
because you'll receive these delicate
call back methods
such as restore completed transactions
fail with Cara if things don't go well
or payment cue restore complete
transactions finished
at that point you can go and inspect the
receipt to know what
purchases were restored unlock those
features and content
but note that this requires a network
connection
and the user will be prompted to sign in
to the store if we have to verify their
identity
so that we know exactly what they paid
for to get you that list of
restored transactions
now just because you're a has to offer
restore transactions
it doesn't mean you should call it all
the time
because it requires a network connection
because it will require the user's use
it as
sign in it should be something you do
only when the user asks you to
I know a lot of developers think it
would make sense to just call restore
transactions every time the app launches
because I don't they always want to get
back what they paid for
yes but when they have to sign in to do
that
it becomes too much a heavyweight
process on launch
so let the app launch an offer a
graceful way for them to restore
transactions
if you have to do that based on the
content types you're selling
so it's wrap this up with a summary this
is my room
recipe for trouble free in app purchases
so when you are loading up your in app
purchase product identifiers
these list of product identifies you're
going to sell or offer to the user
be very careful about how you choose to
host them and where you hosting if you
not gonna bake them into your app itself
because if that first experiences a spin
a while you wait for that to load
or even worse in error because the
server can be reached
at totally derails your sales experience
cash inappropriately if you can and
avoid delay in presenting these products
by fetching just ahead of time if you
can anticipate
a great example this is if you've got a
racing car game for example
the promise a lot of conditions you can
anticipate around when you can offer in
a purchase is let's say I mean offer an
in app purchase
that allows the user to go faster around
the track next time round
will somehow upgrades their car when we
can offer that
well probably when the coming dead last
in the race when I finish last
and so those are two things we could
anticipate in code right
if we know they are gonna about to cross
the finish line and we know that they're
in a bad position
just ahead of time gone grab that
product information
and make sure you've got on hand for
when they cross the finish line
in last place and the you can offer them
a great way to beat their friends and
finish in first place next time around
likewise the same applies when you go
and fetch the product information to
localize product information from the
App Store
fetch only the products you need
sure love you've got tens and tens or
even hundreds have been a purchase
identifiers
in your app be probably only going to
offer
three four five maybe six items to the
user to any one point in time
and because this involves a round trip
to the App Store network
you only want to fetch just the products
you need to this happens as quickly as
possible
surface just ahead of time just like we
said before China anticipate when you
gonna display this
fetched just ahead of time to avoid any
delay their just makes for such a smooth
in a purchase experience
if the user can go directly from the
point in time when they may be enticed
by something
to be able to tap that by months
straight away
now we show your beautiful in a purchase
you why and I've got a mention earlier
today there was a really great session
call designing a great in a purchase
experience
should really check out the video that
cuz it goes far more in-depth
about design techniques about how to
provide a great in a purchase experience
but from a code level make sure to you
ensure proper localization we deal with
the global marketplace
and just because we're familiar with a
particular way represented currency
or particular display style doesn't mean
everyone else will like that
let alone wanna buy a wrap if you get it
wrong
to take a ritual great localization it
makes users feel comfortable and makes
me feel happy
the customs there for many with being
enticed and enjoyed by your app
do I convert the current system
everything you get back in escape random
in the escape product object will be
correct for the store that the user is
signed into
know when the make the purchase that is
you take that escape for a dub check to
make an escape a min throwed in the
payment cue
wanted added it to the queue step back
in the hands of
there's no step 3 remember create the
payment added to the queue
that's it but the payment cute and drive
the further updates
and then processed those updates make
sure you verify the receipt
to make sure it's a real monetary
transaction happen with the App Store
nothing fun is going on
onlookers features and content soon as
you possibly can for a great experience
and avoid deprecated API is an unsafe
receipt verification
the could leave you opened on authorized
transactions occurring
if you could download content to make
feature available
get that ass it is reliably and quickly
as possible user in app purchases if you
can
if not if your gonna download it
yourself make sure you use those
background down API's
and lastly actually finish the
transaction
if you need more information there is
we have an evangelist mailing list set
up the welcome to email to get help from
a wonderful evangelist tame
there is also the in app purchase
programming guide available online and
also the stock at framework reference
and as the Apple developer forums that a
great resource as well for discussion
and help
this related sessions I mentioned
preventing unauthorized purchases with
receipt that's me again Friday morning
up in Pacific Heights that we can that's
where we'll take you through how to make
sure the your revenues protected
your business model is enforced in your
app and your servers
he care about your revenue come along
let's talk about a also designing a
great in a purchase experience racial
did an amazing job this morning
in he had telling developers how to
structure their
in app purchase you why to deliver a
great experience every time
via should be available shortly and
lastly Chris Espinosa session tomorrow
or Thursday
is really good if you're ap in
particular is targeted at kids
thank you very much