good afternoon everyone the are okay
alright a thousand funded IRA
thank you for coming this is the session
such as creating app reviews for
creating
greats app reviews and I really believe
that
Howden after the session I believe you
gonna be able to create a great app
review
my name is Paul Turner and I'm from the
iTunes engineering
division and what that fancy title up
behind you says
eyes that I have a job that requires
many talents
true are
another one to Iran several teams that
keep content processing
such as wraps processing and flown to
the store are but in my tenure topple
I've been lucky enough to be able to
purchase been producing and engineering
and launching incredible projects
on won my first projects was a with from
the coupon from here I was actually the
original app store launch and since then
we've done iBookstore
and I HD films on iTunes action LP is an
iTunes Match in
be roles it's been awesome %ah
this isn't about me better
was actually rolled into you guys though
is that i won the things that Iran
is actually the logistics team for aP's
made by Apple
not only do I help engineer and support
iTunes Connect but I am a customer that
just like you guys
alright let's talk about you and your
app's
and your app reviews first
or talk about how content
as preview customers on store currently
with our amazing and innovative and down
lists music store
we have this great 92nd preview level I
Sedin
click and buy all day long on and for my
favorite store
phone store with this great theatrical
trailers for the TV store we have
episode reviews
and for everyone's favorite the
iBookstore
with those enticing downloadable samples
so we have to the App Store
this week we're introducing app reviews
let's get to know on yeah we hope girl
other clout
this is great this is God was amazing
all right let's get to know our previews
this is this is fun was picking up we're
10 left us on monday with that app the
showed Monument Valley
let's take a look at the way dates
preview to customers on the store
right now means pretty
alright so on the store on the store
front page you can have description tax
you have other information but you know
a picture is worth a thousand words
let's look at the screen shot and
they're beautiful are beautiful and
gorgeous
is an amazing app but I'm curious as a
customer I don't fully understand it I
don't understand how the app
functions this is out previews so if a
picture is worth a thousand words
what's a video or and this is a
the
the moment
aunt
on
in
the
right before our eyes Monument Valley
becomes immersive
puzzle game and you make an immediate
emotional connection
and that's app reviews solar start of
goes on the same page was just some
basic information
up app reviews up to thirty seconds in
length
app reviews are not really brand or
campaign focused
they are the raffle with cutscenes
they're definitely not the actual
trailers the just brief videos meant to
demonstrate
the you are the features and
functionality of your app
app reviews are made primarily have
captured footage
we're gonna show you how to do that will
live on stage today
and once you're finished producing your
app review
your export out high-resolution source
you can upload right into iTunes Connect
very easy
gonna be review launch a binary we're
gonna re in coded for streaming out to
devices all around the world its
incredible so with that
let's talk about the agenda today first
of
recover a little bit more the details an
app reviews the characteristics what
makes them different than anything
really seen before
we're gonna help you take that first
step and that's come the most important
step is
the planning step how to plan your video
creatively
and technically we're gonna
show you that capture future and its
amazing and I love it
we're also gonna do a little bit adding
we're so you're editing options
with iMovie next we're gonna show used
some composition tips
we're gonna demonstrate the uploading
right into iTunes Connect
the roundout everything at the end some
guidelines
the Sun good every death okay
okay to talk but
interactive alright let's talk about
those details
all right %uh previews
app reviews are a feature of the Iowa
app stores
as you saw on monument by the 10 shown
we are you just showed here
app you use a gun show up and the first
law
the new section for screenshots and
videos
firstly I will be dedicated app reviews
shop on the product page
app reviews
are device-specific mean that if you
have a universal app
you upload a distinct iPhone and a
distinct
iPad video for app reviews also we're
making a very easy
you noble just that single so the videos
to your caps primary localization
we're going to disperse them to the
other store fronts
the app is for sale a couple more
details
need those beautiful wide
screens to show off your app reviews so
app reviews are gonna be
a future I was a and they're going to
display on those
iPhone this widescreen iPhones iPod
touch and iPhone 5 the iPod Touch is the
iPad
the desktop store one question a lot
the not required but they're strongly
encouraged and i'm glad you guys are all
here today have taken the first step
on we didn't want to launch app reviews
until we made
everything available and accessible to
every developer and now that we're doing
that we're strongly encouraging everyone
to get aboard really want you know more
we're here for the session we're gonna
be in the lab we're here to help you get
on board app reviews which think they're
amazing
this is my favorite my favorite of all
my favorite we have native aspect ratio
support built-in
no longer well you have to stretch
or pinch or add a thats
to your videos to fit in a wide screen
player I want that of the screens badges
burning eyes
we have native aspect ratio support
right in built right into your you get
the fall
you I really owe in in the in playback
it's it's fantastic
or talk about planning next
I'm sure you guys are sitting here
give me a little bit of information
maybe the wheels are spinning everything
about your app
everyone what you gonna do let's talk
about planning planning is the biggest
part about making your app review the
restroom it really easy so
planning is where you have to start
first you have to figure out the goal
love your app review are you highlight
feature many features maybe
the utility of your app maybe you have a
really innovative you are I
start thinking about what your goal
under thirty second app reviews gonna be
and agree way to think about this is
what makes my app
magical what makes bad magic and
an easy way to kind of put yourself in
that that question is
if somebody walked up to you with your
app you know
hey I've got this app you're out what
would you want them to say to you about
the app
you know of got this app it does this
for basics or all acts really collapse
revolutionize the way I
that or what you plan over there are two
school game it does this in his
character does that
what nature at magical you know that's
going to make your a magical app review
route preview magical that's going to
get people
to purchaser out just like Monument
Valley
you saw those beautiful screenshots and
screenshots are very powerful tool
but I efforts story to tell when you
have this be you have
app reviews to fill in that story see a
look beyond your screenshots
how do you tell your story now with
these
these videos fantastic
a couple more things are contemplating
so now you're you're starting to
to figure what nature out magical arm
you started to understand what your goal
is
now it's time to start listing out these
elements may be left out the elements
that you want to put in your app review
a if your app it's already on store a
great place to start five-year
description text
that's probably first list the event
everyone who got to listen your
description text right now you just feel
that
put that on your list number add to it
serves for
playing with things start thinking about
what your app is all about our
our marriage spent so much time on this
great level i really wanna show this of
kids love this target so much feedback
about this portion of my app that's a
great thing to put in my app review
and I having so that now I highly
encourage you
to make some kinda outline a storyboard
you see the storm or that we have upon
your on-screen
this is first order we're essentially a
previous based on
a little bit but it's nothing fancy
don't retreat charles is
fantastic drying arm they could be on a
napkin
mutually napkin are you know I doesn't
matter what you do when you're trying to
make a beat a series of a rose in boxes
but for storyboarding it out
what do what do I wanna show in my video
how am I gonna put the story together
right arm along those lines
you prolly wanna work with that list
developments your storyboard
start working with the timing remember
you're fine I'm outta time
same I like this oh man I really wanna
show of this you are that takes about
five seconds to load
start work with the timing here this is
the time in the planning stage knowing a
bar down the production stage
you know you working on the on on your
app review and still not know what
you're trying to accomplish by
so for the planning stage miserable
basic things went on time here but
I think it's good reminder 1 I'll get
you you are the weeds if you if you're
if you're the production's
process one last thing are contemplating
just like screenshots yet to disclose
all your in app purchase
so that's a good time in your planning
stage to figure how you gonna do that
if your gonna show the you know the sort
of thunder
and that cost 10,000 coins are you
either have to figure out how to
disclose that with some kind of texture
all meant
or maybe you want to show how the in app
purchase
was purchased in your and your app
review so memory of the
it disclose all your purchases plan for
it
good tip alright couple technical things
to go over
if your universal app you have a great
story more
might have a great plan above your iPad
app
and your iPad version A in your iPhone
version may have different UI elements
that you want a highly or need to
highlight or capturing a different way
to edit into your app review in the
planning phase good to identify those so
you can
capture them when you need them to help
them endure production process
on next one 0
this is a good one arm
you know your customers past and so
therefore we're gonna allow you to pick
your
language for ya preview remember it goes
on your app's primary localization but
you need to choose a language now
yet again you know your customers past
if your app's
primary localizations Japanese as
primarily sold in Japan
but yet you know that your customers
expecting English video:
as long as a passive guidelines were
gonna allow it so the planning phases
good figure out
language in use this is probably the
most obvious thing I'm gonna tell you
today but demo counts
if you're up opens up to a login screens
from your really boring app review
so republicanism I have demo counts you
know
hand along those lines you may need to
stage some information
into those accounts I if your social
opportunities within social media editor
Kyle Drabek gonna need to put some
calendar information if you're a gay man
you really want to show off that fourth
level that you
you know kids really love you have to
figure out a way to get that fourth
level
and I caution you don't stage anything
in your app review that cannot be
accomplished
in your app your app review has to be
representative the app the customer will
buy
just a caution and unknown menu doesn't
do that but it just want to warn you
about that
also are in staging goodyear
about just like screenshots we can have
any advertisements in their previous set
to get under stage those out
hunger alright but show you a cool app
review now
for me talk this is a preview for our
our friends at from from a friend to
talk about her for an app
call to collapse and they just have put
a few capture clips together
they demonstrate their quirky art
direction and they're fine you are I
this is not to get kids really involved
in experimentation in science
just give you a great picture the app in
a brief amount of time
love to show it to you right now
called
well
well West
Ste
go right through any I like it yes
please proper talk about her come on
that's a great app review just a series
of clips is very basic
my kids addicted to these actual loves
loves them alright
now or move on
my favorite part about this the capture
near really expensive cable for this
really lots worked on killing ya you
just a lightning cable
its made it so easy amazing alright a
couple things like after
no estan is seventy and I was a
you gonna be able to you hook up your
device via a lightning cable
writes your Mac open a QuickTime Player
and your devices
screen output and audio are available as
inputs
just like a camera would be yes there
you go the yeah
through breezy I love it I love it
fantastic alright so to do this
obviously
you need I S devices require lightning
cables Fletcher
iPod touches your iPhone 5 Series your
iPad
near the lightning cable support only
works over lightning
but and true Apple form it just works
a special molds no clicking no shaking
an overhead
stop on it three times that works its
plugin
selecting quick time we're gonna show it
to you today it's it's really amazing
just works love that couple tips for
capture
arm we want to display the highest
quality video and audio to the customers
and so we're we've made this capture
tool so that you can capture the highest
quality video and audio love your app
you spend a lot of time making
perfecting every pixel in your you I
know we want to capture every single
pixel
the end make sure the customer sees how
much how much love and you know
everything you put into your apt
so we're hoping that you can use these
Apple tools
on a tip just like toca Boca did there
you can start
your capture are you looking at it in
from your splash screen
looks really kinda cool if you want but
please don't capture street from the
home screen going into your aperture app
has
in her apt operability door switch back
and forth between
aP's this is about you're single app
its functions let it shine capture only
your app
go-slow I know that thirty seconds scary
to some EU but really you can make some
amazing app reviews were showing a
really awesome
couple awesome 32nd previous second
go-slow
if your customer care follow along with
what you're doing they're not going to
understand
your app review that I can understand
your appetite probably gonna be
discouraged by its a go-slow use
intentional move smooth move
moves smooth Moves you know
and there's no filmer anything to load
into the scare earlier only limitation
is your hard drives over her set retake
it
you know if your flow bitten do you try
and continue on don't don't know
just stop retake for her said retake it
you're planning a time
make a look right this is a face that's
now going on your apt you know for 30
seconds for your customers to see
so her street a caps you know take some
time
along those lines I wanna show you a
really cool app review
this app reviews of our friends up to
you
a2z countering ap that I deals with the
different levels of events
in your life and what they've done is a
example what we like to call a one take
and seven and in clips together they've
literally taken a 1-1 take
shot at their app review click Record
about a couple graphics on the front to
back
but they click Record and they go
through nice smooth intentional
movements that populate it with a lot of
a you know data they've stage their app
really well
and in their one take video you get a
great picture above the innovative you I
for their calendar app show it to you
right now milk
awesome right never listen to the music
may just it's got this great feel you
got you
get the whole app thirty-seconds
fantastic which is a great segue into
are compositions action couple tips on
composition
you've been developing a route for days
weeks months years
you know a lot about your out well
because we're probably doesn't have the
same perspective
so when you're making your app review
think about their perspective you gonna
garage them with a bunch of information
are assumptions about what are your app
does
there might be confused maybe put off so
think about your customer's perspective
and you know this is a great great tip
is you know use your friends and family
are you ever your office
show your offer a preview of and look at
look for what their
feedback is you know see if there's
something missing
your story as you might have something
in your head that you're somebody else
doesn't have in their ad
this is a a common mistake a very very
common mistake
gonna put taxed up on the screen you
need to put it up there long enough for
people to read it
people do this all the time that
protects up on the screen they don't
make it
value lead gone for you can read it so
make sure she throwing text up there
allow people to Rieger taxed miss want
easy for me cuz I'm always positive stay
positive
there's no worse sales pitch than a
negative sales pitch this is about your
app
and why your app is the past or why your
app is
awesome so don't imply anything about
other applications is keeping about your
app and stay positive
missus this is real opportunity for your
apt to shine more tips
you may be a cross platform developer
after this thirty seconds are all App
Store so go ahead
relief of those platform logo's in fact
we've of the App Store logo use the 32nd
we like our largest unwanted fine these
are your thirty seconds
leave off the platform logos you might
have
this great idea new for spring
in your app review and then
you know you think you can upload a new
binary a couple new preview
and I your CAC its sector your car
breaks down
and its eight months later and its
winter
whatever season and now it says new for
spring and it makes absolutely no sense
so keep a timeless lawyer up you just to
be about your app in some kind of
neutral time-space
34 transitions
I love a star wipe or pardon or
or contrary as much as the next guy
remember this is about your app so
stream for transitions are really
recommended when you're making app
review
on three French transitions we actually
found just in our task actually
sometimes be confusing though
Arjun cuts is what we recommend for
everyone you see large on cuts here and
I'll show you a couple or
approves the have a great John cuts but
in a couple situations we notice that
in junk cutting you can imply that your
app does something the app doesn't
actually do
so another great story for transitions
like a dissolve or a feedthrough collar
to give your user oh okay this is
a fade to another clip make sure you
don't fly the your app does something
that it does not
don't confuse our customers we love our
customers my last point is
remember the tone these are in your face
marketing videos
is just simple short app usage videos
they're fantastic remember the tone
alright this is my things to avoid slide
above my deep serious voice
for this alright thanks to avoid that's
not answers door
linking crazy flashing loud obnoxious
things
this is that the nineties in these are
banner ads
after watching your up preview their RD
on your product page they've already
click Play you don't need a gimmick to
draw them in
leave keep it simple you don't have to
do this
pricing I if you're a pricing in your
video it's going to law it's gonna be
gonna put you in a corner I member your
got a preview or your app is sold
internationally you may put your app on
sale one day if you block yourself into
pricing in your video talking to make
any sense
leave the pricing out is a good display
in your product page product page RDS
pricing
already a storefront base pricing leave
the pricing for the product page
are local
yeah I you know at local cloak ilysm
means things like that
I references to Game of Thrones that I
don't even understand I don't watch the
show
probably only one who doesn't arm but
this is my route preview
it's not about a anything that's going
on in the media nowadays so just keep it
about your app
keep it simple here's a big one
can't put anything that's just like
screenshot just like your app
can't put anything in your app review
that you don't have the rights to use
this includes but isn't limited to
imagery or photography year tax
or sounds and music or videos if you
don't have the rights to use it
do not put it in your app review right
there was a series is gonna get
one thing we had in here rocks a lot of
questions on it
narration absolutely
a powerful tool if used correctly so
here's a couple tips
there is an incredible voice-over
community out there
look for them they're they're so
talented use professional voices
not everyone has the intonation and
clarity
for voiceover work obviously I don't you
on
remember this is a voice now this is the
voice in your absence choose your words
wisely
the second one is use professional
equipment
it's available everywhere are condenser
mic spot filters
just recording studios in general quiet
rooms but nobody wants their listen to
an app review with the
narration on in the game you dog barking
in the background
or maybe for some more younger
developers in on shoot me cum
there in a whole
no all lastly
narration is a powerful tool the time
comes from the overuse you want to marry
your entire video
you wanna let your app speak so just use
narration
wisely is what I'm gonna say and having
said that
I wanna show you a really cool a preview
as for a game Koleos fortune which i
think are
gonna design or this week getting comes
from a UK FitFlop
really cool
so they have done something really neat
with their narration
they have their character nary in the
intro to their game so the integrated
that narration
with some capture gameplay footage you
can get a picture above
the story of the game as well as the
game play all in one
wheels fortune preloader show Tia I used
to be really you pulled the gold
when night questions the moon from me I
whose
only local the around me
loool to ask him the lands the for the
was lost
aboard church
one whose only fine
my fortune get it back
cool right
I love that hours after you that I
thought I merely when by the game in
you know now unlike level 12 or
something like that on okay
so to give me a lot of information but
really there's no better way to get to
know all this then to demonstrate it
so what I'd like to demonstrate for sis
capture and to do that
I'd like to bring up mister John dnt who
is the
senior product manager for broadband was
gonna help us capture some clips for a
garage band app review
John gonna go over a demo machine here
I will tune up my iPhone tuning
mmm well alright with a Mac running here
Sastry Mac Pro and it's plugged into
this USB cable
lightning cable my hand at the John W
have their
I have an iPhone 5s or a grudge mallone
and I'm a plug this in
go ahead likes a like so that was it
alright that's the in the demo
prepare I'm here tonight thank you are
sorter boxer on a Mac
we are going to open up QuickTime Player
where to go up here to file
new movie recording haha
below this me to plan some guys there
%ah ready on the transfer bar is our
input menu
and you can see John's phone now shows
up as a video and audio inputs we're
gonna switch it over right now
I
now we're gonna switch over the audio to
exploit the great are you at a garage
band
alright I'm gonna give you will sound
here John
okay if you like a warm up Mary II
year I'm a little nervous system injury
your fingers you know
Canada
thank you very much I giving thank you
do anything less liberace maybe a little
more Metallica
9 I think so but there
ryan Johnson now
hi
I WWDC now what's the area
I
alright are over you doing up review now
I so John I
I was thinking doing a nap you like a
one take 1st May will do an example one
take is there something about garage
minutes
makes a magical the one feature that
really stands out that we can capture in
under 30 seconds
well are these is love our smart
instruments but I think the smart
strings is pretty
is pretty 'cause let you know that OCR
OCR dress on a pier
so we are input setup and just click
Record you ready to go I'm ready occur
year ago sauce went through the touch
since my browser
lawn and smart strings and I'll play
little ditty on
boom
%uh
it sounds very close your eyes I
you available for weddings
in bar mitzvahs I alright we just stop
on the screen
was gonna say that out and we will call
that the one take
right there now's a good time just to
let you guys know
up the QuickTime capture capture the
need a frame rate the your app
outputs so when you're putting into
iTunes Connect we're gonna ask you to
normalize that to standardize frame rate
so that one take video will still need
to go through something like iMovie
and be exported out to standardize frame
rate before it gets
uploaded in Titan's connect right but
John we're going to a different one
we're going to a maybe clip base yeah so
we've got a song we started in garage
band already there be a good soundtrack
and then
we could capture some instruments and
added them all together K
from CSR a back up here and
checker and birds all good make sure
not to mention his performance record he
set a maximum member we want to deliver
the highest-quality
video and audio to customers alright so
you're also you probably a smart you
wanna play that song
yeah just a lil sample here so we can
hear snappy number
sounds good through alright so what
we're gonna do is capture the
the the clips the instruments made
used to make the song so what's the
first answer we're going to we're going
to send space
well like this control panel that's
gonna corey has really nice yes we can
relive the eighties
I he's never there okay
30 I'm ready to go. current record
retire any
on
%uh
on like Depeche Mode under
love it I love it is fantastic
I was gonna save
call at the base okay
on another one you know when you shift I
get another one I lied to them
pursue a cent ascent Springer percent
there
and a up
how was school years we have this
feature in garage man where we can do
was call pitchman out so
as the play we get the blue dot but you
also can
the lie between the nodes
like Michael the show that only if any
we're not control panel
you know that's in control oh yeah yes
we pop that okay we show that possible
recapture that church lacquer K
whenever you're ready
castano troll this tap here
and then we think starter good up
up
summer have fun in a red pitch millicent
you can't play
great right one last
instrument from John your know your
concert tour to get Iran Bruins winning
the ban will be time
Union history and I'm a
cirrhosis march on silence our Terms so
one capsule to bring the dais animal
will put it together enough
arms ago area lovers
brown cool
cool as right save and
that's great I'm capture
tell your grandpa Sir John from from
montana
crew okay so there's a great transition
where we can now would capture clips
let's now open up iMovie
let's show you how really easy it is to
drag those clips and
increase your app review pop open I
movie
I'm gonna black project willing to go
look at that current
we're gonna grab those clips that we
just image are a drag mentor event
we ever about right here this is where
we can browse our clips we can favorite
them
can work with them and we have our time
line down here we can start
building our preview can I add titles in
transition so let's just start with some
drums is our drums we captured offstage
the real hard to capture in this room
with the echo
drag those here make the time while
smaller second worker
was the next instrument that was the
beaks
describing along here you can see on the
way for view operate here
think I see where my audio click San
again
Rico
to get them out base right thing
and was an act that was the sent right
with the cool controllers
skip
girl
school we had that pause there so I'm
going to just
with my way former principal ago
gatorade is this come in get that hit
for second looks good
okay we exported out
John song earlier put on the folder to
serve in a drag
that down into the soundtrack section
rate there now I could add maybe some
titles to this
from the content library but I really do
like to end on a fade to black in any
video that I do
let's just track that on there that
literally pro
when I wanna do also
was on mute these clips they don't
conflict that soundtrack
right I was it was %um swirly israeli
about that the call
so cool
I love it alright so we can do what we
can do for this we get out a couple more
Answer Man 3 could work on our timings
we could fill it out a little and that's
actually
what we did the other afternoon I want
to show you that this is a completed app
review
main garage band captured clips
maturity right now
alright I can tell their paws your proof
so if you're happy with your %ah preview
if that's what you love
you to go up care to share you can
export that file you can expect high
resolution file
and you gonna get ready to go into
iTunes Connect
but we have already taken the time to do
that we've explored that file onto this
CrossRef or on the desktop
and show us how to upload these aren't
its iTunes Connect
on my colleagues from iTunes engineering
was Karen present because men ski
gonna come up show it to you Karen hello
i'm karen is Nancy
software engineer at iTunes Connect I'm
here today to show you
how simple and intuitive it is to upload
your app reviews
along with your images in the newly
redesigned iTunes Connect
let's check it out him
her I it's let's open up iTunes Connect
and here we are nineteen connect
has if creating a new version of garage
bands as you can see
there's currently only one im one
screenshot so
let's add to its this is where we had
new screenshots and the app review the
pollen John just Crean
we could add them the old fashion way in
with the file chooser
but it would be more fun to open up
finder
and simply
drag-and-drop from
had has you can see the video ends up in
first position
followed by the screenshots to its right
the screenshots can be rearranged into
whatever order you want by dragging and
dropping
whatever order you choose is the order
that ends up in the App Store
hmm the video will always remain fixed
in first position just as it does in the
App Store cell
this is all looking really good but I
don't love the poster frame on the app
review
by default we select a poster frame for
you
by if you'd like to choose another one
just click Edit poster frame
abut up pops a dialogue on with the
video are no
laps and the currently selected poster
frame on the right
to select another poster frame we can
play the video
and pick or we can scrape through the
video
right for him anytime
or we can get granular and step through
forward or backward
to look it's just the right for him
I like that one lets choose that one
and once you've found the perfect frame
just click Done and voila
there it is once
once you have your screen shots in your
poster for am looking just the way you
want
you can click same and submit for review
and once
the app is gone through the approval
process we can check out what it looks
like in the App Store
and their 10th
so simple as that
I'm in just a few minutes i won and
iTunes Connect
drops some images dropped a video
said a poster frame and now how my app
looks to the world
is completely defense thank you had come
thank you karen
I was awesome alright was go back
just 31 just the second back to that
exporting
are morning yet again reiterate this we
want to show the highest quality
audio/video your customer
so we want to we will we're gonna accept
and we'd like you to export out at the
highest quality video
so that to coincide with the I was
device captures
highest-quality video settings and that
is for the iPad
900 by 1200 in portrait mode
1200 by nine hundred and landscape mode
for the iPhone in four inch series are
that's the 1136 by 640 I'm guessing but
you can just
the National Committee 640 by 11:30 sex
but also we know the guys I have some
are you have already captured footage
in 1080 workflows maybe rena 1080
workflow already
us we're gonna take very answer 1080 as
well for those iPhone
dimensions and here's some technical
data
don't everybody grab your pen this will
all be in the documentation
although you can take a picture if you
are doing poses
by Sears Roebuck Allan Poe's is things
like that not couple takeaways here
I we're gonna take to kodak's that are
very familiar to the Apple ecosystem
that h264
and progress 422 HQ number high-quality
want to take that Progress
are so you high school your customers
I'm comin takeaways is the
30 frames per second would like you to
upload your sources in 30 frames per
second
morning take stereo audio either NAAC
or PCM way basic this all this
documentation will be available to you
don't worry about running dices que
writing it down sorry its okay
it our hedge I liked and out
with a couple review guidelines now
the review guidelines we publish this
feature a is rolled out
and obviously I'm not to be able to go
over every single applicable
review guideline to you but I'd like to
highlight a few that'll help
a find you safe passage remember things
like
I am inappropriate content trademarked
items all applied app reviews
so consult the app review guidelines for
for uploading
your app review first one keep it
relevant
if you're out has screenshots or out
previews are absolutely not relevant to
to your app it will be rejected so don't
sneak in a plug for your uncle Murray's
car wash
Korea are so you know surprise proposal
to your fiance
that's not the time keep it relevant
you're out by the way she said yes
were married day
alright max-1 just like screenshots you
got a keeper for plus
90 you're sitting there maybe have a
game called Mortal Kombat
and the early part of may get into
article first or something like that no
but you're gonna have to get creative
you know what its be overdoing the the
shark didn't work you may jobs it was
awesome so
get creative creative editing I just you
only the violence
those things out has to be four plus
applicable to all audiences just like
screenshots
easy enough alright use captured footage
know our people in you paid for you know
videos and people were interacting with
your app's no hands in the shop such a
move that hand
are this is captured footage you can use
isn't actual amounts
you can use graphic elements that
highlight points
but this is mostly about your app and
your app review needs to be made
mostly have captured footage and we've
given you those tools
so use captured footage
on this one simulated data please goes
without saying
we still use any celebrities don't use
anybody don't use our neighbor your
friend
person sitting next to anybody who would
have issue with you shove their likeness
in your app review are you know about
Johnny Appleseed we use it all the time
you need to find your own Johnny
Appleseed's and if you're going to use
any data
in your app review miss last one I've
got over before I go over to ken
you got to identify your in app
purchases you know the sort of truth
the missiles are in in our touch writer
aP here
you gotta figure out a way in Europe
review for going to use those in app
purchase content
gushing our way to disclose them in your
an app purchases
suppose that just a couple guidelines
keeping your head very easy
made me wanna make this very easy for
you guys alright
time for summary app reviews
are just 30 seconds app usage footage
need to be four plus an appropriate for
all audiences
device capture using a lightning cable
Mac almost 10 your family and I was a
into QuickTime Player you can add it on
your Mac using iMovie iMovie will be
updated
to support his native aspect ratios and
device dimensions
for more advanced editing Final Cut Pro
is
always a great option love Final Cut Pro
and we made it super easy as Karen
showed you to upload them into iTunes
Connect
a larger binary reviewed we're gonna re
in coding for streaming all around the
world
simple our clothes out the really cool
app review
this was gonna personal to me this one
came in I and i believe the SOP also
want to design a word
this week which is kinda neat without
preview came in and it just touched me
arm ever since I was a kid I was one of
those people that would
current certain look out at the stars in
everybody does this for you
put your finger out you can trace the
Big Dipper
are you track awry and or something like
that
and this preview came in and it showed
me an app that
did what I always dreamed I could do I
meet you yet again middle ear and my
iPad but the app
went home sat out on the porch with my
daughter and we
played with the Stars and this the sky
guide
the No
the
lovely
it's just lovely yeah now sky got school
Super Bowl alright few me more
information please
reach out to your Angeles the amazing
incredible Rachel rock
a yes please stop her
documentation to be available this is
actually something you might hurt
take a picture ok too long URL if you
need it all
it'll be available on on the on and
develop perform I and we have the job
forms as well you can interact get
information
I we have some related sessions the new
iTunes Connect
you weren't there yesterday you miss
something amazing but you can always
watch it on the replay
the new iTunes Connect a little preview
over here can show you with the
the drag and drop interface is you a
chance to act is gonna blow your mind
are if you're planning on using camera
capture and you want to integrate and
traps
there's a camera capture session watch
these on the replay really help really
cool
listen we've given you the temps
we've shown you the technology you can
have the tools going out
I'm a great app reviews everybody here