hi my name's James Wilson I'm
engineering manager and
things on my team works on is the
frameworks that power the App Store on
the iBookstore analyst 10
witching course course includes the
unified receipt format that we
introduced last year
so in this session preventing
unauthorized purchases with receipts
what was specifically going to talk
about is a way in which
you can use this concept of a receipt to
protect your revenue enforce protection
if your business model
directly into your app as well as into
your serve as an issue in content
based on an in app purchase having been
made ultimately we use receipts to know
exactly what the customer has paid for
you can do this both within your app
so you can build logic in Europe binary
itself that verifies the receipt knows
that it came from Apple
and knows exactly what the user has paid
for as well as you can engineer logic
into your servers
to do that same verification to make
sure real monetary transaction has
occurred with the App Store
to make sure that you're going to be
paid for all this comes down to one
simple thing
protecting your revenue now the receipt
is a lot like
the physical proof of purchase docket or
receipt the you get
when you're shopping in a store the same
sort of concept
it's a trusted record of the ap and in
app purchases that have been made
and just like that physical receipt you
get when you shopping in a store
it's the way that you can build security
into your app
to make sure that you are going to be
paid for those features and content the
yuan locking in providing to your users
you're just like a department store can
look at your receipt and know exactly
what you paid for before you walk out
with goods
you can do the exact same thing in your
app and that's what we're gonna show you
in the session the receipts office store
on the device
Naz API's you can use to access it and
the receipt is issued by the App Store
will issue a receipt
every time a transaction takes place so
when an app is purchased
and installed there's a receipt in that
when
in a purchase occurs a receipt is issued
and it's available to you to verify that
purchase
likewise when pretty previous
transactions are restored
another receipt is issued that will
allow you to verify the authenticity
those purchases and we achieve that by
having the receipt signed
in a way that is verifiable by you at
the code level
so once you get this receipt you can
confirm that really came from Apple
and haven't been tampered with at all
the most importantly the receipt file
is unique to your app on a single device
it makes sure that when you verify that
receipt you can be
absolutely certain that this purchase
happened for your app
from this user on this single device
alone
now when we're working with receipts
as you'll see in this session it's a lot
like a recipe
there's a recipe that Apple gives you
but there are things that you are going
to need to bring to the table as well
this decisions that you will need to
make along the way to make sure the your
receipt implementation
your ability to protect your revenue in
your app suits your unique needs
there's a lot of flexibility built into
the system
now in particular what apple provides
you with
is the receipt format specification and
we build this receipt on a bunch of open
standards
there's nothing proprietary about these
receipts the great thing about that is
because they're all open standards that
a very very widely used in many places
you have lots of options available for
you for how to work with receipts
we give you the receipt itself nes API's
to find where the receipt is located
and we're giving you instructions on how
to do on device receipt validation and
that'll be the main focus in this
session
and we also provide an online service
that allows your servers to verify the
authenticity a receipt
what use the developing need to choose
is the level of security that's
appropriate for your products
and likewise that will translate into
determining the level of complexity
in your implementation that suits your
needs
this three key decisions that you're
going to need to make and will call
these out as we go through this session
to help you with that
the first decision you're going to need
to make his how will you verify the
signature in the receipt
what will you use to determine that the
receipt
definitely came from Apple and hasn't
been tampered with since women today
second is how would you verify the
receipt is intended for your app
on this device and lastly you will need
to decide
how you wish to interpret that purchase
started that's contained within the
receipt itself
so you know exactly what the user paid
for
when you making these decisions the
primary thing that factors into this
is the value of your products and
therefore how much importance your place
on protecting that revenue he is one way
to look at it
if you are a very high value product you
typically selling im
perhaps an in app purchase that's
designed to be a one-off purchase
large value and that one single in app
purchase
is the primary revenue stream for your
app and the primary enabler for all the
features and content that you're selling
to the user now in that sense you're a
lot like a high-end jewelry store
and when you think about your shopping
experience in a jewelry store
you notice that they implement very
complex levels of security
to make sure that not one single pole
can walk out that door
without having been paid for you when
you go to a
jewelry store you see jury hidden behind
glass cases
see security staff position at the door
mighty security wandering through
making sure that everything's okay they
might be metal detectors
your perfect purchase checking et cetera
it's a very high level of security
and quite complex but the reason they go
to these lengths
is because their business model is
centered around that one of
large purchase the you're not going to
make very frequently
but at the complete other into the
spectrum is low value products
and these are typically the low value in
app purchases
dollar two dollars maybe up to five
dollars and the typically things the
consumables
and your business model probably relies
on customers coming back again and again
to enjoy the same product buying more
currency
final gas for the car mobloc so they can
build amazing things
in this sense you're a lot more like a
grocery store
think about your shopping experience in
a grocery store grocery store wants you
to feel incredibly comfortable and happy
shopping there
so the you come back again and again and
again and keep spending with them
grocery stores filled with hundreds and
hundreds of products that are probably
selling for a dollar or two and not much
more
they rely on the same sort of business
model that you would if you're selling
those low value consumables
they want you to have a great shopping
experience to feel comfortable and
welcome
and to enjoy it every single time and
the not gonna care too much of a couple
the grapes walk out of the store without
being paid for
unless you keep coming back again
against doing the grapes
to take a look at how we work with
receipts in the workflow
starting off with the basics the receipt
itself
is stored in the app bundle or in your
sandbox container
and as an API in Ennis bundle to get to
the URL to locate where that receipt is
it's a single flap file so it's really
easy to work with
it's not too complicated contained
within that single flat file
is purchased on or about the app
purchase itself as well as in app
purchases that have been made
and there's also a signature that allows
us to check the authenticity
you see we take that purchase
information what you're particularly
interested in as a developer
and wrap it around certificates and
signatures
the make sure that when we write that
purchase information into the receipt
we sign it and add a signature the means
you can verify
that it's exactly as we intended when
women to the receipt and no ones tried
to fake it by adding in any product
changing purchase information at cetera
and we build this on open standards in
particular
the signing that we use to wrap up a lot
of daughter in a signature so compact am
but we've
is known as a PKcs 7 cryptographic
container
don't let the acronyms for you here
there's a lot of information available
online and these very widely used in
many many places
the daughter itself in that payload the
purchase information
we encode that that is we structured at
the bite level
using a standard called sn1 now you
would be amazed at the huge
number of places that a yes and one is
used
its a standard that has been around for
a very very long time
which is great because when you combine
the fact that both these are very widely
used
it means that you going to find that
you're not the first person to try and
implement support for this
in fact as we progress through the
session you'll see that all those
decisions you need to make
they generally Spanish gamma from
at one in the extreme they will be
off-the-shelf offerings the you can
simply pick up and run with straight
away
in the middle ground is probably a lot a
sample code up at the you can find a
maybe copy and
adjusted to suit your needs someone but
then because these are open standards
and the specifications are freely
available you're completely empowered to
write your own implementation
if that was important here that is if
you want complete control
over how you protect your revenue you
can do that
so so many options open SSL
which I'm sure everyone has heard of is
a cryptographic library
that serves many functions beyond just
HTTPS and secure Sockets that it's more
widely known for
a bonus for sale include support for not
only doing the PKcs 7 signature
verification
but also for reading sn1 what kind of a
one stop shop if you wanted
alive re that was available the could do
this for you
there's also some other command line
tools that can help you out with this
man sure there is a lot of other
offerings out there
but you can still create your own if
that's what you want to do
so I'm gonna take you through in this
session is a three-step process
that you can use to verify these
receipts the first thing we have to do
is make sure we know that the receipt is
authentic
and trusted that is it came from Apple
and no one's tampered with once we know
we have a receipt that is authentic and
trusted
we can move on to confirming that the
receipt was in fact intended for
our app on this device
because just as it's important to make
sure that no one's tampered with the
receipt we also want to make sure no
ones just copied it from another device
now once we have a receipt that we know
we trust and it's for hour upon the
single device
we can go ahead and start interpreting
the purchase toda to know exactly what
the user has paid for
missed out this offer the demo I have
here
a very simple project
that's just gonna get us started in
terms of getting a receipt to work with
we all this is great but if you haven't
been able to get a receipt to actually
start
verifying the signature with this
process can be difficult so let's see
how we go about doing that
really simple app application did finish
launching
and the first thing I do is a call this
NS bundle API
to get the URL to the App Store recede
I'm simply going to use and is filed
manager here
to determine if the file exists or not
that is do we have a receipt to work
with
if we do have set myself up a method
that can go ahead and do that validation
for me
but if not if I don't have a receipt
what I do is on OS 10 I exit my up with
the special exit code 173
that tells the OS and the App Store the
you believe your CDs battle missing
and lets the App Store going to get a
receipt for your
so this is all in the documentation and
it seems pretty straight forward at this
point
signing a clean this project make sure
we have no receipt
in a builder in a runner
now notice I've got to break point set
up here the first as I wanted to check
that I got my
app store receipt if we see down here in
the debug console I definitely did
and ask for a manager if that receipt
exists
it says no course cuz I'm running from
Xcode and I have not yet put my app on
the store so close we don't have a
receipt
but we want one so we can start testing
and validation
so the documentation says exit 173 let's
do that
and nothing happens this is the first
point the developers kinda get stuck
with
they get started with receipt validation
put the code in place running an ex-con
go
I doesn't miss do anything reason for
that is
when you run your app in Xcode like that
and it hits that exit 173 code
only Xcode sees that exit code said I
was in the App Store's not aware that
you're actually running your Apple
morning to get a receipt
so here's a trick to help you do that
this time when I run the Apple hit the
same breakpoint
me to go down here to the doc control
click on
the app-icon down here and I use options
show in Finder that brings up find a
to my debug build version of the app
that we're running
because remember I want this to exit
with that special coding for the App
Store to see that exit code
so it gets me in your receipt so watch
what I do here go back to Xcode and I
stopped that instanceof the app
back to find a and now I run the app
from Phineas and look what happened
we did the same logic receipt was in pay
and we exited 173
now the App Store has seen that and is
prompting me to sign in
so that we can go and get a receipt to
start working with
and because my up worse I'm with my
development certificate I'm connected to
the App Store's test environment using
iTunes Connect
test accounts to get a test receipt for
us to start working with
so I sign in we get our seed and my
really simple app
has finished launching with the receipt
now
just to double check if I go back here
in Xcode
we got a URL to the receipt and this
time
we have the receipt ready to start
working with the validation that recede
now if you working with I O S receipts
one other team I find handy is if you're
having trouble getting a receipt in the
test environment
making in app purchase when you make an
in app purchase you will get in your
receipt
and you can use that to test a
validation code
so let's go to first step verifying the
signature in that receipt so we know
that this receipt is authentic
untrusted and unaltered
so this vet this verification the sing
to make sure the receipt hasn't been
altered since it left Apple
because we don't want anyone tampering
with and it came from Apple
so that no one else can just meant their
own receipts that look otherwise Ballard
but are in fact frauds this is where the
PKcs 7 cryptographic contain it comes in
it's how we wrapped up for that
protected body have purchase information
around those signatures and certificates
so we can confirm authenticity
now you options available for you for
doing this authenticity check
we mention before there's open SSL can
do this for you there's no doubt many
other frameworks out there that can do
this for you
but of course can roll your own if you
choose
to get you started the first thing you
need to do is find that receipt
week organised bundle main bundle App
Store ctrl
that gives us the URL to the receipt
once we've got that URL
we need to get read into memory so we
can start working on it
and that's the simple as using something
like in a startup it with content URL
Milwaukee through here and open SSL
example of how to do this signature
verification
this is straight out of a documentation
we have online
but one thing to note is this example
makes two assumptions
we assume that you've already read the
receipt in the memory and have stored in
this variable called
the receipt am we also assume that
you've got a copy Apple's root CA at
root certificate authority
which you can find online and you have
that in your app on knowing you've read
into memory and stored in this variable
Colby X 599
why 599 because X 599 is the standard by
which that
RCA's encoded so once we've got those
two key ingredients
the first thing we want to do is convert
tableau binary that represents the
receipt in memory
into useful data structure we can start
working with and we do that by calling
the really simply an aptly named
d2 I PKcs 7 be I up
done with these names full-year what
you'll see here is despite the fact that
these were named by someone very arcane
these are simple concept we're reading a
file into memory
we're setting up in a structure so we
can work with that and we're checking
we're calling some functions on it and
checking the result
anyone can do that so once we've got a
data structure
we've got a receipt on one hand but the
other thing we need
is out certificate that we expect this
receipt to match up against
right we want to compare these two
things we have a receipt we want to make
sure that it came from Apple hasn't been
altered since Apple created
so we set up the certificate store and
we adding to that store Apple's root CA
because if the certificate if this
signature in the receipt is valid
it has to appear that it's come from
Apple's root CA
now we get into the meat of this we
called a much better named PKcs 7 verify
function
pas since what our receipt and how
certificate store
we just checked the result if the result
is equal to 1
that means our receipt signatures valid
came from Apple
his trusted hasn't been altered since
Apple min to the receipt
now you also get another bonus from
calling this function and that is
that it will return back to you the
actual payload have the receipt itself
so that body of purchase information
that you can start inspecting to know
what the user paid for
and you get that back in this example in
the B receipt payload variable
so I have another project here the build
upon that simple example that we saw
before
you see here that I have my same
did finish launching method where a
check the receipt
we know we've got a receipt from the
last demo and so I fleshed out my
validate receded URL method
with these exact same calls that we've
just saw in that slide before
so you build this
hi 12 warnings
12 errors not a great stop
again this is another point the
developers confined really frustrating
with this process
when you take this example code and try
and use it you going to run into a few
roadblocks
but we can get through this the first
thing is
you reason you getting all these our
compiler warnings here
telling you that all these methods were
deprecated is because in fact they are
why I'm out here on stage telling you to
use duplicating methods
we deprecated these in OS 10 10 7
because we want developers that
especially if you're concerned about
your strong cryptography and security
like this we want developers to create
and roll their on building open SSL is a
static library
and integrate that open SSL build
straight into your
applications binary think of it this way
when you build your app unlink against
things like you like it an app care
that's an external dependency you're up
can run on one machine on one version of
the OS
and run just fine on another version of
the OS even know app can you like it
might be very different
their external dependencies that can be
swapped out from under you and as long
as those API's match up to what you're
up to spec expecting
it'll run Magin how easy it would be
for someone who wanted to try and attack
your apt to try and rip you off
to simply swap out and external
dependency like open SSL
for version about an SSL that they
brawled themselves
but simply said yeah everything's fine
this receipts valid trust me
see when you use that external
dependency for strong cryptography in
privacy some stuff like this
you can run into problems where you
create big attack vector the mixer
really easy for someone to circumvent
the logic you're putting in Europe to
protect your revenue enforcer business
model
so what we need to do here is build our
own open SSL
now it's not as near nearly as scary as
it sounds I got some tips for you in the
next slide
in fact I've already built my own open
SSL and I have it here
on the desktop in a folder called open
SSL
now when you build open SSL it produces
two things for you
a folder called include full love the
header files for what we want to work
with
and also a lib folder that contains that
dot a static library
we've built now using this is actually
pretty simple
I like to keep my projects pretty clean
so I'm gonna go ahead and
create myself a group here
called open SSL facts
there we go an all I have to do is
simply drag and drop this build product
from open SSL straight into my project
header files and static libraries
make sure you click this copy items into
destination group folder that make sure
that we copy those headers
and the static libraries built directly
into your project itself otherwise
you'll have a dangling external
dependencies might go away
finish I add in my freshly built open
SSL to my product
call build
built succeeds but I still have 11
compiler warnings
and if you're like me you care a lot
about your project building with 0
warnings
so why we still getting these different
had warnings because Xcode
is trying to build against the SDK the
chips with the OS that has that
deprecated open SSL
the way we get around that is we have to
tell Xcode
that for this app that we're building we
actually want Xcode to use album
I R open SSL we just added to the
project
so I went to my project settings here I
have clicked on
this target and I'm gonna go to build
settings
and as an option you'll find call head
of search parts
double click on that and I need to tell
Xcode here where to find those are
necessary file for me just add
an easy trick for doing that his pop
this open here on the side panel
find one ahead as open up this sign
inspector
and there you'll see the full power to
wear that had a file is located in the
project
notice in this case I've got within my
project folder and it's in a folder
hierarchy call include slash
include okay so we just need to tell
Xcode
to go in allow files to be imported from
that location for headers
so I double click here and rather than
having to enter that full directory path
I can use shortcut assaying
it's in source route slash include slash
include because that's where we saw the
file just before
add that in put it to the top because I
want that before anything else in the
system
I wanna make sure we look at my open SSL
files first
done we say that was updated their close
this far to go back to a rap delegate we
had all these mornings
done all those compiler warnings went
away
because now we're building a project
against our open SSL that we built
that we know the integrity of the way to
ship built into apt binary to protect
our revenue and check our receipts
so let's run this and see how it goes
so we've already got a receipt from the
earlier damn it we did and now we can
enter a valid 8 receded URL
method here these are the same cause we
saw just on the slide before I load the
receipt into memory
I load the root CA in the memory t2i
PKcs 7 by our
to load that Baba proceed into a usable
data structure called p7
create my certificate store and now I'm
ready to do the magic
does this receipt stack up against that
root CA certificate
I step over that and if I look down here
in the console shorn of
result is one that means we can now move
forward knowing that we have a real
valid and trusted receipt we can start
getting purchase information out of
and what before we do that we need to
confirm that for
intended for our up on this device
but now we're over the hurdle not only
working with the receipt we got from the
test environment
but we now got open SSL integrated into
a project
to be ready to be built for both I O S
and OS 10
all I'm doing everything here using OS
everything I cover here applies to I was
just as it does on a West Ham
if there's any platform differences I'll
call them out for you
a couple tips on building open SSL for
you first is you need to build
as a static library not I'll im not a
framework
not something that can be external to a
binary you needed to be a static library
so that when you build your app unlink
it it takes that dante and puts right
into
your caps binary so no one else can swap
it out from you
nephew building for multiple
architectures which you almost certainly
will be few building for IOUs
all the different arm architectures them
what you need to do is build a separate
dante
separate static library for each
architecture you want to support the
on the seven on 64 whatever you might
need to build for
of x86-64 no están
and when you create those individual dot
a static libraries
for each other's architectures use the
life ok a mental
to take all those little dot i+
architecture slices
and combine them into one fat binary
that is one single die static library
the combined all about slices
all-america Texas we want to support
and then you can just drag that strange
a project like we did just before
now we build open SSL the first thing
you do is you to configure script to
configure up in a self
as a cell for the platforms you building
on he's too tipsy you'll find handy
if you're building for OS 10 64-bit
configure with the Don 64x64
x86-64 CC host type if you see
documentation from a tell you something
BST generic types
you're going to run into trouble so this
is much easier and it ensures a proper
build open SSL
on x86-64 refusing
our if you believe I O S try using the
iPhone OS cross-post typing the
configure script to configured for I O S
accordingly
the you will definitely not be the first
person ever that has tried to build open
SSL for the OS 10
or IRS we deprecated open SSL a while
back in OS 10
and we never shipped an open SSL NIOS
the developers can use
so lots of folks have been through this
for a lot to different reasons
there's lots of examples available to
you online
to note about doing the verification no
matter how you do the verification be an
open SSL
roll-your-own another offering do not
check the expiry date
on the certificate when you're
contacting the web server vir Panesar
Virage TPS
it's important to you verify the expiry
date of the signature
you don't want to be talking to a web
server out there
using a secure transport with a
certificate has since expired
but the reverse is true here for
receipts keep in mind the fact that we
meant this receipt at a point in time
and that comes with your apt when
someone downloads it'll make snap
purchase
now at that point in time they will be
certificates included in that receipt
that have an expiry date if FedEx
if someone buys a rap today and then a
year down the track that certificate
expires within the receipt
that does not make the receipt invalid
the receipt is just as valid as it was
the day that you purchased
and would be a terrible experience for
that user
if all of a sudden your app stopped
working only because the receipt
has a certificate in there that has
since expired
bore you do absolutely wanna make sure
you do when you do you receive
validation is evaluate the trust of the
certificates
right up to the root CA you see the
certificates exist in a chain
but at the head of the chain at the root
has to be Apple's root certificate
authority
that's the only way you can be
absolutely certain that it came from us
and not from someone else trying to pose
as Apple
wanting a quick word though about
examples and sample code
I've mentioned a lot throughout the
session that a
there are a lot of samples out there
there's examples I'm sure there's
off-the-shelf
offerings you could literally download
inputs trading your project would do
this for you
the convenience comes at a price
you have to keep in mind the reusing
code brings with it bugs and
vulnerabilities
no matter how with the developer is no
matter how well use the sample code is
no matter how much you might have
paid for it any code comes with bugs
and possible vulnerabilities
and the more people that use the exact
same way of doing receipt validation
the more there is the chance of one
exploit affecting many many APs
you know back in a jewelry example
imagine if every jeweler's shop around
the world
use the same lock on the cabinets and
then one day someone finds out a really
easy way to open at Lock
not gonna be good for anyone earning
jewelry store right
same sorta principle here although this
can seem so convenient to just grab
something of get hubbell somewhere else
and drop it in your project and have got
receipt validation protected revenue
you need to make sure you understand the
risks of what you bringin
because that's your revenue stream at
the end of the day
not third-party the road that code not
the nice individual the put up some
sample code help you get this done
it's not their revenue it's your revenue
so make sure you make decisions that
suit your product
maybe you're okay with those sorts of
vulnerabilities in bugs and the
possibility of a single export affecting
your app
maybe that suits the business model and
level of protection you want
but either way know in the room know the
risks and owners risks yourself
alright so we've got a you receipt that
we know is trusted & verified in a came
from Apple
now we need to make sure that it is
intended for your ap
on this device only to do that we need
to look at the receipt payload itself
now this is a very high level ok at how
a receipt is structured it structured as
a series about tributes
you could think of these attributes as a
cross between an SRA and in Ennis
dictionary
they like in its dictionary because they
have things like
a type and a value a lot like a
dictionary has a key in object
but they like an array because there is
a sequence of days
throughout the receipt you can loop over
to interpret
they also have a version on each
these attributes but that's not too
important to us right now the key thing
we need to know is
inside that body of data in the receipt
is a series about tributes
a chechen it has a type that tells us
what it is what it means
and in a value the corresponds to what
this attribute is telling us
so the first thing we need to do is
check if this receipt was actually
intended for our app
in those attributes that we won call
type 2 and one call type 3
all the attributes and named by a number
so attribute our two
in the receipt if you read that
attributes value it will be the bundle
identify this receipt was intended for
and then type 3 the bundle version but
this receipt was intended for
so you can check the bundle identify and
make sure it's for your app
you can check the bundle version if you
wanna even high-level security perhaps
you wanna make
absolutely certain that someone's not
using a receipt from older version of
your app
the perhaps doesn't have the same
features and content
the one thing to note is use hard coded
values for the comparison
why because if you simply grab the
values that have your info palest
and compare them against the values in
the receipt it's all too easy for
someone to go on
edit your info appeal is to make it look
exactly like the receipt that they're
trying to fake you with
so hardcore those values into your apt
the expecting
that way they parted the code signed up
binary much harder to try and circumvent
now it was a very high level look at how
this receipt daughter is structured in
terms of attributes
but as I said before this is encoded as
in the bites are arranged
using a standard called OPI sn1
this to other attributes along with type
2 and type 3
so we use type 2 and type 3 to confirm
that this receipt was for our app
but now we need to confirm that it was
actually intended for this device
only because we don't want someone to
simply be able to copier ended
receipt around to their friends so that
they can use the app without paying for
it
so included in the receipt is an
attribute call type for which is an
opaque value
just blah but bytes and type 5 which is
a sha-1 hash
national familiar with hashing hashing
is a way to take a large beloved
daughter
and boil it down to a unique smaller
that will be absolutely unique to that
larger data set that was the input to
the hash
so those tight five attributes is a
sha-1 hash
of three key values it's a bundle I day
plus a unique device identifiers like
the guy we don't know is 10
or their device vendor on I O S
and also this opaque value
how does this work to actually confirm
that it intended for your device
for a single device you see the App
Store knows
these three key pieces of information at
the time that purchases made
with someone taps the buy button on your
Apple run ended up purchasing complete
the transaction
the App Store knows three casings 1 we
know the bundle ID if the app making the
purchase
to we know the device identifiers from
that device because it sent to the store
when the transaction is made
and three on server side we create this
opaque value this been a friend a mentor
Peter Rhee inject into this process
to make it harder to attack so the App
Store knows these three key things at
the time of purchase
creates the sha-1 hash makes it into the
receipt along with opaque value that we
used
the great thing is that your app can
know the same three values
at the time after receipt validation
so because you know the three values and
you can string them together in that
long concatenation of bites and create
the hash
and the App Store on you these three key
values and created the same hash input
in the receipt
if the hash you calculate exactly
matches the hash that the App Store
created in putting the receipt
then you're certain the dis- receipt was
intended for your app on this device
only
it's completely unique to this device
now about I S and one
these high-level this high-level look at
the attributes
that explains how we structure them and
how you work with the different
attributes and how we store them as an
array of attributes with a type in a
value
how they encode at the actual bite level
how do you work with us in code
the way you do that is by harnessing sn1
heslin one is this way in which we can
use a textual definition the see here on
screen
to describe how the bites are arranged
in the receipt
we provide you with this I S and one
definition of how we structure the
receipt
and what you seeing up on screen is that
you have a receipt model defined
and in that receipt there is a payload
and that payload is a separate seat
attributes
and the receipt attribute will be part
of a sequence and it contains a type
which relates to that type that we just
saw before as well as a value
it is an octet string or a bunch bytes
and that refers to things like that
opaque
value in the shower 1/2 we looked at
just before
working with the sn1 the trick is
you need to find a way to go from that
textual definition
that's based on the open standard about
an SSL to actually being able to read in
writing
work with it in the code level says a
few options for you because of course
this is very widely used
one option is again open SSL just as it
did the PKcs 7 verification he can read
as: in one just fine
you can create your own pasta if you
want to to again have full control over
this
let's look at an open SSL example
when we did that first step verifying
the receipt we got back to p7 data
structure remember that
now we can use that same data structure
to actually get that payload oversee
daughter the tin ko tin I S and one it's
buried in there
in the p7 data structure we see their
once we've got that we can call this
function call sn1 GetObject
to start pulling those objects out of
that as someone coated bite stream
the object to things like to be an
object for the top-level receipt
there'll be an option up to I object in
it for the payload
they'll be an object in there for the
receipt attribute and then subject under
there for reaching the type value
inversion
seats arrange very high rocky play and
that follows the same structure that we
just saw an SAS in one text chill
definition
now this is not perfectly coated but it
gives you an example of how in which
you would work with a sn1 in open SSL if
that's how you choose to do this
it set up a while loop to essentially
move a
par move the pointer throughout that
stream the fights that represents the
receipt
we want to basically walk through the
receipt and read it as we go
so we set up the wild open stock calling
sn1 get object
to pull those attributes and values out
of the receipt
so I make one call to get my attribute
for example another call to get the type
and notice I'm moving the pointer value
along like a finger following words in a
book
and I'm calling is someone get object to
read each in those words out
and so I can use them after a few more
calls today someone get object
I'm ready to switch on that attribute
types I can see what I'm looking for
in this case just for simple example i'm
looking for. attribute type 2
which you know is a bundle I day and
then I could stop processing that by
calling sn1 get
object to actually read the string value
when compared against my hard coded
bundle ID
but course I want to show you that this
is real world thing that anyone can do
so he is married Emma now same as before
I got a third project here to build upon
the same two samples we've seen so far
see here we have the old familiar
loading up with the receipt certificate
store and then calling PKcs 7 verify
but now when we get a result of one and
we know this thing is valid and
unaltered
and we want to start reading the
purchase information out I'm gonna go
ahead and start using open SSL to do
that to actually read the information
about what someone purchased
so just like we saw before I find the
actual
octet string that stream of bytes the
represents the receipt
buried within my pee 7.0 structure I
start calling this
sn1 get object method to start reading
those bits of information at byte stream
one at a time
when I start doing that in my while loop
to walk over each of those bites
you see that I set up that point earn
each time a call as someone get object
here
I advance that pointer along just like
the finger following the word in a book
so make a few cost as someone get object
because I want to get things like the
attribute I pay tribute version
and then the actual object itself set up
a switch statement
and got a case to hear looking for
bundle I day and a final call here I SM
one GetObject
it allows me to form a string which will
be a bundle ID
let's run and see it work
notice by the fact that I had done the
open SSL integration before in this
project
I don't have to mess around with that
again this project is already setup just
like we had before
so I got a receipt great we move into a
valid receipt
we've gone and called the PKcs 7 verify
here to make sure the receipt is trusted
unaltered
and Indians now we can start reading it
so I got the byte stream
I start calling sn1 get object to read
that receipt in
then I set up my wilder to irate over
each that series about tributes in the
receipt
and as we see is we sale down this first
attempt at getting an object out of the
recede we get all the way down to a
switch statement
and if we pull up the debug console here
you'll see in fact what we found
first is a tribute type for so as you
irate over this while loop is
essentially finding each of those
attributes that we saw in the receipt
and he set up the switch statement here
to work with them accordingly
so in fact if we let this run we would
see a bunch of break points hit here in
a switch statement
switching and as we looked over each of
those attributes we can see this time
we've got type for
advance again we get different values as
we go forward
we can begin working with those to pull
out things like the bundle ID to confirm
that
the hash value a former hash to confirm
that it is intended for this device
we nearly there we have a receipt that
we know is trusted
with confirmed for an hour on this
device now we can get down to the money
into this
and finding out what the user has in
fact paid for so we know what
unlock me know what content to provide
them
now along with those attributes type
2345 we just looked at
you'll also see one or more attributes
have types 17
type 17 is a record of an in app
purchase having been made
and this is how you verified that in app
purchase was real and authentic
and is going to result in money making
its way to you
the value of the type 17 attribute is in
fact a nested set
all that repeats itself so you find the
type 17 attribute
get the value and add value is going to
be a nested said about tributes the tell
you the quantity
product identifiers and a transaction
identifiers purchased a
for an in app purchase that has been
made and again
Wii U VA sn1 representation of that so
you know how it's structured
now if you have a paid app in the store
and every morning to make the transition
to being a freemium ap
that is free with an app purchases one
thing you don't want to do is leave
those loyal paying customers out in the
cold
if they've already paid the full price
for your app they shouldn't have to go
into a bunch of in app purchases just to
get back what they've already paid for
so here's a trick you can do including
the receipt now
is this type 19 attribute called
original application version:
that is the application version: that
the user originally purchased
so if two years ago I purchased this app
the receipt will always reflect
version that was in the store at the
time I made a purchase all those years
ago
and that's your way of knowing whether
to treat the app as a paid version and
give them what they paid for
or to know that they purchase the app
when you're free me a map
to not unlock features and content until
you see those in app purchases being
made
now in terms of your purchases different
types of content have different life
cycles in terms of what is seen
in the receipt if you are dealing with
consumable
and non renewing subscriptions so things
like
our gas in a race car in a racing game
koreans blocks currency not consumable
sorry consumables are things that you
buy use on a single device
and they get used up those sorts of
items because they are that purchase the
comic again and again and are intended
to be used
on a single device they only appear once
in the receipt and only in the receipt
that's issued at the time of purchase
so when that purchases made few 500
gallons a gas in the race car
you need to interpret the receipt at
that point in time invalidated
and then stash that state that is up the
gas tank by five hundred gallons or
whatever it might be
you need to stash that state your cell
that transaction will not be present in
any subsequent receipts that we issue
know will be present if you perform the
restore completed transactions
there a one-shot deal when the
transaction is done
you inspect the receipt stash that state
your cell
now the total opposite to that is non
consumable and order your subscriptions
if you're selling on consumables like
levels in a game for example
those are things that a user buys once
and I would rightly expect to be able to
use that game level on other devices
fight on by new phone and re download
your app I expect to get back all the
lovely levels and I've already paid for
so because these non consumables and
ordering your subscriptions have that
sense opponents say about them
they are always in the receipt and you
can use the stalking API's to restore
completed transactions
which is how the user gets back all
those things they've bought from you
before
in terms of non consumable and order
renewable subscriptions
there are still valid
we've talked about so far is all about
the happy part for the receipt being
valid and true water for seats are
invalid
what if when you validate this city the
missing or something appears wrong with
it
the fact is that doesn't mean something
bad has happened
that does not necessarily mean someone
is trying to rip you off
there are many real-world scenarios the
your app will definitely run into her
where a receipt is missing or invalid
through no fault of the user
not because they want to rip you off but
if you see this happen what you need to
do is refresh the receipt
on I O S if the receipt doesn't exist or
appears to be invalid you refresh
using stalk it stock it has the SK
receipt refresh operation
which allows you to you can now looking
at this as k receipt refresh request
object
said a delegate so you get the call
backs when the reefer she's done and
then start the Refresh
with that request completes you should
get back in your seat
you can repair a fire but not the
getting in your say
we have to talk to the App Store soco's
network connection will be required
which you use and may not always have
store sign in will be required so that
we can go and verify that this person
really is them and check the purchase
history before we wish you the receipt
but what you need to do is avoid
continuous loop serve refreshments and a
tree for Shalit ivory fresh ballot acres
each time you do that
the user's gonna get stuck in this
horrible luper prompt for all yes I
signed in
still bad sign in again and all this
network traffic goes back and forward
so what you should do is on launch
validate the receipt
if it's missing or invalid you can
refresh at once if it still missing
invalid
that's it dunk or refresh again
but always tended is a course a little
different as we saw before if the
receipt is invalid or missing
you exit with code 173 to tell EOS in
the App Store the you need to get in
your receipt
the OS is that exit code tell the App
Store
and the App Store going getting your
seat for you but just like a mile s
he will require a network connection and
still signing will be requested
so this is definitely not something you
want to automatically on launch
now when you do you receive elevation
and it appears to be invalid or missing
and you request in your receipt even if
then you still don't have a receipt
or it still appears to be invalid
what you do next is entirely up to you
invalid or missing receipts will happen
everyone's ap
will see a condition where this happens
and it could be entirely legitimate
he's an example if i sync an app from
iTunes
to my OS device it lands on the I was
device with no receipt
because it wasn't purchased directly
from the App Store the app store doesn't
have that unique device identifiers
week on issue a receipt so it lands on
the device with Norris aid
and when your app launches ill find the
receipt and need to refresh if you wanna
validate the receipt
so to real-world scenario that will
happen you need to configure that you
need to consider the case that that
refresher the receipt may not be
possible
right what if I got my eye wonderful app
from the from the iTunes Store the App
Store
and I'm really excited about using it on
the plane flight about to get on
plug my OS device in sync the up across
unplugged
jump on a plane no wifi
I can get a receipt sup to you now to
decide how you want to handle a
okay you should ideally match
the user experience to the value of your
app miss comes back to the concepts were
talking before
are you can allow full access to the
app's content features
even if the receipt invalid if you
choose you compare haiti have a
you maybe have a grace period where you
will allow some use in the app
you could limit access to certain areas
have the app perhaps is one area of the
app
that is particularly valuable the you
wouldn't want to let them access
even if they can't get a receipt or you
could block functionality entirely
you could have the app do nothing until
a valid receipt is sane
on I was 10 only you can in fact force
the apt to quit if you want to
but the concept does not exist on iowa's
on iowa's the app is always running
so it's up to you to decide what to do
but again
think about which business model you are
more like
are you like the grocery store that once
a comfortable really happy
buying experience and usage experience
every time and maybe you don't care
want to ban on its goes out the door
maybe don't care too much for receipts
invalid for a little bit of time
or maybe you are more like the high-end
jewelry store
and maybe it's totally not OK for your
apt to be used in
anyway on this is a valid receipt it's
up to you
you should really think about the value
of your product and how you want the
user experience to be
if they don't have a receipt know
everything we talked about so far is
about validating that receive on a
device but you can also do that same
process
on your servers if you have service
issue in content based on an in app
purchase being made
he's what you can do when you request
that content
send the receipt up to a server your
server can talk to Apple's validation
service
and we will return back a blocker chase
on that will tell you
whether or not the receipt is valid and
will also include the purchase
information
your server can interpret the purchase
information and decide only to him back
to content
based on that real monetary transaction
having taken place
great way to secure and lock down the
access to that content
the hosting online now for this service
it's over to serve a validation
its only designed for your service to
validate the receipt before they issue
content
and it's your app that needs to send the
receipt to your server
you need to secure that into in
communication channel and then
only your server sends the receipt to
Apple's validation server
never never never ever send the receipt
directly from your app on a device
to the validation service way too easy
for someone to sit in the middle and
return a false positive
and you'll also be exposing a shared
secret for using that validation service
the good thing is the response you get
back as in Jason which is really is a
possible Chile
any server platform out there
now what you absolutely have to make
sure you do if you implementing receipt
validation is tested thoroughly
a bug in this area of code could be
disastrous for you
because it could lock someone out at the
features and content they really have
paid for
and I guarantee that a one-way trip to
one-star reviews
to Tess really thoroughly has you up to
heaven is no receipt
has a behave when the receipt looks to
be invalid has a behave when the app
first
when the receipt appears to be valid
after refresh what if the Refresh failed
in its still invalid how does europe
behave
and if you're selling your app using the
volume purchase program for business and
education
beware the extra feels there in the
receipt to tell you whether you at has
been allocated to use a
or revoked the really important message
that I wanna make sure get through
is that these are not edge cases your
Apple will launch without a receipt
your Apple launch with the receipt looks
invalid know that example before I gave
you an Iowa sapping sent from iTunes
when you buy a new Mac and you move your
caps from you all Mac team new Mac
guess what the receipt moves from the
all-mac to the new Mac
so when you happy launches its gonna
recede see a receipt that was not
intended for the new Mac
so these are real things that happen
that definitely
knowledge cases at all
now you testing this on I O S you need
to use the app stores test environment
to do that you run the app in Xcode
performing in app purchase to get the
receipt
but you must have your app signed with
the development certificate
OS 10 similar but different build in
Xcode
run the app from find remember so finder
in the OS
and the App Store sees that exit code
and we know you need to get a receipt
when you exit with that receipt you must
make sure
eggs with the codes are you must make
sure the OAP is signed
with its development certificate
case you missed the very very deliver
repetition in those last two slides
your ap must be signed with your
developments difficult why
well because the first thing we do with
the App Store layer
when you're up says hell when you
receive hey wanna make an app purchase
is we inspect your code signature if the
app
appears to be signed with your
development certificate we know you're a
developer testing your app
so we're out those request to the test
environment so you can make an app
purchases
test to receive elevation without
actually buying something
but if we see the app is signed with the
production App Store certificate
we know this is an app it's been
purchased it's out there in the wheel
real-world
so therefore we're out those requests to
the production store
so that you get paid for the
transactions for customers making
lastly a quick word on the app
submission process especially as hell
pertains to receipts
when you developing your app development
signed of course and you working with
the App Store's test environment to test
arena purchase a receipt validation
the receipt to get back test environment
receipts
now because Europe may not already be on
the store yet and using a test
environment
there'll be some difference in the
fields that are present
when you ap is on sale in the App Store
and its production signed
you will see production receipts that
have some more fields in them
because your app Israel and live on the
store
but app review is different
app review uses test receipts using a
production signed ap
naps not something you can do only app
review candor
but what you need to be aware of is that
when you're testing your app
if you try to get too clever and think
oh I found a way to determine that these
receipts from the test environment
and I never ever ever ever want someone
out there to be getting a receipt using
my up from the test environment
if you try and implement code that
rejects a test environment receipt
because your production signed
guess what app review can review your
app
we won't be able to use your purchases
and therefore ill get rejected so just
be aware that you will
have your live production signed version
of the app that you submitted
it will see test receipts during app
review
so if you'd like more information you
can contact Arab Angeles TCE
there's also documentation online with
the receipt validation programming guide
and of course as the Apple Developer
forms which are a great place to discuss
this
and ask for help some related sessions
on Wednesday I gave a session about
optimizing your in app purchases
that was around creating a trouble-free
in smooth in app purchase experience
every single time and my colleague
Rachel gave an x1 session earlier that
morning
it was about how to design for a great
in app purchase experience
it's great to protect a revenue even
better to have a trouble free in app
experience
every time you've got also create that
irresistible sales experience
so do go and check out the sessions they
were really good
thanks very much