well come welcome the Friday
thanks for being here
my name is south to go in I am the
product manager for automation
technologies that Apple incorporated
and the secession 306 this is a big day
we get to welcome JavaScript to the
family of scripting languages on OS 10
we've been waiting a long time for this
and I know our customers have to and
we're really thrilled about it
and before I get into the details have
the language and how it works
I like to take a moment to reflect on
the state of automation
beginning with Mavericks
now in maverick's reintroduced
a host of new features some very
powerful things beginning with
notification support
in both the scripting language in in
Automator as well so it became very
easy to use notifications and set a
posting dialogues in your automation
routines
we also introduced code signing ability
in our editor applications both in
Automator in the script editor
which is great because then you could
sign and deliver
automation solutions to your customers
friends and coworkers
we also introduced a new construct in
AppleScript called the use statement
the racks I can importer to import
functionality from
applications and frameworks and %uh
scripting additions
and allow them to be used in your
scripts
and by doing this we also made it
possible to have script
library that we introduced and script
library for scripts that you create
yourself
that contain your favorite some routines
are handlers
and you can call in lo these libraries
from scripts anywhere in the operating
system
they can also take advantage of
AppleScript objective-c
and any the cocoa calls that you want to
use
so they're very powerful very useful
they be introduced
and then finally we had a new feature
that worked on english-only systems but
we thought it was so interesting that we
introduced it it was called speaker
bulwark locks
and allowed you to take your Automator
workflow
and save it as a speaker bull item
in the dictation architecture so you
could say a command in would run your
workflow
and so maverick's is a very productive
release force we're very excited about
it
but we're also excited about what we've
done in Yosemite and how it builds upon
the groundwork relayed
in Mavericks last part of this
evolutionary process we integrated
code signing with workflow files so not
only app lets but now your workflow
files can be code side as well
and because have changes that we
implemented in the app script language
for supporting
optional parameters and subroutines and
handlers
wearin able to upgrade the scripting
library support so that you can now have
your favorite calls
have optional premonition users as well
very good improvement there
and listening to customer requests
they're being
for years and years requesting some way
to indicate a progress
method for their automation routines we
now have
built in script progress indicators
so by calling simple properties
you can have your scripts display a
progress
indicator as a circle or even as
a progress bar in a floating window and
all this is done for you automatically
all you have to do is Sep properties
within your scripts
so I think our customers are gonna
really enjoy that particular feature
and we took the idea of spiegel were
close and we've advanced it now
because %uh the new dictation
architecture in Yosemite that works with
all
languages we now have a new template
item
in Automator for creating a dictation
command so you create your workflow you
save it it's a than to the dictation
architecture
and when you're in the process of
dictating or just sitting at the machine
you can't say the name your command
anymore execute
very interesting very powerful I know
you can have a lot of fun exploring
that so that's just a quick overview up
where we've been
but something that's been on our minds
for a long time that we're happy
and very pleased to have here today is
JavaScript for automation
now those have you there are
premiere with JavaScript from the
web-based community
this is not the JavaScript for writing a
DOM
that uses CSS and HTML 5 to create a web
app
we're talking about extending the
JavaScript cord language
to integrate with the open scripting
architecture
and by doing this you now gain the
ability to pull
all those levers inside the scriptable
caps on your operating system
to perform the kinda repetitive for
interesting or complex tasks
that you do every day and now this power
it's available to you
through JavaScript now many of you that
right
JavaScript professionally or as your
focus
you use to using editors like God BB
added
sublime tax were web storm
TextMate things like that up
initially as you adapt to JavaScript raw
to Mason
you write your for scripts in the script
editor application
and I'm gonna give you just a short
overview up
this application it's interfacing
preferences
so that you understand what's happening
as David presents
JavaScript for you so let me take a look
at
the script editor application so when
you open
the script editor application get this
very simple interface is a script window
and he has a simple but very powerful
design to it
beginning with the little slider that
separates the two main pains up the
window
the script pain where you enter the code
for your script
and the bottom pane contains in a vet
law
so ass the script is executing you'll
see the events listed there with the
results coming in from the Abetz
and this is all I've logged happens as
the script is executed
at the top there are some simple
controls for basically compiling the
script to make sure your syntax is
correct
and there's also control for running or
stopping your script
now there at the bottom here is a
language controls so make sure if you're
writing JavaScript
that this pop-up menu is set for the
JavaScript language
and that's basically the interface in
the way that it works is
you enter your script code
into the top area then you click the Run
button
an acid execute you can see that there's
a progress indicator here on the right
showing the progress at the script and
you can watch the event log go by
now this simple script that exported
open keno documents to movies
you can see the results of it and how
was logged in everything indicated in
the final result that the script at the
bottom
so this is the interface that you have
when you're executing scripts in is
David
shows you the examples this is what
you're going to see
there's some other important preferences
you should be aware of and let me just
quickly show you those to you
so in the Preferences menu
from the application menu in the General
Settings paying
there is a default language pop-up if
you going to be using javascript is your
primary language for scripting
you wanna make sure that you change this
value
to JavaScript now this is JavaScript 100
this is JavaScript for automation 10 it
is not
JavaScript what now we use the current
JavaScript court languages the bases
so don't be freaked out when you see 10
their
also make sure that you check
the show's script menu and menu bar
option
and what this will do is activate the
system wide script menu at the top right
up your menu bar
and from this script menu you can host
your favorite scripts
and you can make them available
contextually within certain applications
so if you write scripts for the Finder
they can only appear the finders there
are few write scripts four pages
the only pier 1 pages so there it's up
to you
the script menu run shell scripts
AppleScript applications workflows
JavaScript
any kind scripting language supported by
the operating system
can run from the script min so you'll be
taking advantage of that
in addition if you want to set certain
coloring for you the code that you use
this formatting pain is where you'll do
that you can choose fonts font size and
coloring
to apply to fit comfortably with what
your use too
next I like to look at dictionaries
now in the operating system every
scriptable
application carries internally within
its bundle
a complete dictionary of all the term
said it understands
it will list all the class sense at all
the methods in the commands in the
properties and elements
that is for mayor with so this is where
you will go to learn about how to
control a particular application
and what you do is you choose Open
dictionary from the File menu
and in the forthcoming dialog choose an
application
when you do that York see a script
viewer window like this one for the
keynote
dictionary and this is
what you see when you I'll look at an
application scripting dictionary and
this is what you will do to navigate
that dictionary
at the top is a language button so this
dictionary fewer functions
for all the scripting languages we
support so
it supports JavaScript AppleScript or
objective c-
and you can change the mode for viewing
the content
right from this menu now
at the top part love this window the top
pain in this window is the model viewer
in this is where you see how the objects
in the application scripting model are
reflected
on the left hand side typically a
scripting dictionary
is grouped into sweets and the suites
are usually grouped by functionality you
buy what they do
in this particular example you'll see
that there's multiple sweet
their suites for I work because keynote
is part of the I work family affair
plications
the I work sweets upcoming objects in
common commands
are included there and then keynote has
its own sweet
are things that are particular for the
keynote application
and then once a sweet is selected you'll
see in the next column
the methods and the classes that belong
to that particular sweet so here we have
commands like export we would export a
project presentation EC classes like
document
and then when you select the class
you'll see he
elements X that belong to that class
in the right hand column and also the
properties
I love that particular class in here you
see the properties
I love a keynote document
now for further information in detail
about these
in the bottom half for the Windows the
dictionary viewer
and the dictionary viewer contains the
definitions for all those particular
elements
so when you want to know about why
hideaway script the Finder hideaway
script numbers
how do I skip keynote how do I script
aperture
you open a dictionary and this is where
you learn and explore
to find out how to control those
applications
so that's the scripting dictionary and
that's the script editor application
so let me get out of the way and bring
up David sign bird
whose the newest member of our team to
show you
JavaScript rodham Asian enjoy this
thank you sell hello everyone thank you
for being here
I it's a great honor I'm really excited
to be showing this awesome new feature
OS 10 yosemite JavaScript for automation
so today's talk will cover what
JavaScript for automation is
and how it works how you can use
JavaScript rodham Asian
from basic to more advanced techniques
and finally we'll talk about where you
can use JavaScript rodham Asian
to talk about what JavaScript
proclamation is
let's take a look at the underlying
pieces
automation allows you to accomplish
tasks on your Mac
automatically from simple tasks such as
changing the name to 100 files
all at once to more complex tasks
such as sending personalized directions
to guests before party you're having
I'd like to demonstrate the power
automation to you now
so I were cracking widgets were company
that makes widgets
as you might expect we have three main
clients Japan
USA and across Europe I'm here i've a
chart detailing
summer widgets prices in the region's
they go to
and in particular currency and so on and
now I have
4 upcoming presentations first
I have to give a presentation to the
president of the company about all the
regions
that we work with all other individual
prices currencies and so on
and I have to give presentations to each
those regions
only detailing the particular
information that pertains to that region
so now I'm thinking okay for keynote I
have to make
what start with the first I have all my
data here
format as I wanted I have some images
that I can use related to this data
I write a script that does this for me
well I've done just that so here I have
a script
don't worry about understanding all a
bit at the moment but the dumpster Prada
mation script that uses
this numbers document and produces a
full slide deck for me in keno
so if I run this here we see our slides
are being created for us
with the information that we got from
that data
and now we have an entire slide deck
ready for my president to see
detailing all OVR widgets their prices
per region
currency and so on is perfect okay
some Cup list one completely
automatically I've three more to do
and each of those are going to be pretty
much the exact same
same number of slides same images same
information
changed per region particular currency
and so on
and in fact all the information is
already in this presentation I have here
I just need to slim it down for each
version sorrow myself helper script
a menu that multiple times so I put my
script menu
and what this does is it let me say
where my presenting today
well today many presenting in Japan so I
guess
slimmed-down Mikey now the few slides
that are important
but presentation mode and unable to go
hello everyone thank you for being here
let's talk about prices it's been a real
pleasure have a good day
now okay right now
I me begin the presentation the USA
okay I don't wanna make another slide
tackle together I'm going to use my nice
little helper here
USA hello everybody thank you for being
here let's talk some dollars it's been a
real pleasure have a nice day
beautiful bed and higher entire
automated will process
was automated for me we just a couple
little script that I wrote
that made my life easier got my work
done faster
and that is the PowerVault nation
those demos were made possible by
scripting applications
and applications that are built using
cocoa automatically have a certain level
the script ability
such as being able to be told to open or
to print
and a wide variety of applications have
fully embraced script ability
detailing the object model at the
application and offering rich sweet the
functionality beyond the basics
Apple events underlying communication
mechanism behind application scripting
they provide access to the scriptable
pieces and parts of an application
that are defined an application
scripting dictionary cell showed
detailing what objects can be interacted
with and how
so when the script an application and
whatever language you may
it scripting dictionary is red an Apple
event for use to communicate with the
application
let's take a look at an example of an
object model
there we have mail but as an application
object
with an inbox property with the messages
elementary with each element
individually accessible
so for example we can pinpoint the
second messenger the
in box on the application male as an
object specifier
or a reference to that particular object
in that particular application
this is great we look really closely at
the things behind automation
an application scripting now let's talk
about JavaScript
have a powerful automation was brought
to it
JavaScript is a scripting language with
C like syntax
and objects a prototype based
inheritance its most well known in a
browser
being in the scripting language image
team of five but it's also become quite
popular as a server-side scripting
language
evidenced by node.js JavaScript
analyst 10 is powered by JavaScript core
the engine used by WebKit
and so far JavaScript for automation
is built on JavaScript core using the
modern JavaScript environment
and the kind of service ie JavaScript or
as we like to call it
OS automation JavaScript and what the
underlying engine is the same
just a proclamation is quite different
from running scripts in your browser
when used as capron mention you can do
everything that you as the Mac user can
do
this is very different from browser
scripts that don't have access to your
personal data
the applications on your Mac and browser
scripts you might expect the window
object or a document object
not gonna have those here you have a
host a different objects you can
interact with
automate your Mac so how exactly was
this brought
to JavaScript what a recap applications
have scripting dictionaries
detail what can be interacted with and
how an Apple event to use to communicate
with those applications
to bring us the JavaScript core we got
the JavaScript Apple event bridge
that reads those scripting dictionaries
and then use Apple events to communicate
with the applications
another we've seen what does get Prada
mission is
and how it works let's look at how we
can use JavaScript proclamation
beginning with scripting applications
we introduce a application object into a
javascript context
which is the main entrance point all the
scriptable pieces and parts of an
application
sup the most common way to access an
is by name here accessing Safari
application
and beyond name we can also access
applications by bundle ID
bypass by process ID
and we can get the application that's
running the script we're currently
n by getting the current application
so now we have this application object
we're gonna want to interact with
let's look at some examples the syntax
for doing just that
accessing properties is accomplished
using dot notation
to access elements do you square
brackets
to call commands you call them as
functions
using print the Seas and you can create
new objects
by calling class constructors as
functions again using practices
Satsuki getting and setting properties
but they were scripting Safari
we create a reference to the first
documented Safari
and now we can do things like get the
documents URL
see apprentices at the end we're calling
this property as a function
because we want to actually send the get
event to the application
and get the string value we don't simply
won a reference to the URL in the
document
you wanna call it as a function and get
that string value
we can also set the documents URL and
this
sends the set event to the application
actually sets the URL
let's say you want to get a particular
window and Safari
well there are three ways to access
elements
jobs for Prada mention by index
by name and by I D
it has benefits and risks associated
with it and it's important to understand
the object model that the application
that you're scripting
to know when it's best to use which
so already with just these basics
beginning some pretty amazing things
let's put it to use first I'd like to
just open up script editor
got a little JavaScript here just ray
JavaScript
creating a string some text
and then I'm going to use Council lot
lot to say I expect in JavaScript to
lock this text
and I log this it's going to show up in
the event lock
and a lower panel summer open the event
log
and if I run the script we see hello
world was line just like we wanted
this is great this in the JavaScript I'm
used to and doing exactly what we wanted
this is hugely useful for debugging we
can log transcript to see what's going
on
but let's say I wanted to write some
taxed and I want it to exist even
after I quit script editor or perhaps on
a style that text
change its finder color and so on
now we can start interacting with
applications to accomplish that
so here we have a text that the document
name flock how many users across a
couple demos
to write some text first
this is a simple script we access the
text that application
we get a reference to the log document
then we set the documents text and we
style it's fine
size and color so before I run this
I'm gonna open the event log and will be
able to see the events that are being
sent to this application
to accomplish this so when I run this
script
we see I love JavaScript was like just
like we wanted
style just like we wanted and the bottom
here we see
all the events that were sent to
accomplish this task
so this is great we have some persistent
taxed it's been beautified just like we
wanted
but what we want to do this multiple
times in the same script
well instead of repeating the
functionality again and again
we're playing in javascript we can write
a function
I've done just that here we have a
function
the exception tax the log an optional
formatting parameter
then just like before we access the text
that
she's me the text that application we
get reference to log document
but now instead of setting the documents
entire text
we're going to appended to the last
paragraph
the Madonna style based on formatting
you pass n
was in default values now we have our
lock
we call it three times at bottom here
passing and parameters
for formatting twice the last time we
use default values
so high running a script
we see that our text was logged just
like we wanted
styled as we wanted this is great reblog
as many times as we want
style any different way that we choose
every single time
sauce this is powerful stuff simply by
accessing
an application an element and a couple
properties
right out of the box power at your
fingertips and it's really easy to
approach
some other ways that we might when
interactive applications
what they were skipping now everyone
access some of the messages in our inbox
but we don't want the entire messages
element Arabian box that's a whole lotta
messages
usually letting wanna get
only the messages whose subject is
JavaScript using the special whose
method
a felony to raise we can do just that by
passing a dictionary
of properties would like to match on
those elements we now receive an array
only containing the elements that match
objects have certain commands that they
can respond to
and you can call this command as methods
locally that send the command events to
the application
so again but they were stripping now
we have a reference to the first message
in our inbox
and we want to open it well
we could tell the message to open we can
also tell mail to
opened the message and both these are
entirely equivalent
some commands take named parameters and
so you accomplish this by passing a
dictionary others named parameters
here for example we're creating a reply
to our message
we're going to apply to everybody and
we're not going to open a window
now remember you can always use the
dictionary viewer in script editor
the scene which name parameters go with
which commands which commands can be
called on which objects and so on
it's a phenomenal tall and really useful
when you're building more complex
scripts
some commands take files as parameters
such as opening a document
using texted to accomplish this
we've introduced a path object into the
environment
you construct with a string that has a
file path inside
and now you can use that path object
anywhere that a file is expected as a
parameter
so we can open a document just like we
want it
be aware but if you pass a string
instead of a path
wherever files expected you will receive
an error
so so we want to create a document
instead of simply opening 1
in fact that well
scripting text that we can call the
document class constructor as a function
but now actually create this object
inside the application
bring it to life we're going to push the
document
onto the documents element array and
that actually create
inside the application then we can
interact with it just like any other
objects inside the application
you get that text for example
and optionally when you create objects
you can pass in a dictionary of
properties
you'd like to have set on that object
when it's created here
we're creating a document passing and
some text when instantiated
we push again under the appropriate
array and it's created inside the
application
living and breathing ready for us to
interact with so this is a wide range of
functionality
inherently available applications
property access element access
con command creating objects but there
are script
plugins funds for scripts and allow you
to extend the functionality of an
application
and the OS has a set of standard
scripting additions
ships these are available from every
scripting environment
including JavaScript proclamation so
let's say that we're scripting the
current application
I want to be able to use the standard
additions to do so
we're going to set the include standard
additions flag to true
and then we can do things I tell the
application to beat
which is hugely useful for debugging
tell the application to speak some text
which extend the functionality to a
wider audience
we can also do things like display
alerts and dialogues which is great
because now we have used in our
skinny user interaction incorporated
with scripting applications
so we've covered a lot of different ways
that we can actually script applications
their object models and so on
let's look at other uses have javascript
running mission
remember earlier me wrapped the logging
functionality and functions we can use
it multiple times from one script
what they want to log from multiple
scripts not just one
this is the perfect use a library
I've taken that log function and I've
saved in a script
named cool box in the script libraries
folder
and now I can access this library and
its functions from
any other script and i right to
accomplish this
I instantiate a library object by name
and file extension is optional and then
I can call those functions as methods on
that library object
so this code would log just like we did
before and the beautiful thing about
libraries
as they can be written in JavaScript and
AppleScript
and used from JavaScript for automation
so now let's take a look how to create
app lets using javascript for automation
app lets our applications saved by
script editor
when you run an outlet the script saved
inside this run
adults have a certain number about
events that you can create handlers for
such as when the apparatus run when the
app lets told open documents or print
documents
there's a special idle handler that
allows you to perform periodic tasks
and you can also create handlers for one
ap lit is reopened
when an app that is quick and just like
libraries
you can have any other functions inside
your ap lit and those can be called
first take a look at an example a basic
ap lit that uses
a script library
here we have a large document like
before
and let's look at the script inside this
applicator
at the top we instantiate our toolbox
library
then in our run handler we log Ron
in green in our idle handler we lie idle
in orange
and in our quit handler Wheelock quit in
red
so if I double clicked this ap lit to
run it
we see that running idle were logged
just like we wanted
and if I go and quit the ap lit we see
that quit was also locked
which is great this is exactly what we
wanted
this is a very basic example using a
couple handlers an app witnessing a
library
but imagine the possibilities here this
is double clickable JavaScript sitting
on my desktop
ready to interact with all the
scriptable applications
script libraries and more
speaking of more we've looked at
scripting the object model of an
application extensively
what you wanna script the user interface
an application
this is accomplished by using
accessibility
which allows applications on your Mac to
interact with your Mac
on your behalf system events uses the
accessibility API's to expose the user
interface and application
and in JavaScript proclamation you use
the system event application
to access the pieces and parts a user
interface
first look at an example
first we're going to access the system
event application
then we're going to access the notes
process
above the system advanced processes
element iraq I'm gonna send it to a
variable
notes you why now we can do things
like close the window by clicking the
first but not the first window
notes user interface but i wanna send
some key strokes in this application
what to do so run access then notes
application itself
and activate it bringing it to the front
and then
we can call the system events keystroke
command
passing in am using command down the
similar to minimize
event to use accessibility
must be enabled in the privacy
preferences for applications like script
editor and so on the use it
and the first time you try to use
accessibility you will be prompted to
enable it
okay so what it another way description
application its user interface
we looked at scripting object models
library is an app lets
now let's look at a more advanced use
JavaScript rodham Asian
using system API's which provide access
to really powerful and important things
like the filesystem
& Co collapse development in javascript
we introduce two objects into the
environment that here means for
interacting
with system APIs obj see and dollar
and for those coming from a browser
environment dollar may mean something
very special to you
but in our environment it's a very
different dollar
I'm seeking be used to do things like
bridging jobs good values
into objective-c bridging objective-c
objects into JavaScript
and importing frameworks that you'd like
to use
so once you imported a framework you can
access it's classes and functions and so
on
using the dollar object and you can also
call dollar
as a function as a shorthand for
bridging JavaScript values
into objective-c
now let's talk about calling methods on
objects well
begin let's look at some objective-c
code
quite simple going to create an ashtray
ng and everyone to write that string to
a file
this is the equivalent javascript::write
a mission code to accomplish this
their couple key things to focus on here
first
the Foundation framework is available to
you out of the box when using javascript
for automation
so we don't need to import foundation
then we use the dollar object to access
the an ashtray in class
we call Alec and because it takes no
parameters we don't need parentheses
we do not use parentheses here then we
call
in it with utf8 string and we're going
to be passing a parameter
so we call it as a function and pass on
our printer
now the method to write to a file is
takes multiple parameters
so we're going to convert the selector
to a Javascript method
name I can cat mating and camel case in
the pieces together
and ima call it as a function passing a
parameter is in the right order
another we've seen how to write to a
file let's actually see it newt's
this is a little script at the top we
create an ashtray
some tax would like to write to a file
then we created an ashram with a file
path
and we call the string by expanding till
then path
method on it to get the full path and
then
we write this string to that file and
when we write this
it's going to appear in this folder here
so if I run this script of I was created
our text was written just like we won
was a phenomenal ok
and this is that simple example but you
can imagine
the power utility that the system APIs
bring to the JavaScript for automation
vir
let's look at other ways that we can
interact with his API's
but so we create a new NS half object
well
access its properties already is dot
notation
so can access the running property get
its boolean value and react accordingly
we can also set its launch pad property
like so missile actually set it on the
object
an interesting thing but the java script
writer mission bridge
is the bridge nail so nil injected see
is somewhat similar to the undefined in
javascript
but they're not exactly the same
different key ways
in objective-c it's absolutely valid
call a method on and no object
and will receive another nail object but
in javascript
if you call a method and undefined
object you will receive an hour
therefore we do not bridge now ended
undefined we keep it as abridged no
object
you can interact with
said create abridged no object we call
the dollar function without
any parameters by Mike you want to
create a bridge no object you asking
well this allows you to accomplish
things like passed by reference
so here we're creating a new NS XML
document
ever going to pass are bridged no object
are error variable
as the third and final Preminger and
will happen behind the scenes
is a banana error object is created the
bridge no object will be replaced by
and now are error variable a point that
and we can use that
so want to create a document we can
check if its male
by calling the is no method on it and if
it is nil
we could for example log the user info
from the
now populated error object
another exciting thing that you can do
using system the PI's subclassing
objects
so accomplished this you call the
register subclass method
RC object you pass in a name
have your subclass its superclass
although this is optional
and will default to and I subject
any protocols that your classmate here
too
properties are defined as an object
where the keys are the names are the
property and values on it typeof the
property
and Methods are again and object where
the keys are the selector
and the value isn't object detailing the
types of the method
and its implementation now if you're
defining a function
our method excuse me has declared in a
protocol
run a superclass the types are optional
for demonstration purposes
we show them here to know what us to use
let's see using a subclass and creating
something using system EPS
so here I have a nap and this is the
script inside
and this produces a Cocoa application
a temperature converter nice little got
for us to use
there to think I'd like to point out for
a actually run s
you'll see at the top the week important
Coco now this allows us to access things
like ass window and so on
we create our windows are inputs and
then
we register a subclass name temperature
converter
that is two methods to convert from
Celsius to Fahrenheit and from
Fahrenheit to Celsius
and you can see that all the logic
inside these methods all the math
is in javascript then
we create a new temperature converter
object how corrupt or inputs
and bring the window to the front so
let's run us
close this here and if I double click
this Apple to run it
we have a nice little Coco application
written entirely in Java Script
course it does what we promise we can
convert Fahrenheit to Celsius
assess Celsius to Fahrenheit and so on
as a little example look at this we can
create a Cocoa application in javascript
imagine what you can do from here with
all this at your fingertips
there is power ready to be used
and definitely make sure to check out
the JavaScript for automation release
notes
we can see other great things you can do
using system APIs
like binding C functions into the
environment
another mechanism for passed by
reference
and also passing functions for boxer
expected
are we've done a beautiful whirlwind
tour all the ways we can use JavaScript
proclamation
for application scripting libraries an
app lets you I scripting
using system API's I'm sure each
everyone he was just bitching to get
your hands on
completely understand before you do
let's talk about where you can use
JavaScript Roc Nation
so as all the demos have shown you can
use JavaScript rodham nation
in script editor you can save Appleton
droplets from script editor
as we saw and run
a cell mentioned and you saw in the
presentation tomorrow
you can say scripts in a system-wide
script menu this phenomenal for scripts
that you're going to use repeatedly
again and again Automator
which allows you to produce workflows
on many applications and processes on
your Mac's now has
are run JavaScript Automator Action that
lets you incorporate JavaScript
proclamation
into your workflows what you've done so
you can save those actions excuse me
those workflows as services
that can be used for many application
and across your system
finally you can use JavaScript
proclamation internal
using OS a script command line tool and
this is great
you can incorporate JavaScript
proclamation into a bash script
and for example display an alert when
you're about to finish a long-running
background process
so we've seen some other places where
you can use JavaScript for automation
already
now let's look at the rest
when I set the scene I work as a
photographer and travel magazine
I think pictures for cover and every
week
I've to send those cover photos to the
same person
to be approved before I can submit them
to print
every week I send the same in our
message to the same person
and on changing are the pictures
so I whipped up a little droplet here
using the open document handler that
accesses the mail application
creates a new mail message for us using
some freak and content
it then uses that contact application
to get my recipient and the email
message gets their name in the email
address
puts on a message and then for each
other pictures that we've dropped in
this droplet
ran Adams attachments to the message
activate mail and have it ready to send
whenever I'd like so
here are some other photos I talk I
happen to know the last three are the
most beautiful
summit drop those right here under this
droplet
our mail messages created a contents
there are recipients they're
and all the pictures we wanted are ready
for us to go
my workflow was cut from a hundred
percent down to
5 Penn 0 percent
this made my life easier and while I
have the script
open I'd like to mention another problem
that I have
I read a lot of jobs for Prada mission
as you might expect I regularly have
script editor windows open
multiples of what what's sometimes I'm
writing a library then
I'm gonna use another script and I want
to be able to see everything at the same
time
so before halftime the automation tryin
I might have had to drag these windows
around the screen
resize them make sure corners are
overlapping each other and so on and so
forth
but then I realized what I automated so
I whipped up this script here that
accesses the script editor application
and get all the windows and then using
the number of windows and the size of
the screen
it carefully meticulously
programmatically
tiles the windows around the screen
based on their size
so if I run this from the script menu
cuz I use it so frequently
we see all of my windows were piled
exactly as I wanted
I can see everything all the same time
this is beautiful for developing
multiple scripts at the same time so I
used JavaScript for automation
to make writing JavaScript for
automation even easier
powerful its flexible and it's
everywhere
now speaking of flexibility and power
and everywhere
in fact we've proven to ourselves how
easy it is
to extend popular text editors for
JavaScript like sublime taxed and taxed
me
to extend them to execute JavaScript
proclamation code
that were writing in those applications
and to prove it to you how easy it is to
write down mister Prada mission anywhere
in run
we flipped up this automated workflow
that uses the new run JavaScript action
what we do is we access the content up
the front most document
we evaluate that is a script then
we display the result and we optionally
copy it to the clipboard
if we'd like I've save this as a service
and I'm a patch that service to a hotkey
some now
my hope work is very very slim
easy to do I am would like you to notice
I mean text edit right now
I've just a proclamation code Britain in
a document
so using that automated workflow is a
service attacks this hockey
I can wrongness cold executing
from the text edit ID in you that I love
so much that I've created using
javascript for automation
we get ours all with a copy to the
clipboard
not right now thank you and soul that's
amazing I just run JavaScript formation
from text edit
missus to show that you can use
JavaScript proclamation
how you'd like where you'd like
extraordinarily extensible and
extraordinarily flexible
and as we mentioned before you can use
JavaScript proclamation
for terminal using the OS a script
command line tool
so let's look at an example
we're going to con the OS a script
command line tool with a couple flags
gonna be using the JavaScript language
we want a result the print a source
and the past and some javascript to run
this is the
this is what I talked about before we
can display an alert so maginnis me part
in a batch process at the end
the torch show us an alert when our
processes up to finish
so if I run this our letters displayed
just like we won
which is great we get our result
we can react accordingly if we wanted
and another
really exciting new feature a voice a
script is it
interactive mode so a variety of
programming languages like Ruby and
Python
have interactive nods that allow you to
interactively program in those
environments
and now this is possible from OS a
script sup
to do so minute call us a script I
languages JavaScript
I'm gonna pass the dash I flag the same
going in interactive mode
not a demo this interactive mode I'm
gonna be interacting with Safari
so I'm going to create a variable
set it to the Safari application we see
it Safari was activated for us
make it a little better to see
that we can do things like create a
reference to this
first window letting want to get that
Windows name
in simply called the Name property is a
function favorites like we expect that's
great
was a lot of fun what's spice it up a
bit
let's create a new pad add that to the
window in real time
interactively first will create a new
tab
and more have the URL be Apple acecomm
then to actually create this in the
application
I'm going to push it onto the windows
tabs element iraqi
and before I do know I know that I wanna
bring the tab in the front when I do
this
and I i can't quite remember I think
it's the front
tab or there's a property that I can 7 a
window to bring to the front
so were acting with this live before I
do this let's make sure they know what
I'm doing
to bring up script editor I'm gonna
access the library window and let's see
lhasa Safari scripting dictionary great
okay we'll look at the Safari sweet yes
window thank you
%ah the current path not the front at
excuse me
South have this property I know exactly
how to create
how to set the tab to the current tab
bring it to the front
so if I push on the array and bring the
tab to the front
we've just now live interactively added
the tab in this window
had a whole lotta fun in the process
and beyond being a cool way to interact
with applications
this is phenomenal for exploring their
script ability for learning JavaScript
for automation
it's great tool to have
part so we've covered what I was to
produce nation s
how it works how you can use it where
you can use it
to summarize task a proclamation is
built on JavaScript core
modern JavaScript environment and it's
built on the open scripting architecture
which has been part of the Mac OS since
before OS 10
javascript::write nation has been
integrated system wide all layers
from high-level application scripting to
system services
to use in the terminal and accessing
system API us
and as we saw Talisker proclamations
flexible
it allows you to accomplish tasks and
solve problems
the best way that you see fit
sup our call to action today is go out
and script the script herbal
applications on your Mac
for app developers make your application
scriptable so other people can script
and do amazing things
and make sure to tell others to make
their application scriptable
the is an already we have a phenomenal
ecosystem
we're really excited for more more
applications to join it every day
the checkout documentation make sure to
go developer Apple dot com
the JavaScript proclamation release
notes as well as some sample code
we are having a phenomenal time with us
great new feature
we cannot wait for you to get your hands
on it thank you very much