good morning welcome to BBC in this is
new in the tax code
yes our a lot of new stuff yesterday
today
we thought we would take a deep dive
into a few specific areas
have Xcode6 before we do though
let's take a look at what happens with
what time that we were here together
I hope you guys are using and enjoying
its good 5.1
since last year
one of the biggest new things that we
added with support for
I laugh 64-bit and you have an amazing
job adopting 64-bit your apt
to take full advantage of our latest
devices
we've also made significant improvements
for our layout in Interface Builder
and added new API's to make your own
classes work with the bugger pick work
this fall
will be releasing Xcode sex with an even
more beautiful and functional interface
to go along with with 10 yosemite let's
take a quick look at some of the new
features an ex had sex
first of all we have a brand new
programming language for Copa
development called swept
and sweaters etc reading up on its own
but we didn't stop there playgrounds
provide alive and responsive environment
for you to develop code
whether you're exploring new
technologies like stray cat physics
courses
or just playing around with swift itself
you're going to love
the experience to play perhaps
playgrounds also offer
a great learning environment the swift
language guided tour
is actually a playground where you can
try things out
right as you're reading and learning
about swept and of course
swiftest fully integrated into Xcode
everything from code completion
to connect from source in Interface
Builder works beautifully with swept
when you're working in swept
Xcode knows if you have to see the
interface for framework laughs
actual show it to you in swept and when
you after a quick help
you get help in swept a quick up
actually had another new track
0 messed up that build to
it we have another new track that works
well with sweats and inferred pipes
if you're ever curious about what type
is being inferred
by swept quick up can tell you and
you can freely make swept into your
existing objective-c applications
will be showing you how easy that is
in a few minutes now let's talk about
some other tax codes design tools and
the new features their
you're probably all familiar with using
storyboards and develop your I OS
applications
an Xcode sex you can use to reports
develop your life can applications as
well
NIOS
the new adopted by:
let you have a single story board for
universal applications
while still retaining foale control over
customizing your interface for both
iPhone and iPad
and if you use custom pancho your
application
you can now see them right on the campus
and Interface Builder
we have some brand new
level editor editors in Xcode 62
like thus make it level editor that lets
you visually a sample seems
active sex has a brand new way to
localize your applications
you can export call your local liable
content into actually
which is the industry standard format
that's understood by a lot of
translation services
and when you get those translations back
just import an actual will help you to
merge Latin content
right into your project
and with Iowa State's support for
frameworks
you can now build ID components just by
adding a few attributes to your classes
you can get them to show operate in
Ivy's campus
and configure them in the inspector
will be showing you how easy it is to
make your views
into I B components
out actual sex makes debugging better
than ever
often when you're debugging the using
cues
it's not quite enough just to see the
code that's running on the Q
so an excuse sex we now show you
how about block caught on to the Q also
when you're developing the new app
extensions departing support is
easy and automatic for example appeared
developing it to debut extension just
hit run Xcode
bring up notification center on the
device an actual automatically attach to
your extension
for debugging
X good sex have some brand new debug
ages
to help you identify problems with desk
and file i/o
this game that work I'll
and viewed about going gives you deep
inside individual problems
will be showing you how easy it is to
identify and fix problems with your view
hierarchy and constraints
using view the bike
exco sex has some all-new
performance features as well
that will help you to make your app's
faster and leader
our premier performance will instruments
has a brand new interface
with the new workflows that make it
easier than ever to analyzer app
performance
last year we introduce tax code server
and one of the biggest request that we
got
was for the ability to customize what
happens when you're running continuous
integration
so an excuse sex we've added support for
traders to allow you to
to add custom behavior to your boss
and we've added support in the actually
pass for a more
in Xcode am in Xcode server for
performance casts
its easy to make a performance past you
just wrap your code
in a measure block performance pass
what Xcode measure the speed your code
and tell you whenever it has improved
regressed
and in order to help you to make your
apt even faster
you can now profile your performance
passed directly in instruments
with just a choice from this context
menu
it from little things right Xcode also
includes all new reports
that show you exactly higher performance
tests are doing and world
will be showing you how easy it is to
start writing performance pass for your
projects
and using them to make your out better
so that's just
a quick two were have some love the
feature areas in Xcode sex and now we'd
like to die
diving deeper and give you a detailed
look and a few other things
areas to get us started with that
let me introduce Daniel dunbar thanks
Mike
this talk is called what's new in Xcode
and obviously the big new thing this
year
it swept I'm sure you're all really
excited about this new language we
unveiled yesterday
I imagine many are wondering how quickly
can I start using this
my own applications so like to kick off
our team is this morning
by showing you just how easy it is
integrates with into an existing
application we've created this new
photo scavenger gay let me show it to
you now a game
is called shutterbugs when I open it up
miltie
a game start with this great looking
fine on screen that take the user right
into the game that's been working great
better app has really been taking off
recently and users tell us
they want to be able to play multiple
games at one time so for version two
we'd like to introduce a new games
landing screen that shows users there in
progress
and complete games and of course we'd
like to do it and swept
now my designers RT updated the
storyboard
to include this tableview controller
shown here
all we need to do to finish off this new
feature implement the code for
so I know I'm gonna eventually want to
cut themselves class for my table
so start with that in a goat abuse
and select new file from the pop-up menu
a course
I wanna I O S Cocoa Touch glass and the
first thing you'll notice on the screen
that there's a new language user at the
bottom the let you
decide whether you want a swift or in
Objective C Class
course I want swept and in this case
I wanna subclass buit will be cell a
call it
games table view cell job that in my
project
annex could take me to the source the
subclass template
are a great way to get started with the
new language so
for us the main thing will need it a
couple
up properties that we can use to connect
Ruit
so let me add that to start with as you
can see
property declarations in sweat are very
clean and simple
and we just needed to add this ID outlet
attributes so that we could connect to
it
from Interface Builder now that's in
place
let me go back to my storyboard so
also like Mike prototype cell and I need
to associate a class with
by pulled on that menu either in its
base builder has already recognized our
new class using are swept indexing
support
just like games table view cell you may
notice
there's a new model field here another
great way
that Swift improve the coding experience
is by officiating classes
with the models that their declared in
that allows he short
comfortable class names while still
ensuring that your classes
won't collide across targets and project
with that in place
we can set up our our connections a
close the utilities panel
and open our source code in the
assistant editor and now
I can I can wire at my connections just
like you would expect
set the name the state labor law
and we have a custom progress here yet
that should be enough to let us get
started with our custom cell
now let's fill in the details of the
Comptroller re-added the basic subclass
template
with that with a couple tweaks but we
need to fill in the details
so the first thing that every controller
class need
is access to the model data that it's
going to present
for our application most of our model
data is stored
in a user session class let me at a
property to hold that now
I'll call it user session and declare
its tight
naturally we have live issue support in
sweat
and BiPAP this open I can see felony
there's an undeclared type here user
session
haven't imported that class yet now in
swift
all the classes in one target are
automatically visible
each on the source miss wit
implementation piles
you no longer need to worry about
manually importing the headers
for each other classes that you use
get
however you do still need to import the
modules
for the framework that you depend upon
to go along with I O estate
new framework support Xcode now has
support
for unit to find models Arab your own
frameworks
and those models can be used in both
swept and objective-c
we party state started taking advantage
to that in our application
by moving all over model code: into this
new core shutterbugs framework
vacancy
that means to use this in my proctor to
fix this problem
all I need to do is tight import core
shutterbugs
just like I would for any other
framework on the system
and of course the air goes away
now our table view is gonna have two
different sections
by 11 per the in progress games and then
one for the complete games
so I want to start by creating utility
method but let me easily get
the appropriate lists for each section
I'm gonna call it game list for section
and what I want to return here
is the result up user sessions
get filter game last night you can see
that
even though this is a method that we
declared in our objectives the source
code
in another framework I still get code
completion and
even the documentation for that method
in mice with source code
so complete that out and what I want to
get is the in progress list
when the section number 0
I'm also gonna add a cast here to a
gamer it
what I'm doing here is taking advantage
ups with tight collection support
the tell the compiler that each object
in this array
is an instance at the gate my game class
that way whenever I use this array later
in the code
was with compiler will know the exact
height each object
one more utility I'd like in a table
view you frequently want to get the data
associated with a particular cell
an accel as represented by an index to
so created
up a method that lets me easily get the
game for a particular index
in a call that one game for index Pat
and it returns an
option on getting with those methods in
place
should be easy to write our table the
datasource
let me drop at it
what I'm doing here setting the number
sections to be too
I'm gonna return an appropriate number
rose for each section
using that first utility method yet and
are used game for index pack
to easily get the particular game and
then propagate its data into our custom
cell
whenever we need to DQ a new cell
and also added to prepare for Segway
matted to set up a destination view
controllers
when the transition happens okay we're
almost done
but I'd like to do one more thing before
we call a controller
rap you can see that I'm Rd modifying
the separator
inset on this table to to give our table
a little bit of a custom look
that's alright but I've just heard about
I O S 8
new separator affect property I'd like
to try it out here
I know that it's called tableview that
separator
fact but I can't remember exact object
and i'm suppose two assigned to that
property
when X good six it we jumped a
definition
it'll take us right to you a table view
but it's rendered in swept
even though this is actually in
Objective C header in the system
framework
Xcode has dynamically translated it to
the swift interface just like the
compiler would see
and even though this is happening on the
fly we take great care
to preserve all other API comment that
you need to use these libraries
effectively
now that I'm here I can see that
separator a fact
is a UI visual effect if I navigate on
on words that up now I remember
what I want the %um vibrancy of that
munies a dark color style to go with
that
so let me add that Micah
now when I go to specify the style here
I'm gonna take advantage
switched advance type imprints and that
lets me type
just tight dot dark the compiler is
going on automatically in
for the right enumeration type to use
here
because it's obvious from the context
that save me having to type the full and
numeration name
it can really save a lot of typing okay
that should do a prior controller but
there's one last thing we need to set up
remember that user session property that
I started off by creating
we've never initialized anywhere said to
fix that let's take a very quick look at
the
other sites with development using yours
with classes
inside objective-c the place that we
want to initialize this object
is in the signing controllers prepare
for Segway met
and if I go to signing controller United
this is an objective-c file
and of course in objective-c before you
use your classes
you need to import them but a class is
defined in sweats so
how can we do that well when you're
using swept in a target
Xcode what automatically generate a new
header for you
that contains the declaration that each
have your sweat classes
all that you need to do to use those
buses it import that header
for this target no be called shutterbugs
dash wept
and I've added important now he also
noticed I'm taking advantage
a the at imports and tax in objective-c
because to to import my own core
shutterbugs primer
so does in place I can fill in the rest
to prepare for Segway
I get the games view controller and all
set its user session property
way you'll notice is that even though
gains table view controller
is in Objective C Class that we to find
air
site is a swift class that we just a
fine we can use it in objective-c
just like any other class and we can
assign this property
and if I came back to this code later
and I'd forgotten what the type was
I can even use quick help to get the
view
as objective-c would see it it even
includes the description on my property
even though I only ever wrote that one
place
in mice with sore spot so it doesn't
with those in place but see how it looks
in a building run an Xcode will launch
our app
in the iPhone by the simulator
there's a great-looking sign on screen
if I click to play shutterbugs
there you have it a new landing screen
completed Inc
completed entirely in sweat and with
this great-looking by pretty effective
we've integrated switch support
throughout Xcode 6
so that you can use the same great
development features that your
are you familiar with to immediately
start working with any language
and with that I like to turn things over
to John Hess
to talk to you about our brand new tools
for visual interface development
thanks
thanks Daniel I'd like to show all
appear how you can take advantage of the
new features back said six
the design the visual aspect the
application a tad over to the demo
missing
I have respect for my designer to
implement a circular ImageView
it's gonna take us where images and by
crop into a circle
and optionally be saturated color
now I'm finding Xcode new playground
feature to be indispensable when working
on be just like that
I love giving being able to see the
result in my code
side by side as I write my code I have a
playground set up just for this
it start the sample image in europe a
basic function to manipulate a graphics
contact and returning new image
well paced innovative new code they will
take an animal
an impediment optionally be saturated
and two-sample call to render my image
here in the prime Wine I can see all the
result in my code
and by pressing this button I can bring
in a persistent preview
any %uh values that are starting image
in here that you out but right now all
three look the same
because I haven't done anything the
process the image I'm just taking my
source image
and drawing a rock at the destination
okay
the first step is the crop to a circle
America rated as a path
for the noble and thrive in our square
at that the clipping path
and now we have circular images things
look good
I'd also like a desaturase my image I
mean it simply wash over it with the
white color
you the special court rafik 10 that
attract out the color and said adding
white on top
and I can see that our third call
produces a desaturated image
things a great I'm ready to start using
this in my application
gonna grab a copy this code
and head over the mic what I've been
working on
here's my prepare image function not
implemented yet
so we're gonna pace than my coat on the
playground and I'm ready to start using
that to my storyboard
all option click here open it in its
just that
and down in the lower left corner you
see the square BO
this is where I'd like my circular
ImageView to water to be
and interpersonal there's an inspector I
can people still in its essence
regular you I be on
of high Interface Builder auto we you'll
see it build in the module name as well
my circular ImageView by with the
finding a framework
while my story boards in the main
application so the model name in the pot
name together complete the reference my
class
now still awaits where here at this
point
Interface Builder is doing what it
always make a beloved doing
it saying this you a view will be a
sensible circular ImageView
hour runtime a record six we can make
any sense and the circular ImageView
at design time as well let me show you
how to do that
we've added a couple new source after
beard you can add your classes
the first is I be desirable goes right
here at the copier class
goes in the same place for objective-c
spelled a little bit differently
but has the exact same result
interpersonal was able to pay per class
build our framework instantiated and
render
live in the campus you can see here
now you may be wondering wears hats lol
coming from
down here my source file I have
overwritten the new method prepare for
InterBase dollar
this is going to be invoked honor view
right before renders into the campus
and at the last minute chance for us to
do any additional setup
here I'm simply making sure that we
always have an image repair
now I like just configure my image
directly there based on their an offer I
saturation as well
no problem we have two new store another
news or Saturday a
I the inspector Paul I can put it here
in front of my property
and when I returned Interface Builder
I can see an inspector they have two new
bo2 directly drive these values
but pick another image alright
that looks great but when user comes
here
I can refocus on this photograph
not distracted by the bright colors in
this player image
that are saturating comes into play but
it comes down to bed
can see the campus is upping highway and
things were good
makes her look at another image ho Yanks
she gets wet and
not sure what's going on here but I
suspect it probably has something to do
with my prepare image much and I just
wrote
gonna go ahead and put a breakpoint
there
and with my view selected I can't use
the bugs like the beers interprets voice
and a cake topper request to render this
view why the campus
so that I can see just what's going on
now not sure the problem is here
but stepping into the code now actually
I can see right away
bring up a quick help a quick work on
this rectangle
I can see it really is a rectangle it's
much wider than it is call
and Interface Builder taking a
rectangular image my view is
in squishing it down and that's where
we're getting this product image
I think what I want instead is to
produce
a square image and draw the source image
centered in the destination
interface dollars in automatically pick
up my changes
rear-ended a campus and I can see we're
in business things were great
alright I'm done with the scene
mine accidents that happen this is
typically
the head over to my iPad storyboard and
make much the same sad about it
because without had arrived at
storyboard
and I can see that I have a lot of work
to do. I haven't even started on the
scene yet
no problem Xcode 6 all this for us as
well
we have a new feature universal story
boards that allow it to build a single
storyboard target both the iPad and
iPhone
gonna head back over to my iPhone
storyboard thank you
and i wanna show you just how easy it is
to get started with universal story
boards
and the file inspector
there's a new checkbox used by squatters
I'm gonna go ahead and label them
size factors are foundational new
technology reform
underpinnings the new adaptive user
interfaces and I was a
what size boxes I can customize
which using constraints participate any
to my way out adopting size matters
also upgrade all the same way to my
storyboard to the new adaptive
counterparts from ISA
segways the for example no to present a
popover on iPad
in a moral condition on the iPhone now
you can see Interface Builder is
rendering my campus here as square
this is an abstract representation its
met her mind you
you're not heading for specific device
you're editing for all devices
if I wanna see how things look on
specific device
I can open enhance preview editor an
Ecotec
here you can see there are allowed as a
great job
a trampoline my interface the screen
have a porn site on
I can zoom out and I can add more
screens as well here's some interface
will be presented
on an iPad in portrait and
you can see as well the auto layout has
translated my eyes train all the way up
but I have a custom layout just for iPad
Karachi that would Peter well
but it started the first-order
businesses that is part of our
should be short behind shorten it up and
how Interface Builder
up at the conference Obama constraints
from the brain to campus
and wall you can see they both got sore
well I'm editing both interfaces they
want to do universal storyboard
how do I edit just wanted them me on do
this change
down here in the bottom center at the
campus is a new control
for picking which side last year adding
then right now we're reading this I spot
for anywhere
at any high the basis for all them all
layouts and Karen s
as represented as this choice here in
the center
as I move away from the banner things
get more specific
down here in the bottom right corner
is the regular where regular height
layout it's the largest
and it's the basis of my iPad layout I'm
going to use it
and Interface Builder enlarges the
campus to remind me that I'm working
in a specific size box now but go ahead
make the parts order again
and update the contents
and now you can see that the iPad
has changed while I thought has remained
just wait I designed it
down here in the bottom left at the
scene
I have a completely new way out in mind
rather than as editing the constraint
conference
I want new constraints no problem off
select all previous years
and have been a bit over clear the
constraints
in only the size class and reposition
I'm gonna have the image front and
center
read about their me a little our and
I signs the same issue arbitrarily I
need to pay and its size
all start with an explosive with
constraint and now
I said that the with should be you know
some complimentary happened to be
120 points I want too high to be the
same around and duplicating the constant
you since last year
I can add an aspect ratio constraint
saying the weapon height should be equal
her
I could continue those at
position abuse underneath and have been
a faithful gather many constraints
to produce an iPad layout there was
unique that I've had her face while
maintaining my iPhone buyout
just the way that it was now they can
turn it over
take can ordinary what's new with the
biking and xxx
alright thanks John
morning so I just taken over the
for details screen from another engineer
on our set a box team
love to give you a sneak peek at you I
now okay
so the first thing I'm gonna do with
them in Iran and then we will sign into
the game
on navigators in progress game
and I'm gonna click on this particular
picture and then here we are at the
photo details
you I'm so what we're seeing in this
case a
is a picture that paula talk we see a
list of all the other players in the
game
along with comments they made on this
particular photo
and whether they like it or not you know
is I looked at this you I hear
I'm a little bit skeptical that all
these players
are missing their picture so they're
also in this kinda placeholder image and
that not something I'm expecting to see
here
so let's go ahead and let's dig into
that now
I'm relatively new to this Kobe but
I do know that our problem here it's
going to be a want to place
so do you are going to be on the model
side things either the that maybe the
image there just isn't there
or it's going to be around the you I
thought it thanks we have the image data
but we're not pushing it to the screen
so we want we want to figure out exactly
where a problem
so the the first they need to do here to
figure out what you controller is
responsible for
this you here and I think
is this guy photo detailed new
controller
so what I want to do is I want to set a
breakpoint I in this
you did appear and then let's try to
trigger that and see if
if we are in the right place when I get
away
welcome back and
there we okay if the breakpoint good so
probably in the right place
but I'd like to be really sure that were
in the right place
and I'm gonna do that by using the brand
new
quick look for you I D you an exco so
now I can just mouse over this view here
to get the data tape
which is the view on by the view
controller and I can click on our little
pocket button
and just like that I can see a rendering
I can see a rendering a this viewer any
some placid you I view
rain your next call on stepping through
my code and a course if you're
developing a Mac App
this works great for an issue 2 are
so now step one complete we know we're
in the right place
good but we care about is the model
the model optics and I think our model
objects
are these game comments looks like we
have a game comment for every row of
data here
so these rows are backed by a game
comment now
when I'm debugging I really love to use
quick look I'm a really big hole guy
quick look is a really great way
to visualize my object when I'm stepping
through my co
wouldn't it be great if we could have
custom quickly representations for our
own classes
one fact now inside an expert you can do
just that
we've gone through our project and done
it all throughout our classes
let's see if we have one for this game
comment there were investigating
and sure enough we do and what we'll see
is that somebody's implemented this new
the ball
quick look object method so this is a
method that you can implement in your
own classes and it's a matter that
external call when you initiate a quick
look
from the water now
from this method you can return anything
that has a built-in quick look inside
expert so
maybe a an image or a busy past or a
string
for this case in attributed string
which is gonna let us have a little bit
more complex visualization so we're
gonna be able to take
text and image and put those together in
a nice
a nice visualization cover model of now
I'm really curious how was he with the
section looks like
so let's go back to where we're paused
and I'm a mouse over our game comments
array
I can see there's 3 upon which matches
what I see on the screen that's good
and then a I'm just gonna press quick
what button
bone just like that I'm seeing my model
object exactly the way I wanna
intercourse with a narrow down through
the and great
so now we know we've eliminated the
model as being our
source in our problem here we can see
the player images right here
so we know it's not a model side issue
so let's get ready this breakpoint in
let's continue onward
okay so to the issue must be up here in
the UI
and you know whatever review is
responsible for
for drying this BTU I isn't doing its
job
now like I said I'm i'm new to this code
base I'm not really sure what views are
responsible
for pushing these particular pixels to
the screen
how are we gonna deal with that how are
we gonna
are willing to buck this issue
well Xcode 6 introduces a brand new way
to visualize your app when you're the
bug so you can press this new to bug you
are given right here
in Xcode will poll in a representation
you're tired you are
hierarchy right inside mexico where you
can see things like
snapshots of all your views their frames
and all sorts of other interesting
properties that when you combine them
together
they help to give you a really great
understanding why your app
looks the way it does or maybe more
importantly why it doesn't
quite match expectations so I can for
example let's cook on this
this label here and open the inspector
and I can see that this is a UI label
I can see it's tax I can see is fought
I can see its fontcolor all the things
that I'm used to seeing when I'm
designing my UI and I B
well I can see those right now wanna be
bugging it as well
really really powerful so what we care
about though is this
this'll picture right here so it's like
that guy
and what I'm interested in seeing is
what
cell owns a picture so what sells
probably doing the wiring up a
the model data to the UI controls now I
can use
Xcode jump or to see the entire view our
key the selected
object and somebody go up here and Missy
that that view is in this game comment
table view cell so let's find out over
here in the navigator
and it's this guy okay
looks like a very clean a very simple
class it has this use game comment
method which takes the model data and
then it looks like it wires it up
to the UI controls so what I see here is
a see that
the player's name is pushed into this
player label
I see that the comment is pushed into
the comment label
what I don't say as I don't see us
taking that player image in pushing that
into anything so that's probably our
problem here
and it was me it was really easy to find
that using X cuz new Peter Parker
so I'll go ahead and fix that later and
that is probably gonna take care on this
this missing image that we're seeing but
you know
as I look at the UI here it doesn't
quite match
doesn't quite match the design that I
was looking at earlier with my designer
so this post actually be a little button
right around here in the bottom left to
the picture
that lets me like this image from first
to come to this you I'd say
I like polish picture right now i i
can't do that
now the question then is where is there
but
well mainland but was never added to the
view hierarchy
may be trying out of screen somewhere
maybe it's the wrong size
maybe it's album component is wrong
maybe hiding behind another view
is also to really visual kinda problems
that we could have was control and
they're all made really easy to track
down
with the new YouTube are so let's go
back let's go back over your Xcode
and lets look at our view hierarchy
answer what I want to do now there is
one explore this view our can look
through and see
if if that money is in fact here
so the first thing i'll do is i'll just
sorta twist this guy sideways
I wanna people hide summaries & reviews
sure
and then I wanna I wanna whole the use a
par
so let's do that and hey
feel little something peeking out right
back here
that could be a button but this still
some stuff in the way
sewn to peel back some interviews in the
front so I can just hide things from the
front backwards
yeah very nice
and sure enough are button is hanging
out right here
so but select that and the next question
I'm asking myself is and why is our
button
down here and i no reason auto layout in
this project
so I wanna I'd like to look at the
constraints that reason here so I can
show the constraints
for this particular view and just like
that
Xcode hides all the other views that are
relevant
inches me just the constraints with this
particular control
and we can really easily see that the
button is pinned to the bottom
left which is not where we want it we
want a pin to the bottom
on the picture about so that's something
that might be really hard to track down
before but is really easy
to track down now
okay so with Xcode 6
as we've seen the you have the ability
to visualize your apt when you're
debugging
like never before you can create custom
quick look representations
love your own classes that show your
data
exactly the way you wanna see a
and you bugging well that adds an entire
new dimension to the way you can explore
interact with your app runtime: really
really powerful
and a unified really insightful as well
and with that like to turn it over to
Kate's tone to talk a little bit more
about how we can enhance performance
cover-up kinda
thank you can it looks like we have a
spectacular game coming together
we think our users are going to be
really happy with a lot of these new
features
if we can just make sure that we should
quality product of course that a lot of
pics
the development process is to make sure
that what we're about to send out into
the world
is going to live up to expectations my
team is done the right thing every step
of the way
we've tried to make sure that what we
have is a product
that high quality because the course
we've got a set a unit test
running so I got
the product up and running I can go to
my test navigator
and the test navigator shows that I have
several
32 the anatase here so I can go ahead
and run knows one last time
make sure that when the game comes up we
put it through its paces per green
across the board
looks good from a functional perspective
the game is doing exactly what we expect
and that's great because I got one last
change I want to make to the game
I was thinking about and tinkering with
me filters to give
a little bit more life to our images
specifically here are taking advantage
swept feature let me build an extension
the UI
image quite so I can take an existing
+class
and add the ability to apply filters to
it so I have a variety of filters here
the vignette filters when I was thinking
about trying where
so maybe I should go ahead and build one
more test but this time
a performance test to make sure it's
going to live up to my expectations
34 heidi was going to ask for one
mean file pick a test case class you're
probably already familiar with I'm going
to go ahead and use with
for that and you'll note that of course
like all templates I have that choice
swifter objective-c
the tax code knows that I've been using
Swiss throughout the conference so with
the default
for me want to call this for to
put in my existing group with my to
and a country that far from
so now I have what should be fairly
familiar it's got the usual set up
and tear down method written into a it's
got a functional tapped
we're not focused on me those today want
to set those aside
and focus on the one new method that's
been put in place
the ability to test for performing so
I'm going to
test filter performance here and all I
need to do
is fill in this measure block call now
you saw the objective-c cent tax on a
slide earlier
the swift intact is really clean
it's just call to measure walk that
passes one trillion closure
that does the actual work and so in this
case
for my work I'm going to go ahead and
fill in
a testament to pick up when the player
images and then go ahead and apply
internet filter to
but the vineyard filters not part of my
test project so again we're getting a
live issue here reminding me
but I don't have access to that class
directly so all I need to do in
is important the shutterbug module
and I've everything I need excites the
taft
indexing is found the taft I'm one click
away from building my project
and running that tough and seeing just
how long this takes it's going to run
number of times to get figure out how
long it takes whether there's any
variation
and when it's done it will come exactly
how long it took to run and what kind of
standard deviation I'm seeing
4 percent in this case some getting
pretty consistent run to run
time summit sounds good but
taking a little longer than I wanted it
to so what I'd really like to do
is twist this open and see that I
haven't set a baseline haven't set a
target
from my timing and i really wanna the
target I wanted something that was
snappy to live up to our users
expectations so I can go to establish a
baseline
either based on what I have now for I
can go in
at a patent say 0.25 seconds is more
what I had in mind here
and now I'll get a reminder every time I
run this tapped
but I'm not living up to expectations
this test is going to fail
rad because it wasn't after we could
take time to tinker with that but I
don't apply
a number of different filters as
extensions to you I am in shares for me
just go back and choose another one of
these
appointees for nor filter we bill
retest and make sure that that many
expectations
looks good for all grain so across the
board
were in great shape to ship this product
what about had a problem that I wasn't
able to take care of here
what if I had a performance issue I
needed to investigate well of course
instrument to be answered of such
questions
instrument is a great way to get more
detail about what's going on in your
project
cell I'm scooping up the context menu
for this cast
and choose to profile that particular
filter exercise behind the scenes were
gonna go ahead and built specifically
for profiling
and launch instrument and now we get our
first glimpse up in new instrument fewer
instrument has been overhauled
dramatically this release both
to be consistent with the new OS 10
yosemite
but also so that it's more familiar for
people who are comfortable with Xcode
already
we start of with the temperature here I
can see at a glance
want to buy from targeting 1 I'm
planning on running
can find the right template to exercise
what I'm looking for I'm just gonna look
at memory in this case
I can look at what I've been using
recently for pick from the completely
watches that template I'm going to
insurance proper
I mean sure its main window is also
dramatically overhaul
the fee a few things at a glance one is
that it's not immediately recording
how many times have you chosen a
template founded it starts recording
immediately stop it
go back and tinker with the settings now
we give you an option to go in and
change the settings before you record
or to go straight to record
so I'd like to do with be able to browse
through make sure that got the settings
I want
any fear that the settings are now of
centralized in the inspector
again for familiarity for Xcode users so
I can make sure that my allocations to
intercept the way I want
my VM tracker set up the way I want and
when it's all good
I go to New overhauled toolbar weaker
cleaner and taking a blessed screen real
estate than ever to start recording
and we start recording and as always
allocations is tracking
everything that's going on forgetting
are a recording about Amalek regions
all the objective see objects everything
we could possibly want
we can go and look at that a little bit
more detail perhaps we'd like to filter
down to a subset
this while filtering is now just a
simple quick contract no modifier keys
made
so I can see all kind to detail about
all kinds of objects
by Camaro and on something like my first
task of
I know that was allocated and of course
swept object
are represented alongside everything
else here we can see the module name
as well the classroom and get detail so
I can say for this particular class
what inferences were allocated and when
that inference was allocated
what stack trace Senate it came from so
it on a detail right at your fingertips
and of course that carries over as well
that if I want to look not just
individual object but overall statistics
where objects coming from
I can see that on allocating about 15
mags total
during the process for bringing the app
up and running the task
so what part about is actually in my
apply
nor filter well go ahead and filtered
and we can see that it's just about 430
K
that we're taking that sounds reasonable
and indeed
my factories here is showing me
highlighted the black michaud
so I can see at a glance where it is
rather than drilling down a step at a
time
I can just click on my code and see
where in the stack trace
that occurring and look in detail what's
going on
so instruments again the perfect way to
take and understand more deeply
what's going on now come to a session
later this afternoon to learn more about
not brings us back Xcode everything's
working the way we want
of course my next step is to check and
and when I check and
Xcode server is going to start doing its
work
and we can feel we have a server setup
my team has been using the perfect way
for
a small group of engineers to work
together we've got
overviews here what's going on in my
project so I can feel recent activity
my success tree which is looking good
for being successful and my complete
history
up to a little bit of a rocky start
initially with one failed bill
but but all in all looking good a unit
test count is creeping up
I can see historically what failures
occurred so I might be interested in
taking into someone that
I'm really most interested in my most
recent integration
and so fine showdown about integration
and look at all the tests that are
running
I can see that I'm not the only one has
been doing performance to
because besides my green check marks
here I'm also seeing
variance from baseline so at a glance
ICANN fee for this last run
that we're doing well against the
baseline in a couple attacked my
coworkers about adding
was great with twist one is open see in
fact that we're tracking baseline
against individual devices so as be
exercised in all the vices
we have individual targets props for
different generations apart where
and I think these numbers are great I
wanna make sure we don't slide from here
either
so I can go and and added that baseline
right there
and accept the last run as a baseline
target for all future
on missus spectacular because it means
that from my machine
I can change the baseline push that back
to the server and that baseline will be
updated
on all my coworkers machines so they're
measuring the same target
but I am so I think we've got a
spectacular round-trip process here for
you
you're going to love it and to wrap
things up I'd like to turn it back over
to Mike
thank you cape okay
backtracked good sex the seat is out
there available to all of you
so try it out then please let us know
what you think
this is going to be a great week we have
a condom sessions that were going
into even more detail about all this
about have a great show