hello welcome thanks for joining us for
an introduction to switch
kid on a share with you a little a
little back
so im out swift yesterday the keynote
and
as part of the announcement made
available to you
this document its but with programming
language
it's a guide and reference to the
language and in bed when the doc you
online but also in the iBookstore
something really remarkable happened
from the time we made available
yesterday
we've had 370,000 download
say yes thank you anyway this is an
introduction to Swift
I am to my fed Island by day buddy this
is the first three talks on those with
language
this at the conference and we're
focusing today on a broad overview
but the language giving you as much as
we can a few little pieces or some other
more advanced features
before we get started let's go back in
time and it away
many many decades ago
this program appeared in the printed
hello world for the first time
it is a course introduction to came out
pending an image you see book
but many decades that's quite a long
time in CPI terms
so what's changed in that time call
it becomes much shorter inspect yes
thank you so what will happen in this
fight but we've got rid
be include statements no need to bring
in the standard library should just be
that we should just be able to find it
should just work
remain well
within 25 slide a single line of code
that is a complete program right there
and do something like this
we shouldn't need to have to specify you
know this is the entry point for their
so we don't have to gonna call a
function not returning any random value
anymore
and last but not least no semi colons
so that's how the world is a very simple
app little bit simpler than what
we'll right day in day out so what we
gonna come today
we're gonna focus on month in taxes in
key areas house with makes your code
safe makes it much easier to read rights
more concise because on a modern
features we've introduced
and consistency between decorations and
all all this in fact that we have
and of course house with give you extra
power
to do things to kick us off gonna hand
over today buddy
to take us three the basic so I want to
start with some other
the fundamentals and thus what language
start with something really simple as
defined about
we do this with the bar keyword then the
name
language name in this case ACO long and
the tight and this colon appears
quite often switch this means is a time
so language name is a type string
so we'll give it an initial string buddy
the stars of
or three initial value but this one for
you might notice about this variable
it doesn't vary so there's no real need
for this to be
a variable instead you can find it the
constant
with the like he would instead and if we
introduce a few more of these things
that have the version of the language
that the double 10
will have the year it was introduced the
challenger
2014 and the fact that the language is
awesome
that's a boolean clearly true well
the new among which wasn't achieved and
the fact that it's also I'm
these also on going to change so they
may also be constant
and this is a general principle in sweat
that
we prefer immutability or Constance by
default
any really often to mutability of
variables
weapons actually need to change this
makes your code
safer in a a multi-threaded environment
it also means Swiss can optimize your
code more effectively because it knows
what is going to change
and it just generally makes you could
more readable make sure intend clearer
you're saying what is and isn't going to
their for here
I created a string a double an integer
in Abuja
and it's pretty obvious from these
values on the right hand side what it is
that I want to create
if markets so obvious from the bodies on
the right hand side
that there's really no point you might
in the types and swift
in many cases you don't need to refuses
type inference
to look at the money is on the right
hand side with the swine work at what
point these things should be
who this makes good faith without the
efforts this means all these constants
and variables or
explicitly types you don't have to write
tenneco's
to get those times in place morphing
on constants and variables before we
move on and that's that you can use
pretty much any unique a charity like
your constant variable names such as
part here
and yes does
including those this is the stuff that
matters seriously
so that some other basics
talk if you can we also have a morton
fast
Unicode string implementation called
suitable enough string
and them as we just saw if you're
initializing straying from string
literal
as we are here certain for the time for
you is clearly want this to be a
stranger
now swift string syntax
is very lightweight look like a c-string
but it's as powerful as an estranged
and indeed if you working with condition
you can use a swift string
anywhere you would use an industry so
here with I think the
HTTP method property event and its URL
request using a first-rate
moreover if you working with foundation
you have the info and a string AP only
available to you
on any Swiss train you create so we can
call that the path components property
on this train
and get back in to rate the companies
they read
for every switch string is a collection
of characters
and you can use of or in lieu to its
rate over those characters
so just hit with printing the five
characters in The Woodlands
falklands this work just as well in
English
as it does in icelandic all
Russian all Chinese
and even with emoji so if you want to
create a character you can do so just by
assigning
a character annotation mystery the
string
literally the site with lazy want the
street we want the string literal to be
a character
district if you want to add together two
characters
you can do so just with addition and
this goes for two characters make
strain goes for Strings characters
making long distance likewise districts
sometimes you want to make more complex
strings than just addition
so let's say we want to take these to
Constance a
be which are inferred to be integers
from the full bodies three in five
and would like to make this string 3
times five
is 15 but in a way that would work for
any values have a in the that we have
them
us with a really elegant way to do this
three powerful way
writing these kinda more complex strings
known as string interpolation
this is how it looks we can insert
Constance
variables and even expressions such as
three times five here
directly within a string literal just by
looking them in print sees
escaped with a backslash and it's really
clear what the string interpolation
will make when it's evaluate it makes
exactly this ring would expect
and this works with any value have a be
but you might be wondering the swift
have immutable strict or
and the answer is actually doesn't need
wall instead
stream usability is a case in working
with variable
in which case the string can change such
as adding to the strain on the N
or alternatively working with the
constant in which case
the stream com change if actually a
compile-time error
to try and add another string on fiscal
constraint
about string what else do we have but we
have collection sites array
dictionary in the same way we saw you
can use a
switch string and and a string
interchangeably with API
you can use and array anywhere that
takes an anniversary
a dictionary anyway the Texan and
extinction it but earlier on when we
called that path components property on
off switch trains
we got back was actually right not
tonight s right
even though the API a wrister it defines
return and it's free
the easiest way to create a new
collection is a literal
and array index initials and swift very
familiar from objective-c
arrays are just square bracket from the
edge commas between the items
here we have an array 4-string ideas for
names
dictionary literals also very familiar
cohen's between the keys and values
commas between the key/value pairs its
way back from the edge
here we have peas a which is strange the
names are some animals
and integer values the numbers are like
those have
so the literals a very familiar but
arraigned dictionary
actually have two things that a quite
different from an disarray
and Ennis Texas the first that they can
work with any type
here we have strings and integers you
know elections
they don't have to be object they don't
have to be replaced
second difference is it in swift
collections are
types collections but the 1i means
to his or a real names and is an array
for Strings
now is pretty clear from looking at this
away in Ames
that it would be owned to have an
integer into this right or a boolean
value
all a bicycle I would be just called
an array named should always be strings
so it would be nice to have a way to say
that it can only always be strings and
its first week at
we can provide a 20-minute Asian this is
how we right away array of strings
string for a bite his weapon and then we
can only considering the mystery
from thing on the right hand side here
is pretty clear
that we want an array of strings just
from looking at this little
and so if we initialize an array in this
way we actually don't need to write the
tight
switch Confederate force and we still
end up with the time to write
the same goes for dictionaries here it's
clear we want string
keys and/or a integer values
as we can for this time for us as well
this but we have point elections
makes good faith for two reasons firstly
it means you know what you're going to
get back
you know what you get out to these
collections it also means that you can
insert the wrong
claims about his by mistake is actually
narrative to insert the wrong kind of
things into these rights
and the six so having defined a
collection
they would now be useful to to loop over
them to iterate over the values
we have all the leaves you be familiar
with from see
we have while loops do while it's a four
tips
and as we saw earlier we also have the
foreign leave which we use with
strings and characters but it's a bit
more powerful than just rings we can use
it for a few more things than that
we can use it with ranges this is a way
to write arranged
that includes the numbers are both ends
it's warm talk talk talk
fine that's known as a close-range is
includes both 15 in range
it we just printing the first five items
in four times table
sometimes however who wants to arrange
to start from zero
incomes up to but not including the
funnel money we have a
way to write that as well to seeing 2
don't threaten 3
to this comes from zero 25 but not
including five is known as a
hoff close range conclude about at the
beginning but not want to be a
we can use foreign within a right sewed
for print a nice welcome to the four
people in our names array
and we can even use it with a dictionary
I'm new here
that we're extracting the key and the
value at the same time
in a single foreign Lee this makes much
more expressive code when working with
pictures
this combination a key in value rub
together in parentheses
is an example of a swift feature known
as a tuple and these on tweeting the
Values
group together as a single compound
finally you can pass around in your car
welcome back to couples later in the
session the sea world that can be used
so that's how we create collections and
how its rating heavily modified
problems but with an array he is a
shopping list contains two items
eggs and as an objective-c
we can access the first item in the
array just using subverting
here retracting X if you want to add an
item to the right
we literally just added to the right way
and it's Liam they're running if they
don't comply
we can also and multiple items in one go
just by adding a compatible away
hey we're reading cheese butter and
shoppers but tallest
to want to change a buddy subscription
again we just signed a new value
pre-existing a right he was changing
eggs to be sick
but if we if we want to make a shopping
list a little bit healthier perhaps
we can actually place an entire range in
one go so we can replace
by 2335 but the cheese the butter in the
chocolate spread
with some bananas and apples instead
about
but the rave about dictionaries well we
can modify his own text me from earlier
we have three
p-value as the animals likes and three
starts off with free but we want to add
a new animal to this the right
this is easy is just signing a new body
fittings a key that's not already in the
dictionary
here running the fact that spiders have
273 likes
but as a problem point is do not have
273 likes if you find one that does
runaway although be warned it will
probably catch it
but this is not a problem we can fix it
we can just to find
a new family for existing key and change
the body index
expires Nov 8 likes to have been
modified
dictionary want want to retrieve a value
from this dictionary
what we want to see if our dictionary
contains the number of likes for
ok or perhaps a number of likes for the
gong
or maybe the number blacks for
Venezuelan Google
well I think she might contain the
numbers like these animals
but it might not might be no money with
all we knew
we need a way to model this fight and
this is a really good use case for every
powerful feature
swift known as options lighting like him
back up
it anymore optionals and some other
passages think is beyond the basic
thank you Dave so I'd love to use but as
well including of that my samples
actually find it quite hard to say
funnest it with
aardvark how do we get the numbers like
that will weaken subscript to make
enquiry this book washer we get back
well we kinda wanna be able to get to
type something back gonna want the
number of legs
as an integer opening a says this body
wasn't found
so that's something else we could use
some magic integer value like an 80
perhaps but
but there is a possible value here
snakes don't have any legs
so weak on his era in Objective C you
might be feeling things like and it's
not found a -1
you know we could use minus one here
father no its not possible to have -1
legs
but we could be using example when -1
was some kinda value wanted back
so wouldn't it be great if we could you
some kinda value that didn't take up one
of the possible integers
well yes and swiftly to this weekend
optional
an optional integer indicated he reliant
question mark
means that we either get an integer back
we get nothing at all was nothing at all
mean
well nothing in swift is represented by
Neil three different objectives email it
means nothing means no value at all
in some optional body so we can test to
see
if it's possible I count his mail to see
whether the animal was found the net if
it is nil then the animal was not found
what have been found how we get this
value out how to get back into out to
the
other the option to would will you stop
by
we do that by forcing the value out
using the unwrap operator
the exclamation mark here so i'm saying
is I think that the constant like count
to the underlying value in five possible
like count that's what that
I'm not operator does notice on not
specifying a type
up like come here I don't need to
because this is an optional and
the compiler knows that it's not plans
when I forcing that value out I get
the underlying inside like count here is
an integer
I fed forcing forcing the body about me
unwrapping it
why my using that word well I am forcing
the value out
if I try and unwrap an optional and that
in fact there's nobody that's nil
actually gonna session social only do
this when I know for sure that the
values that
because %uh this was a very common
happen in swift which is to say
if their value in this optional thing if
there is
and unwrap it give me the value back so
I can use it so common in fact
that we have a special syntax this is
much safer bundles a
the two steps into into a single step
what this does is it says
if possible let count has a value unwrap
it
get it back to the like on constant and
I can use in the locker code
if there is no value located skipped
so it in a number examples of this
statement so far an if statement since
we have to look much like they do in
other languages
one exception there not is that there
are no parentheses here
we can use principally like but that's
the optional Pat
a so in this case they just that on that
this a punctuation noise
so I'm gonna leave them out the braces
though
races are required and as I can hear
from that utilizing this get a whole
chain a bug that happen with nested it
fire training it's that you know if you
if you have about it statement to live
the code and even then to them correctly
but the
the second one film gonna happen that
bad cannot happen in swift we have
braces for that they're required
so we can do more complex things in a
statement of course we can have an l7
that
but in this case I'm watching mushing
multiple bodies I'm saying if the
account is 0
I'm printing on my animal slippers and
slides around
about his one it may be hops around
otherwise it walks
fun watching this that this like count
against multiple possible values
really I should be using switch
a switch in swift home try to I'm not
saying that three times
is the most popular mall are controlled
by statements
let's start with the basics fighting
with my count switching on that
I'm using case to indicate the possible
values value 0 citizens lines case wanna
help
otherwise it walks the use case like you
do in
see an objective-c not if I'm not
specifying break here
cases in swift do not automatically full
free
I'm also not limited to just matching
against integer values
and swift I can much been subject to
need anybody's I like
much in this is an IT action method and
I'm tracking which
which object either is as interacting
with flick a switch on the Send
much against it outlets in principle
message like Amazon objects
ask about two inches from moment miss
reply to me much more expressive
say I'm watching multiple bodies in a
single case at a time of numbers between
1:13 animal limps
even numbers between 10-14 it walks not
that nice
very expressive but there's a problem
with this example if I trying compile
this
again ara the Arab says switch
must be exhausted
in swift you must include a case or
default for every possible value that
that could be matched against
so the easiest way to do that if the
supplied the full case
and the reason for this is it again
makes you could say for
much in your writing something that you
the state machine and you have a big
switch statement in the middle
and you forget one of the cases well in
your state machine grinds to a halt
not bad I cannot happen in swift you
must have an exhaustive switch which
means either case for everybody or
default
so we must get individual values here
but what I want too much against a a lot
a lot about he's a big range values
well I can do just that like a match
against a range
so this is bringing in pattern matching
a little bit so here we have there is
still no legs
128 as a few legs missus this close
range operator that they showed you
earlier includes both the one
and the aid three dots so that much is
have a few legs otherwise not have legs
about an introduction to a pattern
matching
as a whole load more awesomeness that
you can find out about
by watching the intermediate swift or
so good examples we view so far we've
seen a lot of print line
what is this thing the functions defined
in the standard library Prince
somebody to the console with the final
own
functions when Swift functions this
define with the funky would see can read
this as declare function
called say hello doesn't take any
promises it doesn't hurt anybody's
and this case difference hello to the
console call it as you might imagine say
hello friends
course I got a promise I may be able to
say hello to someone specific
plucking out in a name parameter notice
the consistency here
name coat on string the name is a type
string matches with the variable
declaration syntax and Constance as well
so this means like a mouse a hello BBC
hello BBC and using string interpolation
I get my name in the hat hello that
in swift my promise I could have the
full value as well
so this I you really want to say hello
world I can about
with equals same name coal on is a type
string
and how the default value world this
means I can call the function without
specifying any name at all
it'll say hello world but don't say hi
to you guys so
hello BBC I can still do that anyway not
promises passing values into a function
like anybody's out
we return values in swift with the arrow
say I got a new function
school build greeting this time takes a
name
and it returns a string with the
concatenation operator that plus
that so
function returns a value with the arrow
and we get about body
you look at a constant school greeting
I'm gonna set it to the return value
from this function
that is what I'm not doing I'm not
specify a type a free thing here
it's very clear this returns a string
because that's what the function returns
the compiler knows that it wasn't for
this correctly for us so we don't have
to specify the Ken
we can supply the value right that's a
vent line and it just works
we talk about returning a single body
what about multiple values
by Swift we can return multiple values
with this topple
think that they've introduced earlier
what is a tuple
will topple just a grouping up number
gripping a values
negative any type any any number I D
that you want in this case
first couple three double values
otherwise could have an interesting if I
like
or interesting and a double any
combination of things that you like
what what I want one of these well it's
not a replacement for a full-blown data
structure
sometimes you really wanna class or
struct at to be most explicit
to topple the really useful when you
just wanna POF multiple bodies around
very simply
such as when returning multiple bodies
from a function
some this example I have a refresh
webpage function ago that the pressure
the web page and it gives me back
the status code that means an integer
code and a string message
maybe get bundled together so I return
that with a tuple
friends and comment string friends how
do I get those things how to use them
skretta constant stomach got two names
also in parentheses with a comma in
between
and those get bound to the values the
comeback from the function
it means like a man use them
individually and print them out
separately
so with decompose the tuple with these
names
again notice thank you notice that I
haven't specified types
hit return to the function is obvious
we've got two bodies coming back from
their own internal string
so these map to the names and compiled
in a statement and a message
right that as I enter the string you see
an example this decomposition already
that was when table showing you
enumeration a dictionary
the way that we keep you the key in the
value in one go
is for each iteration through the
dictionary you get back to top or pat
containing the key and the value so
these names here these binding to those
returns and then you can use them
individually in in the for statement
the couple decomposition is one way to
get the bodies out with another one
not as we can actually named the bodies
in the tuple so I've got nothing to
stream it is not entirely clear what
they are
what if I could name them I must say I
have a code
which is a type int and a message was it
it which is a type string
same sin taxes promises and burial
decorations
thing is a tight type
this means when I call this function I
come out just declare a single constant
call status I can then grab the
individual bits out by names that have
taco dance that I thought message ready
for use
plus functions only two related thing
now which is closures
closer than swift much like books in
objective-c
I just blocks of code you can pop in
around they can capture values from the
surroundings
go to have a very simple one school
greeting printer is a constant
and how's this this disclosure that just
Prince hello world
again I'm not specifying any type agrees
in principle it is very clear disclosure
doesn't take any value doesn't return
anything either so the compiler will
infer that this is
this thing empty primes are MT per annum
that's the type to disclose it doesn't
take any promises doesn't return
anybody's
everything looks kinda familiar I
recognize this this friends are a friend
syntax not because it
it looks very much like function syntax
there's a reason for that
in swift functions are just named
closures
so I can call my greeting printer thing
just by saying greeting printer prints
antique prints hello world
as a simple pleasure as a local variable
perhaps what about closures parameters
what to do this same syntax again I'm
gonna create a repeat function this time
this will repeat a toss to give a number
of times in the task is a closure
so again empty friends are empty friends
doesn't take anybody's doesn't return
anything
and it will be repeated for the number
that I supplied how do I call it
as call it twice I won't disclose a
trippy be repeated twice
so i cant supply my closer in line right
there in the function call
that about you not talking about syntax
and we could do something really special
in swift not as if
the closure is the last argument to this
function we can shifted outside at the
outside to the front to see the function
called turn it into a trailing closure
this paper code much more readable it
looks like a control place they are now
which it is in this case
and much more readable for modern
bringing trailer closes
and so that's close as we talk for
functions we talk for tuples
take us forward I'm gonna come back
today to get it data types and
specifically
classes let's take a look at how to
define class
in swift we do this with the plot
keywords followed by the name of the
class you want to create
here I'm gonna great the vehicle and all
the places definition all its
implementation appears between these
curly braces all its properties all its
methods
all it initializes we'll see how to
write all those
in just a moment the first there are two
things you don't have to write
and sweet you don't have to import
vehicle don't age
and the reason is because they called
age does not exist
swift doesn't have had a file there's no
need
instead you just write your
implementation for your plans and that
becomes a interface as well
was no need to do to get the second
thing you don't have to write
is we don't have to have a base class
civic
because with doesn't have a universal
base class that every class must
much time has come from you can still
use
and a subject or any other cocoa Cocoa
Touch
passes if you wish that's fine we don't
have to
it make sense to vehicle to be a base
class for some
high rocky places in Europe that can be
it can be it basic
where we want to create surplus also we
do this by providing the
sup last name followed again by coming
on and then thing we want surplus from
and we'll come back to this bicycle so
surely the first left on a bit more
detail
to on basic storvick to stop buying a
property
a property call number: wheels its
variable property the whole body is a
right
know that this is exactly the same
syntax we would use if we will be
playing this is a very
just moved into a place called here we
made it the
variable property what we call rely
property objective-c
but it could be constant in this case
and we just use less things were
different
a noble cause we'll keep it as a
variable for now see what the changes
proposed changes value
some supplies no
big big difference that we have been
switched from objective-c
is that we don't have any a distinction
between instance variables
properties things with their one and the
same thing
and in fact this for number will seek a
zero is will you have to Roy
to find a property switch provides the
backing store for you
you don't have to fight itself and
handles all access to them
back in store for you as well in this
case where we just storing a value
these are known as store properties we
do have a second coming of property as
well
known as computer properties but have
one of those who are vehicles
subtropical plants
who has a computer property that
provides a description about class to
the string description of the
the number will that house know that
Computer Properties
don't have a backing store instead they
the generator or calculated value when
the court
to write warm we provide that type that
we want this property to have
unjust return a value of the appropriate
time here
we using string interpolation to return
the number wheels
in this case I've provided read only
computer property
is why I only have getter I could also
provide a sector as well
if I wanted it to be weird right it
doesn't really make sense for this
description to be relied
is generated based on other properties
something to keep it as a read-only
property
well computer property is read-only you
can actually
lose the getting the braces and just
return a value directly from the
the m2 description of the the computer
property
the end result is the same you just
don't have to write an extra level of
nesting
note however that Computer Properties
even read only ones do you need to be
defined as variables
even the you comfort them the file you
can change it can vary
so they need to be there
now that we've created a vehicle given
it a few properties
let's create a new instance about
vehicle which we do with initialize the
syntax
this is the name of the class followed
by a pair of parentheses creates a new
instance of this class
because we provided a full body for our
school property
it's clear what to do when initializing
this just that number will 20
know that we didn't need to write clock
at the point we created this is
circles all the memory allocation for
you there's no need to write our
we also didn't need to buy the type once
again swift and for the type we want to
create is clear from the thing on the
way
confide that we want this to be a
vehicle
as I mentioned earlier we we have these
default values number this means we
actually haven't had to write
an initializer at all because it's just
clear what to do here
it's clear to create a new instance give
it a little funny there
now that we've created our vehicle
inference we can use don't syntax to
taxes properties photo printers
description we can see that it has a
description is there wheels
we change that with the two we can see
the description change it now has two
weeks
but it would be nice to create a class
at always has two wheels by default
a bicycle supplies from earlier let's
see how we die we do that we make it
have to be by default
because we want bicycle to change the
value of an inherited property
we do need to write an initializer and
this is how we do it the unit keyword
followed by a pair of parentheses and
these come conferring from it is
you can use provinces to customize your
initialization and they look just like
the function from
system showed earlier but we're not
going to use them in this case we're
just going to use a new value to
because we're changing
an inherited property we do need to get
a superclass
a chance to set up property for which we
do by calling secret of the net
after all it introduced the property so
we need to get it give it a chance to
set an initial value
which we may then use the modified by
the week
that with them so we can change the body
we can fit into that will go into a lot
more detail on initialization in the
intermediates with talk
the final one final thing tonight swift
initializes
than return a value rather main role is
to make sure that every store property
have about you by the time its
initialization complete
so now we have a factor we can create
any bicycle we can
printed description which we inherited
from vehicle and see it has two wheels
by default
all the old bicycles wanna to it
so that changes the for money inherited
property but what if we want to change
its behavior
what if you wanted to do something
different every time it's called for
this we override the property
will create a new surplus vehicle call
call give it a new store property called
speed
initial value 0 does the right thing for
to be a double and will add an
initializer that that's the
because number of wheels before
wonderful same approach we just saw
for for bicycle so override a
description
in this case I'd like to have the speed
onto the into the description
we just want them we want the property
in the same way as we did before
to have that same name at the same time
to the override
we have the override keyword on the
beginning
this makes the avoid safe for two
reasons firstly it makes it clear
we want to provide an override we
haven't just accidentally resent it
property to have the same name into
things like this something else the fact
that
maybe we didn't even know about moreover
it should prompt swift to go and check
that this property exit
somewhere in of Cyprus Czech so there
definitely is something with the same
name and things like
Sourav right will do what we expect in
this case
we'll just call the super description to
get the number of whales
and without an actual text on the end
the show the speed
so if you for the car we can see that
the the description default
four wheels their loss per hour if we
change the speed it affect now includes
news feed is 1
about the way to change the behavior
have inherited property but
maybe sometimes that's a bit overkill we
don't want to see
want to change how it works I just want
to know when it changes wanted changes
to
for this we have property of service
so to show these accrue to suppress a
car called parents come
the parents car doesn't stop me going at
a certain speed just watches how fast
you going
and if you go too fast it issues a
warning that says careful there
that's a bit too fast to do this we
still
override a property in this case where
overriding the
speak property we inherited from car
know that this Android is first or
property
not a computer property but still within
the same way
this time however we will provide a
custom getter and setter
will provide either will face or did
settles over
and will for his call just before this
just after the valley changes
will forget a new value constant that
you can use within the body this
observer
did that getting old buddy constancy you
can see what about you was or
has just changed to be within the doctor
in this case will just use whilst and
will use but new value comes into
keep an eye on the speed in this car if
it goes over 65 miles an hour
will issue a warning careful
about how we are properties what about
methods having a mattress topper
well is a simple clerical counter just
keeps track of how many times
something up does this with a store
property call camps
anything way that the store property
looks just like a variable
methods and swiftly just like functions
want to miss to study a
here this in criminal matters looks just
like we're going to function at the same
time
this case it just fans want to count six
points called to make it a bit more
complex if we are to privatize
again is just the same as a function
from it as we saw earlier
know that when we refer to come here we
don't have to use over-the-counter
inside the method because it's clear
what we're referring to there's no
ambiguity
want when we do it yourself is if we
have affected his promise to name is the
famous the property name
here we have a mathematical can't so in
this case
we you thought still can't refer to the
property and can't refer to the front
so that's how we treat classes we given
properties we give initializes and how
we give them back
another invite them back up to take it
beyond places
and to show some of the other data
structures you can create in sweat make
the building blocks of your
thank you thank you so be on classes
which we go next
gonna structures structure this week to
define using the struct keywords a
hearing at a defined
a couple maybe three a point to have an
X&Y coordinates
size to the width and height rectangle
with an art and a science
with structures I get a break from the
member was initialized by default
it means is really easy to create
instances these structures just by
supplying values
the properties in lines like supplying
an X&Y with my height
point to the site for the rectangle if I
really wanted to
I could actually provide custom
initializes in my structures
find out more about that check out the
intermediates with talk
okay so this is a simple structure has a
margin as a size as the two
two properties it would be rather nice
if I could
Adam area to my rectangle a public
computer properties are coming up on
others
yes yes we can so here's an area
property on my rectangle just returns
the wait times the height
okay property is a great but what about
methods I want more than just the
property
when Swift structure can have a method
as well so here I haven't is bigger than
other wrecked method I compiled a
rectangle in return
about me back indicates whether it's
bigger than the other one
structures in swift incredibly powerful
a lot more functionality than you
when you use to NC so that raises the
question
what is the difference between a
structure in a close
in a couple examples we got a rectangle
thats at the moment the structure
we've got a Windows a hypothetical
window class the first to some user
interface
object how do you determine whether you
want
a class or structure given you gotta
love the same functionality
whether to primary differences between
classes in structures the first
difference
at the structures cannot inherit from
other structures
the second difference is how values the
past around
political window I'm gonna create a
window
that means I get the window object right
now this is a a reference to that object
but what the I declared my window as a
structure
well-struck to the pass by value that
means the body's a cop it when they
passed around so my setup function here
would get a copy of my window that seems
weird what would happen will
a public at a second wind on screen not
doesn't feel right at all
so window it should be a class because
classes apart
by reference in swift not means my phone
function
get a reference to the window but I gave
it reference to the subject
okay that's classes what about
structures what look at the frame at the
window
it's a rectangle I want to get this
frame I wanna do something to it I want
to use it somewhere else
so I can extract it into a variable me
frame
what happens if rectangle was actually
class
well if I felt the origin here I can
affect my window
clearly that's not what I want to do I
just wanna change it and use it
somewhere else and is covering up my
flight so
clearly bad so Windows
frame is a rectangle and the rectangle
that should be a value type
a structure structure the pass by value
that covered around that the past around
to talk about the difference between
weapons and body types of the constants
and variables with these things in mind
a cell like rates a window and I this
time I declare it with molecular that
means I have a constant wind
reference what does that really mean
that means I have a reference to a
window object
the window object isn't affected by this
constant is only the reference that is
so I can still change my windows title
quite happily I can still set out to
hello and it just works
but it's a constant reference that means
if I try
ok but this reference to a different
window a compile-time error
because I cannot meet a to constantly
I'm trying to take the constant
reference here
what about value types a spot with a
variable I'm gonna create a valuable
point
for a value type try to think of it as a
big value in and of itself the whole
thing is a value
so appointed an X&Y coordinate so this
point one has an X on the line that
if I change my point 1x going to update
that value inside 25
not find is available it can do that but
if I use
let to declare point2
the entire value is now immutable that's
not constant that means I cannot set
point X a the x-coordinate that because
I cannot meet a to constant entirety
that value is constant
him so when I wanna like a me take my
ValueType depends
on the declaration use so what does that
mean if I want to add some kind of a
method to my structure that that
change it so I want something that moves
a point
to the right by given number well thats
changing that the value so I shouldn't
be able to do this on a constant
if you do want to do this then you must
declare the method is mutating and it
tells the compiler that you're changing
the underlying value
that means if you declare a point with a
constant in this case
and you try and move it to the right you
get an error because you cannot meet a
to constant
structures that's one example a value
type in swift
another one is enumerations Sony rations
which can have moral values much like
see
to have a plan numeration and has a rule
value Int
so I'm using a one based index nectar is
the first planet venus is a second I
could use if I wanted
but I want one so for must have some
somebody how do I determine what that
value is
escrita constant number unaffected to
the to rule
value all planet daughter that will get
me back three
that's how I get the real value back out
so I can use
integers an underlying value but it's
worth I can use other types as well
such as a string of maybe a character
here I can now named the top line P
ten-count return characters
with using any known sometimes it
doesn't make sense to have
an underlying value at all sometimes
the cases just bodies in their own right
to have a compass Pointe
has north south east and west have no
real number or string that really makes
sense that I to these
so the dust bunnies they despise in
themselves
how do I work with them as credit
directions ahead and survival I'm gonna
maybe change that in the future and I
decided to Compass Point dot West
compiler will and say oh to compass
points so it knows the direction to head
is a compass Pointe
a sampling some directions might change
direction I wanna head East how do I say
that
because the compiler knows that it's a
compass Pointe all I have to say
is enough to change that to East which
is don't East in this example
this works extremely well when you're
working with Coca touch Inc okay
we've done some incredible magic made
important things that are into swift
so that if you're dealing with the UI
label for example you want to set the
text alignment property
in Objective C you do that with and text
alignment rack right
but the combined those text alignment is
and its textile I mean that the type
that all we need to do
its supply enough to specify that it is
right so the text alignment is now right
much more readable much more concise
super awesome
incomes can have row values underlying
values
no bags at all but that's a different
type I wanna talk about not
enumerations with associated values
neither public discriminated unions
that the given example let's consider a
train trains are usually one of two
things that I've
on time sometimes all that delayed
if there on time they just on time if it
delayed
the delayed by a number of minutes so in
this case we have into imprint disease
after the delayed case
and it says that I want to be able to to
catch both either on time
all the delay in the number minutes that
is delayed
let's see how we work with that greatest
artists variable
and i guess its initial value to train
status dot on time
trains very optimistically always start
on time but as we all know
and sometimes stuff happens and they get
delayed
and so we can change that just by saying
he is now delayed
and we can supply the value 42 minutes
right that
so that's associated value very powerful
but we can't do we can do more than this
I know out a little bit more
functionality to my train status I wanna
stop by adding
an initializer this means that when I
declare something that uses the strength
that I think will automatically get the
on time status by default
not gonna stop that as I have a computed
property called description
this time I'm gonna determine what the
value is and then get back a string that
mean something sensible so
it is on time it will say on time if
it's delayed
gonna grab a number minutes it is
delayed by by binding minutes and head
to the number
and then I can build a string using that
with string interpolation
Sony missions a hugely powerful here how
do I work with the things I've done this
when I convict delay I can declare it
without a sequestering strange how to
spur and that will give me
and on time status by default so if I
print the description it will say it
sometime
then it gets too late and so I can set
the delay
and now Michael description it will give
me today by 42 minutes
but this about us it's very much tied to
a train
very likely that the only place we will
use it in our app is inside some kind of
training class
seems a bit ashamed to have it display
thing around for anyone to use
when he's making it super easy for
anyone to use be nice if we could
high of status into the train class
itself
when Swift we can do that by nesting the
type so we can grab
we can put of others in find the train
class
nested right that's not just call status
because inside the train
set up as before I can still have a
property on my train that is a bit of a
status and it will be set on time by
default
and we can just use it so we can def
types and swift
as we want a more power I like power
extensions
for expansion in swift very much like a
cab to be in objective-c
we can extend any class we like but in
swift we can go a little bit further
we can actually extend any names tight
we like
including value types so here I have my
size structure you saw earlier
that's the structure like at this
mutating function it increases the size
by given factor
because it changes the underlying values
but not as mutating
but I'm not just limited to name typed
that I have been swift
I can actually also extend any name type
I have available to me
to him on extending CG song is that from
coal graphics is a structure defined
see at the same increase by factor
when I've done that is available
anywhere in my swift code
from this extension traffic sending in
names type
I wanna see what else I can do this
wouldn't it be fantastic if I could
extend
mmm and in will
yes it would and let's do that interest
just the structure defined in the
standard libraries like an extended
and I had eight repetitions function to
my integer
this is going to take a tart the closure
has been repeated how whatever value
the integer is their adult self that
will get me
the number repetitions I need to know I
can supply closure
on the call to repetitions on any
integer value
so I can say for example 500 repetitions
and supply closer
and I'll get hello printed five hundred
times for the small
because because the closure if the last
argument
and it's been this function call I can't
wait it out
put outside to the front sees you know
what
for training closures if there are no
other arguments I don't even need the
parentheses
so this turns into five hundred
repetitions do this thing
like control flow for just extended an
int
a value type internist and alive how
amazing is that
as we head more into gonna blow your
mind territory I'll leave you with one
more thing
not generics let's start with a
non-generic example
here I have stock a vintage isn't back
and I can push bodies onto the stock I
can pop them off again
and that's that's great but what if I
wanted a double stack or strings tackle
hell even if
backups tax how I would I do that what
happened duplicates
this definition multiple times than
anything I would change would be these
highlighted bits
the ins across that the types used for
the array and
the two functions that I have the two
methods
went to be lovely if I could just so you
know this should work with any type it
all
we can do that with the generic so
generic sense with you indicate the type
with these angle brackets under a rock
anti says there is a generic type
parameter here
and anything that you 250 that must be
the same time
elements is just an array of teas push
now take the teapot not return dirty
was that mean means that we can now
build of documents
like this week into sacred documents put
on 50
notice I'm not specify anything here to
compile a nose that push must take an
integer
if it's a fact events so I'm pushing 50
on I can pop bottle
and it knows that lasting will be of
type int because that's when dealing
with
what about strings likenesses with the
spring as well tonight the greatest
strength back a backup strings and put
on a string
began compiling know that many what the
string when I pop it off it knows that
I'm returning a string therefore I can
print it
so that generics it's a very very brief
introduction to generics
to get further details on all the or
some stuff you can do you should check
out
the advance with talk brings me onto a
question
how do you learn sway how do you go
figure out all the cool stuff you can do
with this language well before up front
this book is available in the document
online
made when the iBookstore thus with
programming languages the canonical
guide and reference to the language
we also have using Twitter taken a
jetted series in the document tells you
how to work with coconut get to see from
existing code
house with them to operate with okay for
more information on the language itself
check out the intermediate and advance
with talks more information on
objective-c and interoperability check
out the two interoperability
in that and into meetings with the check
to see talks
we are in lab all week come down tell us
what you think we want to hear your
questions
if you're playing on a home talk to this
guy they belong he's our fans left
check out the developer forum thank you
very much that is swift