good afternoon and welcome
welcome the intermediate swept
my name is Brian lanier I'm an engineer
and developer publications
later i'll be joined on stage by my
colleague Joe crop
is an engineer on this with compiler
team for both really excited to be here
today
to talk with you more in depth about
this web programming language
have been allowed to last couple days
and I've been very impressed
are ready with what you've been able to
deal with sweat and I think
that go into some more detail on really
key features a swept
you'll be able to take advantage of
those features even more so in your code
so
in particular we're gonna look at some
features into more detail
including optional and how you can use
them to make your code safer
we're gonna talk to you about memory
management swept
how it's largely automatic we're also
going to talk about initialization
and how you can take advantage have the
power closures
and pattern matching in your code so
I want to begin by looking at once with
most powerful features
optionals but first I want to take a
look at why we might need optional
in the first place so you need to work
with input data
from a user here asking for the users
age
the response comes in is a string but
say we need to convert that string to an
integer
using this to it method here now
when the user enters a string that
represents about
manager the 28 method returns the
correct result
but however because you're not be in
control other users response
you have to deal with cases are
situations where
there's not an obvious value to reach
her the user has full control over what
their entry in
so if they try to get here or
snippy a we don't really have a
krier value to return in this case so
what do we do what value do return well
we have lotsa options right
well I should probably aware
various sentinels have been used in
various different languages
to model these kind of problems but
having so many sentinels around
isn't very good it's not very say it to
Commons for some bugs and problems in
your code
for one you have to know which of these
possible sentinels
was chosen by the author the API and
then have to room you have to remember
which one
to check against it so this is a very
good pattern
to really how should we model this well
in swift remodel problems like these
using the optional type
the optional type represent
possibly missing values I've any type
whatsoever
and the optional but I'd has two
discrete state
a default mill State
which represents literally the
absent a any value whatsoever and
officials are defaulted to know
you've probably seen a couple examples
and options if you've seen the
introduction this web talk
you write them by running the bases hi
followed by a question mark indicator
optionality
now in swift
mill is not like sweat in objective-c
foreign object to cease with is an
object pointer to nothing
they only work for the reference types
in swift
mill is a true Sentinel value it works
with any type whatsoever
it literally just means there's no value
president though the other state
a fan of you indicate the presence of a
value that's been wrapped up in the
optional think about hope that this
rapper
container their wraps up values when
they're about his presence so he
retained a valuable option number two 6
and the value is wrapped up in the
optional their wifi had unwrapped this
value and access it
in just a little while so
now that we have single fentanyl value
that works with any type at all even
integers
it's clear what this method should
return it clear that
whenever we have a value that's not
valid we should just returned an
optional and in fact
the two it matters defined in the
standard library on the string tied
and does just that returns now know
because we have optionals
we also have non optional types as well
Twitter non-official pipes
well they're just ordinary types you
think they are integers
streams even your custom object
in the great thing about non-official
pipes is it big
hand to be now we think this is pretty
cool because it makes your code safe
and predictable we declare a valuable
non-official type
can't be email you can be sure that it's
there when you needed
and you can't be surprised the
unexpected no values propagate
throughout your code
so now that we know of some type are but
they represent the see how we can use in
our code
for example to write a function the
returns
an optional tied so here we're gonna
write a function that looks for a string
in an array of strings and if the string
is found the array it simply return the
index
but as you might guess this is a case in
which
if the string is it found that we need
some value to indicate that failure
because we have mill and also that our
disposal
let's go ahead and change a return type
here 20 of shock by an act
the question mark at the end so with
implement the fuckin the first thing you
do is a numerate the array
here using enumerate method the finest
in our library which actually in
numerous to an array and returned as a
to Paul the index and the value a each
value in the air
in the Iraq and we can use that in the
foreign statement here
and check to see if the string it were
looking for matches the value
and if so simply return the integer they
were returning
an integer here but then it gets wrapped
up as we sat in the optional
the turnpike because we have no or
disposal
we know exactly what to do when we don't
have
a ballot result we'd simply return 0
nor the 72 unwrap optionals so
with use this function here to look to
an array
and try to find a name in the Serai here
you can clearly see that
the string that were looking for is me a
ride so we have a valid result to return
and we can check now we always wanna
check to make sure that the value
is present so we can simply ask if the
index value visenteno here
and notice that I don't I'm not checking
explicitly against No
enough because of course can be used in
Ballwin contact
that mean to you can check them directly
very naturally like I've done here
so if the value is present which it is
we can simply try to
use that value in the subscript to the
Iraq
but if we don't like this we have a
problem
because we're the arrays expecting a non
optional
integer we've said that the function
returns optional integer
so the types don't match here in the
compiler will let us know the first
before we use it we need to unwrap the
optional but when we working on rap
optionals
is using the force unwrapping operator
was simply consists of an exclamation
mark
you write the exclamation mark after the
optional by giving you wish to unwrap
in here because are surgery returned a
valid
respond we can simply print out the
result
but you have to be careful as I said we
should check to make sure the values
know first before we can wrap
so we tried to use the force on rockin
operator here without checking
we would actually get a runtime
assertion a runtime error
because we need to make sure the buyer
was there and we're trying to force it
when it's not
so instead it's what we have a better
way of doing this we can actually
test and unwrap at the same time
using it what we call optional binding
of combining uses this
if let's unpack you may have seen
earlier introductions with top
to the flood state how does it work well
first as I said it test so a test to see
the optional type here to see if it
actually present or if its value is now
and if it's not male it find on rapster
and find the non optional tight
to the index value here this temporary
content
you can use a temporary content because
it's unwrapped
as the index as the subscript to
disarray
and everything should work just fine but
we can actually combined together
there's no need to actually include
a temporary variable we can simply
evaluate the result
the function directly in line and then
to find out after some rock to the index
here
which now index is up type not optional
and just regular old
but that we're off from Iowa taken a
very simple case let's look at how it
might look if we
did something a little bit more complex
so to do that
let's set up a couple passes say we have
a person class which has a
optional residents and a residence which
has optional address
and finally have an address fat ass
three optional properties
building number street name an apartment
and all of which are optional
and let's do a little bit more
bookkeeping let's go ahead and create
a person instant Paul here and
let's keep our resident and let's also
give Polish President an address so we
can receive his mail
now because Paul doesn't live in an
apartment were not going to stop the
apartment number
but we're going to the building number
two the string 240 three and the
street name to main street now let's say
that we wanted to
get out the address number as us integer
not as a string we could use if not
binding to drill down
through all these properties in some
properties are the classes we've defined
so first we can start to see a pause a
resident up so
unwrap it a sign at the home we can do
the same with the address
and finally we can drill down and
finally used to it mattered to convert
that string
into a number and assign it to you the
address
variable but this is really cumbersome
as you can tell
the stuff is not lead a pretty code arm
and it's kinda hard to follow all over
the net to deflect unpack
and statement here so in swift we can
actually use
optional chaining as a way of
accomplishing that same thing
actual chain what you work with optional
to conditionally perform operation
like messaging mill in objective-c but
in such a way that it works with any
type whatsoever
after attending provide a clean and to
think syntax for doing these kinds of
operations
so what we're doing here is we're just
the value in it each point using the
question mark operator a chain operator
to see if the thing to its left would
have an optional type if it no
of its present before we proceed to the
next expression
so to see how this works in a little bit
more detail let's look at this example
and see how it evaluates
you think the evaluation optional chain
expression
like two parallel railroad track in two
different destinations are two stations
for station being the optional value
that's wrapped up
here so in this case and and the trapped
in an optional
or simply know when there's no value
present so let's see what this looks
like as we go through the expression
for paula is not optional so that
obvious we said I'm is about instance
we can go to the first option on here in
the chain expression
residents well we know that we set it as
a residence but if it were no
who actually just take the No track and
the entire expression would return
know it's all been awful pipe but it
simply returns now and the rest to the
expression is ignored
but of course we did set a residence and
we can do the same here
along the path and we can check every
single
optional in a chain expression to see
whether or not it's valid
and this case we've set an address we
set a building number
and finally come to the last and method
call
after we've checked all the rest the
options now the two emitted as you
recall returns of some type itself
through actually one more path we need
to consider it could in fact return know
if it can convert the value
but we said of course to a valid string
representation
energizer and so to admit that has a
result return 243
and the entire expression is completely
evaluate
it to rapid back up in a optional so
that the address numbers now
and optional with the underlying value
but because it's an optional value if I
need to use it
as a real integer I need to unwrap it
still
well actually we can combine these
operations together optional chain
and if let's unpack corruption by name
to test on it to test and unwrap at the
same time again
so here we can take the entire of
protein expression evaluated
see if it is it now on rapid in a sign
in to the undescribable
we can use like an ordinary non-official
tight for example the added to a
database
so that option was work
34 that two of those work so awful
training workshops combining work
they want to take a step back show you
options look like under the hood
don't spend a lot of time here but I do
wanna show you how powerful and
expressive this web programming
languages
that we can actually model something so
fundamental Collingwood like optionals
in the language itself officials are
really just
simple enumeration a generic enumeration
at that
at any time you can see the some type
here represent the case in which
I said that there is a value present the
two wrapped up you can see that wrapping
here going on
and the non case just simply as the
default value which we've said that you
can indicate using now
we haven't talked much about generics
and we're not going to go into generics
much detail here but I anchored you to
watch the advance with talk
we can see the four-party American
action
so that optionals use optionals to work
safely in your code with possibly
missing values
missing values are nil and present
values are wrapped up in the optional
you could then on route the optional in
two ways either with the force on rockin
operator
but only do that if you're sure there's
a value there and it's not now
and you can also use if let contactor
optional buying two unwrap attached to
the same time
in a very safe way and finally you can
use optional cheney
to work in a very succinct and eloquent
way with multiple optional expressions
chained together
and that's optionals highlighted by Joe
back on the stage to talk to you about
memory management and sweat
my name's Joe groff I work in this with
compiler and I'm really excited because
managing memory is my favorite thing to
do
when I program no it's not
thankfully foot is built on automatic
reference counting the same
mile we use an objective-c or art
we don't make you use the point if
intact we are making spell Alexa
but still way to clear a class like this
any construct the class
you get a memory allocation implicitly
and a reference to that is what gets
stored
in a local variable at these references
back keep that memory alive
now we can juggle a couple be there
bowling pins here
when the last reference to a class goes
away to not that goes away
about it automatically get the allocated
arc is a horrible juggler but great at
reclaiming
unused memory
when a reference go down in Scopus
automatically released
but want to get some reference to the
object is kept alive
in only when the final reference is
released is the object the allocated
it's a it's predictable it just worked
it that for the cycle
sometimes it doesn't make sense foreign
object to be own
for instance apartment literally are
owned by their
tenants but they also you know we'll
have like multiple people living in them
over the
my time in the building and on the other
hand a person will move from apartment
to apartment over their life
even if you move a person into an
apartment
missus relationship isn't really in
owning relationship
as a problem if we try to model it as
such
but set up a a dictionary the are
renters in our power apartments they
were landlord
and let's move one of our tenants
elsewhere into our apartment
now is a problem if you tried to move
out
she's trapped the reference to the
apartment
heater object alive and even worse if we
try to stop the property
we're stuck with the deed both objects
keep each other alive
in our reference cycle
like objective-c we have weak references
and the stealth wept that this object is
the responsible for keeping the object
on the other end alive
now when we work to the example again
with a weak reference between the few
objects in
affecting me about her apartment
and make a clean break with her landlord
and the reference automatically gets
reset the nail
there's no dangling reference to the the
allocated objects
course when we thought the property both
objects and that the allocated and
there's no
be in
and weak references in sweater model
that optional values you can use all the
optional operations that Brian just
showed you
to work with them and when you take an
optional week value
and you bind the not optional part out
today
you get a strong not optional value
any can safely work with that just like
any other reference
if you're applying a single method are
looking up a single property
conditionally
on a week reference object you can also
use the chaining operator
as I shorthand in
something to be aware are that the path
in Iraq pattern does not work very well
with week
you could go to cash advance rent check
find out that abound
and evict them before you have a chance
even greet them and end up with the
runtime a reading expected
chaining of it doesn't preserve a strong
reference if you use it to try to apply
multiple methods to the same object
here cash rent check code again 'cause
the
tended to get relief and then we'd end
up greeting and no object
and then in fact not calling free at all
in weak references are great for
breaking cycles
but they are always ideal
but they were a modern landlord and we
accept credit card payments from i 10
a dream I know but now bear with me
now a credit card should only ever be
owned by one person right
so you really want this to be an
immutable binding an immutable property
up the credit card we offered only
really want to
track a credit card if it isn't owned by
a person
it shouldn't be an optional property
now there's obviously a cycle here we
could break that cycle with weak
references
but that bored there's nothing to it
some unfortunate loosening up the model
here
for them all week references have to be
optional because they have to be
resettable the nail
thinking about all they have to be
mutable
because he's they could be reset the No
at any time
and we are really want this we could end
up accidentally
reassigning a credit card or ending up
with an orphan credit card
just to deal with memory leaks that
would suck
sense that we have another kinda weak
reference the %uh known reference
and what this stealth with that although
I don't have been owning stake in the
object
my life depends on it I cannot live
without my AI my owner my card holder
so we can go back to our renters cable
we can save our
attendance credit card information you
can see here
but the credit card is uniquely own by
the person record
so that when her record as the allocated
the entire object graph get the
allocated there's no need
to observed the be credit card
independent other person
because there's this assumption that the
program is not correct without the
object on the other side you can use on
on references
just like strong references you gonna
find them into a local variable
organ call methods on them directly it's
a bit like unsafe and retain in fee
our objective c- but it still fate we
still assert that the object is still
allocated
every time you access it going on and
reference
so that we kinda references in sweat
strong references are to default and
that's because their way should use my
for the time
but the time you have an ownership stake
and an object you want to use
however if you have independent object
object with independent lifetimes
Mysore to be a casual relationship going
on where you couldn't move on if they
went away
weak references are great for modeling
that sort of thing
if part part of your program and that
the allocated to maybe a low memory
the rest your program marches on and
options are a great way appealing
with week referenced objects going away
and i dont references are great for back
references from dependent objects back
up to their owners
a party at a Cracker the way the entire
autograph goes away
and there's no need the deal with now
that memory management was swept its
automatic
its automatic reference counting it's a
every what do you think about the
relationships between objects
rather than the Rama katha memory
management
a strong we can on references
to model those relationships and provide
the knife a firm foundation for swept
talk a little bit more about that
foundation and I'm bringing back to
Brian
the talk about initialization thank you
thank you yeah so we're talking about
initialization sweat
initialization and swept up old one very
simple rule another said every value
must be initialized be forty years
this one simple rule is enforced by the
compiler
ensures memory safety in your code
ensure that you never read from
uninitialized memory
and therefore helps eliminate an entire
class about
let's look at how this rule applies
throughout the language
slow start with a simple variables swift
doesn't default initialize
variables constant for properties
because are often isn't and natural and
correct value for everything
the only touching this is optional where
we start earlier that
actual have a very natural defaultValue
now
this means that you need to set these
values explicitly in your code
but it doesn't mean that you need to
declare these values at the point that
you declare
your variables constants are properties
it just means that you must do so before
you try to read from them or
access for example say we want to set
message here to an appropriate value
depending on
whether or not a condition was true and
then print that message out
even though the condition is true in
this case I mean we're in the middle the
session after all
we get a compiler air
because we haven't considered every
possible branch in our code
we haven't said what the value %uh
messages when the condition is false
so what's on our clause to do just that
now and weary from message to print it
out we can be sure that it has an
explicit value
for every single condition: in our code
but now as I'm sure you're all aware
it's quite easy to forget to check
all the conditions in your code to
rather than
surprising you by unexpected and hard to
track down behavior
this with compiler catches these kinda
mistakes for you
and ensure that your explicit about the
values you want to set for every branch
and under every condition in your code
and has great for memory safety
now that we've seen how this rule
applies two simple variables let's see
how it applies
when you're define your own classes like
caught like dat
our classes are structured your own
types
so in five a structure a class
declaration initializer
handle this responsibility the hill the
responsibility of Solace find the rule
that everything's a
is set me forty years
now you've seen some initialize urs and
some Joe's example the memory management
just a while ago
their declared using the keyword in it
and their invoked and object creation
for instance creation here using this
initializer syntax
now they can have initializer can have
any number I've labeled arguments for
parameters
and when they do you need to call the
you need you calling using these labeled
primers are required at the call site
before we look at initialization classes
let's take a look at initialization
and how it works in structures was to
find a suitable color structure
that's three properties red green and
blue to represent the car
aren't and it won't deal with alpha
later
noted that we want to create colors and
different shades of grey
well to do so we can define a single
initializer here
very simple one that simply has takes a
single grayscale double value
and set all the sport properties other
structures that same value
now free for gotten the that the red
property for example
we get a compiler air because we haven't
thought of by the rule
every value must be initialized before
Cheers
in the same is true for calling a method
in your initializer before you said I
love your properties
for example say we want a ballad a we
won a method that validate the color
components to make sure they're within a
valid range in value say
021 da 0
if we didn't call this method here
inside the initializer
before we said all of our properties
weed again get a compiler
because we're trying to call a method on
sup on the instep
but before South has been fully
initialized so if you need to act for
fell
this customize any property values order
calling methods in your initializer
always do so after you've said all your
sport properties to appropriate values
now in structures if you don't define if
you're own initializer
will provide you with the member wise
initializer
automatically the member was initializer
has argue with the corresponding to each
that emphasis for
each adult classes are suckers for
property you can also provide
defaultValue airline directly for your
sport properties
and when you set all yours for
properties and you have a defined in
your own custom initializer
sweet provided default initializer for
you two years
back takes no parameters increasing
instance with the property to set
as default values when you declare your
structure
so that only solicitation work in
structures
don't take a look at how it works in
classes
really it's no different so let's start
with a simple car class here
has a single property a paint color in a
single initializer that just sucks that
pink color
to an appropriate value now in practice
classes often subclass inherit from
other classes so we need to deal with
how initialization work for subclasses
as well
so as to find a subclass called race car
have one extra property
and own initializer when race cars
initializer is called it first started
own properties and then a call the
superclass initializer
in the superficial other forces its own
properties to an appropriate value as
well
and only after the super class and all
super classes
in the class hierarchy have had a chance
to set their own values
is a classic fully initialized and ready
two years
now if you're coming from objective-c
background you probably noticed that
this is
officers are different in what you've
noticed the what you do in objective-c
where you always call your super class
first and then you to Iran properties
so in swift if we were to do that if you
were to call a superclass initializer
for
inventor and properties we would
actually get a compiler error because
not only thing to do though
do so in this order and the reason swift
initialization
poses order is that insurers memory
safety
so that you don't try to access memory
before being completely initialized
may not be obvious where you might run
into problems
by doing things in this order so let's
take a look at example were calling
your super class initializer for is
unsafe
say for example that we wanted to find a
function here our method
on our car class that build up the gas
tank we wanna call that function inside
initializer for every time we get a new
car
to come to the forecasting because race
car to use a different kind of gas a
regular car
we've overridden this message nr
subclass
so when we create a new race car
and its initial either is called it
first called the superclass initializer
which in fact its paint color properties
and finally called it
stochastic method but because we've
overridden are subclasses
a good thing then we think this back to
the fun part version
that's a method and that's where we have
a problem
in our problem is that we haven't got a
chance in our own initializer
the set our own properties and so we're
trying to call a method on fell
are trying to access this objectors
instance it hasn't been fully
initialized
and that's not fair so in swept
we always make sure we have our own
properties before we call our super
classes initializer
to have a chance to do the same
to so far we've just seen example a a
single initializer in a class
but you can have multiple initializes in
your class just like you can in
objective-c
it back you can have designated
initializer what we've seen so far
designated initializer which you may be
familiar with coming from objective-c
have the sole responsibility of Corey
did not object inside in all its
properties
and it has a job hauling it super pas an
initializer
and delegating up you can think of them
as fun appointed funneled initialization
process
all the way to the class to the base
paths in the hierarchy
we can offer have convenient initializer
convenience initializer czar sorta
secondary initializer provide and
alternative
implementation in Darfur initialization
interface
it allows you to say pastor in default
values
make it easier for your clients to use
they can only call
across I can only delegate side to side
in a particular pot they can never call
up so they can call designated
initializer
anything past or other convene its
initial litres
open windows giving its initial others
need to call a designated
actually do the heavy lifting obtain the
properties
so let's see how you might try to
convince initializer your own code
say we have race car again we want to
reconvene its initializer
that lets just passin color and it sets
the triple property to true
and it does so by delegate in the past
to the designated initializer in the
same class
now when we do this kind of thing in
swept wing define a community fish
finder
we pull ups with compiler no banquet in
the convenience
keyword in front of the Declaration
looking even provide
more than 12 minutes initializer so we
can even
provide a convenient initializer the
letters poured a race car providing no
parameters at all
and delegate his past here providing a
a default great value and it called the
other conveniences like your we've just
acquired
and that in turn of course have to call
the designated initializer
actually fit the values and because we
have a super fast to deal with here
that initializer need to call it super
and how our initializer is inherited in
sweat
well they're not inherited by default
because doing so is an always say
however we're craft provides no
initializer
at all n you set default values for all
the store properties as we've done here
with the Formula One race car
proof that a single for property to a
minimum regulation wait
and that we know that way consider
directly we do that
we actually inherent automatically all
the initial either the super PAC that
include
designated initializer in a convenient
initial is that we've declared
nope we did this in this particular case
we have a problem
because wanted convene its initial
others we've inherited
that the wrong value for sure about
Formula One race car going allowed to
have a turbo
by regulation and so this would be
appropriate in this case
so instead all the finer own initializer
here now to designate
initializer because they call Super and
pass through that trouble value
fall because we've done that we provide
our own initializer
we actually don't inherit as other
convenient in the sliders
for the other designated initializer so
that's how
you would use initializer to set
properties and how you can
Sep property in line directly but I
haven't told you about a parent may be
familiar with the objective see
sometimes called lazy instantiation lazy
initialization
for you wanted the way the evaluation
a property in studying it because
for example may be doing so is
computationally expensive
so we have the same concept in sweat
using lazy properties
and let's take a look at an example for
you might use one where it might be
appropriate to say we have a game class
in the game for it to be a single player
game or multi-player game
now the multi player manager let's just
suppose
that it does a bunch of expensive
computation it so we don't want to
create it
if there's only ever single player we
only want to create winners multiple
players
and so we want to lay that
initialization and told to appropriate
so we can do this in swift by including
the
at levi afternoon in front of the
Declaration here
and when we do this it'll only be
evaluated
the time access and only when a doctor
only that one time
just as we have initialization it's with
you also have
just as we have initialization it's what
we have the initialization the
initialization
responsible for tearing down the object
knows Joe is already told you
memory management with is automatic so
most the time you don't even need to
think about the initialization
it just works it just happens for you
but for cases where you do need it for
example 200 just yourself as an observer
for for example to pose a filing may
have opened
we want to have a chance to close at
file Incredibles non memory resources
so for that we use Adi initializer
the initializer are just occurred using
the DNA
keyword so for example here we have a
class that we we open up a file
it this craft 50 allocated before we
have a chance to close the file
that's not good so think this is the
last resort
last chance you have to clean up non
memory resources before your object
is d allocated again most the time you
probably won't need 'em
so that initialization swept it say you
initialize
all your values before you use them set
your sport property values
first and then call your super pass
initializer always not order
designated initializer only delegate up
and community initializer only delegate
across
and finally we have the initializer if
you need them
but most the time you want left
initialization highlighted by Joe back
on the stage to talk to you about
closures and sweat
thank you
now there a lot away the store in RA
and we keep our center library writers
busy buying a million different format
that Vonore
but we'd rather not son so we have a
single for method
that take the closure you've probably
seen a better this in the entire talk or
even in the keynotes
a closure in sweat its belt inside
curly braces you follow it with a
signature in the case the sort
it takes to argument for the element
type theory in this case string
and has a billion telling us whether the
elements are sorted in the right order
but with the in keyword your you're
buying this argument inside the body and
the closure
and then follow it with the with the
body at the function
and now we have a single format that
back in for an array and a number of
different ways
we can store aided the offending using
the left an operator
we can sort descending using the greater
than operator
became into something like sort from
shortest the longest by counting the
number of characters in each string
now for the great interfaith but there's
also a lot of typing
and closures in this form are our little
awkward to work with
and the actual interesting part gets
lost in a lot and syntactic noise
thankfully we have type inference the
help us here within the definition of
swords
for of course already knows what kinda
closure it takes
in this case working with an array of
strings so it takes two strings
returns a ball
but forget the their call fight again
that's really it's really offensive
that's really burning my eyes here
why do something about that
much better we can infer that the
argument and return type
from the signature %uh the function
that's a great improvement but we don't
start stop there about closure consider
the thing overturned statement like this
we all need to specify return a single
expression closure and put early returns
its results
thank you
at this point even the argument left to
sign a look a little heavy
let's get her that too their implicit
argument names dollar zero dollar one
dollar-million they may need a little
pace in some cases but there there there
if you need them and they may closures
really think think that an easy to use
me about the thing that we are trailing
closure syntax when you have a single
argument like this you can move outside
and was the only argument you can drop
the parents altogether
as make functional programming in sweat
really express it and fun to do
and we sort and we've that without a
method to the array
class to the race track to make this
possible
affair with a list about the words in
the English language that we got from
the dictionary service
now we can pick out words that share
some common
trade for the one hand in GR why and
turns out there's only two
we can use the F filter method which
flights out
with which apply the closure each
element of the array at and
for the ones that returns true returns a
new array containing those
we can then transform the with the map
method which apply the closure each
element and collect the result into
another array
and i'm looking to reduce method the 4
B's into
a single strain
now each of these is chaining another
method call on to the result the
previous expression
even if we're using trailing closures in
tax we can just a chain method
invocations you think dot like this
and because the thing or expression
we can even include and I get larger
expression
and include a lot of complex logic into
a very small amount of code
it's an extremely expressive way to
build up your logic
in a paper for code that doesn't involve
hall
thank you
closures can also capture local state we
could sum up all the elements in array
using a for loop or reduce but we can
actually abuse map to do it
inside a closure we can refer to local
variables that we can even mutate and
there's never any to mark them under
under block
or in any other in any way it just where
and then we can return that results
just
closures are really just a literal
functions and swept
just like him path a literal in a chair
or named intercom stand as an integer
parameter
you can pass a closure or indeed a name
function
at the closure value we don't have to
wrap up print line
in a pusher like this we can just pass
print line there's only one kind of
function type in sweat
we can even do this with bound method
is that a packing an index at like this
wrapping a call to the method enclosure
we can just pass the bound method
directly at the function value
closures and swept are just art objects
they follow the same memory management
rules as classes
so if we want to have a global variable
that
we can install call back on and write a
function
that installs a call back using local
state and that function
that reference will keep
back closure and all but local stayed
alive there's never any dates but we
copy a closure order worry about
dangling references to its environment
and just like closures are functions
punter also closures we can %uh
functions in flight other functions
and refer to the local state at the
outer function and we look at these in
the debugger an instrument
they show up with their names so when we
start reference to this
in a global variable even when the local
function goes out of scope
that reference keep the local function
alive just like a cloture
now because closures are
arc objects that they have the same
ownership in reference cycle problems as
classes can have
if he did something as seemingly
innocent as taking this
call back and putting it into the
property
upper-class will have a problem
when we go to that these objects a
fourth what we're really doing is we're
capturing felt they were capping as a
strong reference
and then we store reference to the
closure inside
the class we end up with the reference
cycle
and a memory leak the compiler actually
won't let you implicitly reference to
sell
reference South inside a closure because
of this problem yeah it's pretty nice
now in a past life you may have thought
this he is being a %uh known reference
using a local variable with weak
ownership
in sweat we can use a on ownership
instead
but this is problematic even if we did
this
if someone cut and paste that code into
this closure it would still be capturing
self strongly
so have a better way to do in and swept
you can suffer by directly in fight the
closure how to capture its local state
and now we set up the other crap is no
longer cycle
and there's no we love closures in swept
they have an incredibly expressive
syntax and much simplified memory mile
from a check to see
and they make functional programming and
sweat really off and and powerful
now like to talk about other powerful
feature a swept
pattern matching you may have seen
in the into a top thats which not only
works with integers
it also works with strains are indeed
values have any type
and also what's up ranges the values
but that's just the tip of the iceberg
you may have to remember that
enumeration sweat can carry associated
data we can tell not only that the train
is delayed we can say by how much
with an integer value that only make
then when the train is delayed
because there's a 38 data is tied to
that
case at the enough we access it through
a case statement
we can bind it to a variable and then
use that variable
in fight back a statement it's what we
could go to that
to like 8th cases are like the girl
scouts by the pollen swept
we can access it anywhere else is much
safer and easier than using in on what
the union or
struck like you may have been see
move with the bookcase a pattern without
her
construct delayed only matches values
up the delayed state inside the NAM
and if it isn't that the late day it on
rats the associate data and passes it
down to a sub pattern
in this case the lead pattern by the to
a variable
but the actually a completely
independent and fully powerful pattern
anything we do
at the top level up to switch with an
aunt weekend due to its associated value
so we can match against a specific
values they were delayed by one minute
good match against the Rangers values
they were delayed from two to ten
minutes
enough ignore the value altogether match
any delay
using the underscore which is wild card
pattern
thank you
you can also use in and have a 30-day to
other unions
we can track not only
both the out at the bar train however
well we're traveling we can track the
entire save our vacation and when we do
so
can tell our friends on social media
based on that state
the match at simple case that you know
I'm we can match
a nested associated value to level speed
for 15 minutes then we might be a little
50 minutes away my bill snarky but still
the compose if we're delayed a more than
that we might get a little upset
pattern matching doesn't just work with
the numeration the last word for that
the dynamic types of classes but they
were going to have a car and an
arbitrary car
if if someone bring the Formula One car
into our
into our on mechanic a to our mechanic
he's trying to be a little confusing my
might take you to a specialist
we can do this using the ads pattern
this above to check that
a value if a type and if so calf it and
path into the side pattern which you can
then use the binder variable
and then we can pass it on to a pic crew
who will then
to not that formula 1 car for more
mundane car
weekend pattern match it and then if
they have the turbo tune up the turbo
before falling through using the profits
name and into the deep okay with
that that the normal turnout for a car
we can also pattern match multiple
values simultaneously using two bowls
people are a great way above returning
multiple values from a function
or for combining related values like be
component so this
have a color and we do so ito madness
people pattern is an independent pattern
we can match red against a single value
the match green against the Rangers
values fine blue to a variable
and ignore the output component all in a
single pattern
we can also match out multiple values
and test additional conditions with
those values using a WHERE clause
here we're testing after all people to
see if it's a gray scale value
soldiers in the parlor trick let's try
something a little more real
what validate a property list a
dictionary
the arbitrary values i unknown type and
given a valid one we were returned a
well tied
struck given
a property list with the name key that
the string
a population at the number and a
two-letter personal abbreviation
we want to get a record like this
however
it while the fear that the wrong type or
if the personal abbreviations too long
we will return L but they are we can do
the same pattern matching
will start with a single
Kia the be property list you may
remember
optional just an enumeration so we can
use an enumeration pattern to both
reject property list that don't have the
key and on rap
the value for ones that do inside that
pattern
we can use the thai pattern to both
reject property list I don't have a
string name
and get the string value out for those
that do and then working as a lead
pattern to buy into that string value
and store to a variable no with the
single default clause
handle all invalid names now
we can repeat this for each element that
we care about inside the dictionary
but there's a better way member we can
use tubal patterns to match the
simultaneously
and repeat this pattern for each
ki aahat property list that were
interested in
we can see that the the name as a string
the population is a number and the
abbreviation for straying
all family tenuously and with the WHERE
clause even checked the abbreviations on
the appropriate link
and we're done with the thing on the
ball 'cause we handle all invalid
property with
al fits nicely on a single slide that
the power had a net
it's an incredible way to test the
structure and values
and really improve the readability and
safety of your code
so we still
just scratched the surface of what's
with can do we look at how a
optionals allow you to write state code
we look at the
foundations are swept in memory
management and visualization
we look at how powerful closures and
pattern matching are
the 10 more information online
there's that the but they prolly already
downloaded read by now
there's also some additional material on
the developer site about interop with
Coco
if you're a final on from home a
talk to date he's great and as our
forums you might also just what's ABC he
read a lot about the greats with
sessions right here in Presidio
thank you