hi up my name is John McCall I'm a
compiler engineer
on this web project and a horrible nerd
and a today I want to talk to you about
how you know you can picket van into
pretty about the language schools that
we build and thus we have to make your
code
so much more expressive and powerful 16
I
we're gonna start off by talking about
how you can take control love
buddy the basic the basic name which in
syntax a swift
when to follow that up by talking about
a much more advanced topic
to your programming and I'm gonna finish
that up real quick with
by talking about how swift
is implemented and how it turns your
code integrate
machine code that's funny XQ so
when we design swift we wanted to avoid
hard coding too much about the language
we think it's really important to
provide a great standard library that
lets you ready get started right away
and making great aP's for your users and
just jump right in and and be able to do
what you need to do
but we didn't want to knock you into
just the tools that we provide
we wanted you to be able to extend that
basic language with
new idioms new abstractions
and not feel like you're talking
yourself into bat in order did show you
what I'm trying to get out here I wanna
work to an example and since this is the
advanced talk
I wanna work to an example that really
shows off the advanced capabilities of
our platforms
if you've never seen a text adventure
before
you never seen a text adventure before
the idea is pretty simple
US the pair are wandering around the
world solving puzzles and having
adventures
you interact with the game by typing in
commands had a
at at a terminal prompt and the game
responds back to you by interpreting
those commands
trying to carry them out and then
telling you what happens
so for example in the game you're going
to
I gonna be
wandering around exploring new look a
lot of new locations and
finding a bunch of new objects and when
you find an object you gonna be able to
you want to build a look at it and you
know try to interact with it and maybe
even
sort of tear things apart and really get
chaotic now
in this scene we've got a whole bunch of
different objects
that in our game we're gonna have to
like many model
one by one it's going to be a donde
taxed all these objects are going to be
a are going to be instances all-time in
the
love this thing class i think is a
it's really simple it's not anything
more than just a name and description
and the current location on the Argent
here's a couple love
really simple objects third that are
nothing more than just a name
and a description you can see you know
you were just calling the initializer
directly passing in a couple are
passing in a couple that are all values
when I have a ton of objects like this
scenery audits maybe 30 for the season
every single place in the game
added up over what could be a very large
game that means we're going to have
several
make several hundred these maybe even
thousands it's going to be really
important to me that
that this code and up looking very
compact that have been really convenient
to read and write
well it's already pretty compact
but these these keyword arguments these
argument names on twenty doing a whole
lot from I can actually tell Street of
what each one of these things are
because there's two different strings
that the name of an object the two
strings 113 short one man's body dawn it
doesn't take much for me to memorize
this
it being really great since I'm going to
be buying this over and over again if I
didn't have to have all this redundancy
so how do we go about
actually changing argument names well in
swift
these argument names come from
the decoration of the initializer by
default
these be premature names that we use in
initialize are also going to be the
argument names
but that's just the default we can
expand the syntax out bikes so
it's exactly equipment now I've got the
argument names specifically
right next to the parameter in
how do we actually make something
anonymous
well Swift has a very consistent syntax
for doing this
and set up giving it a real meaningful
identifiers
you just give it an underscore you can
use the syntax in a lot of different
places in the language
for example and this small up for new
I'm just iterating over all the entries
in the dictionary
but I'm actually care about the values
I just wanna print out all the keys I
could give this
I you know its own program its own local
variable name
but then if this were larger new I you
know
somebody coming along and weeding leader
would instinctively feel
wonder if I was actually using the the
value somewhere in the new
and they'd feel like any division the
search the entire time did
so instead I can just mean with an
underscore which is not a real variable
it just says
ignore this value
and that's not just an initialization I
can even a sign it as a sort of values
Inc so if i've a collar I can break it
down into its component
and into its color components but in
this case
I only care about the red and blue
components not the green in the Alpha
so I just assigned to the green Alfa
components to underscore
which just immediately drops them
going back to our initializer
I have all these argument names and if I
just moved to come
I'd end up back in that default state
where where the purpose which was using
the parameter names out the default
argument names
but if I want to drop them completely I
need to tell swept that I don't want
this and the way I do that as I name it
with an underscore this is just
a very simple way of telling swept I
don't want any argument names
just let me call this initializer
position
and so I get exact a much more compact
definite I get much more compact
definitions evolve my objects
this isn't something you necessarily
want to do all over the place
there's a lot of value from that I get
from keyword arguments
argument names usually provides a really
important semantic you
but in this case I'm thought about it
very carefully and decided that it's not
providing much value in about a
much rather have the compactness
art those were coupled simple objects
in a more complicated object I'm gonna
want to be able to give it
addition maybe even additional state
additional
I logic maybe make it respond to an
action
so for example going to back to the
original scene I had up I had seen
boards that were nailed up in front of
the door
I want these boards to be horrible so
I'm gonna
end up giving in its own subclass other
thing in class
well how do I actually make it possible
my game when the when the user who
writes types and pole boards
is gonna its gonna hand that string of
the parser which will break it down
and up find that find out the burbs poll
and
find and look around for object called
boards
take over from that pool part we
implement up
function that takes in an all resolved
object and implements the poll command
on
well how do we want to work at a high
level
if the object is possible we want to
pull it and otherwise we're gonna
print out some sort of error message
saying hey the you can't pull this thing
well that's a great use a protocol
we've talked about protocols are not and
other talks but
I wanna show you what a particle
actually looks like now you've probably
seen the San
you know meeting the entire book but
a protocol but he just looks like us on
a blueprint for a type
we aren't actually implementing any
other things and that you're just
describing what requirements are
actually there
are portable protocol is extremely
simple just has a
one method doesn't take any argument
doesn't return in
in order to adopt this protocol we just
go back to our boards class and either
extend it
or add horrible to the main
definition other on this case I V
decided added to the main definition
the compiler warns me straight off that
I
that I haven't actually fully
implemented this so I need to go out the
PLO method
which for my boards is going to be very
strict is very straightforward and
functionality
this check to see whether its tip
whether the boards are still on the wall
and they are you move them to the ground
in print a message
and then we'll just print an error
message if they're not so on the board
so that the use in
the player knows that they don't need to
care about these ob-
about these boards and im not gonna be
useful in the rest the game
now let's go back to are are performed
poll function
how do we actually check whether
something is possible
well that's very straightforward we can
just use a conditional cast
down to the protocol type this
conditional cast would give us a value
love a possible type which we can then
actually poll if it succeeds
and if it doesn't succeed with just a
friend up an error message
and that's great that's all we need to
do in order to implement the pope
now how do we now I'm gonna take a
little bit closer look
out this error message I'm gonna have a
lot of text like this in my game other
messages that need to work
applied would arbitrary object and this
isn't bad
this is this isn't this isn't awful
syntax minutes
it's not compact let natural there needs
to be because both .name
why can't I just put object in string
interpolation
here well I can Swift knows how to print
out an arbitrary object
however the rules like me swept will use
to print out an arbitrary object aren't
necessarily the most useful to faults
how do I actually take over this syntax
and hook into string interpolation to
actually do what I want
in general the way that you hook into it
for the language features like this and
swept
if they even implement a port protocol a
special protocol that the compiler
actually already knows about
for example I can use special built-in
protocols to
make my type be usable as a booty in
condition or to allow the user to
iterate over is enough or do or can even
take over one of the basic general
syntax is
when this example what I want is the
second one I want to implement
printable so that I can accede which is
how you
takeover string interpolation printable
is again a very simple protocol
it just has one be quite which is a
property
and all we have to do for that property
is implement is providing cover for
I could also provide a sub but I don't
have to this protocol to inquire
so in this case I'm gonna go back and
add an extension to thing that
implements printable
I have to provide the description
protocol and others haven't returned the
Name property
and that's it that's all I needed to do
well
is this we're going to work for an
arbitrary object
I mean if I look at this text here it
doesn't even read write to me as an
English speaker
because a object that's not good medical
when I come along and pole and tried to
pull something
that starts with the a bowel sounds for
that apparel or mass noun in English
you can't just put a in front of it I
need us to be able to work
for arbitrary thing which means I needed
and if I want us to feel natural to the
user
not so I don't take the player out there
experience I want us to be good
actually grammatical well
how do I actually do that
from a class design perspective I can
just to find a new
property on on team that's going to be
name with an article titled
so the right word from the vet that's
great this is a great
class design but it's not actually very
usable for me
if I wanted if I'm gonna have a ton
attacks printing out this thing
that's this is actually worse than just
object of name was so how can I do
better than this
well i really wanna stick something in
the string interpolation tubes or to
modify it
it be great if I could just write this
right and object right there
but that's not actually balance with
syntax
for not a very good reasons but I can't
sort of slight tweak this in a way that
feels very still feels very natural that
but still very readable
fine said Oprah just putting them next
to each other separating them with the
binary operator
this is a new binary operator that's not
currently defined language
so how do I go about actually adding
well the way you define a new operator
for you know
either taking an existing operator in
defining up for news other types
or actually adding a new operation
tirely
is unita global function and a global
the global function just takes for
binary operator just gonna take
two arguments one for the left hand side
and one for the right hand side
and just normal but global global
function with the kinda funky name
but sweat on actually let me do this
because it's actually chapin
checking up on me so it doesn't know how
to actually parson expression
that uses this is a binary operator I
need it elsewhere
the basic rules for for this out a
binary operator
in order to do that I just need to
provide an operator declaration
somewhere in my program
I could do in modern information up in
here in order to describe how to
how this operator associate with other
binary operators been this case I'm not
planning on actually using it
next to any other binary operators so
all that is unnecessary I can just have
a very simple decoration
now let's go back to this function
declaration the right hand side of this
we wanted to be a object what we want
the left hand side to be
remember this is the that this is the
syntax we actually want
to be able to write object here is just
an arbitrary expression that's going to
be
resolved in the open and local scope n
we need and is also going to be in
identifying needs to actually
resolved to something in scope but we
want this to be usable anywhere so this
has to be something that's actually
defined global scope
in the most natural thing to put a
global scope in this case would be
would just be a function by using the
function
and having it take the object that was
on the right hand side
I can make this syntax very very
naturally extend to any sort of
decorator that I want to stick on the on
the left hand side
I just happened to find a new global of
and new global function with that name
the in function which can implement by
using that name with Article property
that we already defined
with all that I can go back to my
operator function and the left hand side
of this is now going to be
a function value and the way that we can
implement this
is we're just gonna Cole function value
with the with the object that we will
pry provided on the right hand side
and that's it against me grade a great
new ATM for expressing that sorta
decorated interpolated string
this isn't something that would
necessarily want to use casually
but in my game its valuable enough to me
to make this easy to write that its
worth
forcing everybody used reading my code
to learn this new
eighty on a working one more example
I talked a lot about objects in the game
but I haven't talked about places
in the game we gonna be able to walk
around Byzantine
visiting new places and all those places
are going to be connected to other
places
by going east by going north by going
south
in our class system places just a
special kind of pain
that's gonna also have a dictionary that
describes all the exits out
when I'm defining on tax this is what
that's going to look like as a sort of
first
house but this is kinda syntactically
heavyweight
again I'm gonna have lots of places in
my game i buy custom look
really inconvenient and natural more
compact and this
well why do I have to write dot exits
here
isn't the exits dictionaries for dove an
implementation detail love
up my my place class
wouldn't be more natural I could just
directly subclan
directory subscription to a place in and
specify that work we're a particular
actually goes to
the way that you do that is with the
subscript declaration
a subscript declaration swept look feels
a lot like a property
use the subscript keyword and then you
give it
a parameter clause which is kind of like
which is going to be all the indexes
that
up to you are being used a subscript an
and then kind of like a function you
give it return
what feels like a return type that the
typeof
the other mint you subscribe to
well here's where r for strong more like
a property
yes provide a get and set method like
any other property
so to get is just wanted other day tax
its
and a set just writes back and accidents
all what all done here is provide is
provide a subscript
I A subscribe directly on place but just
immediately delegates down to the exits
for property but that's gonna let me
bite
bite this and a much more compact and
natural style over and over
I've been talking a lot about ways that
you can hook into the basic syntax swept
I do want to talk about little bit about
many should actually do this
using taking over basic syntax like this
developing new ATM's and developing
things that don't look
exactly like other things and swept can
be a little bit dangerous
non the sensor being dynamically unsafe
but in the sense a big your coat a lot
harder to understand
the key thing to do in this well as to
make it feel natural
think about how someone coming along in
reading your code later is gonna
understand its order intuitively think
about how what your syntax
actually suggests about what it actually
doing
a major part of that means not taking
existing syntax
and making it do something that doesn't
feel like what other instances about
syntax and doing
for example my subscript is just
supportive
providing a view I'll an aspect of a
place
you wouldn't want a subscript to do
something completely different
you could syntactically of course the
name but will let you use
subscript operators to do anything you
want you can
make it do calls you can make it take
all your methods
and implement and using subscript
methods but i wanna be
natural it wouldn't feel like
like you really ass accessing part of
the object in the way that the subscript
offered us
and that's when I'm making a major
obstacle to somebody trying to actually
understand
code and finally
it okay to add new idioms that everybody
who read your code is going to have to
learn
people coming into new code bases have
to do in New idioms anyway even if
they're just expressed using properties
and methods
but when you expressing new any when
you're inventing new ATM's using basic
syntax
its hasn't tweeted extra cost it's an
extruded
you know thing to learn that the program
needs and burned justed
understand even what your code is looks
like
doctor OK'd to do that's okay to expect
someone to do
if it's actually worthwhile make sure
that the syntax is paying for itself
that its worth somebody's time to have
actually learned it
and that the value you driving from it
actually pays for I've been talking a
lot about
about a very a
sorta superficial ways that you can
extend the language I'd like to bring up
Dave abraham's to talk about a much
deeper interesting topic
to generic programming thanks John
as everybody doing good
because we were a little concerned you
know with but
maybe after 3 deserve total immersion in
swift
you might be feeling a little uneasy
maybe a little jittery
even because you haven't seen one of
these in a while so I'm just gonna give
you a moment to sit with it
okay printed in okay because you won't
see another one before the into the talk
and we're gonna go to our first slide in
to one sorry
semicon lovers okay
so let me tell you a story about my
friend Christy christy is
all school programming in swift is like
his one concession to modernity and
he doesn't trust modern tools like ID's
or debuggers
no he likes to do but his swift code
by logging the console he was using
family of logging functions like this
now when initial
look at an interesting string value he
would text ring
and if you want to pick an interesting
in value would be ten
and so on but it turns out
every once in a while even all crusty
take the step into the future
and one day he strode into my office and
announced that he had rewritten
is walking to use overloading he said
he said to me dev
well swift takes a look at their
arguments on actually passenger figures
out which portion I wanna call
now I just always right peak
and leave of the type name now I have
used overloading before
so you know this wasn't a big deal for
me but it is kind of a big day when
christie changes
well anything so I was
didn't want to burst his bubble you know
I was about to say something encouraging
when you look over my shoulder and said
what in tarnation is that
and what I said he said
that leaving a smudge on my gorgeous
Retina display
well any well
any is the empty protocol type I told it
it's got no operations in it
but it can hold literally anything and
by the time I looked up crusty was going
on here run back to his office to
reimplemented logging functions
like this those Virginia peak
work great and it left room for more
code in the 18 by 24 terminal windows
that Christie favor
also
since everything in swift can be printed
peak
even work for some types that crusty had
never picked out before
so all was right with the world across
the was happy
that is at least until the dog house
showed up in his window title
now this was a problem because nothing
gets all crushed his dander up
like pesky modine as winter title so he
said
see he had written
this fancy extension on string adding a
computer property
so he could eliminate these MOT and he
carefully use this property
in its computation of the window title
Christie scratched his head in
thought about his next move figured
what I really need to do is to see if
the offending characters are there in
the original string
song gonna peek at that that some
expression now
normally he might have rewritten is code
like this: so breaking out the
expression of interest into a a named
constant peaking at that and then
carrying on with the computation
but across the benefits like this before
he was sick and tired ok reformatting is
code every time you wanted to do a
little debugging
work hot
across the I know what I'll do are
returning interesting value from peek
and then I'll be able to insert a call
to it right in the expression
which was an awesome idea except that
doesn't work
so you see
using any throws away the string this
up the argument so of course the
compiler doesn't know what's coming out
that peak function could be in
in this document controller delegate
where it could be an end or could be a
string
at the call so I
the compiler only sees that signature so
question knew that he could always
downcast
to string get a string back out of the
any
but if there's one thing I can say for
crusty
the man's gotta taste you know he cannot
tolerate
ugly code in this was starting to get
ugly that's when christie
dove into the sweep language guide and
discovered that the tiniest change could
make
all the difference what he did here was
turned peak
into a generic function now generic
function
is declared with a type parameter list
in angle brackets after the base
function name
in this case just one
T you can think up t as a placeholder
for any type when you run a function
this way
swift deduces what he is from the take
the actual argument you pass it's a lot
like figuring out which function to call
in an overload set
in the case above we pass a string
two peaks a peep returns a string that
string wrapped in any bud
goodall strength and it just worked
now we've seen to very different ways to
deal with
things a arbitrary type we could pass
them as
instances have a protocol type like any
or probable that John showed
which are racist type information
or we could pass them as generic have
parameters
we can let them buy into the can their
types by to the generic parameters of
generic functions
and that conserves type information now
there's nothing wrong with the racing
type information
when what you want is dynamic
polymorphism so you wanna make
collection a objects that are
all different all different types about
X and
you know that has to be dynamic at
runtime great
used high-pressure but when you don't
need dynamic polymorphism
there are some pretty compelling upsides
to conserving type information
so first when the compiler keeps track
what types you're actually using you
don't have to resort to
unsafe downcast like we saw in the
previous example
and you don't have to deal with the
possibility that those cast might fail
second when the compiler knows just what
types
you're dealing with you can generate
much better code
can generate code just for those types
and John will be talking more
when he comes back about how the
internal mechanisms
work with that
another reason to like conserving type
information
is that it allows us to express
relationships
among types consider this function
which comes with swept it just exchanges
to arbitrary values
here X&Y can have any type at all
as long as they have the same type
so for example student-teacher ratios
being what they are
might make sense to exchange the number
of students with the number teachers
but exchanging the name of your school
with the number of students
is nonsense
I love the way swift help to be right
correct code the first time
because that doesn't tolerate this kind
of stuff
no you can't do anything like this with
any or
what your similar thing and objective-c
like I D
because converting to these types throws
away the type information
it takes real generics which conserve
type information to get this right
okay let's look at a more interesting
example
here's a simple function that takes in a
razor array of strings
iterates through the indices near a day
looking for
index where there's a string that
matches a the one you passed
and if it finds the returns the index
otherwise it returns no
rights returning an optional
okay so let's generalize this
first we just find the country types
that we want to make variable
string and we replace those with generic
parameters
but that's not quite that simple
right know that he is no longer a known
type like string
the compiler is an entirely sure that we
can compare these two things with equal
equal
so let's fix that by constraining T
to be equitable
see the function secure picture already
impose one type constraint
that the typeof value match the element
type direct
equitable at another kinda tight
constraints for callers a fine value
and in exchange for constraining callers
now we have a new capability inside of
the body
which is to compare with the political
alright let's see how the quotable is
declared
of course equitable is a protocol
a blueprint for a type as John put it
now this one imposes a single
requirement that there's a new political
operator
if you're familiar with protocols in
objective-c
it may help to know that every single
objective c- protocol is also us with
protocol
however for protocol so have some
capabilities that objective-c protocols
don't
which makes them especially well suited
to generic program
case in point because switch in urs
conserve type information
they have access to the full type
implementing any protocol
here were saying that there must be an
equality operator that takes two
instances
have the type implementing equitable
know the some popular languages
implement what they call generics
with type a racer essentially any plus
downcast
and because these languages throw type
information away
there unable to express even something
as fundamental and basic as this
in their generic system but swift
handled it beautifully
right now let's quickly thank you very
much
now let's quickly make an acquittal type
in
so temperature here is just a little
rapper over in an
and there's a couple things to notice
first temperatures this truck
protocol adoption is available to struck
unions and classes not just classes as
in objective-c
second ball be satisfied its operate a
requirement
outside the type body and
thats sort of specific to operator
requirements
all other requirements you find
satisfying inside the tight body
or inside an extension
okay so you may be wondering well where
is not equal
well it's not a requirement we didn't
have to write it
because with provides this one it's a
generic
not equal that
depend on equitable and uses the
political operator
to implement it so that works for
every equitable type which is pretty
swift indeed
okay let's look at an example
love how we can use what we've seen so
far now I want to come up with a
really practical example something that
you know you would use in your
day-to-day cocoa programming so what
we're gonna be doing is computing fee
the golden mean which is these the
the ratio love consecutive Fibonacci
numbers as an
approaches infinity this slide warn you
that we were horrible nerds right okay
am so
first we need to compute the incident
watching number so
that's just the storm the previous two
for notching numbers
where the first two for the nineteen
numbers are 0&1
this is not the fastest way to compute
the Fibonacci numbers
but it is really hard to beat for
simplicity and mathematical purity and
elegance
really easy to verify that this does
exactly the right thing
and here's p
we need to go a few iterations right up
to about 45 so that we get enough
precision
with our estimate now running this part
of our program
take 11 seconds 11 seconds on a fast
machine
well it ceded to see why
if you look at the call graph so just
looking at them not you
5 that depends on to the not chief oren
three
and for the night you four depends on
for me not you
3 and two you can already start to see
the
repeated computations in here and if you
look at the entire call graph
where you can see there's a lot of
repetition now
expand this up 45 levels and you've got
a recipe for slow program
however
if we could just store our results in a
dictionary the first time we compute
them
when we could turn all these calls
into Facebook us right and these calls
well they would just disappear entirely
this technique
is called memorization and while from
NRG makes a great example for it because
it
you know recall same function over and
over you cannot
appliance to speed up any pure function
where you might be calling it over and
over with the same
set of arguments okay
went to manually mem was seven RG affect
first we need a dictionary
next we change the function body so that
did a checks the dictionary see if it's
got the result
and only computes the result if it isn't
found there now how does our function
perform okay
100 X speed up that's pretty good it's
one hundred times
more swift okay please forgive me
with him now
this is awesome but we kinda have
destroyed the readability
and mathematical purity of our function
I mean if you
look in there really hard you might be
able to find the original computation
among all that boilerplate up there it
is
okay it would be nice
if we can encapsulate all that road Co
transformation
so we can be easily memorized any
function without destroying its
readability
something like this well in swift
you can in fact
memo rises in a language it's just a
generic function I rode
and the code between the curly's
well that's a closure for an anonymous
function
being passed as an argument to memorize
with trailing close
syntax normalize returns
another closure and that's what we're
storing in for the Nazi
so feminazis just like a function you
know a regular function is just a
constant down to a closer
so
in fact you don't even need that type
annotation in this case because
Swiss type inference configured all out
for you
and now memorizes general
so when I discover that my app is
leading CPU cycles by
parsing the same property list strings
over and over again
I can go back and use memorize again
just like this
okay let me show you how this works
so this is the first cut memorization
function
a simple version alright yes I know have
a look that simple but
I'll take it apart for you so
it takes one parameter called body which
is a closure
I and the types the argument return type
so that closure arbitrary
except that there's this constraint
on the argument type that'd be hassle
why do we need that
well so we can use the argument type as
a key in a dictionary
I and returns the same type of closure
that I guess
okay inside the body this is
actually pretty straightforward so first
week
create the dictionary that we're going
to need to use to memorize that function
and then we return to closure which is
wrapped around
an indication that the body which is the
actual computation
right and the usual memorization dance
where we look in the dictionary and
return the value we found a profound and
otherwise computing put it in the
dictionary
thank now this first remember was works
great
for functions like parts property list
this just works which is awesome but for
per person functions like factorial or
for the Nike
well not so much
seats with doesn't want us to use
a use a variable own value
to initialize it like in initialize
itself in terms of itself that just
doesn't make sense
right it's usually a terrible
programming error
so what can we do to get out of this
well
we could do this two-phase
initialization deaths
here we've done is we've meet factorial
variable
and we've initialize it was something
throw away like the identity function
right dollar 0 in braces just returns
the argument gets
and then we reassign factorial to
memorize
okay this works but it's got a few
downsize first ball is ugly
so produce not gonna be happy with us
right
second of all we had to write out the
explicit type annotation an inherent
and that used to be to deuce for us
but most importantly of all mixed
factorial mutable
which we didn't intend and keeping
things immutable as often as possible is
a
you know is a great path toward
correctness and and easy to reason about
programs in all kinds of things
including food safety so
fortunately there's a better way
ready for take to I'm gonna warn you in
advance
that this is a little bit mind-blowing
okay
for months not already gone so let's
just have
memo rise past factorial
as an argument to it own body
right okay but stick with it to get
okay so if we can pass factorial in as
an argument to this body
then that factorial on the right well
that refers
just back to the function parameter is
just like referring to axe
see our closure has two parameters a
function
and axe are
so where we need do to make this happen
well first we need an additional
parameter
to body right you can see body is taking
now a new parameter
and that parameter has the same type as
were returning from Emma was
world lotsa Veros
everybody okay okay I'm sorry
next to get easy again
next we do the two-phase initialization
dance
so here you can't we can really get out
of the tube is initialization
problem but at least we can hide it
inside a memo it's
and tube is initialization said
scenarios like this one
are great application for implicitly
unwrapped optional
because but once you initialize the
thing
after that the thing can never been ill
so there's no point in going through all
that
syntactic baggage unwrapping it and in
this case
the impossibly unwrapped optional
unwraps when we return it is not
optional
right and because it dies at the end of
this
go well any scary possibilities the vid
being milled I along with it
so this is actually pretty elegant
now all that remains is to pass result
to
body when is invoked and there you have
it
a reusable tool that elegantly memorizes
even workers the functions
fell a point of course is not the you're
gonna go out memorize all your functions
but the you can do stuff like this since
worked you can
write your own modifying crazy language
extension type functions like this
and it's pretty cool so
being able to do this relied on the
synergy
love 3 powerful features first
tight deduction for concessions
so we would have contact and readable
code next
trailing closure syntax which evokes
control flow while
supporting functional programming idioms
and lastly
truly generic functions that are
flexible
say and fast okay
now wanna bring it back down and talk a
little bit about generic types
so you've already seen a bunch of
generic types yourself a raise in swift
are just
generic struck and so are our
dictionaries
and optional czar just generic unions in
a few
watch the other presentations I know
that was covered you can often make in
our classes and swept
let's make a generic struck so we'll
start
with a simple concrete structure
concrete stack of strings
it's got push in part methods in this
just implemented
in terms have been right now let's make
this into a staff have any type
we just do what we did with our generic
functions
when we made a concrete function generic
we took the country types and replace
them with the type parameter
and there you have it now I can make a
stack have
ins for stack up in its windows if I
like
so noticed that unlike with generic
functions
when you use a generic type you actually
supplied the the type argument six
possibly muster
time the functions the type arguments
are always two dues
now crusty probably want to be able to
log our stack
and he would probably right is one
function like this
but unfortunately that's not gonna work
it's not going to work because before in
syntax as john mentioned is governed by
this
sequence protocol and we have
implemented so let's take a look under
the hood
at how swift does foreign lives so when
you ride
a loop like this swift internally
rewrite your code
like this so what's happening here
first did first year sequence any calls
generate
to get a generator out next
repeatedly called the next function on
your generator
until it gets no so next returns an
optional
and those options are filled in with
values until the sequence runs out
okay so what is this generator thing
I'm sure you can guess it's a protocol
pain and the first thing you see in this
protocol
is this type alias now when you see a
type alias
in a protocol that's called and
associated type requirement pay
they can be satisfied just by writing
any nested type called element inside
your
your generator but why do we do this
well it's usually a type that involved
in 1 I've
the protocols other requirements in this
case next
you have to express that you know here's
a name for
a type that's going to come out next so
let's build a generator first at here's
the code
so it's just another
generic struck right conforms to
generator
and you can see that implements all the
necessary parts are up the blueprint
here now we've written a little bit more
here than we actually had to
see when the compiler matches up
that next requirement with this next
function
vacancy that the element type have to be
T
so that associated type is deduced
and we can just leave it out think it's
really convenient
the next thing I need to point out is
that we've used this
place type sis places a lot like a
reggae
thank you may come from a raised by
slicing the array using the syntax
the past arrange to the subscript
operator and
slice differs from Ray and that you can
efficiently dropped things off the front
of a slice
in for one-time so that's why we're
using it because we want to go forward
through the sequence
so we do first to check to see if the
place is empty
if it is we return 0 otherwise we get
the first item of the slice
replace the slice with the rest of the
elements
return and there's our complete
generator
but we're not done yet because we have
implemented sequence
writers the two protocol protocol
so sequence has a very similar structure
to their generator
the most notable difference is that its
associated type
is constrained here to be a generator
and that's how
Swift knows that it can call next on the
thing that gets outta
generate
affect so let's implement sequence for
our stack
there it is notice first that I've done
the entire implementation inside an
extension
is dedicated to that protocol and this
is a really slick with a partition your
code
especially if you have a lot of protocol
conformance is
and that's going to be pretty common in
swept in a lot of ways
swift as a protocol based language
next I want you noticed that I haven't
given the
Associated type explicitly right because
to do so from
the signature of dysfunction which
returns a stack generator which is the
thing we just
created
lastly I want to point out that there
are some circumstances where you don't
even need to write the type parameters
on a generic type in this case returning
stack generator
and I haven't written the T in angle
brackets
that's because the type contacts the
fact that we're returning
Aztec generator T allows the compared to
deduce what type that is
okay and now we can finally loop over
the onus for stack and christy is happy
again
okay there is a lot
more I could tell you about american
swept I know this is pretty intense
so we're gonna stop here I wish we had
time
to cover the collection protocols index
protocol protocol refinement
how to build lazy functional adapters
like we have like map
filter and reversed like we have in the
standard library
but you know you can find all that stuff
if you dig into the
documentation if you remember only three
things about this part of the talk
let it be these first protocols are will
let you put it into the basic
core language features like four and
string interpolation
second generics offer new dimension
speed expressivity and safety
from people coming from objective-c you
can do really
totally new things and lastly Swift is
fun
encourage you to dig into these to these
capabilities and find out as much as you
can
experiment play around
okay now I'm gonna bring up John to
close the talk
he's going to tell you a bit about the
us with model
we've talked a lot about what you can do
in sweat and I want to tie it up
by talking about house with actually
works in a couple
quick ways likes
be objective C&C plus plus swifter the
statically compiled language with
relatively small runtime:
thats not a coincidence and it's not
because we were forced into it anyway
we actually believe very very strongly
in this model a programming language is
other great model for you its it pretty
flexible
it's really predictable in 20 efficient
its flexible because the thousand really
simple interoperation
you don't have to write everything and
swept
or runtime requirements are are so small
that we can just
transparently interact with your
existing see
objective-c assembly
ada so on
don't wear your coordinator
and all that makes it pretty straight
forward to deploy
or deploy swift to Virgin's abiola's
and OS 10 they don't even know anything
about the language that were developed
without swift in mind
soup is a pretty predictable model
because it leaves you fully in charge of
the code
actually going to run on new users
devices
the compiler is going to be even on a
complicated magic making generics work
optimizing this and that
and so on but when all that is done when
all that settles
you see exactly what's left and you can
feel confident that
that that in hell that's actually going
to run
on the device there are no Akshay just
in time confirmation steps where all the
pretty interesting optimizations are
implemented
there's no nondeterministic places and
where'd I could
secondary thread is pausing your entire
application the garbage collector
right in the middle of the user
operation you can understand your code
exactly how is compiled in exactly the
result and
and feel confident exactly how it's
going
and finally it's really efficient
thrift generate native code Needham
could that's ready to run
as soon as you put it on a device there
are no
be compensation or warm up today's wild
while you're out launches you're free to
organize all your high level code
and swept into cleaning easy to maintain
abstractions using powerful things like
tin eric's
and because it's all statically compiled
an abstraction disappears
immediately during compensation not
nader win that shit actually kicks in
and you and
know is it all down to nothing hopefully
and the predictability population means
that you can really feel confident
exactly what's going to
fun after all this is done so you can
feel confident that you're really tight
efficient no level code
will always do exactly what you expect
I want to talk a little bit about the
swift compiler architecture
the way that we accomplish this is very
very similar to how
these claiming C compiler restructured
with one
major modification
we add an extra step an extra phase a
compilation
for high-level analysis and optimization
this is he said language specific
analyses things that we know specially
about swift and its by Barry
allows us to do very high level
manipulations and produce really great
coach trade-off
on a talk about three of those in
particular
the first one but i wanna talk about
obstruction
these suppose that you're writing an
application
and it's got alt in it talking to a
whole bunch of sensors
know how much different subsystems and
some of those a giving you value
yeah values back in someone kinda unit
and some other McGivney doubtfire
back in a different kind of unit and you
really important to you that you're not
ap not burn up when entries when it be
enters the martian atmosphere
you can use the type system and swept to
do this strikes have
0 added runtime: obstruction cost fifty
designed
swept from ground up to dominate this
kind of obstruction cost transparently
in fact in swift even basic fundamental
I very types like
int inflows are actually implemented as
left as
struck types wrapping even more
fundamental LVM types
see you can feel very very confident
that we've done and an extraordinary
amount of work to make sure that these
things don't add any action
actor overhead
the second thing I want to talk about is
generic specialization
some languages implement generics by
immediately
expanding out your code whenever you use
it with a different other genera cards
now generates very very fast code for
this particular
expansion because it means that you that
bike
the code generator never even sees the
concept
a generic function but unfortunately
their couple downsides to this its
terrible for the bug bug bill times and
into
generating a ton of code that the
compiler and the nature and everything
else need to conspire together to try to
hide
runtime: and also steals a lot of
flexibility from the compiler to
actually unify these things
so in swift generic specialization is an
optimization
it's something that we can we can do but
we also maintain the ability to run
generic code
as generic code
the last thing I want to talk about this
diversion is Asian
the virtualization is an incredibly
important optimization and sweat because
so much in your code is written about
classes
win it's an it's very very important for
us to be able to take something very
simple
very lightweight like a getter and
turned out into direct manipulation
member they're not away so we can do the
virtualization
and swept weekend we can see when where
you actually constructing the object
we can do hierarchy analysis to see
their craft doesn't have any subclasses
but you can also text take control this
manually by marking methods and classes
final in order to tell us with that
doesn't have to worry about the
possibility for being overwritten where
they're not about a high-level
optimizations I really wish that I had
the time to talk to you but I'm
actually already two minutes overtime