morning
session 406 integrating swept for the
objective-c
now many of us with demos here at the
conference start by creating either a
brand new project from want to expose
project templates
or a playground and that's great
playgrounds are a great way to explore
this with language
but many have you already have Mac or
Iowa saps
and some areas but years writing
objective-c code
here written a carefully you're the bug
bit
polished it optimize it is just perfect
from and we certainly don't want you to
have to
through any better way or rewrite
anything that you don't want to
also someone you had really a lot of
objective-c code that shouldn't may be
spent a decade writing and maybe it's
not so perfect it's not not as clean and
shiny
so on you we're gonna be using
objective-c code for
a while you might want to rewrite its
but it's not gonna happen this time
around because you're gonna have to ship
et cetera so objective-c is not going
away
boats with an objective-c our first
class citizens
for doing cocoa and Cocoa Touch
development and in fact
we don't want to to spend any time that
you don't have to win when you stop
refining objective-c code we want you to
be able to integrate swift
as you want to and we do think that as
you implement new features
as you finally get around to replacing
crafty
subsystems that you want to use with for
that because if it's better
a type safety its expressiveness
its performance now
many viewers also gained a lot of
knowledge and experience
thing cocoa and Cocoa Touch two years
objective-c development and
that applies a swift as well you use the
same frameworks
the same classes the same API's with
some syntactic differences
in fact the same design patterns such as
delegation
all that knowledge applies and so we
expect that a lot of view
are going to end up with projects that
contain both
swift and objective-c and we worked hard
to make sure that Xcode lets you freely
mix with an objective-c
so this session over the next hour we're
gonna be talking to a bit more
detail than what you've probably seen so
far about exactly how that works in
practice
we're gonna start simple by just
introducing some sweat code into an
exact
existing objective-c ap they will get a
little more interesting we're gonna
start to add some swift code to a model
level framework
which had is then embedded in
objective-c ap thank all that project to
see
will talk about how to start accessing a
pure swift framework
which there'll probably be start showing
up up from an objective-c ap
and then we'll talk as we go along about
how to adopt some other commonwealths
tablished coca patterns
been swept and again Swift is designed
from the ground up to be a great cocoa
Cocoa Touch
development language and so it has
language support
for some other Coco idioms that we got
used to it so I could go on here for
you know two dozen slides and talk in
detail about how this works but
a rather just get a demo because that's
a usually been more clear
alright
so got a project here
that some Sep I was ap
and it has a better framework so it's
decently design here it's gotta
the top layer which is the actual app
with the view and controller layer
and our NBC design there is area
framework all mister kit down here which
contains our model objects and all this
is currently written in objective-c
just get a sense of what this is
let's go to run in the simulator and
gonna go ahead here and bring up the
simulator
we see that yet so typical is taking
application that can go and
have color list here I can check off
items at cetera
edit them when I can't do right now is
to add
a new list this happens to be and I
cloud app so I could do that in my Mac
happen it would show up here but for
this example we're going to use with to
add the ability to add a new list
in pilots facts I'm gonna back here
and %uh the first thing I'm gonna do is
looked out here to the group you
controllers
and here we have some %uh view
controllers already written
and objective-c kind Jake objective-c I
go to File
credit file and in this case I was gonna
create an mp3 file cuz I wanna show you
how to get started from scratch
Xcode has great file templates and can
fill an order code for you
we wanna do it on a basic way here show
how it's going to work
I'm gonna call it new list controller
and I'm gonna make sure that it is I
gonna coen go into the application
target here
we also see that I have mister kit which
is my framework and what are the new
extensions here for showing India
a the status of your so news controller
now as I create this my first with file
in a cure objective-c project expo will
offer to create for me was called the
bridging header
so abridging header we'll talk about
that more detail later
but basically what it is is a way for
you to expose some with your objective
c-
API's to swept
gonna go ahead and create that so I get
that by default
now import foundation actually I'm gonna
be needing some you like it
if you're here so I go ahead and change
that you like it
and I know that I will need to import my
own model framework because we wanna
obviously crater model objects from
within
that you control and I'm just gonna go
ahead here and say
new list controller
and now when I complete we see that
because I said import
you like it there swift balls in the
objective-c framework you like it
and gives me a swift you all those
symbols
something a subclass from your
controller and just leave it like that
for now
so we are just a basic empty class this
with class subclassing in Objective C
Class
that we get from you I from Cocoa Touch
now we could sit here and I got
rectangles and create an API
credit you I for this but fortunately it
happened already have one
I how lucky it isn't wired up though so
we're gonna do that right now
the first thing gonna do here is just
like with objective-c
I need to set what the class above your
controllers
sign up here and now we see that the new
list controller that I just created
is shown here among all the ones
implement an objective-c so when you
access your classes from sweat from
Interface Builder the swift Objective C
Class A show up next to each other you
can work with them
as equals alright so now the next thing
I want to do after setting that
I'm gonna go ahead and create a bar
button item here
gonna drag that up into the toolbar up
here
and I'm gonna change said in a fire to
be
added that also changes the visual
appearance to give it a standard Cocoa
Touch
Add button block all credits segue
it's gonna be a mobile segue this is
after all storyboard
and or change the name that segue to be
new list
now that's gonna the important a bit
later on so that we can access it from
within our cut
okay so now you may have seen and what
are the other demos how we can drag from
swift code and connector objects
inside as I P we can do the same thing
the other direction as well
if I option click here on my swift class
my view controller class implement in
swift now I can drag the other direction
for sale gonna do is I'm gonna go ahead
and dragged from outlets
and and certainly outlet here and I'm
going to call this
name feel and we see that the UN text
field
and a storage is weak because we have a
controller class
two superb you are the view our key owns
the button and the name in the fields
and the buttons
in here and so we just won a weak
reference to it
and in fact for me insert this
Interface Builder knows it is what file
so uses the swift syntax
just as it would have for objective-c
and uses the ID outlet property
for the stored property a sorry the idea
of what attribute for the stored
property here
and this is implicitly week and also
optional
because not all the outlets may be
connected
get myself some space there gonna go
ahead and do the same thing
here for the buttons I'm just gonna
control drag these and just gonna
Phillies and the same way now this is a
sample app
Megan just the space heater this is a
and so it's not risk able to just have
sex partners and six outlets but
I know that your design better a make
more maintainable code and this
this is for illustrative purposes only I
you might want something I where you can
load colors from a table you
from a popular Stern Show the minute
able to you or something like that
I'm gonna go ahead and finish connecting
these
alright so now we have our outlets to
the UI components
can also create actions in this way if I
choose the cancel button down here and I
drag n
that I can create an action up at the
top here just for as for objective-c
a change the connection type 2 action
I'll take a council
and we can just leave the typeof the
center as any object here we don't
actually
care because we're not going to be
messaging app
what we will do however is to invoke
some Cocoa Touch API
give myself some more room and i cant
say so
dismiss and then code completion gives
me access to
the Cocoa Touch API that we already know
I can complete here
I'm not gonna need hey I wanted to be
animated site but true
I don't need a completion blocks I get
it now now
in objective-c we always have to message
cell if we want to talk to self
Swift knows from context when you are
messaging yourself
so we can actually leave this out make
this a bit more readable
excellence alright so now we will
connect the buttons here as well
and I'm going to be calling this pic
color
now in this case i jus you I button
I'm sorry I may need to make an outlook
an action
archer's you I button down here because
in this case we will actually want to
talk to the button or compare the button
a so we want to have that type and as
you can see
Interface Builder generate the code and
makes the center be a white button
before forget I'm also going to wire up
the other
actions here as well you see here
to connect to this one
for myself will be dispersed there
and now they're all wired up to the same
action for all wired up to the same
action the center will be different
depending on which button we touch
now I wanna show the summer the power of
the swift SELECT statement here
had a switch statement unlike
objective-c rather see based languages
I can actually switch on I a wide
variety of different kinds of patterns
in this case I'm just switching out what
the sundress
but this is a very rich constructs
and this win this with language and I
encourage you to catch one of the later
talks about advance weft to the really
get into the depths of
what you can use this for for right now
to keep it simple I'm just going to use
it to match on a button and what I will
say is
okay now I need to assign something here
so I'm gonna need to have a store
property
credits toward property called selected
label
because we're actually choosing labels
here represented as colors on the screen
and then what I can do here as I can say
this is an AAPL
list label so this again is an
objective-c
type that has been imported
through my import a blister kept up
there I'm gonna start out by saying that
that is an AP list label
stack great that's the default value
other
because I don't put a question mark I
don't make it optional that means that
it has to have a value
remember the ID outlets are implicitly
optional now
it's kinda early to have to repeat the
same thing here and in fact Swift has
great support for type inference
and what it knows exactly what type you
mean then you can go ahead and leave out
the type so from this
swift can tell exactly that okay this
has to be a catalyst label
because that I'm initializing it so I
can just play about the type now I can
complete my
statement he recounts a selected label
it was dark grey and in fact
I can address them here as well very
fast typer
now we see here that objective-c
I mean sorry Xcode swept has a message
for us here
so in swift a 10 things to notices
each other cases is impossibly ended
at the beginning the next case see don't
have the cases see where you can
possibly fall through and that's a
source of a lot of parts
in fact switch with the clothes
explicitly designed to avoid many of the
common pitfalls
that are common in sea bass languages
now in this case
another thing about the switch statement
is that it has to be exhaustive you have
to say that you cover all the cases
in this particular case I'm just gonna
add the fault
and what I'm gonna do in this case right
here is to use a swift standard library
function to just wrapping to the
debugger
because I wanna make sure that if I add
new buttons and help them up that I
actually have the code for that as well
so the record is happy
that excellent we just set a property
that's all we've done so far
but now we can use some more love the
Cocoa Touch
API to actually make the button schorr
elected state
show its absolute that state I should
say so
we say I this case we can say sender
dot and then we can use our code
completion to access the layer
and then it will set its border with to
be
fart and of course we have to initialize
that to be a border color
as well now in this case because we're
accessing the layer
that's a core graphics API we get the CG
color from
the UI layer you eye color and all these
are standard Cocoa Touch
API so you see that when we access our
own objective-c API's
for the couple touch API's it looks all
the same we still use the same nice
sweat syntax I don't think we can do
here is just say that the views
a tent color is going to be the color
that corresponds to the label
have for this we can call another one of
our
functions that we brought in from
objective-c
and we pass it the
selected label benefactor for command
click on this
we see here that we can get to a Swiffer
presentation
above our own Objective C API and
navigate we could actually go back to
the header itself
that we declared from alright so now
those are you are following closely here
made simple but a problem we set the
border with 25
whenever actually diesel like two
previous but so we can do is to keep
track
the currently selected button and in
this case
I'm going to explicitly say that it's a
week store property
so this is not gonna cause I the extend
the lifetime of that button
which is after all owned by the view
hierarchy and
I'm going to declare that this is a UI
button but its optional
because when we first start out it has
no value
and so we're gonna be able to check
weather has a value or not
we had some code
to set the selected but to the sander
at the end up having assigned it and
then here we can say
if Select button then
we're gonna go ahead and clear out the
border on that one now
this happens to be a object reference I
could do the same in objective-c with no
value
the one on the nice things about
optional since worked is that they apply
to any tax value
even a boolean or a scaler so in this
particular case
I'm just gonna go ahead and set the
selected buttons layer
border with 20 now you'll notice the the
exclamation mark there this is the
unwrapping operator and that says that
if I have an optional value
then when I determine it has a value I
get at the actual value
and if I forgot to check whether has a
value that will cause a trap if it
doesn't
so this is one other ways a swift makes
it safer
to to write raps because you can catch
these areas earlier
without having to add a lot of
assertions your cut so I think we're
probably good to go here
I'll was going to take a look and
sure forgot something sour Selected
button
and that's because I mistyped so that
shows that this is live right I'm not
play in Quicktime reappear
okay it's an hour here we have our ad
button
to bring up a model she as we select
the various buttons we can see that we
have the border and then we do that
tense attempt the buttons down here and
of course
the Save button doesn't yet work now I
just do you like I so I just by just
make it look pretty but actually do the
model level work we're gonna ask I want
my colleagues to come up at the moment
first let's take a look at what we did
and
this part okay
so
when we just do so first of all we added
some swift code
to an objective-c ap and Xcode offer to
create as a bridging header
which tracks actually going to some more
detail about with some plastic ok a
class
Kolkata class and swept in this case it
happened to be a quick touch class
that's part of the standard libraries
this up Kat touch itself but it could
also be one of your objective see crisis
that you've declared
we use with class in Interface Builder
and as I hope you saw
it's exactly like working with Objective
C Class that's actually if a mother here
that we wanted to feel like yeah
exactly the same thing it's
interchangeable and so now
to I make this a bit more real in terms
of the model
I'm gonna ask my colleague dave to come
up and complete the project airport
work on a further
art think Sounders a what we saw
I is that you have access to everything
in Cocoa Touch and the power that you've
got an Xcode
from swift without really doing anything
but I'm sure what you thinking now is
what about my code what about the
objective-c code that I have in my
target
in my app and that's what I want to show
you as ender said
we could spend a lot of time and slides
and everything else in I'm actually
kinda love shorter than he did
and just go straight into a demo and so
we come back right where we were before
and for our purposes the person you want
to do here is a little bit of tidy up
and that is to make are you i text field
behave the way that we want
for our User I it offers a great deal
with configurability
I using the delicate pattern and to do
that
are we're going to make new s controller
conform to you i text field
delegate which is easy
as if I could type
fine being are you i text feel man
I'm having some time here
it's a comedy show I promise
there you go alright something call out
there
is success
met the hardest thing I'm going to do
the whole time I'm up here
not so you i text field delegate all we
did here was
at add the protocol conformance to the
end of a comma-separated list
after our class hi in our case it's
important because we're actually
not we actually have a superclass that
the superclass is the first thing
in that last and then our protocols
follow now that I house I
managed to declare takes a delegate I'm
actually gonna take it easy for the next
part
and just bring in the implementation
text field should return
the only thing we're doing here is
resigning first responder
on a text field and returning to make
sure the keyboard dismisses when the
user hits return
I'll not particularly interesting
fun it was just as easy as it would be
an objective-c
to go ahead and implement this protocol
next
as under strongest we are going to look
a little bit more
at the interaction with the model side
of things
and actually implement save first thing
I'm going to do in
got the air here somebody knows what I
forgot to do
and that is managed to the clear to the
UI text field I get but we never
actually
connected Matt would have made for an
interesting and now we've got
that set up I will control drag over
manage hit the button set it up as an
action
college say now
insight here I actually want to interact
with
a the representation
are documents that we see in the
document list
on the main screen and that's a part of
our ap target
not a party with your kids and because
of that we have to take a different
approach we can just simply
import our framework and and this is
where we make use of the object to see
bridging Hatter
that Xcode offered to create for us when
we created the first with file
in this project so will navigate over to
that
and it gets created in the same
directory
are in the same group I should say as
this will probably created its
not overly interesting at first it
simply has a comment that's
very instructive this is where we put me
imports
for the classes in our target that we
want to expose to swept
in our case it's a single class and that
is are
list info class this is the
representation that backs
view to the table view that you see when
the app initially comes up
save my and
head back to really don't need the
storyboard anymore
so I'm gonna go ahead and collapsed
things down
and let us actually focus on the coaches
the wrapping really kinda
gets on my nerves when things I like
about slip Swift is it a little more
succinct
so just heading back down to our Save
now that we've pulled in the bridging
Hatter her
now that we've added our class the
bridging header we can actually create
one
I'm gonna create it as let because it's
going to be counseling in a sign at once
and so my list info
is equal wished
info
and of course keeps saying list info
like reinstruct you guys to do when
reading object Seco we actually use a
prefix
and I've been writing about us with good
lately so it's not on the forefront of
my mind so
our list info and it offers us two
constructors
one of them takes URL the other takes in
in this meta data item for that I cloud
support we're talking about
Realty you are on I could construct the
URL right here
little bit aforethought thinking forward
I know that I'm actually going to want
to
revise this a little bit later and
iterate on it so I'm gonna set up
a computed property as a convenience
after the car computer property
is pretty similar to the way we do
define
a stored property and
movie with a far I'm gonna call file URL
now with the computer property we do
have to be
explicit about our type I'm going to
make it optional
and that's because if the user actions
and providers a value in that actually a
I can't control I can actually construct
a valid URL
I've got an implementation ready that
just happens to
make use of the list coordinator from
down in which to get
and after defining the computed property
I can come down and make you submit
right away and unnoticed as Anders and
mention earlier
we don't actually have to explicitly
refer to self when accessing our
property
set up a few pieces of information that
we've captured for the user
so you get the name from our name
feel its text
and the label
is going to be equal to you are selected
label
and that looks good
so now we set it up we actually want to
save this out
and list info provides us a convenience
for that and we will
Creek a and say with completion handler
this completion and was actually I
called is gonna come back to us
with a ball letting us know whether or
not the same was successful
and I could use what code completion
suggesting here
and fill out Maya completion handler
closure
inside the parentheses but because it's
the last
I argument at
in the call and because its closure in
skimpy little long
I'm actually make use up Swiss trailing
closure cent tax
and in this case I don't even have to
put the forensic after the method call
because are up create and say with
completion and we're actually doesn't
take any other
arguments so inside here
I will note the variable names being
passed inches success
have more typing problem so that you
guys can get a good laugh
and I just checked the value and for now
I'm going to
print a little debug message to let me
know that it was saved
and
just like cancel we want to get out of
the user's way now so we'll go ahead and
dismiss
so
let's be building Ron see that
everything is doing what we want to do
make sure everything is on a
good to go bring it up
up RC I need to go to the hardware store
a little later
I and shown the more with hardware hit
return
keyboard goes away that's good time up
hardware store I frequent actually uses
orange in the logo rather have a week so
that's going to help me remember what's
going on there
an overhead hit Save button knots
not really what we've wanted I really
wanna see my hardware will show up here
did actually save go over check the
debug console
indeed it did save
and just for fun actually stop
and run the app again and you'll see
that it actually did saving it created
but we never passed anything back to our
document list
to you let know that we created anything
new and
what kinda wanted this to not be sitting
there in polling the filesystem
over and over and over again just
looking for new files that might show up
so for our purposes we're going to take
a page outta you i text fields book
and erection use delegation to pass
information back to the view controller
the presented us
the first step there is usually to
define
a protocol that we expect our delegate
to conform to
and in swift we can do that
just as easily as declaring the class or
struct or anything else
will just start with the protocol
keyword
that I actually spoke color correctly
and new this controller delegate
and Rd have a method
that I want my delegate to conform to
that I've prepared that just
takes a new s controller analyst info
wedding at No
what's been created done over here now
at this point this protocol is visible
too much with co but i wanna make sure
that my object seeker can see it as well
to do that it's a simple
as adding attributes
at obj see and this is gonna go ahead
and say even though this is all swift
here
we do want to make this available to
objective-c
a little bit later on to know that I
have a delegate protocol
actually define a delegate
and will make it we care because
we don't really want to own it we don't
extend its life time
and I can declare it as
being just above the newest control a
delegate type
I don't have to do something like I D E
an angle brackets around my protocol to
indicate what's going on here
I can simply have a property that is %uh
this delegate type
it's gonna be optional because I may not
have Adelia
snow we've defined a delegate property
thing maybe we ought to do something a
little more useful than printing a debug
statement down here
after that we're going to reach out to
our delegate
and I make use I'll
another swift feature which is optional
chaining
so the delegate is an option of it may
or may not have a value
by adding a question mark here before
actually calling out to you
the method that we want to invoke I'm
going to be able to say
if I have a delegate if there is a value
their
make this call if there's not
don't do anything
and now I'm trying to remember what the
name of that was out there we are
past myself and
the list info that we just created
really not much but I pissed in case you
can't tell
and at this point we wrapped up the
swift implementation
have this but we've defined as delegate
now we actually need our objective Seco
to be able to see the swift code we've
just put together
and interact with it to do that I'm
going to head back over to the document
the the controller for the document list
and inside here
we're brunt to give me what comes to
your mind
is the fact that the way I make one
object an object see
available invisible to another object is
by importing its header
wall was swift we don't have headers
I we think that's a good thing within
swift we've gotta find a way to
your bridge the gap back to you
objective-c
and so in that case Xcode got her back
and
is going to provide us with 8 generated
header
that contains the entirety of our swift
interface
being generated obviously it has to have
a well constructed a
naming scheme and that's going to be our
product name
which in this case is Worcester dash
swift dot H
and so this is the generated header some
gonna go ahead and take time to build to
make sure we get the most up-to-date
items in it I and after importing
that we will
come over here and we're gonna go
through basically the same process that
you would
ordinarily to implement any of the coke
or Cocoa Touch delegates
on your own clash out our protocol
conformance
and we can pull in our newest control a
delegate
I'm going to choose to
use the jump are to head down to an
appropriate place I feel too I go ahead
and implement this
and as I could complete here
with the newest controller did create
list info you'll notice that
even though we declare this completely
in with within swift
we get is a syntax
that matches what I'd expect from
objective-c so that everything still
feels natural everything feels like a
first-class citizen
in its place
happen to have the implementation
where a or the implementation the last
thing
ready hi in this case what we're really
doing is just updating our data sources
and then refreshing the table view with
a little bit a new information
and the very last thing here
the final stop is that we actually need
this view controller to
make itself the delegate for a new US
Comptroller
we're using a modal segue
so why not do it and prepare for Segway
down here will just check
to make sure that it's the right segue
will grab the newest controller
and we'll set ourselves in this case are
with documents you controller
as the delegate this point I fully
expect things
to do
what I want
and coming up with another list
to be every CE
morass have apps
not really sure what those are yet but
I'm pretty sure I'm gonna pick something
up
and this time
it actually comes through shows up in
our document view controller
just for you know groups say I come into
it I can change it around
I really like the salmon color that
they're using for the Apple badges this
year so I'm gonna actually picked that
and that sa
integrating our code
and just to head back to the slides for
a second
what we've just seen here
is that it's very easy to expose our
objective c- code
to swept simply import whatever headers
you want into the bridging Hatter
and will be made available to the swift
in your target we define a protocol in
swift
which was as easy as defining a protocol
in objective-c
finally we've
exposed that protocol and the class that
we just created
in swift back to the objective-c code in
our target and
we actually have to do anything there
Xcode did
the generation of the header the
provided that interface
just to reiterate
little bit more win we wanna go from
our objective c- hatter's and make our
objective c-
objects available swift we're going
through the bridging Hatter
this is going to be creative actual
offer to create this for you
automatically
when you at it's with file to an
existing objective-c target
for an objective-c file to an existing
swift target
when we want to
get our swift interface
exposed to our object see implementation
there we're looking at the generated
header the tax code provides
and this is going to be named after our
product and it's going to be
our product name bash swift dot H one
last thing to remember about these
is
that the bridging Hatter
is created for you by Xcode but you own
it
from that point forward so it should be
something you check in your source
control system
it should be something that
you maintain you manage and it's there
so that you only exposed to Swift what
you want to expose to swept
in the case to the generated header it's
just packets generated as part of the
build process
it's going to contain your compy the
complete interface
for thus with files within your target
and those you can be readily available
to check to see simply by importing Mad
Hatter
so this point to talk with you a little
bit more
about what you can do with frameworks
in your product in your project I like
him but my colleague Jordan up
think they've alright
so we see no UV it is to deal with
integrating your swift code
into an existing object if the app and
it could pretty much take care of all
the details for you to tell one
Interface Builder it going to show up in
the simulator
everything works just fine but I can
move a step down in the hierarchy
and like the framework
so at this point we've been working
pretty much the entire time up in this
twister part of the application
which the actual application target now
we're gonna move down to
lift ticket which handles the model and
the object graph for this target
and specifically we're going to add new
functionality the ability to add
attachment to every but i dont something
like
a a photo or a voice recording
to do this in Objective C you would
create a new class added to your object
graph by adding new property
and in setting up an interface to manage
it we're going to do the exact same
thing
but using swept property are by going to
file
new file and this time a tease the Cocoa
Touch clap template
I can name that APL with Diane
attachment pump at the Venice object and
the language support
is swept and make sure that in the lift
ticket target
and click Create you noted here that
Xcode did not
offer to create a breeding better for us
this is because we're working with a
framework target in a framework you
already have a header that backed by the
entire content on the framework
that's your umbrella hat er so when
you're working with a free market are
getting
swept everything that's available in
your umbrella hat er
what automatically be visible to the
swift code no work required
311 a taxonomic superset
to the very first thing I'm going to do
it at a compartment to
a standard Cocoa Touch protocol and its
coding attachments are made up of two
things their data
which I will represent anything in its
data and their type
for tight update at Cocoa Touch like to
you
uniform type identifiers which are very
general way to represent filing data
type and these are just
start at strength the next thing to do
here to declare and initialize there
and that just take the data anti prom
outside
and will I find them into our own field
but we do need to be careful
because the data that we are given might
be in and it's mutable data
and somebody might try to change it
after they've created our attachment
so in order to work around it we need to
call the copy method
however copy returned ID and objected
the
and swept that's going to come through
as be any object type
we can't go directly from any object and
at the day that
in swept because that's not guaranteed
to be day so instead we have to
explicitly tell the compiler
to do a cat here and this is important
because anybody ever implement the copy
method incorrectly
and doesn't return and if they're we
would much rather find out about it
right here in the initial either then
crashed somewhere down the line we try
to you that
on the other hand we can just to find
the type directly
and this is because touring in swept
r-value
unlike in a string every fourth string
has an independent existence
and when you find across the vehicle
operator you get independent string
so whenever somebody dead over here to
there string want to pack your string
over here the next inning to implement
the end up cutting protocol
because this for a bit more room and
here we can code
that complete here Naoko completion
of them
so I here I'm in it I'm implementing the
end it's colder than it
initializer and another something a
little funny here
Anna in objective-c we have the method
named in it with coder but in swift we
have an initializer
that's it in it coder so in order for
more consistency in the
Westworld where object recent contact
with a little different
and in it method from objective-c that
starts with in knitwear
will come into swept with the with
dropped
this ensures a consistent world with
objective-c security implementation that
it's pretty much the same as what you'd
expect
just called the code object for key and
again explicitly down capping to the
type we want
if somebody hands off the bat archive
will find out about it now
rather than crashing later on finally
polite thing to do here
is implement the in code with cutter
method and
this one does not get any name changes
because that is limited
specifically to initialize urs and
implementation this again is very simple
we call in code object 40 with both the
data
and the type and that's it this is an
entire
with model object and get on one flied I
didn't do anything crazy are confusing
here
be on them and I think you need to do to
be a good Cocoa Touch they defend
way the next step up quite the
added into our object graph I go back to
our objective the header
now ever been a problem because last
time that we want to act sex swift code
from objected
see what we did import generated header
into the Pride into the
objected to the file we can't do that
here because the generated header
depends on the swept and the swept read
the entire public content of our
framework by the umbrella header
and that includes this header right here
so instead
I you think that with a mechanism that I
have an objective feet this is what we
used to break cycle
if they forward declaration using
Acrobat and I can forward acquire the
first class just like I would any
objective c-class and now
I am perfectly able to create a property
here using the attachment
the last thing to do
apart is to update the implementation on
the list item to actually
handle the attachment and for that I'm
going to import generated header
now that wouldn't in a dot on file and
because this is a framework
and the generated header is part of our
public interface we are going to use
framework syntax to imported
all that what to do here now is to
update the implementation in this class
so that we actually handle this new
property
so that means having an x-ray he for
encoding here
setting the attachment
X explicitly to now making sure that we
can encode and decode it
and while I'm doing that i'd like you
all to know that this is exactly what
you'd be doing
if we implemented the attachment quite
in objective-c there's nothing
surprising going on here it's exactly
what you would have done before
finally
we do need to make sure that we have the
copy method for that with me copia with
item
that we actually do you get a copy of
the attachment as well square bracket
and since women are attachment immutable
using that like keyword to define the
properties we can just the sign of the
Cross directly
we don't need to do anything for copying
to ensure that they are
independent and not going to change on a
so that that
at the entire model and now you're
probably thinking
so great here we go again back today
Interface Builder to define a new layout
new control our and
at a buncha out with an accent and hook
everything up all again where he thought
that
any be rape except that were actually
really lucky here
the 30 but work in a department with
what about a gay people and another team
is working on a very
similar app that means to deal with
these kind of attachment and because
they rapin new they've written entirely
in
swept but they've also factored out
there
attachment view controller into eight
separate framework
which is a new feature in my life 8 so
we're going is their framework written
entirely in sweat
to implement the interface that deals
with this model object I'm
to start up here I'm going to go to the
bottom here and check the plot
yet another way to add me about to our
target to you had filed here
I'm going to the media your folder to
select their project me give you our
director prime
want to have the in my project
then I can just add this to our target
by going to our own project
selecting the Leicester target and in
the embedded by an ear infection
quitting the plot
this what the at the framerate directly
notice what we just did their is a new
feature IOSA
to allow embedded framework course if
your Mac programmer
you're probably used to this by now even
better framework need to be made
available to Interface Builder
two other classes in your project link
into your binary for you can actually
run it
and copied into the app so that when
other people down that they don't need
to download the framework separately
an extra texted all that for without
asking if the framework was written in
objective-c
or swept or mixture about
coroner storyboard now convene out and
bring up the
library here to bring out in you view
controller
and in this case I'm going to set the
classes that you control or
to be the media view controller from the
other framework you'll see the model
feel care populate as well
that be trips with to keep different
frame eyeglasses
from stepping on each other at runtime
even without a prefect
we don't need the view that Interface
Builder provides for us because it
already has one
in its own framework fighting just to be
back and now to make sure that we can
actually get to that
of what the tables out here and dragged
over control drag to create a new
segue make that push that way and we'll
give that a name
attachment
now if that up Interface Builder we set
up the Interfaith and model object
it's time to put them together and once
again we're going to the delegate for
that
but coach R objective-c code this is the
code that displays
the with we at the top here we have been
notification center
which is the system framework and the
import prolific at
which is our own model framework within
this project I can add a third import
for media your which is the free market
any other project
men hit build again to make sure that
everything is compiled an up-to-date
and now I get code completion for the
media your delegate protocol
just like before
gonna jump down to a nice communion
plate me application to implement this
and the first thing I'm going to do
implant a little helper method here
they just returned the selected item
again
even though this is sordid details like
how the application currently work
I want you to remember that everything
we're doing here is exactly what you do
in objective-c
from the perspective that this code you
can't really tell
that the entire framework was written in
wept meaning a code completion for the
delegate method here
the view controller didn't use new media
type and now that we have all that set
up
it's really easy to add an attachment to
the currently selected item
so here we say that its attachment
is going to be a new attachment that we
create now by calling
I like in it with their wait a second
we define as attachment baton swept and
it had an initializer name
in it datatype when injected see it's
showing up as
in it with data type the see that this
name translation work but wait for you
have a consistent world
in sweat and in objective-c do better
housekeeping here to make sure that we
update our back and start
and now we have of everything set up
here all idk what to do
just like dave did if that works out at
the delegate
for the media view controller so the
start of the same week that the
attachment
and we set ourselves with the delegate
and then we can also set the title of
the new controller
and make sure that it's showing
attachment that actually
on the selected item for if that's what
time does not have an attachment
make sure that the controller isn't
showing anything so with that everything
should be working
but building run I'm
going to the tech toy section here
anything now we have these disclosure
indicators on each other
be item going to find about this way
then I can see it says no attachment
banquet with edit button using the view
controller from the media views premark
that bring that standard I was control
making sure that our privacy is
protected
and this kid looks like he'd really
enjoy
under will play K I we can go back to
another want to be here
managed to get myself back anything
there we go
and you can see that the image actually
does persist in the Thunderbolt Display
Jackson so it looks like everything's
working I'm
the thought he was not just deal with a
new model object are trying not to the
new object in your application target
but also in new model object in your
framework
additionally this is not related to put
it all
when I with a we now have embedded
premark an ex-convict will handle
all the detail that for you death trap
finally once again we updated our
interface and added a delegate adopted a
delegate protocol
and once again I wanna impress on you
that is exactly what we would have done
had be delegate protocol and then view
controller been implemented in objective
feet
we didn't have to do anything unusual or
different because it was implemented in
swept for you feel you did it with that
could take
to you view their framework and in
general we want you to be tree node the
theme that we do system framework
Flemington where you'll be using import
my free market an objective-c
I'm using at import my premark semicon
in general we do want you to be using at
important that it has to import
for swift for free with containing swift
code this is absolutely required
but even for other framework that
they've been bill would act could
Dec and have a defined model bill
pending turned on
which he is on by default then you have
then you have a framework ready for you
in objected the or swept
the only reason now you have to import
are if you are working with an older
framework
that have not yet been rebuilt with
Ecotec and defined model setting
for you're working with the post what
which does not yet support model feature
introduced last year
so with that everything seems to be
working in our walk is complete and i
cant a backhander
thank you Jordan
so over the past hour
we've seen several different ways and
mixing swift
and objective-c Swift is a better
safer way to do coke or development it
was designed to support
the cocoa frameworks the Cocoa Touch
idioms and the common patterns that we
are ready now
it's still Coco and Cocoa Touch
fun I last so that means that the
knowledge and experience that you've
gained over the years
tenneco you have apply to swift as well
and as we've seen
some other patterns such as actually
calling a delegate method
are much easier and swept and much more
suspect and in other cases you've seen
how swift
makes us to find our intentions much
more clearly
which can help save us later on so we
don't just accidentally message naylor
message in object to the wrong type and
another thing that I hope you've seen
here's we put a lot of effort into
making sure that Xcode take care the
details
so that when you're using objective-c
your swift code
looks like objective-c and when you
using SwiftKey objective-c code looks
like swept
and you saw some examples of some class
in Cocoa Touch
classes but that equally placed your own
classes as well
so for more information about this
a there is of course the Swifts book I
the iBooks bookstore but also especially
like to call attention to the using
swift with cocaine objective-c document
that we have a developer Apple com
Savile was a PDF file you can download
and read on your
there I was device and it really goes
into
a lot more details about this the summer
related sessions
one of them in has already been but it's
on video
the introduction to Swift a course later
on today there's going to be a session
on
in swift interoperability and DAP and
that goes into more the language detail
so
out to mix objective-c was swept there's
a great great session on creating modern
collapse coming up
and another one a building modern
framework so that you can make sure that
you make a framework some better ball
on iowa's and usable from swept thanks
unknown
enjoy the rest of the week