so I'm to Gregor I'm an engineer
on this earth compiler team and we're
here to talk about swift
interoperability we're going to talk
about a couple different things here
so for swift is a new language for cocoa
and Cocoa Touch
development now koko's not written in
swift it's written in objective-c
a languid you've been using for years
and that of your abs are written in
so interoperability between these two
very different programming languages
is absolutely critical so we can talk
about how that improperly works
at the language level we're gonna hit
a number of different topics today were
in talk about working with Coco
seeing how the cocoa API's your
objective c- APIs
look and feel in swift and how to work
with them as well as working with some
more swift concepts like dealing with
any object and during dynamic checks
with on your types then we're going to
talk about bridging
the core Coco datatypes and disarray in
its dictionary and a string
into their swift native equivalents then
we'll move on to subclassing
the ratings with classes that some
classroom check to see
and how they're mapped back into
objective-c so you can use these two
languages together
and finally we're going to talk about
Corp and Asian core graphics
and this general motion is CF
interoperability within this with
programming language
let's get started
talking about working with Coco so swift
provides the most access
to objective-c p API's through the
objective-c module system we introduced
last year so you can pull your
objectives the API's for the from cocoa
or your own into swift and use them and
then swift map says objective-c API's
into the swift syntax this covers both
the
objective parts objective-c classes
protocols methods and so on
as well as the lower level see things
like functions and numeration strikes
pointers see the access to all if your
objective c- API's
now when you look at what are the
subject to see a Kaizen swift
it's going to be different from
detective see their inherent syntactic
differences between these two languages
of course swift also has some modern
features
that we use when expressing those
objective-c API's
in swept that'll make it look a little
bit different as well as
the bridging a core Coco types that I
mentioned earlier
now despite all these differences that
you see when looking at the API's
it's still Coco it still Cocoa Touch
and the same conventions and idioms
still apply
so what you know if koko works in swift
it's just a different programming
language
for the same great platform same great
frameworks so we're gonna walk through
part love something we know and love and
that's
the UI document class here's a tiny
slice a bit
in objective-c we're gonna walk through
how and why
that maps into swept first thing
something simple property file
modification date isn't an estate
this comes into swift as a property
is the bar keyword the NSA class of
course just comes into
swift nothing interesting there except
for this little exclamation point you
may have noticed
now that its mission Pointe is
implicitly unwrapped optional what does
that mean
well let's look at swiftly objective-c
their different languages
with some different ideas and so in
swept
when you have a value of class type so I
have and and it's a date
that can never be nil so very strong
constraint
and it makes life a bit simpler when you
know that thing is not nil
now when you want to deal with nil
you have an estate that could be nil you
use
an optional type an optional types are
covered extensively in the intermediate
swift
talk we're going to cover them a little
bit more now
that's the swift side of things what
about objective-c
well it does not have the notion love
he never knew a pointer like we have in
swift
and so we have a little impedance
mismatch here the objective-c API's
don't have the expression of this is
the notion that this is not nil we need
to bring them into swift
and so we have the implicitly unwrapped
optional
with the exclamation point here and this
gives us a nice balance it means that
we can express the notion of nail and
you can test it against Neil to do those
checks
however you can also just directly
access properties or directly call a
method on it
reading converted downturn and Esmil and
will unwrapped that optional object
automatically for you doing the checking
so it's a fairly syntactically
lightweight way of dealing with nil
in a language where neil is a much more
explicit
entity I can swept
let's look at another property
so here we have the file type property
to tennis string
this is going to come into swift as
a native swift string now again we have
the implicitly unwrapped optional here
so that Neil can be passed through since
string doesn't have a notion of nearly
in sight at
and there's a number of objective-c
types the kidnapped
slightly differently into swept so
there's some very very fundamental type
League cool in and as integer that
map into the pool and and in two types:
within swift so working all the swift
types
there's I E D and Class which are very
familiar with
in objective-c these map over to any
object in any class
something we can talk about a couple
minutes and we also have the core Coco
types that are bridge like in a string
an ass array
mapping to their swift native
equivalents again we'll talk about that
later in this talk
let's take a look at methods here's the
objective-c method
file name extension for type save
operation
comes into swift here as again a method
now one important thing to know here
that all the selector pieces from the
objective-c method
are here in the method signature in
swift
the first selector peace has become the
so-called base name of the method
the second sex lecter peace save
operation has become
a label on the second argument
really important thing here is that
these labels
and their order are enforced at the call
site
so you must call it as file name
extension for type
save operation just like you do in Cocoa
with the exact same
ordering so to preserve that nice
readability from cocoa that we all know
and love
now the other thing to note here is the
consistency here on this website
all the names in the Collins in the
parentheses in the Commons
aren't exactly the same places in the
declaration of the method
in the middle and in the call site other
method at the bottom
the kind of consistency we like a
building in new language
let's look a little bit more complicated
method here we have some blocks going on
some more interesting things
and map and a swift and here there are
two different things on talk about
first thing i wanna talk about is the
naming love
these argument labels and the internal
primer names
so here in Objective C you always have a
selector peace
goes before the call in and then you
have the name of the the internal
parameter
that you use when you're defining the
method in your .am file
Objective C you always have to write
both that these of course and many times
in the same see have some redundancy
we do a little bit a syntax optimization
here in swiftly just write the name once
it serves both as the label and the
internal name
if you want those names to be different
fine we can handle that too
you just write the two names next to
each other the first one is the label
that's what's important for the caller
to use and then the second one
is the internal name that you're going
to use within the implementation
up your method the next thing I want to
point out here
is the block so
here we have a method takes a block and
blocks in objective-c
get mapped into closures in swift
you see again this is an implicitly
unwrapped optional so that you can pass
a mill flocking here now the really
great thing
about getting objective-c blocks mapped
in the swift closures
is that we get all the great closure
syntax this provided by Swift
including trailing closures when your
block is the last parameter
so all a few blocks based API is that
you've written all the ones from cocoa
when they're following the conventional
putting the block last
get this nice trailing closure syntax
and swift
let's talk a little bit about
initializer
so in objective-c we have in methods
and in it methods have lot of
conventions built around them
they start with the word in it they
should be returning instance type
well that's a fairly new inventions are
sometimes they're still returning ID
and when you're implementing these
things you have a lot of requirements
you need to call super in it you need to
reassign self you need to check self you
need to return self
so all the streams we needed something
formalized in the language and so swift
has this notion
love initialize urs and we import
objective-c
in it methods as swift initialize urs
how do we get from the top objective-c
code to the swift code in the bottom
well we find the in its we match that
the in it name in the camel case
string here I'm we actually look forward
a little bit to see if it's really in it
with
because that's extremely common and then
we take the rest of that selector
and lower case the first character in it
and turn that into an argument label
for the swift initializer know why do we
do this well let's look at how we
build objects in objective-c person
swift
so dejected see you doing Alec
underclass and then you immediately send
it
and in it message to initialize the
object
these two steps are almost never
separated
now in swift we have our initialize urs
and we use this unified object
construction syntax
where we we write the name the class and
then we pass arguments directly to the
initializer
and notice here were using the argument
label file URL to say which initializer
were actually using
and then give it the argument and of
course we folded the Alec in the in it
together in this 1i syntax
that also happens to work for all other
types within swept for the be struck
certain times
so let's talk about factory methods
because this is the other way
that we build objects in objective-c so
here we have something from you I
colored stepped away from you I document
with color with red green blue alpha and
of course we can go construct that by
calling you I color color with red green
blue alpha
all of this can be directly imported in
swift it would just be
a class method color with red and green
blue alphas
as argument labels and we could just
call it on the class this will be fine
however we don't
really love that they're two completely
different kinds of initialization
so we recognize the Connor and
comment patterns and how factory methods
are described in objective-c
and bring them in swift initialize urs
and the really great thing here as we
get that comin initialization
syntax for all these objective-c API's
you don't have to think is there any
method for the Spurs their
a class method for this it's there as an
initializer
like
let's go a little bit down the stack and
let's talk about the noms
so here's the UI document save operation
you know
as defined in objective-c and if we look
at this we see
a whole lotta redundancy this UI
documents a prefix is used for the
in um and for both its enough values
why is this world this is seat
the in on values and see are in a global
namespace
we can't call these the number I use
just for creating for overwriting
because that's gonna stomp on some other
completely different animation somewhere
else in the system
and cause havoc so
we do this common prefix by convention
helps code completion find the right
thing
but we're talking about swift it's also
a great cue for us
that we can do better and so we can
import this and if he knew
as this week 15 um chopping off all
those common prefixes
to give us a nice short names for the
cases
now the reason we can't do this is
because the Ingham cases and swift
are scoped within the EU num type itself
how does this play out an actual code
well okay if we call file name extension
for type save operation
we can refer to say for creating
with it fully dotted name classname dot
im
same doubted syntax we use for a member
%uh anything in swift
but Swift has type inference we know
that this method takes
you I document save operation so there's
absolutely no reason to write that
you can just pass dot for creating and
we win for %um type
from that
of like to talk about and this error so
this is our pattern in Cocoa for dealing
with errors
and so there are many lessons throughout
Coco and throughout your naps
that take an errand and Essar star star
and that's a 3-pointer
to and an Essar object we bring this in
with a special type in swift it's
actually typing alias for
a much longer typename called and Essar
pointer
we're gonna see in a surefire twice in
this talk
for now we're going to talk about how to
use it when we're calling into this
API and on archie all that much
different from objective-c
so we bring this up
we declare local variable it's called
air
it's a type and mister optional and we
pass it address in
when recalling contents for Thai pair
and so in this code we check
whether we're getting back some contents
from this then we can deal with those
contents
if we failed to find any content we
probably have an air so we can go on rap
that
that optional air and percent the user
and if we fall through the else here now
we're in trouble because something
failed and we have nothing
we can do about it we hope that doesn't
happen but
this is the pattern you'll be using when
dealing with and Essar
in swift if you truly don't care about
the air you can also pass until
so we walked through a lot of
little pieces love the objective-c
mapping
into swept and their lodger rules that
we've talked about the you're certainly
not going to remember
that's perfectly fine exclude has your
back here
use the tools to help you so if you're
in Xcode
you're in some swift code you can come
and click on a classname
and will show you the swift projection
over the underlying objective c-class
so take your favorite Coco class and
look at how it maps into
swept get a feel for the language into a
feel for how these languages work
together
and you get into swift really fast
and the great thing is all these tools
all the rules that talked about apply
equally to
any objectives capi when it comes into
swift
doesn't matter if it's Coco it doesn't
matter to your own API the same rules
apply
and you can view your own objective-c
API's
in swift to get to know them better now
this works best
when you're following modern objective-c
practices
so the user using features like
properties
instance type marking your numeration
with and it's the numer and options to
described more semantic information
about what these hymns actually means
see
we've also introduced and its designated
initializer this year
to mark your designated initializer
formalize it doesn't initializer pattern
both in objective-c
30 ish no warnings and as the
initialization model
for swept so of course we want you to
follow these modern objective-c
practices
but we don't want you have to go it
alone and so
this year we introduce the objective-c
modernize ur that helps
find these cases in your code where we
could possibly modernize them
to work with all these modern
objective-c features and give you a
better projection into swept
and that modernize are discussed in the
what's new in LVM talk
earlier today highly recommend you catch
it on video of you mister
with that
let's talk about ID
what is ID in objective-c
its kind of a placeholder in some sense
it means I have a value I know it's an
object
but I don't know or I don't care what
the static type of that object is
it's going to vary at runtime most
likely and there's an old couple core
operations so you can perform
on it. you can do a casting on it so if
I have
this variable objective type ID I can
put in on
and Suro into it later I can go reassign
it
and I can put you i've UN that's
perfectly fine they can both be
cast essentially to ID they're both
objects
I could you message sends to ID just buy
directly doing a message send
I can subscription ID if I really feel
like it
in swift any object is
the equivalent to ID and it provides the
same core operations
up casting message sends sub scripting
that you can do on ID in objective-c
now one of the things we know from using
idea objective-c
is that you sometimes have to be a
little bit careful
because if you send a message to an
object it doesn't have a corresponding
method
you're going to get a runtime failure
that this isn't unrecognized selector
now in objective-c we have an answer for
this using the
response to select a radium to NF check
whether response the selector
then do it in swift we like to do a
little bit better
so let's take the same call and was to
remove from super view call on the
subject
and the thing to note here is that
removed from super view on
object given known type it may be there
it may not be there
well how do we deal with this notion in
swift we use an optional
says there may be a value their there
may not be and so the reference to
remove from super view
on object is in effect optional that
means we can use the optional chaining
operator here
to
what we're doing of course
is were folding the response to select
your check in so we do the reference
go look for a move from super few if
it's there
go on call it if it's not there stop
evaluating this expression were done
now something that
I V does the any object does not do is
implicitly downcast
so I have object which is a type any
object and I'm trying to
signed it into a UI view this is going
to produce a compiler error because this
is a
unsafe downcast how do we deal with this
well there's really few cases here they
need to think about one case
is I know it to you live you but for
some reason that
strong type information got lost when
going through some API somewhere
if I know for sure to you I view I can
use the cast operator
ass to say treat this object as a you a
few
we're going to do these kind of class
check
at runtime to make sure that absolutely
true but
the type system or believe you at this
point now if you don't
no whether this object is to you if you
were not
you can use the as question mark
operator that perform
a conditional downcast
thank you guys I figured it out but just
to be sure
this is doing is kind of last check and
trapping the result in an optional you
i've you
it's Neil if the check failed it has the
UAV if the checks
if you have to check seceded we can do
is let here
two completely different higher things
safely and viewing here's a few
you i've you were looking for so let's
take a little bit of a detour
and talk about tiny bit protocols here's
an objective-c protocol for you a table
view data source
and its swift equivalent not a whole lot
new here
but there are two things that I do want
to point out first thing I want to point
out
is optional and required so in
objective-c optional or required
are specially moods in the protocol you
say an optional
and everything that follows is optional
up into the point we had an app required
and then everything is required
and we're not totally thrilled with this
decision
now and the basic reason is that you
can't just look at one single
declaration in the protocol and know
whether it's optional or required have
to go stand up your protocol
to find it and so we did something a
little bit different swift
in that for rickles heard requirements
of protocol are
required by default and swift if you
want to make them optional
been tagged in with the optional
attribute to make them optional the
other thing I want to point out here
we're doing a little bit of a protocol
inheritance
and we're inheriting from and a subject
protocol
so in objective-c we will have
and this object the class and and its
object the protocol
and they have the same name so we have
to add the
the class or is up for a call the end
when we talk about it the language
keeps these insect accent actually
distinct points
so the language in confused but
in swift we wanted to bring all these
things into the same namespace
that's far more convenient for the
general case and so we need to rename
something
and essentially when there's a conflict
between a class name in a protocol name
will and protocol to the name of the
protocol
why we do this well
let's take another at look at another
use love ID
that we see in objective-c and thats
protocol qualified eighty
so this data heat source here is an
object
up some unknown type but we know that
the type conforms to the UI tableview
datasource protocol
we describe that a lil bit more directly
in the Swiss language by just saying the
datasource
is you a table you do source that now
so many have you noticed with photocall
fight I D
you can have many different particles if
you want we can use
the protocol keyword with angle brackets
to describe more than one protocol
now want two things we do it for a cop
informants as we have an object if I
known type
and we want to determine doesn't conform
to the protocol
this is the conforms to protocol
checking the objective-c runtime
in swift we do the same thing
with the conditional downcast operator
so we can just ask is my object to you I
tableview datasource
conforms to particle check happens in
the runtime captures the result an
optional
here we can go easily do that Cohen the
methods and computer number of rows
in the first section up this table TD a
source let's make our example a little
bit more interesting
let's give you the number of rows in the
last section
so here we need to compute the number
sections that exist in the table view
subtract one of it and then we can ask
for the number of rows in that section
now there's a problem with this code and
the problem is the number sections in
tableview
as you might remember is optional method
it might not be there runtime: so we're
gonna compiler out this because we need
to deal with the optionality
up this protocol method and we deal with
this the same way we deal with
optionality
everywhere else in a swift language
using the mechanisms we have so here
we're going to use
the chaining question mark operator for
checking
does my datasource have a number of
sections in tableview method
if so call it given the table view and
then we capture the result in um
sections
so we can compute the last section
number and get the numbers
rose in the last section ever tableview
that's about all we're gonna talk about
what protocols here if you're interested
in for a calls and so many amazing
things they can do
there's no advance with talk tomorrow
morning that goes into more depth on
those
and their interaction with the generic
system
so wrapping up here
any object is Swiss equivalent to ID the
functionality is similar to the ideas
are similar in the uses are similar
however it more safe by default
now we didn't talk about it but there's
also any class
which is Swiss a look equivalent to
class and has most to the same behaviors
now the other thing that we've seen is
how options are used throughout the
language
to represent dynamic checks we've taken
is kind of class checks conforms to
protocol checks
response to select your checks and
folded them all into the notion of
optionals within the language
with their optimized syntax to make them
easy to use
and easy to do with the right thing
with that with switch gears a little bit
and talk about bridging of cocoa
datatypes now first let's talk a little
bit about the native strings arrays and
dictionaries
within swift the goal swift is to have
one set
general-purpose native value types that
you use for nearly everything
these need to be safe by default this
means bounds checking for a raise
automatic memory management and so on
they need to have predictable
performance so that you can look at code
and have a sense of how it's going to be
a haven no surprises
out to perform and of course we want to
raise in dictionaries
to be collections and they need to be
strongly typed collections that work
with any type week
we can't let them just objects because
sometimes you need an array of strings
or ends
and we don't have a city to fall back to
you for the cases where the other tools
don't work
this is it
now to support having this one notion up
17 general-purpose nato value types
we're going to bridge from Coco's in a
string and SRA and its dictionary
into this with native equivalents
so let's first talk a little bit about
the native
string type itself so string is
efficient unit code compliant string
type
core string type a swift has unit code
built-in through and through makes it
easy to work with
you provide flexible and efficient
high-level API's
to work with strings you can easily view
concatenation
searches prefix matches substrings
and the strings provide value semantics
nixon easier to work with
and nice semantics is generally it's a
fairly simple
notion love if I have two variables a
string type
modifying one of them doesn't affect the
other one
very nice for a fundamental data type
now of course you can also think of
strings as a unit but even they give
them as being composed of characters
which in fact they are and so we can go
walk over strings using the for loop and
get all the characters out a string and
you get the answer that you would expect
there are five characters here
even though there's an emoji at the end
so want to talk a little bit about
characters and code points
because the character that you're
getting out of here is a full Unicode
characters not
UTSA code point retailer sixteenth we're
going to have to deal with
it is a unit code character and now what
are the challenges with unit Unicode
characters
is you really can't encode them
efficiently
in a way they treat a string as just an
array
a characters to be too large
and so what you generally see is that a
string
is encoded as a utf8 or UPS 16
but working with those utf8 are you fit
16 code points
that requires you to her expertise to
get right all the time
and so we made a really interesting
decision here
we decided not to provide the super low
level operations like LinkedIn character
index
the cheap ok directly at UTSA 16 it if
it a code points or whatever stored in a
string
because doing so causes big problems
instead
we want to use the high-level EP eyes
and let the library do the hard work
if dealing with all the intricacies
United
course they're still comin operations
you want to use I you may want to
count the number of characters in a
string so this account don't
elements however that works on any
sequence
and allows you to well just count the
number of characters in a string
and this produces the right answer which
is there are five characters
in this string so if you want to work
with
code points you may be your code experts
and that's wonderful you can get access
to the code points
there's a property Utes 16 did give you
a leisurely computed view on the string
producing and the Utes
16 code points in that string
and we can go walk over these the 16-bit
unsigned integer
code points weekend print out the number
of code points here
of course you'll get the answer 6
because there are 60 TSX texting code
points industry
last thing I want to talk about with
strings is the relationship between
string
and and a string so in a string has
a well %uh really great text processing
API's
you've probably been using for years so
we've made all this foundation
API's directly available on the string
type sleepy eyes you know and love are
there
you can use them now in doing so we've
made them
a little bit more swiftly typed up
tightened up the tape signatures so if
you're gonna
split a string into its components will
you can get back in a rave
strings rather than just an array of
some things
now you may have developed your own
categories on a string
with additional functionality that you
use within your own applications
you can get to those with a simple cast
so you can
take us with string turn into an end a
string this is just a conversion
am and then call your ass string method
if you find yourself doing this a lot
Friel
32 just go ahead and extend the
underlying string type
add your string method make it a little
more Swiffer stronger type signatures
closures if you'd like
but this should help you feel at home in
swift fairly quickly
and use the string type
now let's move from string to container
let's talk about arrays
so here we have toolbar items that is an
ass a wreck
that's gonna come into swept as in a
radio
any object now these two types
are fairly similar you can iterate over
them
and what you can get out a bit are
values a type any object
their objects but you don't know what
kind of object is you can some script in
the
into them and of course you will get in
any object
now in swift you tend to deal in type to
raise more often
and so there are some other operations
that
the core language needs to provide for
you to make this clean
so maybe I'm composing my toolbar items
into
a swift array and that's with the Rays
gonna contain
you I bar button items that's what
actually goes into the UI
into the toolbar items property I can
work with that Swift array
and then I can a sign it into the any
object array so this is essentially
doing a safe
up cast love an array of to our items to
an array
any I'm checks it also happens to be
calling into
objective-c which we'll get to in a
minute
now we also see the flip side of this
where we want to say
iterate over all the two are items and
this particular new controller and
here we're going to get any object
values and we talked about cast earlier
so we can downcast
each of them this is fine but it's a
little bit and achieve your side
and so we have specialized syntax here
to
downcast an entire array at a time
doing the is kind of class checks
necessary to make this safe
lisa Lee behind-the-scenes and then you
can walk over Europe
now we've seen and it's the reason the
objective seaside
swift arrays on the swift side let's
take a little bit of a peek under the
hood
at how this actually works because
you're gonna be writing
a lot of Swiss colluded in Iraq's with a
lot of objective-c code and we want this
perform well
so is a swift direct
and a swift array actually has to
internal representations
its first representation is probably
what you'd expect that a swift
it's a native representation it has a
link which is the number of elements in
the array
it has a capacity thats you so we can
algorithmically efficiently
add things to the array and then it has
the buffer elements that there in the
Iraq
and of course does buffer elements
whatever kinda rate is
that's what stories they take if we have
an array of 32-bit integers
each element takes 32-bit storage
there's no extra boxing going on here
next performance loss it's just and
native buffer
now we also have the second
representation
and we do a couple pointer tricks so
that we can fit it into
to tiny amount of memory and that the
Coco representation
so any swift array can actually be in an
SRA
underneath as representation and
all the operations on an array handle
both these representations
so if I subscript meyer et and it
happens to be in an SRA
will use object index behind-the-scenes
to get that result you want
we do an appendicitis an array we can
put the representation quickly
and give you that efficient and
operation
so given we have these two
representations we can talk about the
notion
a bridging converting
between and an SRA as objective-c would
sing
and swifter a that use within swift
there's two directions here going to get
to see
coming back so first let's talk about
coming back so we have an objective-c
method
in this case it's together for to a bar
items in objective-c that returns an SRA
in swift that's going to come back as an
array any object
how do we do this well given our two
representations
extremely efficient to do it because we
have a representation
they can just take that an SRA directly
all we need to do is one copy operation
to make sure the contents don't change
underneath us to fit in
mutable array but the common case here
isn't not amenable rate it's an
immutable an SRA
and so this copy operation is trivial
it's a message sent to retain
that's it this conversion is extremely
fast
let's talk about the other direction
going from a swift array2 anniversary
so this would happen when we take say
our toolbar items at a swift array
and Nicole the objective-c Center which
expects
and an SRA well now we have an
interesting question
because there's two possible
representations here there's the really
easy answer
it already in the Copa representation
and we can just hand of the NSRI
no work at all but the native 1
that's a different question entirely we
could copy the whole buffer but that
would be awful
I mean we could possibly go allocate a
little shame object that's
also possible instead we decided to make
are needed for representation to a
little bit even objective-c object
it's already in an SRA and we've
optimize the allocation here
so we can build these objects superfast
and just pass offer native
representation as if
it were an SRA it works beautifully on
detective seaside
think that's enough abridging
talk about subclassing
so swift objects
are all objective-c objects now what
this means is that
if you define a class in swift it has
basic
get to see interoperability built-in we
use the same layout as an objective-c
class
so there's an is a pointer in there the
is a player points out to objective-c
meta-data
there's the same underlying
infrastructure think make
are work for the basic frameworks work
with 14 release
can spend expect the class that's our
thing they're all available
now if you really want to make use if
your classes
from within your objective-c code well
then you should
inherit from Objective C Class where
there's an ass object
or some other class and this is going to
expose your class
to the objective-c world and make all
the things you write in swift
available also tear objective-c code so
we're gonna continue with their UI
document example from earlier
and we're gonna create a little my
document class that inherits
from you I document and we're gonna talk
about
a couple other things that some classes
do they override methods
so here going to override the the handle
air user interaction permitted
method and you do this exactly the same
way as you do if you're over writing a
swift matin
it doesn't matter the syntax is the same
the fact that the superclass was written
in objective-c
completely irrelevant to the syntax of
the language and how you work with it
now one thing to note
in swift is that the override keyword is
mandatory why do we do that
there's a couple reasons for doing that
one other reasons
is because when you look at a method you
probably want to know if the intention
here
is to override your sub your super
classes behavior
to get it really important part of your
API
it's really important part understanding
what this method is supposed to do
and the other thing it does is it helps
overriding accidents for example
I meant to override something for my
super class but I type are the selector
on
and the method name no longer overrides
my code isn't running
and I have no idea why with mandatory
override
we catch that if you didn't override
something you thought you did
compile complaint there's also the
real surprise which is when you
override something from the superclass
that you didn't even know existed
and this is the case where
you just wrote a method and maybe in
this release them as it happens to exist
or maybe doesn't
exist in this release but some joker
added it to the next release and the
frameworks that you use
and now you're overriding something that
you didn't exist at the time
we can catch that by requiring override
throughout
the language can also talk a little bit
about overriding
properties so
in swift you don't overwrite the Yetter
for the center separately instead you
override the property itself
and then you provide together or center
as appropriate so here we doing
something very simple were overriding
thats
just description property and providing
in together for it
now what this means to the objective-c
runtime
your objective-c code is that you've
overridden together but the semantic
model in swift
is different it's based on overriding
the actual thing that was declared in
this case
the property as I mentioned before
and if there's going to come back so we
have contents for type
air we're going to override your
subclass and remember that the
objective-c method took
answer star star AC pointer
to and an Essar which could be nil the
way we work with these
in swift is at the end of their pointer
class
provides a couple of operations that you
would expect out of a pointer
you can test it for nil as we do in the
if check HERE
to see whether we're actually given a
valid pointer versus being given nil
our caller now if it's not until
we can point at the memory location
associated with that pointer
amor by referring it to as to it as air
dot
memory and we can read from that memory
all right to that memory by just reading
or signing to it
now in this era pointers going to take
care the nitty-gritty details if making
this
are releasing to fit in with the code
conventions
love cocoa and its air handling was
actually fairly
easy to deal with this see pointer from
within the swift world
else take a look at this with class that
we've been building here
we have my document inherits from you I
document
it has a property and has some method
overrides
it's just a swift last through and
through
but all of this is accessible directly
in your objective-c code
so if your project this into objective-c
it would look like some
like this all the same ailment so there
we have properties we have methods
now there's some interesting things to
point out well for one
we have this items property that is an
ass a reggae
remember we talked about bridging here
the original swift code
had an array of strings
we bridge that seamlessly over to an an
SRA
the contains and a string objects for
your objective-c code to use
so you can use strong typing in the
swift world
and it maps over to the natural thing
within the object to SeaWorld
other thing I want to point out is this
really ugly name up top you've noticed
so this is the mangled name usually iraq
you're gonna see this as my apt at my
document
unless you're poking at the internal
somewhere
and the purpose of this mangled name is
to put everything in a namespace have
some sort see don't have to prefix
all if your class names instead with
swift eyes
is it puts the module name which is your
target
your framework or your app that name
into the name to the classic creates so
you can use
the simple names that you want to use
throughout your application
and not worry about a conflict with
something else in the system
somewhere
when you're in your sis classes you do
need to be a little bit cognizant
I'll the limits objective-c so it has
allowed a cool features you might want
to use them
two pools generics and so on and
if you go crazy in your classes and you
use these features
you might be a little surprise that this
generic method that returns a tubal
doesn't show up in your objective-c code
because to check if he has no way to
express that signature
there's nothing we can do it we don't
have to put in objective-c
so if this happens to you and you're
surprised by it
there's nashville you can adhere method
the obscenely attributes
and what this does is it actually
compiler to check
and make sure that this method
or property or initializer or whatever
is expressible in objective-c so can be
used from your objective-c code
and if it's not express more objective
c- for some reason
the compiler will give you a hard error
to tell you this is not something you
can use from check to see
now the ancien tribute actually has a
second
purpose and that's controlling the names
that you see in the objective-c side of
things
so here's a property enabled has a gator
it has a center
in objective-c this is going to come
through as a property named enabled
a getter named enabled and a center
named said enable
corn that's not coca convention
really rather the call getter is enabled
and so to do that we just use the OBS
the attributes use
providing with the selector is enabled
so we can
control the mapping ourselves between
these two languages
don't expect you to do this often but
it's there if you need it
you can also do this for the name a
class
and what we have here in the in the
parentheses in the autopsy at review
is the non name spaced name for class
so why would you do this well perhaps
here
porting part of your application from
get to see the swift for some reason
and so you had ABC my document now you
just one caught my documents your
secret taping ABC however you have some
archives that you still want to have
work because this is gonna be a drop
incompatible implementation
in swift for your objective c-class you
can use the I'm see action you
give this class the run-time name:
ABC my document and keep all of your
archives working
one last thing a promise to talk about
and that CF interoperability
so by CF referring to all of the the
seed like
API is that that work with the see
objects
so this is core foundations this core
graphics
and other frameworks maybe some of your
own frameworks
and let's take a little look at using CF
particularly core graphics in
objective-c
I'm gonna do something really simple
here I'm gonna draw
agree in in a rectangle using or
graphics
here's my start I need to go build up
the color space
and build up the gradient now there's a
couple things here that I find
non-optimal so the one thing is bridge
cast
so we're an arc partly great handling
are in disarray for us reason that nice
or a liberal syntax
but now we need to do bridge gaps
between CT Colorado
and ID so we can put things into the SRA
and we have the CF array cast sorting
toll-free bridging their
between Vienna suray and the CF array
and there's also this semi amusing thing
that we're using
three different kinds of arrays in four
lines a code
and you can write that I you can try to
rate this better I couldn't actually
find a way
to make it cleaner than this and its
it's really unfortunate because the NSR
a
gives us some useful behavior arc is
managing its lifetime for us
that's great we need to fear a because
we need to put CD floats in it
and we can do that with an ass a reggae
and finally we needed do the toll-free
bridging over to see if a rare after
because that we use with for graphics
API's now moving along we can create
some points with CG point make
and of course even though you're under
our where memory management is automatic
it's not automated for CF thing so we
have to remember to release the color
space
and release the gradient we feel like we
can do a little bit better in the world
so let's start again this time in swift
and first let's build a color space
so here we're just calling CQ color
space created by Sir Jimmy
nothing different about that however the
type that we infer
for this color space variable is CG
color space
note the lack of a rat at the end of
this this isn't some
opaque pointer this is the CG color
space
class we've created
what's the nice thing about being a
class well that means we're in the arc
model
we're going to automatically manage the
memory for you
school little further and create a
gradient talked about
so here we member we need to pass couple
a race through
we can use this nice swift array literal
syntax
to form an array containing star color
and color
we're doing all the bridging
automatically here for you
so we created the anniversary we need
we've told free bridge did
to the CSRA behind-the-scenes so you
don't have to deal with the fact that
there are so many array types running
around
did the exact same thing for the sea
parts
so here we just have an array a
floating-point values
says treated as a native swift array of
CT floats
that we bridge seamlessly to the
underlying Sea Ray
that this C function expects
let's keep going with our example here
CD points you can use CD point make if
you want
perfectly fine works exactly the same
way as it does in objective-c
however whenever we import a struct like
CG point is a struct
we provide it with initialize urs that
have labeled arguments
and so a better way to build CT point in
swift is
to just construct a CD point value:
using that seem constructions and
actually been talking about throughout
this talk
and then use the argument labels X and Y
to make it absolutely clear what you're
doing and this brings
aluminum a flavor up that nice Coco
readability
using argument labels into the
underlying CF API's
and that's it for example in swift its
smaller
its easier this far fewer concepts that
you have to deal with
because we've automatic taking over the
match he
now you may have some of your own API's
we refer to as explicitly bridge
so these are CF like API's where we're
not quite sure whether you're following
all the CF memory
conventions because unlike the world
cocoa
which is fairly tame in we've been
following conventions fairly well for
many years
we haven't been following them so well
and see as a community
and so we may have this function get
random color
produces some random color when people
listen
the Swiss compiler doesn't know whether
we can really trust
its returns plus 0 or not has getting a
name but
we're not sure and so we do the safe
thing and we imported as
and unmanaged CG color 32 can't
directly manage the memory here because
we don't know what the conventions are
so what is unmanaged thing so unmanaged
is actually a generic struct
over an arbitrary T now the details
engineer trucks we don't need to go into
now
they're covered in the advanced of which
I highly recommend
wanna look at right now it's just the
simple API
at this unmanaged tight we have two core
operations
take unmanaged value which use for
placing your returns
and take retain value few surplus one
returns
now when the colour CT color get random
color
we want to immediately use one of these
two functions so
we know to get random color returns a
plus 0
so we're going to a taken retain value
of it now the reason to do this
immediately after the call is this gets
us
a CG color which hit us right back into
automatically managing memory for you
so the window in which you have to do
something with
manual memory management is tiny it's
just this one little line of code
where you establish what the convention
is for CG
color get random color
now if you
own CG color get random color
you can audit your API's to make sure
they follow the core foundation
naming conventions for memory management
and when they do you can use these
annotations here in CoreFoundation
see if it was a bridging enabled and
disabled put this over a whole header
10 audited all the methods and that
header
and when you do that well now
your function when use from swift get
you right back into the manage world
directly so you have the great automatic
memory management
the swift and a ride for SIA
let's wrap up here we've talked about a
lot have different topics
we've talked about interoperability
between swiftly objective-c
we've talked about a whole other rules
about how that works but let the tools
and documentation
help you they can show you Swift in
objective-c side by side
you can get a feel for how your
objective c- API's
work in swift we've talked about some of
the details of bridging
core Coco datatypes and using Swiss
native types
and we talked about automates the F
memory management available in swift
for more information check out the Swiss
programming language book
and also the using swift with cocoa and
objective-c guide
that goes into more details on the
interplay between
these two programming languages
thank you