hi welcome to Swift playgrounds I'm Rick
Ballard
and with me today is my colleague under
walk a mile we're both engineers are the
expert team
we've been working hard to bring
playgrounds for life richard is preggers
the world Monday morning
you talk a little bit more about the
Monday afternoon and yesterday
work today going to going to a lot more
depth we're gonna start today with some
conceptual background
what playgrounds actually are and what
you can use them for
and then we'll show you examples how do
you stay grid for learning exploration
and visualization and the result if your
cur we'll show you how you can use your
own custom resources with your
playground
and how to use program for algorithm
development
and development other several pieces of
code were introduced the XT playground
framework
which include some really powerful
utilities that you can use to enhance
your playgrounds
and we'll show you how you can develop
your own custom Quick Looks
to the you can visualize your own
classes the same way you visualize the
clashes that come with the frameworks
next we'll show you a great day my love
how awesome playgrounds are for
developing custom views and any other
kind of custom drawing
and we'll show you how you can use your
own a synchronous code
fragrance finally will finish up to date
with a little bit back
limitations apply contact today so what
exactly are playgrounds
records our new type of document
introduced in Xcode sex
and they're actually a fire rapper
containing a few useful things
first ball is your script code the code
will be run
and resort I and generate results to
display automatically
every tiny editor program file swiss
burger
also contain a folder embedded resources
which are made available to your code
or your program can reference resources
elsewhere on your system you wanna make
available
finally your pecker can contain a time
line
fourth time in items to provide used for
visualization
view results yard what you see in the
sidebar when you first open a playground
we show the playground editor
with your swift code on the left &
Resorts sidebar on the right
showing the result every expression in
your code every tiny
edit your source rerun your playground
source from the top to the bottom
and protect the new results from that
run in the sidebar
this is the basic editor mode but if you
go into the assistant editor mode
will show the time line assisted by
default which allows you to visualize a
result in more detail
for example you can display the value
history from a light in your code
in this case into the numeric value will
draw a graph
that value overtime I since it was
iterated multiple times in a loop
if you're looking for consul I put like
that from print men
you also find that in the time assistant
their couple other useful things
you I wanna call out here in lower right
hand corner
there's a time stepper and this controls
how long your playground will continue
to run
after the top %uh sources finished if
you're using my views
or indefinite execution explain what
both those are little later on
there's also a slider
which allows you to go back in time and
view results in the time line from a
specific point near playground execution
so here you can see reviewing a numeric
result from part with you to take an
execution
but you for this is very usefull with
live uses it allows you to scrub back
through the recording that view and see
exactly what your animation was doing at
a specific point in time
that's what programs are
let's talk a little bit about what you
can use them for we think your first
great use a playground is going to be
learning
we've introduced a brand new language
for you to learn and we think the best
way to get started
is just to open a playground and dive in
and play around
our documentation also includes a
special
interactive program called the swift to
work I
this allows you to see documentation and
playground editor
side by side in the same editors so you
can read about how to do something
and try it out right there without
leaving the editor friendly
we think Tiger are a fantastic way for
people to learn how to program in the
first place
beginners don't have to learn how to
configure a project in targeting
building run and debug they can just
type code into a player and editor
and immediately see the results if you
know anyone who want to learn how to
program
we encourage you to suggest trying in a
playground we picked records are also
going to be an indispensable tool in
your toolbox
for everyday code development if you're
developing an algorithm or any other
separable chekhov code
you consider starting at the playground
working and apparently have it how you
want it
and then driving that code in your
project for use in your application
any sort of drawing code you want to do
is also great in a playground because
you can
immediately see the visual result what
your code is doing
and every time you change your code you
can immediately see how that affects the
visual result
finally processing code like value
transformers or secretive
image filters are great in playgrounds
because you can visualize
the result that every step in the
transformation process
when you change something you can see
how that change ripples through all your
results
we think you'll find a playgrounds are
fertile ground for experimentation
and in particular anytime you trying to
learn some new API
you should try to turn a program because
you can immediately see how it works and
what result gives you
you don't need a project you don't need
to build and run
you just open up even a standalone
program document
type in your code and see what happens
I'm sure already have many a time
going to create a new project from the
application template
not define application did finish
watching just a borderline echoed in two
tries in API
when you probably have to in a small get
to see you can see what happened
you don't have to do that anymore now
you can just open up a playground
and try it papi you wanna try effect
we recommend you consider keeping a
playground in your dock at all times for
quick access
to any can you try something it's right
there your fingertips
so with all that said let's dive in and
take a look at national program
to do that I'm going to invite my
colleague Qatar Open Stage
thank you Rick hello everyone my name is
Connor I'm an engineer
on the Xcode team in today I'll be
talking to you about how you can work
with playgrounds
as well some other things which we think
programs would be really great for
now trick is already covered many of the
basic concepts behind playgrounds
and so I think really the best way to
show you how to work with playgrounds
actually just by jumping straight into a
demo
to let's go ahead and do that so here I
am at the diminishing
and I'm just going to go ahead and
launch Xcode
you notice here on the Welcome window
for Xcode
we've added this brand new get started
with a playground but it's that way we
want to make it really easy for you just
get started with one
please click on that okay to play ground
and I just given a name
and a place to save it so my playground
is fine and click on the desktop is fine
as well
so they create and then we have here our
playground itself
you know if that were importing Co Co so
we have full access to be
Coco API's and then we're also creating
a string
and we're signing the value hello
playground to that string
illness that I in the result sidebar
we're seeing the result about so in this
case where seeing the string hello
playground
okay so best to come to the basic idea
let's try something with numbers
so say 4i and 0-10
say I times I see their
that we execute the code and we're
getting an indicator in the result
sidebar
we've executed echoed ten times okay
I'll try putting that up to 100
let it run and will see there that we
immediately get an indication that this
code is executed 100 times
now nine that is very useful information
but sometimes actually wanna see the
value
there and we have support for that as
well it's okay I'll just
hover over this results you'll see that
we're highlighting line of code with
which its
with which it is associated and were
also showing this button here
that's called the value history button
and I go ahead and click on it
will open up the assistant editor into
the time line mode
this is the place where you can see
results over time as well the place for
you to store results would you like to
see persistently
as in this case we're showing the graph
for I times I
we've seen as you know that night a
curfew
so K so that's how the basics abusing at
the time line
and killing numbers at the trust me a
little bit more interesting
out let's go ahead and do you I
something with apt-get assets
first start by cutting a color say black
color equals
and its color da blue color
you see there that we're now showing in
the result sidebar a color swatch
indicating what the color is as well as
indicators and all the components which
make up at color
as I can you pick the color and its
credit should be string using it
so say lent achieve its training equals
in S
attributed string it will pass it and
the
string and attributes: dictionary to
leave the street we already have
and will create a dictionary CL CNS
foreground color actually name help
after the color we have
and they all say INS font attribute name
others pass the parts of saying this
font stamp on its size and
go something fairly big so I just put in
42 to about looks like
okay so here you notice that we're
getting a result for this as well
his team that we're showing the plain
text representation this as well as an
icon indicating
that it is and attributed string
now that's great you know we know this
girl is executed but I really wanna see
what the actual value is there see
how the attributed string look for
itself I am disappointed as well
so I can just hover over the results and
in addition to the value history button
you'll see that we have a quick look but
and so if I go ahead and click on that
will show a quick look about value as to
show you the full representation ovett
ad was created in the playground source
so Kate that colors and strings at let's
try something with images
attack was set up by creating an array
of his name's sauce a
but image names equals will put an array
there and
and out something to do you think in
this image name user or accounts or
something in that line so I was gonna
create an
array with image names I think you could
be
image image name user
aim user accounts image name user
group and Tecate beer in the code any
notice that we now have
an array of strings action wanna see an
array
images and that's very easy to you going
to say something like
but images equals image names that map
a passive trailing closer to just say
image named
acid at the positional argument dollars
and zero
in an affair that we're now seeing that
the final code executed four times
and so basically we can see that you
have okay that makes sense where
exceeding the final cut three times for
the challenge closure itself
they're executing at once for the
assignment two images
actually only wanna see the images array
itself and we have a nice double check
for doing that in a playground
you just go ahead and put the thing that
you wanna see on a line by itself
so there you see it with the image is
there we run the code and we're seeing
the images array I can put that and I
can see
ok you know here's the image i'm looking
for. and so
I just get that image Philip image
equals images 0 will be runnin output
look to make sure it's okay and
in fact get 1 I'm looking for let's go
ahead and put this into an ImageView
so say but ImageView equal INS ImageView
will pass ourself a frame so saying it's
pract
I will say year for the origin because
it really care about that
they also say 512 by 512 for the size
now I'm gonna go ahead and put this
image view on it so might as well
I can put show this result in the time
line
this is a neat little way a building
something up you take the
the use are creating the object and then
you put the
own other line where we show it as a
result and working after could in
between there to see how it builds up
over time
so we see here that we're starting out
with empty ImageView you know we're not
seeing anything interesting there
so at let's go ahead and add our image
the image view
something in his view that image equals
image
react if you you'll see here now that
we're in fact showing the image there
but it's not feeling the full image view
it's not doing what we expect and
because we haven't sent a PM skelly
appropriately
SoCal set that as well
say image scaling equals image scale
proportionally up or down
react with you and now you see that
we're seeing the image at full size
in the ImageView we've seen what we
expect its okay
taken work with system resources country
have many resources at your own d like
to use and playgrounds as well
and we support that too there is going
to go ahead and I'm going to show
the final inspector of item on the right
hand of my
playground you notice here that we're
seeing we have this new section called
playground settings which is shown every
year
viewing a plague on document you can
select the platform against which the
plague on should execute
and you know I was 10 is what we're
doing right now but we also support i OS
any conflict a path for resources is the
faults to none but you can select one
if you have resources that you're
interested in escaped I was going to say
I have a folder resources on my desktop
to dismiss a
I'll it is the absolute path option can
go ahead and choose that
say here's my resources folder shoes
that
and then want to make that choice I'm
actually go ahead at hyde
the utilities area
and to access the images themselves I
just use you know
in this bundle API you know the
resources shoppers resources for the
main bundle
I can see something like that my image
equals in a
image named I have an image in here
that's just called Xcode so
let's grab at will be executes
and understand when now we're getting
the Image result here
a quick look to confirm that it's what
I'm thinking in San in fact is we're
seeing px but I come there
and not going to happen ImageView show
The X but I can't step
sauce a image view Dan image equals
my image well we execute
and I think this new result let's add it
to the time line as well
you can see here that we have what we
expected the exit icon is showing up in
our Image you
try also notice that we're still seeing
the older version here with the
user icon in the ImageView and that's
because playground actually capture
results on every single line if
execution she can't so you can do these
kinds of comparisons
like in France city no but they could be
an issue we first created and it's empty
then I added the user icon to their and
so we see that earlier version that
without words
small in the center the next to the
image scaling appropriately
and now filling full image you finally I
updated its use my image and we're
seeing that it's showing px Kodak
that's great so that you don't have to
you know go back and see what happened
at a particular point we're catching the
data for you as a player executes
I think that about covers the basics so
let's go back to slides and
talk a little bit more about playgrounds
one of the key ideas that you saw there
is that playgrounds will automatically
execute
he just type in some code you'll see the
result in the sidebar on the right
additionally you saw that we can at a
value history to the time
so here we have a live coal which
executed 100 times
I hover over that result to see this
value history back
I click it was switching to the
assistant editor and will show that as a
history of that value
additionally many values in the
playground have QuickBooks ice on this
case we have been attributed string
we don't see the full representation in
the sidebar just had the plaintext a bit
the pic click on the quick look button
will see the attributed string as it was
created in the playground source
we support many different types for
quick look in the playground with
support
colors strings both plain text and
attributed
we can show images use in this case will
capture a snapshot of the
at that point I'm we can show a raise in
dictionaries
as also a structured version at the rare
dictionary I like you might see in the
variables the on the bugger
we can show points exercises how to
create a graphical representation of
those
because you're busy iPads so both
inexpensive path on the Mac
and you like to see a path on I last
you can show your else for this will
take the plaintext BRL
showed in the sidebar but a few quick
look it will show you a WebView with the
content that the URL
and finally for texas we don't have any
too quickly representation
we can usually get a structured be a bit
again the cutesy and the variables you
in the debugger so here I have an an
object other class that I created in the
playground
and it is it has a couple properties if
you property and a bar property
using the values that those at that line
of code when executed
in this demo I also show you how you can
use your own resources with playgrounds
in this is actually fairly easy the just
go ahead and show the final inspector
you select a location for playground
resources and for this we have three
options
got in absolute path option which
basically says
okay about this folder resources some on
my computer and I'd like to show it in
the
use it with the playground we have a
relative to take on path
option and this is really great if
you're sticking your playground at SCM
because he can say oh you know here's
this playground and here's the spoiler
resources this next to it against the
south and then when you other people
check out
your repository Bilawal automatically be
able to use the playground with its
resources
finally we support inside playground
option this is great if you're sharing
in ways
other than vs CM because you can just
say I
you on so my resources in my playground
email that out to other people
and see at when they open it will be
able to see those resources
immediately
want to have made the selection to
access these resources in your
playground source
just use things like in its final path
resource a type
an innocent named the resources just
show up as be resources for the main
bundle
during program execution
so now that we have the basics out of
the way I think I'd like to start
talking to you about some the use cases
for which bygones be really great and
the first abuses experimentation
I'm sure that all the out there have a
folder on your computer which looks
something like this is just
a buncha next good projects created from
the template that
REM maybe one or two changes to see how
something works or to test out an idea
it's actually isn't that easy for
process you have to do many different
first choose the right project template
then find the right file in that
project at which maybe if you're maybe
not depending on which simply chose
nephew what you're trying to do in the
first place and that's right thing coat
what you've written something you have
to build your project
in run but every bill and for I watched
the me involved point2 simulator to a
device
and if you didn't get it right the first
time you don't have to redo this stop in
the debugger and scepter your coat
figure out where things are going wrong
we think playgrounds can handle this a
whole lot better
it's because there's really only two
steps you just say get started with the
playground
and write your code once you start
writing your code
will automatically executed for you and
show you the result in the sidebar
so you can see where things are going
wrong
now I think a pic to show you a demo but
this looks like so let's go back to the
demolition
so here I am I'm going to go ahead and
just want tax code again
and the summer going to create an Iowa
State's playground sauce a
file new file
and all say ISL s playground and
I one actually test out how the UI table
view cell File API works
as I was gonna called the K this
playground and call it test
table you cell save it to the desktop
and okay so here we have RI with
playground its importing you like it
I'll but otherwise the same way to
screen a string saying it to a variable
so if I want to use you a table view
cell style any day you a table view cell
and best way to show that is with the UI
table you
in order to get the cells into you a
table view any data source
at some let's just go ahead and
implement a datasource so say
class datasource will hear from in this
object
or conform to the UI tableview
datasource protocol
nice now that we're getting an issue
here and that's because the datasource
we've created is actually conform to
your table
datasource and the impact expected we
have actually implementing methods yet
so I'm actually going to jumped to
declaration you a table view data source
by Command Option clicking on it you see
that we've been open the assistant
editor
and instead of showing you you a table
view that H we're going to show you a
swift version
I'll thats header in this case we're
seeing
here's our protocol we're seeing that we
need to implement these two methods
and so okay I was going to take this one
this first one to you
atop a table view the number of rows per
section
I'm gonna copy and paste it in here
understand it to sort things out
return 1 from this okay
that number rose I let's also by the
south
and okay let's just go ahead and create
are you a table view cell say let's sell
equals I table you sell
need to pick typo here
will say style what to say that font
style
and then for the you say then fire we
are actually going to be reusing the
cells
so we can just pass no for this
parameter okay
so that we have our cell let's go ahead
and configure so I can say something
like sell that text label
that text equals text
okay so that's the text label will see
what that looks like UT will you sell
may also have a detailed text label
that's not guaranteed to be the case
going explicitly handle the fact that
it's an optional I can say something
like
if flat detailed text able equals
sell that detailed text label
and so if this at the code inside this
if executes
they will know that we have a detailed
text label second say something like
detailed text label texts
equals detailed text and we know this is
safe we're not going to axe
accidentally tried to sign a property
now that we configure your table view
cell
I can't go ahead return that you can see
now that we
no longer have an issue in our
playground I'll go up not getting any
result in the sidebar that because we
have actually instantiated art
are datasource so others say something
like a datasource
equals datasource and the neck and you
know
Asgard tableview and helped you start
datasource
so that table view equals I tableview
will pass it frame so CG racked
again we don't care about the origin
I'll pass 320 for the width and for the
height we just need enough to be able to
show the all the cells we care about
such a system like 240
family will pass if I love playing until
the table view
to use our data source
and then we will tell the table view to
reload data
what that plague on execute and one
spandex
finished executing I will be able to see
be at a table we
we created so I'm gonna just go ahead
and the the time I'm we can see here
we've created a table view we're seeing
the south we want with the tax that we
want
okay so that you know get it up and
running but actually want to see
be styles for all the styles that we
have
I so I went to jump back to the
declaration a guy table view cell style
and see here there are four options sign
going to change this one to a4
so we're four rows and some always
passing the default style I'm going to
criticize it based on the road that
we're currently
at sol se let row equals
and XPath row nothing like
let's I'll equals you a table you self
style
that from rock well past the row this
from Rob will convert
the the UI tape the Rob Rowe integer
into you a table view cell style
optional we can confirm that basically
help
and we can see that oh yes in fact the
style is an optional you a table view
cell style
we were past this directly here we were
getting in air
you can see here we net we need to
experts we
handled the fact that could be no you
know the US he will you sell
initializer doesn't expect that thoughts
go ahead and
check that's will say if we have a style
what's unwrap it
otherwise you just use the default style
it's okay and we've handled that well
the play country execute and thus impact
the time when using the jump are
and wanted to be executed will notice
here that
we're now seeing all the different UI
tableview cell styles
in our table you ansohn I have a play
around with second share with my
coworkers or just keep as a reference
for myself see with each you a table
yourself style looks like
I let's go back to sites now so that
should you how great playgrounds are for
experimentation
you just it started with an idea write
some code in see how it works
announcement by Rick back on stage to
talk about another great idea we have
for playgrounds and thats
algorithm development wreck
ex-governor developing algorithms
any other several pieces occurred in a
playground is a great way to go
if you're sure you that I'm gonna dive
right into a demo so we're gonna do
today
is implant insertion sort fairly
straightforward sort we're gonna create
a brand new playground to do that
so I just say get started with a program
mccall playground
insertion sort and save it on the
desktop
if you don't play with insertion sort
imagine that you have a handcart
you were put in an order with the lowest
price on the left and the highest praise
on the right
when we might do that is start with the
second to last post card
and compare try reference card if it's
max it swapped the position it to cards
in your hand
you can look at the third to last post
card and compared to the second to last
most
if thats swap it compared to rappers
cart
swap if needed and going are doing this
for every card in your hand
into every card reach the correct or
position when you're done
your hand will be in order so I let's
let's implement that a playground to
start with we need some random data that
we're gonna sort
so I mean go ahead and I mean it
prepared a rave data
I will use bar because this needs to be
mutable array so I can add to it in sort
it
it will just make an interior in Star
Trek and I can say for I
in 00:03:20 maybe 120 data points
if it got out of hand to add a new
element and that use the
arc for random function to generate a
random number
that is returning swift it so we're
gonna cash it explicitly to a swift and
modular set by 100 to get a number
between 0 and 99
so far look at data here you can see I
have a result you're on the right
I here's an array have what looks like
pretty random numbers
you're finished by at the precursors
again reruns and I get a different a
rare brain remembers
okay so that's great I well effective
generated data but
are probably wanted to change in me
every time it to pay current source I
make it hard to develop biographer so
let's grab this rain and data and use it
every time
to do that i mean a quick over the
result sidebar and use command a
to select this data command see to copy
it
and I'm just going to pace the same here
as an array literal an actor work of the
same random data
every time okay selector implementing
our algorithm
the first thing we need is a function
tests what you pointed at a
in RA there actually is a built-in
function called swap for this already
but for the sake of argument well
implemented herself seventy fun a coal
mine exchange
I you know we're gonna make this a
generic because
well we have an array of its are
insurgents or should be able to work on
any type
on so any type at least as long as its
compare about one element
can be compared as greater than or less
than another so we're mostly work on
compare all types here
exchange function to work on any type
because we swapping tax
so this is an exchanging a tight t and
it's going to take an array ft
and two indexes which we're going to
exchange
in the array so the simplest way to
exchange the object is to assign one to
a temporary variable
its and the second to the first and
assign a temporary variable to the
second so we can say that
10 because Dad II data
I equals data J and data
J equals 10 okay I think we've
implemented as quickly but
let's try to find out are going to
exchange past my dad I rank
and was a change 0 element with the
second and we'll take a look at our a
when we're done so before own it 0 was
in a moment she was 15 now amateurs 15
and I am into his 12 so it looks like
exchange works properly
okay the next thing we need is a
function to given index
look at the data point that index
compare to the data point which left
if last exchange them and keep comparing
in exchanging until it reaches the
correct position
indirect so let's call this function
swap laugh
again it's a chair at this time we need
to actually do comparisons or Saar
haiti is compare a ball ever gonna pass
an array ft
index the that appointment to start
swapping left
okay so let's implement this we're gonna
I start with her indexing go back to
position one
not 0k there's nothing to left here to
swap sanity for I
in and you know I could do a range from
12 index
but what I really wanted index to one
term in a reverse the range
with reverse wine three dots makes it a
fully close range which means go all the
way to index
so then reversing this goes from index
in in that one
and free to these our data points I'm
just gonna say if
data have I is less than data I
-1
exchange data
I and II -1 okay if it's not less than
data I -1 imagery the correct order
position in the race so we can stop
there
so it's a else break
okay let's try this function out I am
gonna go ahead and say it's
swap laugh past data and thats
pass on an 1,2,3,4,5 sex respect element
sex
left and look at
our data and you can see 0 has moved all
the way from the six position
the beginning here a everything's been
moved to the right
it looks like its functions working
great too okay the last thing we need is
to actually
implement the sort should be pretty
simple well caller function I sort
works again on tape he that is
compatible
and we can just pass array ft answer
correct
you this and is gonna say for I in one
we're starting at one cuz there's
nothing
left here sortie to you
data doc count
swap left
data II so let's try it out
I sort data and we look at her dad I
remembered I'm
you can see it did a whole buncha
retirement appear and now here's our
final array
and it looks like this is in sorted
order so we've correctly abroad
insertion sort
so this is great for simple algorithm I
can search insert that wasn't too hard
but you know if I was doing something
more complicated it might be nice to
have more visibility into exactly what's
going on here
let's look at how we might visualize a
result in more detail
westerner with extra graph the resort's
added at the beginning
do that it's gonna say for action
director iterate through every data
point
edges prayer X it so you see
there twenty get a point here sits right
next year twenty times
a quick on the value history button I
get a nice crack here showing my dad at
the beginning and boy
that does look random okay so
now I I wanna try to print out another
graph
everytime swap left is called so I can
see what's happening to the graft over
iterations have swapped left
and I could put this for statement in
the end it's what left again
ensure that I history but a given value
history term I am forgiven
I line is when show all the data from
that line
so you can swap it it's called if that
would be appended to the same
i graph that's not what I want I want a
new graph every time it's called
to do that we're gonna need a new tool
in our toolbox I'm gonna go back to
stride
show you that with playgrounds
worshiping a new framework called
XE playground it contains some very
useful utilities
for enhancing your playgrounds right now
with I have
API for menu recapturing values to
display in time line item
showing your views live extending
execution for a synchronous code
right now we're going to use the API for
many capturing value
that API is called XCP capture value
it's a function that takes a ride in a
fire which is a string
and your value which is at any time
when you pass it your value it would
take at value and put it in a time line
item for you
but so the aid in a fire that you pass
it identified what time I am you want
that night to go to
if you call this function a different
lines but passed the same identifiers
the values from the different lines go
to the same time line item
conversely and what we were here if you
have one line because actually be
captured value
but it's called multiple times with
different identifiers and it passes
those different identifiers
that 19 can generate but whatever time
line items
for grabs in our case that inter-party
talks are shown as the name at the time
line item
you can easily see what data is what
the value passed can be anything it's a
generic but it helps
if it's a type a value that we know had
a quick look appropriately
so let's go back give this a shot to
start out with any
import a key player in to make APR
available
and I'm gonna go ahead and define a new
function
a car visualize and it's a generic and
take
an array of type T and I'm going to use
this for the pin it
so distant that and close the Fortune up
but instead of just putting a tax
what we want to do is capture that I
soco XCP capture value
I need needed a fireside chat when
terror function so
I don't get a fire string
and we can pass it in a fire
an hour value is X okay so let's try
this version now
and visualize the data at the start have
are sort
Emily which star it in a fire just so we
know it's white
and you can see Iran in here's our data
at the start
that's a good start now we're gonna go
ahead and visualize your data after
every iteration
swap left second call visualize
a pass data as it is after his
iterations right left
and brighter fire that certainly would
after the iteration
number time it's robert is called which
is the index
parameter at seven let us right now
you can see it's generated multiple
graphs lady
labeled after the iteration that were on
so now we can just scroll through here
and see what's happening to our data
overtime as
swap left runs and the sort completes
you can see it looks record data is
getting started
piece by piece into at the end we have a
nicely sorted array
so there we can easily visualize exactly
what's going on with our algorithm
we think you'll find it's very very
useful
okay let's move on to another example
ago he
they can I made here earlier and it's
got this he prefered crash
top which explain in a moment but to me
this crash
is my keep grass which I if you're not
familiar with the heap
a heap is a type a balanced binary tree
with the value every node is greater
than or equal to the value of its
children
each are often used to implement
priority queues because it's very
efficient to remove the highest priority
and that's the top of the tree
it's our tradition to insert new aliens
into the correct position in the tree
for their priority
wherever amending our heap with an
underlying array
to represent the tree and inner ring the
tree noted index hi has children it
indexes I times to you
and I tends two parts one you can see
that here at the bottom
we've got some random data that we see
ourselves with and we created new heat
with that data
and we he provide the heap which is to
say with that data into correctly heap
sorted order
on the right in the result sidebar you
can see our default
treatment are discussed in class it's
sure the name in the crash
and show its properties in this case it
is one property which is that he parade
and here it is before it's been here a
fight when it's not a correct E
and here it is after its been here for
five minutes reportedly Creek keep
you know it's really hard to tell
looking at this array
whether that's a correct keep this
history represents a tree in
you know that's a good at visualizing
overhears I am here I times to you in
yeah that's less wouldn't be much better
if I could just visualize this
as a tree everywhere my hip is reference
to my pregnant source
so let's see how to do that in order to
visualize my own custom back
we're going to implement custom
QuickBooks support for this class
our custom QuickBooks support allows you
to add QuickBooks
for I said prices have in this object on
me right now
and to do it you implement the debug
QuickBooks object method
which takes no parameters and returns
any object is an optional
and you're gonna return the value that
you want to represent your object as its
quick look
on so right now that value
the values that we support here art
colors
strings both pain and attributed images
and busy a Pats for your custom cookbook
you can use any of these tax
so let's try to
okay so I imagine before I head over low
heat graph request that I wrote
that's right across the new data taken
arraigned right is a treat for you that
well implement our debug quick look
object method
it takes NERR returns any object
as an optional and we're just gonna
create whatever
he graph first
and the see CREF earners had a
generation in this image which is one of
the
custom quick look tight support tights
so we're just gonna return the images
generated G dark grafite
and past self that he parade
and now when this runs instead of
showing the people representation for a
class
it shows our custom quick look
representation which is an image
and so when a quick quick quick button
you can see here
it's drying my keep as a tree this is
before it's been here before I
when you can see for example 78 I is
less than 89 to this is not a gritty
but if I quick look at after its been he
provide
I can now go a great +91 is greater than
86 89
86 is greater than 84 in 79 and so on
and so forth
and I can really easily visually verify
that this is the correct keep
that's how you can quickly your own
prices in playgrounds
we think you'll find that very useful
art next we'd like to move on to showing
you
how great it is to develop do custom
view development and other drawing
development
in playgrounds and to do that I'm gonna
hand it over to Connor
thank you Rick another great a use case
we think playgrounds
I will be used for is custom you
development that's because you can just
start writing some code
and see the actual view as it's being
drawn as you're saying to build up your
drawing code:
syphilis I have a goal I want to take
this play can I come in at some
animation to it
the economy have is really great pygmies
the playfulness the playgrounds
but my playground themselves it's static
there's
nothing dynamic about it and so I'm
going to try to add animation to this
and what better way to do that then when
in a playground itself so
what's improper to the demo so OK out
here and then ok go ahead and open up
a plague on the party started
okay so here we got a playground we've
got our so passive in its view
a player and i cant view as a few the
layers attendees at three instance
rd3 instance methods I was actually the
Center for those layers
you see that their animal minute right
now and we'll come back to that moment
also have an extension I finish color
which defines a couple
love colors for the play and i cum
itself
I didn't have as a helper function to
convert
in in this busy a path to a CG path for
use with caca player
family I just go ahead and create an
intense my playground I can view
and then I put on a separate line so I
can add some stuff later
let's go ahead and show that in the time
okay to see now that we've just got
ourselves in Mt view here
see if we have an interview here we
actually just now need to go ahead and
implement these
setup functions I so let's go ahead and
do that
so set up by creating the path for the
background player
so you can you see here working in this
busy Pathan we can put look at to make
sure it looks right
M in fact yeah that looks more less like
the playground icon
so tell outside set up earlier
taking our saying at the lair you can
see here in the time line that we're now
dry in the lair where you have the back
and we've got a little border there and
so
okay it got back on set up but also do
the C sub base and will do the same
thing
while create a path for that
and will that execute and we'll see here
let's quick look make sure
yep it looks more less like the little
base that we have for the player for the
see-saw so let's set the layer south as
well
and their we just make that change
immediately get the feedback i've seen
what that looks like
when drawn in our view so did the sea
somewhere
about sankara set that up as well see
here that we just you know have a
closure which will create the child by
itself with an II
create couples layers for the children
on each side have the
see-saw I know is that the bench itself
and then add those layers to our city
somewhere
okay so now we've got ourselves
something that looks kinda like the
playground icon
but like the icon itself it's not
animating so let's go ahead that support
for an emissions are playing on my
country
I wasn't for that as well and so
let's walk through this is doing I find
a constant for the maximum angle and the
see-saw
I'm you know what do this I think I over
twelve is about right
awesome a property for the current hang
on the see-saw after any pending
animations finish
and have a property which determines
whether or not it should be animating
I'd set out as false but we have this
code here which executes where this is
set
say well if the animation state has
changed and we're told to enemy
men just start animating dipping on the
current angle the see-saw
and have thus helping method were
actually performing animation itself
there is no go ahead courtesy a basic
animation said a couple values
Center timing function to match but a
sees how it actually looks like
the duration to what was passed in which
defaults to 1/2 seconds
Abbott can be customized depending on
the angle the see-saw
within an animation to RC Sullair we set
the underlying chance for property that
sea salt layer so that what the
animation completes
it looks cracked and then we update our
currency sign your property accordingly
finally we have I we implement the
animation did stop finished
delegate call back basically say that if
we finish and was the first is to be
animating
then just go ahead and me to the OPs in
angola but we currently are at
soaking let's go ahead and some disputes
are in a meeting
so what do that and you'll notice that
after reruns we've seen the view
update its look you know so we see that
it tilted over to the side
we're not in the animation itself if
that we're going to need some help from
the XT playground framework
so but switchback decides to see what I
could look like
the second piece of functionality which
the XT playground framework provides the
ability to show live use and the time
he do that by calling this XTP show View
Function it takes in identifiers
and the view that you wanna show after
calling it will show the view live by
the playground executes
anything over court frames as the pecan
executes see can play them back
what execution finishes they defy you
pass a dysfunction
must be unique insight at the playground
because this is how we refer to the live
you internally in Xcode
I and it is also a week show as the
title for the five you in the time
the view past must also not have a
superb you this is because we will add
it to our own
the hierarchy and it would generally not
produce the results you looking for
so with with this in our toolbox let's
jump back to the demo and see how to use
so go ahead and just go ahead and import
XE playground
and then come here incentives having
this view item I'm gonna remove that
from the time line
I say something like XTP show view
pass in identifying it can be anything
as long as its unique sauce a
playground icon you
in the past the view that we created so
we'll just let that we execute
you see there that in the time I'm
showing the view live as its animating
yasser probably noticed at this little
timeout feel down here
and that led to specify the amount of
time which will let the playground
continue executing
after you reach the end execution at the
top of a coat
now i'd the faucet 30 seconds but I can
adjust the fountain I know my animation
only takes about
a second half so under 10 seconds to get
a few times around
after we had that will rerun it an and
so
that's great we see it running back and
I like to show you how you can integrate
XTP should be with the XCP capture value
API mentioned earlier
and so what I wanna do then to capture
be angle at the see-saw
ira the left it to the see-saw an
as we're animating so here is conveying
XTP
capture value a pass left see-saw
position else has the role because we
know at this point but it you know
it's flat on there make take this and
I'm going to put it in our animation did
stop finished call back
now in his past the negative currency
tying goal
SS because that's what we need to do in
order to get at the left
position at the see-saw edged having all
works out for the chance for
see he see here that as we're executing
within the graft and a building up over
time
and then what execution finishes the
graph snap back into place in cash show
you
their best view of the data collected
suck it you probably also noticed the
slider became active
and I can just go ahead and take that
and dragged through here
and you'll notice that where updating
the graph at the bottom or also showing
you
the animation your adamant there in time
so this is the I fairly basic animation
and doing what we expected but yeah if
you had something more complex than you
wanted this kind of take a look at
small portion a beer animation you could
do that as well
ackhouse do something like you know
click on wannabes points secretary see
it
no that the two things are in sync I
could bear that that's the point
he's the heir key is to go through the
graphs points and see that okay yeah you
know we're doing what we expect
it to do and so that's how you can show
wide use in the time line
with the ex the playground framework but
the back to fight now
now I'd like to talk to you about how
you can use a synchronous code in your
playgrounds
it'll taste in this minimum before but
like to go into a little bit more detail
now
the third piece of functionality which
the XT taken framework for brides
is the ability to extend execution
by default execution turn it's what all
top overcoats executed
at the playground ok provides API for
extending execution and definitely
that this XCP said execution should
continue indefinitely function
he's gonna this is actually not quite
indefinite the execution time is
controlled by the timelines timeout
which defaults to thirty seconds
additionally
at execution will be terminated if you
at the playground while it's running
at this is so that we can show you up to
date results rather than let
leaving you with sale results while way
for an earlier execution to finish
additionally at the Sun lasting oh we oh
we can actually call this function but
we saw
bad execution continued after we reach
the in a palpable code
that's because XCP shove you implicitly
calls XTP said execution should continue
indefinitely
you think about this as if nothing in
the plague on sources told Xcode that
the plague on Lisa say live
in the playground will stop executing
one seriously in the top
now officially a quick demo but it's
like he's a synchronous code and
playgrounds
he ran back here and I have playground
which uses at a synchronous code
we create AAA we have our session
delegate which is an if you're all
sessions I'll get
has a few call backs I and then we also
just you know
benefits every delegate pitted miss you
are out session
and then created a task to add download
the content
at the Apple homepage with Intel the
data task tourism
and you notice that you know the plan
itself is executed but were not
receiving any results appear
and if I open up the assistant editor
you know is that we have received any
consular output even though they're
clearly longing
here I that we've received some bites
and it's because nothing in the
playground has told the playing on the
to continue executing
I so we at call past that reason we
resume the task and then
estimate that measures we could be in
the top level code: and the plague under
stops executing
let's go ahead and say imports XE
playground
and then could say XP set execution she
continue
except execution should continue
indefinitely either take the ball
that defaults to true see typically
don't need to pass anything there and I
want you back here
now noticed that you know we were seeing
results from here processing the Consul
output we expect
in the time okay at a use
a sickness can play counts let's go back
fights now
there are few alternatives but we really
think that you should at typically is
actually peace and execution should
continue indefinitely when you trying to
use a secret code in playgrounds
if that won't work for you though you
can use other methods for waiting for a
synchronous operations to finish
basically just need to make sure you
don't reach the end a typable code
before your operation completes
before we leave today I'd like to talk
to you a little bit about from the
limitations we have playgrounds
first of you should not use performance
playgrounds for any performance testing
I that's because the long a result in
the playground will generally dominate
the runtime
I'm not your actual code this means that
the performance will be dependent on the
number of lines of code executed
that the actual performance whatever it
is you're developing
and that's not necessarily what you'd
expect
he said we'd suggest that you use the XT
test framework to perform a test in a
testament
where you can get at more accurate
results every session later this week of
testing an expert sex which will go into
this and more detail
there are few more limitations of
playgrounds play Dance Camp use for
things which require
user interaction so we have great sport
for showing my views
be can only see them you can't touch
them
we all should not support you can play
counts for anything which require custom
entitlements
for I was playgrounds we only support
executing against the simulator
Sony thing which requires a device I
will not be supported with playgrounds
and finally we do not support using your
own app for free Marco in a playground
I wanted something that you can just
copy and paste into the playground
source
basically you can only use things in the
standard library in the fck
or that in the play concerts self
in get around some these limitations by
using the rebel rebel is the command
line interface the swift
and it works this way because at the
rebel can actually executing your own
process
you just stop at a breakpoint and that
the LDP prompt yet few the rebel command
and you'll be destruct down right into
the swift trouble
gonzo provide a richer experience the
red in the rebel that's because you
automatically execute your code from a
non-state
I means you know you make a single edit
to align and then you know we just be
run it from zero
whereas with the rebel if you wanted to
make an avid something earlier in the
source the retainer getting get the
process back into the state
then you re enter the raffle retype
everything making it one change to see
how it affects things
Picasa support from these high-level
features like but looks and the time
line
which we do not support which the rebel
does not support
you like to learn more about the rebel
in go to the introduction to Aldi be in
the swift rebel talk
and we're going to much more detail
about how at the rebel works
in summary we think playgrounds are a
great way play with swift
cocoa and Cocoa Touch you can use them
for things like burning
exploration and visualization and
frankly public on the things that we
haven't even thought of yet
yes the playground framework provides
API's for use in your playgrounds
for more advanced things so you can do
things like menu week after values with
the XCP capture value API
you can show my views and the time I by
calling XCP show view
and you can also extend execution for a
synchronous operations with the XCP said
execution should continue indefinitely
function
finally we really like to think ready to
go out and get pic on the Tri
thank you know the really approachable
and if you just sit down with them for a
little bit you'll find a number of great
ways to integrate them into our
development process
for more information you can contact our
developer tools evangelist Dave too long
assassin information up against the
source editor help racks good sex
you can also ask questions about
playgrounds on the Apple Developer forms
if several related sessions about us
with this week
I so there is an introduction to Swift
session yesterday
which impact on the video we also have
an intermediate sweat session
out later this afternoon there's also in
advance which session at tomorrow which
will be able to see
we had an integrating switch with
objective-c session atlee
earlier this morning which he kept on
video and we also have
admits with interoperability in-depth
session later this afternoon
finally if you'd like to learn more
about the swift Apple you go to the
introduction to LBB
in a swift rebel session thank you all
for coming and I hope you have a great
week here at WWDC