good morning I'm
on countdown
you thank you arm I work on the debugger
team
at Apple and I'm really excited to show
you this
stuff today now a funny thing before
when I was preparing the slides I
thought by the time I'm giving this talk
maybe some people have looked at the
language manual for swift maybe some
people have tried a playground
it's gone a little faster than that I am
really impressed
you guys I look on the lobs I look on
Twitter
you guys have ap started already entire
ops running in swift
I saw somebody with a rate racer it's
crazy I'm
this is the sort of thing that makes me
happy to be working at Apple
you guys are such awesome developers
it's really just an
honor to write the tools you use thank
you very much
cell I'm gonna tell you
about using lol TB and a swift rebel now
as you're writing a swift top you're
probably gonna write one or two lines up
by key code
and that's where I want to be fit and
now
the good news is lol GB is better than
it's ever been
were swept I'm gonna tell you about some
of the basic features that all to be
house to help you find bugs in your
program
I want to be as its core
is a tool to help you fix problems in
your code it's got
a great set of basic features for
tracking down
where your bugs are ok the first wall
as the stock the stock
is a for is a tool that lets you look
at why the your program is stopped
downed
what functions got called to get you to
the point
where your program stopped now
your program doesn't always obediently
stop where you want it to
in that case you need break points break
points or another great tool LTB
provides that much you stop whenever you
want to
finally no matter how you stop your
program
we have a great expression command that
lets you inspector data
right at the point where your program
stopped and today's presentation
I'm gonna show you these tools working
with swift the good news is
the compounds are basically the same as
they used to be
but I'm gonna show you how to find some
familiar box
but you may have seen before and also a
couple of new ones
that are introduced when you're working
with swept now
the cool thing is this is an all I have
to talk about
we now have a rebel to the swift rebel
is built on topic lol to be you can
access it just
at the old to be command prompt and you
time
that you're debugging a program that's
not although
you can also access the swift trouble
when you don't have a program running
you can access it directly off at the
shell prompt for a clean slate
I'm gonna tell you lots more about
interacting with the
rebel later but there are two basic ways
that we want you to use
the rebel the first is when you've got a
program
with some code and would like to find
out
if it works if it's doing what you
expected to
you can use this ltp rebel
to test your app interactively another
great use for those
LTB rebel is to add new code
you can call right new functions new
classes
in an existing LDP session and they get
put into your code and they can interact
with your code just as if you threaten
them
in your source files now
if you've noticed one theme this year
one thing but kind of over and over
we're seeing
and all the presentation starting right
at the keynote is how everything seems a
little bit more alive
everything's a little bit more
interactive stops coming in Christ
telling you about his hair
its everything's everything's much more
immediate and I want to be as the same
way
now we have a couple of tools that
art that already existed that are very
interactive and we're adding more this
year
first of all you happy expression
command
as I alluded to earlier that's a great
way for when you're stopped
to poke at your variables to call a
couple of local functions
we also have if you're
a little bit more experienced old to be
users may be watch them some of our
previous session videos
lol to be Python scripting I'm not gonna
tell you too much about that
in this session but it's a great way to
create new debugger features
and automate your debugging processes
this year we've added playgrounds which
allow you to prototype
entire new algorithms from scratch and
learn API's
and we've also added the Lobb rebel
now what's the difference between the
LDP rebel and playgrounds
playgrounds as I told you and as you saw
in Wednesday's demo which
reckon Connor showed you all the
fantastic ways you can use playgrounds
playgrounds works from a blank slate
you've got a text editor
you import the stuff you want to import
when you write some code
and you see how it works on the other
hand
the point that the LTB rebel is to let
you
investigate how code would work if it
were inside your pre-existing program
now in today's session I'm gonna give
you
to basic things first
an overview are the kind of beat skills
that you're going to want to apply just
working with lol to be in your regular
debugging
and then I'm gonna tell you about some
new debugging workflows
the torch swift rebel enables
finally I'm gonna sum up and tell you
where you can go for more information
sup lots jump right into basic debugging
now in this slides I'm going to show you
interactions with lol TB but really
there's two basic ways of talking to Ala
to be
the one is if you're inside Xcode
in Xcode you have the debugger console
which is usually at the bottom of your
window when you're debugging
you can work with the debugger console
an answer compounds
and also Xcode provides you with a bunch
of you why features
that but you automatic but but you
automate certain things like stopping
there's another way of working with LTP
but some %uh view more experienced users
may use from time to time
and that's the terminal the RTB command
line interface
uses the exact same commands that you're
familiar with with typing and commands
in Xcode
I'm going to show you the command line
interface
but there's great sessions I'll tell you
why later the tell you more about how to
use that through Xcode
now this is up situation
but probably all all if you have run
into at one time or another
you're debugging along in your program
and your program crashes
it stopped and now the question is well
what do i do there's all this
information here
there are couple basic questions but you
should be asking
that will help you find your back as
quickly as possible
the first is what is the stop a reason
wire we stopped
the stop reason is a facility that Ltd
provides
the tells you why are your program its
was told to stop
something makes it stop
the next question is alright well I know
wop
mmm dot the program was told to stop how
to get there
what code around to get us to this bad
point
this is where you use the stock as I
alluded to earlier
you want to look up the stock and find
your own code
so look for all the framework code look
through all the standard library code
and find frames in your own code that
are responsible for this
once you have located the place where
things might have gone wrong
than you can start investigating the
failure conditions looking at your
variables
and seeing what variable values might
have gotten you into a bad state
so let's get started and look at
applying these basic techniques
to some crap to some crashes you might
see out in the world
now but their programs crashed the first
question as I told you what you want to
know
the stock reason why did it crash
but command that helps you find this
information is called
thread intro now I'm showing you two
versions of the command here
they both do the exact same thing
it's just that the short version TI
is very quick to type and if you're
doing repeated stops and you're trying
to get their work done quickly
know probably use short versions the
commands there's also a long long
version of the command
now there are two reasons why this might
be helpful
the first is it's more explicit about
what you're doing
and the second thing is you can find it
in the help
so if you use the Help commander the
Opera poke a mountain lol DB
you can find this command very easily
now let's say you type thread and for
what the hell to be prompt
you're gonna got some information about
the thread that's currently stopped
there's two pieces of information but
you want to know when you're crashed
the first is what piece of code crashed
in this case were stopped in a function
called swift
top underscore get optional value
now the swift underscore pop as a swift
top part
is very important here because it tells
you
but you're inside the key swift module
the swift module is the swift standard
library so we are you know
but standard library code crashed
now what was the reason that it did for
crushing
the reason is a bad instruction
now some of you may cutscene this
message before
about instruction is when the CPU
doesn't understand the instruction
that's being given
but wait a second we've got a compiler
error that's
being pretty smart about and issuing the
right instructions what's going on here
well it turns out but much ninety-nine
percent of the time despite instructions
are used in assertions
soil the code says if something is bad
if something unexpected is happening I'm
going to issue about instruction to the
CPU in the program will stop
so when you see your ex about
instruction what you should be thinking
as
assertion failure now
what we can see from the stop reason
without even looking at the stocker and
if the stock frames
is that we failed an assertion in the
standard library
know what might cause that to happen
okay let's move on and have a lock
the next commander gonna wanna use is
the back trace command
the thread back trace command Prince
all the frames on the car stock up the
current thread
that is it tells you what functions
called each other
on the current thread to get you to the
point where you've stopped
in this case we see but just below the
the the function but was actually crop
stopped
you see your own code now this top-level
code function
may be familiar to you if you played
around with with command-line tools
that's the code but outside any function
in your main source file
other command line tool so you recognize
this top-level Cody you say aha
this is my code but Apple ok top-level
code is frame number one
cell that means we called directly into
the standard library and an assertion
failed:
let's have a look at why that happened
well
we select the first frame and now we
have information about the source code
because it's your own code and we have
to
here we see that we've got on optional
and the object
that we got from a source that looks a
little shady
and then we unwrapped not optional
without checking well
turns out if you print the value of that
on drop knocked out optional
you see that optional is non well
thats but not too difficult to fix you
instead try
if not and that will let you and and
that will make the
unwrapping code conditional on there
actually being something in there
now let's take a little detour before we
look at more examples
if you're using Xcode you're gonna see
more than just
the stock but i just showed you if
you're using live dispatch in your
program
ax code will additionally show you all
the conscience that got called
in order to despot in in queue your
currentfile your current block onto a
cue
done after that once the Q started
running your code
you see the stock frames that your code
invoked
now why is this relevant to this talk
well
all the stock frames that are above the
last a
block execution you'll be able to see
local variables for
however all the local variables from
before it got in cued
are not going to be available to you so
you need him that's why they're great
out in Xcode
and you need to make sure you know you
remember that
alright well Grand Central Dispatch is
cool
but we're focusing on LD be so let's get
back to it
here's another case where we've got us
an assertion
now I told you earlier but there's a
compound called thread info
and that's a great way to find the stop
a reason for your current threat
another way to find both bus stop reason
and all the stock frames is just too
issue the back trace command
if you do this and this case with
crashed in a different spot
we see still that the the reason we stop
is about instruction and we're still
stopped
in the swift standard library in this
case though
were stopped in the gutter for on a rape
him
member
well what's look at our own code
now this is a function in your own
program
on on the left hand side you see the
main macho
and on the right hand side of the doctor
C the name
your function in this case find element
now what's this code doing
find element is iterating across an
array and for every element in the array
it's applying a function to it one stop
function returns true
it returns that element of the year
right and if that function never returns
true
the function returns no there's some
problem here
maybe some have you figured it out but
just
but the way I would and look at this is
I would look at the
current and oxen to the right again
using the print command
which is short for expression
in this case we see that the index is
that the fourth element of the array
well let's look at the right the count
property off the rails 3 we've walked
too far
what happened here we use the radar
count right didn't win
are not quite so here we have
a case have missed you serve the close
range operator
we shouldn't have used the close-range
operator we should at least have only
used a half open range operator because
the course the index is over in a race
start with 0
so the and at count -1 instead account
but the real answer here is we shouldn't
have been in using the index at all
we should have just been using for
element in array and what
swift and all the details of the
indexing for us
alright what's look at another crash now
that we've
kinda seen the basics this crash looks a
lot uglier suddenly there's a time
frames on the stock
what the heck is going on in all of
these look like they're and Lipsky plus
plus a BI and so forth are scary
so what's
what's use our method and look through
the systematically
the first thing you see is that the stop
reason is Singapore
that means that we ran into a situation
where the colonel had to put the kibosh
on us
and say no this has gone too far you're
cut off stop
why does not happen top often happens
because an exception that's thrown when
second exceptions were coming and swift
here
alright bar they're still there if you
look on the stock
in fact in objective-c exception is
being thrown
alright well we've got a track this down
so we look for our own code here and in
fact we see
again a function called find element
as functions causing a lot of trouble
let's have a look at it
so we select that frame and now we see
our code again
this time find element is looking across
an annus array instead of a swift
standard library array
again we've got the stupid coding error
with the close range
but the more interesting thing is
because we were using and Panesar right
we were calling in to objective-c code
no objective c- code does throw
exceptions
now one if I took an unofficial survey a
vial of DB Developer's last night when I
was sitting in bad
and the most popular the most popular
crash by far
was this one
yuck CBR access addresses 0
this means that you are trying to access
memory
out a bad address
no tends to be about address
so what's going on here I'm coding and
swept it's supposed to be safe
well what's have a look and see what our
top level code is doing here
I go to that frame and I look at my code
the code is importing foundation and
it's getting some and ice data from a
you are all that looks kinda suspicious
and Van it looks at the bites property
of dot of the resulting data
and pulls out the first element up
what's the problem here well let's look
at cars
Charice is a nolle unsafe Poyner
we're working with objective-c API's
objective-c API's can give you unsafe
pointers
this is sold your old friend
bunol Poyner is still around and
whenever you're dealing with unsafe
pointers
you have to be very sure that you know
what you're doing
are a sold the last year as
Swift is safe but the frameworks that
you're working with
may not be safe
not some up we've looked at a couple of
different ways in which your code can
crash
and we've seen that the most important
thing to look at is the stop a reason
the next thing once you figured out what
the stop prisoners
is looking at the stock to find where
your code fits another picture
your code is going to have local
variables
and you can use the expression command
to figure out what does local variables
are
and how they connect to the prompt
across you're seeing
now unfortunately we don't always live
in a world where your program stops
when it's doing something wrong
for those for that world there's break
points
and also beer up
you can use a break point if and leave
the following things are true
the first case is when the problem isn't
a crash
I've been showing you lots of cases
where your program just can't move on
because at tried to access something it
shouldn't have
but that's not the only kinda Barack
your program might be outputting wrong
Dadar and it might work my piece
you not something something embarrassing
to a social networking site
that's a little tougher to set a
breakpoint on but bear with me
so ok and there's another reason
you may just wanna say you know I saw
the failing code on the stock but I'd
like to stop when that happens
not when the crash occurs well
breakpoints are a great tool for all of
these cases
breakpoints have a couple of attributes
and you can edit them in tax code really
easily as well
the most important part of a break point
is the specification
when you say I want to stop at places
that look like this
what that means two allele de beers this
is a specification
I need to be listening down
lol TB goes out and looks in the world
for locations
that match your specifications
now I want to be as clever about this
not only
the locations that are already in your
program when you issue the command:
have much the specification but also
if you load a bundle or some other
framework dynamically
Lobb is still sitting there in the
background saying all is there anything
that matches my location here
finally there's a couple of optional
parts two break points
the important than that I'll show you in
a moment the first as the breakpoint
condition
the condition tells alot be I only
actually wanna stop here
when a certain predicate is true
finally there are actions that you can
perform without having to type antique
amount
automatically when the breakpoint gets
here
so let's look at some code
here at implemented a very very
simplistic banking application
based a little bit I'm on my own like
wish wishes arm
the bank account is
has a value that's represented in
santa's
and you have two functions you have a
withdraw function
and you have a deposit function now you
is little bit smart and it charges an
overdraft fee when you
go below when you withdraw more than is
actually in your account
now because this is my kind of wish list
are
this wishlist account function this is
actually
are overdraft fee of 10 cents but bear
with me this is just an example
cell you wanna stop exactly when
an overdraft fee is charged
that's over here on line 6
and in order to stop there you simply
type
break points at with the file sent to
your current source file
and the line Sat 26 the way you were
doing this in Xcode is just click
next to that line and that was the exact
same thing
now once you've sucked at break point
you can look at the break point last
to see all those attributes I was
talking about earlier
the first thing that's relevant here is
vote specification of the breakpoint
allele TB will tell you
but you wanted us break point at a
certain file and a certain line
the cool thing is I want to be also
tells you
all the locations that actually found
for that break point
now in this case there's only one
location
but there might be more now let's have a
look at a case where there might be more
locations
but first lots do a quick segue
I've seen people that have Hunza break
points at
and one thing that can be frustrating as
you've got a budget tracking down
and you've got a bunch of break points
that you had sent from an early Europe
right from
from debugging an earlier problem and
you wanted
not stop it all of those what will
happen to have the breakpoint disable
command
to let you do exactly that if you
disable a break point
you can obviously enable it later but
for the time it's disabled
LDP will simply ignore it and all of its
locations
now but say we have a little bit
different code
this is a simple example where we
implemented a function called times too
times to applies to integers it applies
two doubles
and it also applies to strings
I want to stop whenever any of these is
called but wait
they've all got different line numbers
how am I gonna do that
in this case we can use a symbolic break
point
if I type breakpoint on times
to lol TB will say okay
you want to match all functions that are
called times too
and it already tells you it found three
locations for that
now if you do a breakpoint left you see
some more information
but can be very valuable the first thing
of course is your specification you said
you wanted the name to be times too
the next part is all the locations that
lol to be found for your break point
in this case it found a location where
you were processing an int
and returning Int it also found the same
thing for double
and the same thing for a string okay
that's cool
what can I do with this information well
let's say you only care about the case
where you
are Pampling a string and that case
you can disable all the locations except
the ones you care about
now this is non this is a course handy
when you hop source code
but if you don't have source code this
is even better
you may be saying to yourself well I'd
really like to know when I'm
in this array subscript operator from
the from the standard library
well why not use a symbolic break point
we don't need source for that and then
you say well all I said the breakpoint
on the subscript operator but there's a
bunch of them
well it's okay to just disable the
locations you didn't what
there's another another cool way of
doing this
but uses a skill called regular
expressions
now someone you've made may have worked
with regular expressions before and if
so you're always looking for new ways to
use them
this is actually a joke rock from my one
another of my colleagues are used to
give the talk some
blame him arm the
ones when you set this breakpoint use
you say I wanna stop at times too
followed by
Anne sequence of characters as long as
they're so
the word string in there son now you've
broke
you've set a breakpoint specifically at
the swift dots
at at the version of times to that
handles swift arts training
alright well we've got regular
expression break points that's really
quite what else can we do
well we can use regular expression break
points for other types the categories a
functions
so for example if you wanna stop on all
matters have a certain class you say
well breaks out on the regular
expression account
backslash backslash top while these
backslashes
well the reason for that is that we want
to make we won
top 10 actually be a dock here
we don't want it to mean any character
and regular expressions that would
normally mean and character
you can do the same thing with functions
in a module although watch out
once you start setting a breakpoint on
all functions in a macho you're gonna
find out there are a lot of functions in
a module
including some automatically generated
ones so you wanna watch out for that
there's a lot more on regular expression
break points in a couple of other
do topics like dot India advanced
debugging with Ltd talk that we did last
year
that should all still apply it to us too
swift as well
ok all right
back to our examples not say you've
applied
symbolic break points you've said sumfin
online break by Bay gets hit all the
time
you're like oh man this is this is
really tedious to pee ke pressing
continue
why can't there be a better way well in
fact there is a better way
now let's go back to our bank account
example and let's say we're being
extremely gracious and we're not
charging an overdraft fee
but we find that the users have this
bank account tend to be kinda
responsible in their spending
again we can set our break point on the
withdraw function
but now run
once we've set a breakpoint we'd like to
now
when would we charge an overdraft fee if
we were to charge one
the way we find this out if I'm setting
a breakpoint
condition on the break point
now a condition is simply a swift
expression
that good value rates to either true or
false
if the swift expression evaluates to
true than allele TB stops
at that break point if the condition
evaluates to false
lol to be automatically continues and
you never see a
another thing you might wanna do is
instead of just stopping when you were
were charging overdraft you'd like to
see what kinds of
amounts are people withdrawing from the
back at what is what is their balance is
looking like
you can do that too in this case
you use a facility called breakpoint
commands
breakpoint commands a really cool
because they really minimize the number
of times where you have to stop your
program
if you say breakpoint command add
you can at the break out commands to the
last break point that you created
in this case what we want to do with see
the local
the value of the current account in
science
and then we want to continue which means
but the process just keeps running as
normal
finally once we're done typing and
commands retype capital T O N E
and done when you run your program
you got output each time the breakpoint
gets hit
but you don't have to touch anything
this is a really cool feature that
is very useful for when you've got your
program but you don't wanna have to
recompile it to insert print lines or do
something horrific like that
now there's a little bit avert caveat
here
when you're using next project
breakpoint conditions on break point X
and breakpoint commands
both use expressions involve language
where the break point is located now if
you set a breakpoint
on assemble top there might be
break points matched there might be
locations matching not break point
at multiple places in your program some
of them implemented in objective-c
some of them implemented in swept
now we thought about that so we've
provided the ability to such breakpoint
conditions
and break point commands on specific
locations of a break point
not just on the break point as a whole
cell
if you're stop if you've got a break
point location and swept
you can type in a swift condition and if
you've got another location
in objective-c you can use objective-c
and your condition
now that raises the question well okay I
said a symbolic break point
not a ton of locations how r tell them
apart how do I figure out what language
they ran
well I'll give you a quick
overview of how to read Swiss symbols
in this case we're looking at a couple
of different symbols
and different that are implemented in
different places in your code
the first is called main if you're in
Objective C or C++ programmer you
recognize that Maine is the
the main entry point have a C++ program
but the more important thing to note is
here as that their
it doesn't have any argument names
and it doesn't happen adornment this
typically means
but it's a C or objective-c function
there's another thing dull but you have
to remember
especially up with when you're dealing
with swift and that is the top-level
code acts the same way
so just remember that if there's no
adornment like this it's either
objective CRC
or if its top-level code that swept
the next thing as you if you have an
objective-c class for instance method
but class or instance method name is
going to have brackets and a dash
or a plus sign finally
if you have a swift function than we
no the return type and we know the
argument types for the function
so we're going to be very verbose and
tell you all the information right up
front
alright cell now we've seen how to stop
a nap
at the right time in all TB the tool
used opted to do that is break points
you can set breakpoints based on all
kinds of filters
and you could even set conditions on
your break points
so that once you know where you wanna
stop you can also tell to be
to some extent when you want to stop
you can even set automated auctions on
your break points
so that you don't have to stop
investigate your variables
and then move on
well house talk about some other new
stuff that we've got an Intel all TB
this is the stuff I've been having fun
you with for the last couple for the
last yourself
the first thing I'm gonna tell you about
is validating your existing code
using the LTB rebel the LDP Ruppel
is really amazing tool and the slides
while they kinda for scratch the surface
of all the stuff you can do
I'm really excited to see what all what
you all can do
and what kinds of workflows you're gonna
discover
so let's try validating some existing
code but first
what's figure out when we can do that
well the rubble and the old to be
command line exist
in harmony with one another you can
launch the rebel from a shell
with an empty target just by typing AXI
run swift as I told you earlier
however also when your program is
stopped
at any point you can type rebel and you
get to in a rebel prompt
just the same finally
you can break you can break back into
allele TB
by pressing Colin answer and that drops
you back into the old to be prompt
why this weird colon and her thing
well there's another thing that colin
can do for you
if you're stopped in the rubble you can
use the colon
can the colon prefix and type in lol Tbk
mound after it
and I want to be command will be
executed just as if you typed at the LDP
prompt
this is a really handy way and it shows
but really Lobb
and the rebel are living right next to
each other
alright enough with the explanation much
let's go right into the code
suffering a function here and it does a
partition of an array
now you may be asking yourself okay what
what kind of partition we talking about
here
and maybe i'd maybe you have the
implementation hand year maybe you don't
how can we use the rubble to discover
more about this function
well with our program stopped we drop
into the rubble
and then weakened call the partition
function right from there
if we send at the rate 345 now what we
get back
is the array containing three paired
with
the array containing four and five
alright this looks interesting
I guess there something about that being
the
bottom Park the array in the top part of
the right
what's formalize the slot test a theory
about what's going on
what I'm going to do is now write my own
code
in the rubble the expression commanders
really great for one liners
but the rebel command is is awesome
for editing your code and adding
entirely new functions
in this case we're gonna ride and is
partition function
that as partition function into rates
across all the
members of the left-hander ray and
checks
but their last than or equal that their
last stand or equal to the numbers in
the right-hand array
if any of them are greater than the a
member of the right hand or a
it's as always the look like the kind of
partition I was expecting and returns
false
finally once it's checked everything up
returns true
you can run this is partition function
on the result
of partitioning a larger array and is
partition will tell you indeed
thought was a the result was a partition
this is something fairly deep you've got
a
function that exists in your code
already you've compiled it using the
swift compiler
swiftest an interpreted language or
anything but at the same time
you've used this rubble to interactively
cast by adding new code
this is just one of the kinda
interactive debugging scenarios
that we're hoping world well change the
way
you work with code let's look at that
neither example
using this partition function I've
implemented a sorting algorithm
called my sort now I want to validate
that my sort works
well I can to the rebel again
if I am to the rubble I can run my sort
on a rain and the result is
but the rails men dice the result is an
array
that I can kinda by Paul and see
assorted alright
Caldwell it fit on a slide it's looks or
did to me it's
this this is probably good enough bar
many of your real wanna many your real
data structures I'm gonna fit on a slide
in you can't easily eyeball them for
correctness
what's write a function but shocks
whether an array assorted
in the rubble we just type we restart
the finding a function called is sorted
the notion here is we're gonna keep
track of the previous element that we
saw
you're right and for each element in the
array
we're gonna check is it indeed greater
than or equal to with the previous
element
if there's oliver after an element of
the array for is last land
the previous element let me know all
this arrays and sorted
now wire were using and optional for the
previous element
minus last optional well
the first element of the array doesn't
have a previous element
so the last so the last element in that
case is going to be no
if I run is sorted on the resulting
using my compiled
my sort function on on the rain
I see indeed that the my sort function
was implemented
correctly for this case and returned and
the
is sorted function returns true this is
the kind of ad hoc unit testing
but I was talking about
now let's take another example
but instead a validating existing code
we'd like to try out some new code in
our program
and this is a good example to kinda
review the role that the expression
parser
and the rebel have in your program
when you're running your program you
have two aspect if your program state
the one aspect is your stock that all
the functions that your programs called
all the threads that you're currently
looking up
for investigating those ok we think the
expression command
is a wonderful tool however
there's all this code that you've
written
that may not be currently running you
may not have a stack frame representing
but you'd still like to play around with
it
that's where the old to be rebel comes
in to both built on the same technology
but they both but they serve distinct
purposes
let's look at an example dispatching on
a queue
in my program I've imported foundation
after squared dispatch queue: using
dispatch queue: create
this code has set up a cue inside my
program
I can dispatch blocks onto it well
from the RuPaul I can do the same thing
I stop by program and to the rubble
and then I called dispatch sink on the Q
and M and out a block that Prince world
indeed if I do not I get the output
world
now there's one thing to remember here
your program is stop when we talk when
we when we do this
so let's say you had a cue that was
running in your program
that was already running some of their
code now
if you try to dispatch to it that
dispatches
gonna that dispatches gonna return
because there something happening on the
queue already
what you should do in that case is
dispatch a sink your block
and then as and then you can continue
approach your program
and the and your code will run this is a
great way to manipulate
a resource that needs to be serialized
on from the debugger
and actually lots you debug in a more
Safeway
let's look at another example
in this example I've got a protocol
this protocol says I'm a type of thing
but can be doubled
and in my code I've implemented an
extension to the spill 10 swift integer
class
dot is that make said be double ok
so calling twice on an integer now
returns two times that integer
using that protocol I've implemented a
dark function
that knows how to get four-time
something
by doubling it twice
the rebel can mess around with the stuff
too
we can write an extension on the swift
built-in String class
that makes a double right in the rubble
we can make twice concatenate the string
with itself
and returned the result
and done we can run print and then we
can run four times on the result of that
and four times works because we're able
the rubble is able to register that
extension
so then we see the output 3-4 times
just as we expected
now this is just the beginning and i mix
I'm sure that next year
I'm gonna be why I am or some one of my
colleagues is
going to be telling you about all the
quarter new debugging
workflows but your colleagues have found
and
at his work we're gonna have a pretty
fantastic session next year
but some up and tell you about what
other resources there are
to help to help you rock
Lobb provides great tools to diagnose
bikes in your program
I've told you about stop reasons the
stock arm
I told you about the print command or
expression if you like
I've told you about break points and
also told you about the great new
LTB rebel that lets you debug in an
interactive way
writing your own code and interacting
with your programs existing code
if you want more information on this
first of all you can contact our
awesome developer tools evangelist tape
too long
you can also check out the quick start
guide in our documentation
the old to be quick start guide is a
fantastic document and I will tell you
lots of stuff that I have uncovered here
finally you can communicate with other
developers and chat about
lol :d beyond number and the kinds of
work clothes you discover on the Apple
developer forums
but that's not all it turns out we have
are
right session for you on Friday morning
it could be just the thing to go with
your morning coffee
cuz my colleague enrico granada is gonna
tell you some
really neat stuff but Allah GB does to
help you
under the hood and debugging your swift
programs
another thing but you wanna check out is
the head
is the aren't debugging an ax code six
talk
that was earlier this week so you wanna
check that out online but it tells you
all about the UI implementation and
how to deal with arm for example are the
geez the Grand Central Dispatch
integration
finally as I told you earlier we have a
session last year we talked a little bit
more in-depth
about the about working with lol TB and
especially about break points and
stopping
again I want to reiterate thank you so
much for being up all developers
thank you so much for working with LTB I
look forward to seeing you in the lab