hello everyone
how's it going I heard the bash
was pretty amazing last night and I'm
sure a lot of you are hun your
so I'll speak release toughly to so that
now
just kidding there's no mercy here let's
get rights
carnage we have a lot of great content
for use more ink
you may have heard that Apple
released a new programming language
newsweek it's called swift up Ryan Kylie
and its the new language for the cocoa
and Cocoa Touch platforms
it's a language we told her we live in
filth just saw some
and what's even better is that the told
you know 1 lob the axe call you know a
lot the source added for you know a lot
they all just feel great and debugger
you know I'll of
albee Baby also feels jobs great
the thirty years you've heard about
tools that can help you
explore swift one of them
one of them that is not usually thought
of as a tool for exploration
is the teabagger 30 Bacher
has the unique property that it can help
you explore
in the context of your application most
of you probably do you have aP's
and those are written in objective-c and
US started of things we've
features so what you can do you can code
some swift
inside your application and you can use
the debugger
to help your staff through your code
look at your data
and feel your heart are your fancy new
suite features
are interacting with your existing code
base and of course
if he that ever happened that there were
bags in your code
you could actually use the debugger to
be productive to fix them
we have a lot of stuff to cover
we're going to talk about
some swift types email DB we're going to
talk about
optional types protocols and generics
these are all category subtypes this
with introduces
what can you expect when you're
debugging your code and you try to use
this
we're going to talk about the makes a
match situation
like I have some objective-c code and
some swift code clerk
inter operating together and you have to
be back to resolve that
we're going to call our staff pick
we're going to talk about data for
matters and how you can expect data for
matters to work in swift
and we're going to stock would name
uniqueness
explain how swift solves name clashes
senior
your code between different frameworks
elaborates and from there are we gonna
see how that very same feature
also helps make debugging awesome of
optional types
optional types introduce a leveling
direction
if something inside the optional or is
it not
the way I like to think I'll optional
types
East a box I get a box
add excess there's a string here but
I have to actually open the box to look
at the string in C
purvis ring here manufacturers nothing
here
inchoate that opening the box is
something you have to do
and it's called and dropping the
optional LDB helps you out
when you're debugging it will employees
silly out a medically
and wrap the optional opened the box for
you and show you the contents
and if there are no contents will just
say Neil
how can we expect that to look but they
were riding coat and we train about to
buy apples
we create a native swift strange
optional
we create and then it's racked it breaks
C struct
optional and we created a nicer out
optional
and we choose to not put anything in DNS
a row the viable views
will transparently I'm prop for you your
strength
will show just book contents of the
string literal you put aimed
in the optional the box is open others a
string LDP will show you the streak
the same thing if through for DNS
wrecked
of the actual a rectangle in there I'll
tell you about it sergeant and
its sites and 50 NS you're out happens
to be Neil
well just say Neil there's a point
one this situation gets a little
trickier since option also like boxes
I can put boxes into marxists it
probably happened to all of a tomboy we
order something online
and the shipping company sends of really
big ball key box
and now we opened a really big bulky box
and this is more a box inside
and that is not a smaller box inside and
then a naturally for all the packaging
all we order is a tiny little thing like
a clicker
in swift you can do a similar thing by
having
nasty adoption of in this example we had
an optional an optional
and what we say is in the outermost
optional in a big box
were actually putting a smaller box but
was more a box is empty
there's a fundamental fright pension at
war here
if I am the debugger I have to decide
what the calendar story
I have to decide if I want to tell you
that there's few boxes here
and one of them is fall and one of them
is empty
or I can just look inside the whole
layering a boxes
and be doesn't mark died tells you yeah
you know what does
nothing here just per gallon just to
bother with that
by default all the beach show this to be
that smart guy
a look inside all the level a box s
added calcium
you know what I looked there's really
nothing there is no stranger at the end
of the day
but in some cases I may actually want to
know
that there's a box with a box and that
there's more boxes the one to Tempe
maybe matters for my API contract but
that's the way things are
for dose cases what you wanna be using
is the road display mode let me give you
a little background here
by default al BB has a feature called a
tougher matters
the data for matter feature is used
throughout the debugger when you're
looking at data
to present %um no frills just get needed
a data matters in my contacts situation
but sometimes you need to actually I'm
CD underlying true without the debugger
trying to be smart about what to show
you
in those situations what you want to use
is this raw display mode
at the LDP console the row display the
show me the real gotshall
up my object in memory without
formatting it in an intelligent way
is invoked with the dash dash role or
for short
dash uppercase are option to the
expression command
or the frame viable command
some love you have probably Nadia's the
frame battle command before
it's a little bit a beautiful debugger
trivia
there some kid this work me be your
debugging really
really tricky situation and you're
trying to
this barb to perturb the state of the
route as little as possible while you
try to figure out is really weird
situation
in those kids this you want to look at
your data
but idk dont want to be running code
that could change the state other up
as you look at data you can use the
frame variable command
to say show me one variable show me a
bunch a viable
surely all my locals without having to
execute code
and that is the friend parable Kamat if
you also batted
the bash our option you got the road
display
you get things for what they really are
other callers
and if we don't act or big box was more
box for nothing inside
we see that the first thing I know the
beach house of is
that yup their ES a big box
and I see the curse something in that
that's what that some
its now I'm your panties big box and see
exactly what is in there
and we see that the race as more box
would nothing inside but it doesn't stop
here
week told the swift compiler that we
wanted a box
that would feed us 3 Inc and those with
compiler made other box
that was fetus frink if there was a
string here
we were pretty much see that we would
see bill low-level no frills
representation office with Frank
but there's no string in this case so
everything in a storage that the comp I
restart from a string
is 0 out because we're actually is not
think
we've been talking about optional types
but we can also talk more in general
about types
we could ask ourselves the question when
we talk about it type
what are we talking about
and that's a deep philosophical question
that's a question
with potentially a lot of answers and
I'm sure we would all like to spend the
rest of the session going back and forth
exchange in definitions up type
or you could just write me for a moment
I could give a definition that works in
the context of the following slides
and we could keep moving just do that
well with
I'm going to go with the idea that a
type is a classification
the house may give him some data how can
I expect that data to be represented
how can I expect to be interacting with
that data
in a sense I'm going to talk about it
type
as if it was a hat therapies update at
him where
had data can wear little hat saying I
many
anarchism data can say I'm a string
and a fancy guy down the whole can fade
I make you live you I'm really pretty
look at me
the interesting thing is unlike on
people's heads
data can have multiple types the same
please update up
can wear multiple hats at the same time
host of possible there's a number ways
to look at that
one of the ways the one that is actually
interesting in the contents above
language runtime sandbaggers is for
instance the static dynamic
type distinction where all
pretty familiar I assume with the
concept of declaring a variable
we've all done that at one point or
another one of the things we do
well require viable if gimme dat
type what are we doing explicitly
liking see your objective c- all we
liked the swift compiler
in for that for us we declare a variable
and a viable hands up having type
what's left that tied deal in the
declaration
in a sense that type is telling the
compiler
to keep ass the code writers honest
when I black how the compiler that think
is an any object I'm in a sense i'm
kalin the compiler
please make sure that whenever I used
that object
i play by the rules are there any object
and as long as I do that the compiler
will be happy
and if I break the contract black told
the compiler
this is an any update keep me honest
than the compiler will complain
when I'm in run time I ever things
become a little different
let's say I wanna get the hash code for
senator al object but that object
there's a lot of different ways to get
the hash code for some think
how tough the system no wanna see your
outdoor hash
the implementation that I expect is the
one that will get cold
harassed at work well that
can't rely on the fact that that's in
any object cousin any object could
potentially be
almost and I think at that point
adjuster well choose randomly
what happens is that our reliance on the
run
time type up the object the system looks
at the
hype that that ought to the house while
my code is running at that moment
and that called a runtime dynamic type
and uses that information to decide
which
hash gets called that's the magic a
little mechanism
called dynamic dispatch
so we're here and we have are real
you're all object
I would trying to call hashing it
we sat does a hat on our URL object that
s
I'm a URL it turns off that's sort of
true
that object has I've arsov course but he
also has
type information forgot to view that
use objective-c that would-be self the
ease up on her for that object would be
to type information
what are the Finks that the type
information power
of is which Matt thoughts
that these objects type implement
and in this case one of the ones that
and I shall implement
the sample and applied is hash so we
found it
we know which cash the call and we're
done that I'm a dispatch actually worked
what if we're trying to call something
that is not
in the least a matter that that object
type implements
what we could try asking the base class
if something have the and that's your al
Haq
it probably also have the end its object
hacked
that means we can say any that didn't
work for you
as an ass a row maybe that will work for
US on a subject
and thats what happens man I'm a
dispatch we go to the base type
we try to find a method our if that
succeeds
than we found it we can tell the method
papules an option for you please
do your thing for me thank you
the same concept is also interesting
in the context of me back
let's say we have a code example like
that with a base class
with a derived class which out some
information
and we have a math out we have a
function but takes an operative the base
class
we're telling the compiler in that
function keep me on FB
and make sure all we do things that are
okay for me to do
with the base class type
but I can call with an option to the
right class can I knocked
that's perfectly OK
when I hit my break point the compiler
has the kid me on it
but the debugger doesn't have to give me
that honest actually
the very opposite I want the debugger
to tell me as much information as
possible about that
argument axe I wonder debugger to tell
me
the dynamic typeof axe because I'm that
dynamic type
rely the fact that I coulda morning
Subbaiah
that I could have changes in behavior
and indeed
that is exactly what I'll divvied up by
default
it shows you the dynamic typing a viable
spiel
similar thinks apply to
protocols is we've protocols are
pipes that means a number of things
Iman laminne means that I can be climate
variables
as of some protocol type in means that
I can declare functions they cannot
documents a protocol type
or returning upset the protocol type
by design Optional Protocol type
are leaving Egypt their constraint there
we
ollie let you play by the rules of the
protocol
that's the whole point I wanna make sure
that only do what's okay to do on the
protocol type
but again when I'm debugging I want to
see the full truth
actually want to see my implemented
object and that's what I'll be we'll
show you
let's look at an example what's a
and riding any our 40 system
and I'm product I don't think so I have
abacha previous year I have a cat and a
dog I don't have a doc how yep that is a
prototype but
I'll get that
I have a function that takes 10 Mike
Richards
and asks it replace peak your works for
me
we can hit a break point there
were in a similar situation as before
woody clarke something
we gave something a static type that is
somehow
abstract compared to the real thing that
were probably passing around time
and LDB no still figure out the dynamic
type information on our behalf
and show us that even though we sat we
want to just any creature
in that specific moment why lock code is
executing
what we got here is a poppy and a very
happy puppy for that matter
for those over you that like the LDP
console you may be tempted to try to
reproduce this result
be careful by default if you just
ask the debugger can you please show me
dis viable or protocol type
the result could get maybe a legal
disappointing
you will probably look like that
what's going up what is that that'll
look happy puppy at all
what is happening is you're seeing the
static type
we mentioned that the protocol is
somehow it limiting
object by design it once at the same
time
to make sure that you all your things
that are
declared in the protocol but you also
get the dynamic dispatching
are this operations the real object that
implements bad
the result the that is what you see on
the screen
what you want to do is you want to tell
DB
please resolve the dynamic type for me
the way to do that is with the dash deep
black 2x pressure from babble.com and
that left the debugger resolve dynamic
types
now risk you ways in which you can ask
the debugger to resolve that I am in
types
doesn't less restrictive and a more
restrictive way
sometimes in order to figure out the
dynamic type other objects
the debugger might decide that it's best
or run some code on their collars
to go watch the language runtime can you
help me out here
in that most liberal settings the run
the alarm target
are here citing you tell the debugger
okay
you can go around some could offer me I
don't think there's gonna be any problem
if you do that
just plumbing other than any type when
you're dumb place
and understanding is do not from target
in the lot in the nod from target mode
you're telling the debugger
I feel really like to know about the
dynamic type on this thing
but I've free for real not to run any
Cody mime fear process
if it turns out that you have to do that
them just don't tell me about it and I'm
a type that's okay
understand the mancation is
dad information to resolve the type will
be passed along your data
you will call it a night function within
Inc annual you're a
data will be passed to the function as
well as Medicaid up
double towel the language this is that
Inc you're dealing with
all the be can use that same information
to reconstruct the meaning of code
how does that look like
let's say we have a protocol for
producing arbitrary thinks
and then we have a concrete class that
implements the protocol that conforms to
that protocol
and it produces ins and now we have a
function
that fast I can accept any producer for
things
as long as what they produce the same if
I hit a break point
I expect to see my Jarrett result
that is indeed what happens but how does
it work
well Ltd looks at your function and in
realizes that your function takes
a generic argument be so all to be
have to look for type information to
result beat and he finds it
when you buy generic code you're going
to see a lot of these dollars with top
type: .name
special variables the special variables
carried a generic type information
there be swift object meta-data for your
generic type
armed with that knowledge 1l BBC's
the argument of type be he knows to
actually use the generic type
information
to resolve it to its actual dynamic type
we talked about a few roles about how
protocols and generics behave in swift
those are
general rules and for the most part
they apply to the black Belles a debug
build up your code
is a very very very literal translation
up the call you just broke into native
execute a ble code
the fact that it's very liberal a
translation is actually good thing for
tobacco Billy
and thats wider call the buck bales if
my code is translated literally
as an be back in through it it's really
easy for me to see the correspondence
evolution on evolution in machine code
execution
evolution in source code execution it's
really easy for the buyer to maintain
the correspondence between what he wrote
and what is actually going on at the bar
on a bar madeleine the hardware
in an optimized build your code while
maintaining the same semantics
the compiler is actually free shuffle
things
a little bit behind your back and that
means that that literal evolution a
machine code
will not correspond anymore to the same
sequence evolution of your source code
there will be staff there will be champs
data will not be doubted it was supposed
to be there
as a result of that the first rule up
the bond an optimized code
is that you dont I'm sure it's a lesson
some unions have had to learn
you probably have our ups and you
probably get box from
those outsmart by rally I'm sure
but sometimes it happens and a first
think
you should only get one of those rare
incoming box
is reproduce it in a debug build up your
app
ollie if that doesn't work
as I'm sorry tough luck you're gonna
have to be back optimized code
all the usual caveats applied has waived
and there's a couple new while that are
specific to things recovered
in the previous lights while in general
tied monotonous passed along
this with compiler is free in optimized
builds
to actually specialized away some
types some your generic functions for
some specific types
also of if the compiler can understand
what's going on with protocols
and the concrete I plan implement them
it's free to do
the virtualization to skip dynamic
dispatching indirectly calling for
implementing object
objective-c isn't really going anywhere
some love you we sat already have
elapsed
and if are likely those are written in
objective-c
but even if you start a brand new Swift
out for the first time
today after the session you're going to
use
Coco of Cocoa Touch you're going to
import
foundation import you like it those
frameworks are written in objective-c
that means wherever you look around
there's gonna be objective seeing the
picture
and you're going to have to deal with
the Bakken mixed swift and objective-c
situations
what can you expect when that happens
what can you expect to see
in the LD be in the tax code bibles mu
what to expect as you try to evaluate
expressions and yelled to be consul
what can you expect when you try to PO
your objects
the variables view goes by what's called
a mass media experience
will show you data in the language in
which the
type was first raked in in this case
which he is with three Inc and
administering side by side
and a swift training is shown at this
with three little
as your tie pins with source code the
Objective C string literal
is shown as an objective C string
literal is shown
as if as you type that same thing in
Objective C source code
in all cases data format us we'll
apply
if I'm evaluating expressions however
things
become a legal more strongly separated
expressions CQ sapper waltz
objects that exist is which frames are
all usable by Swift expressions
and the same is true for objects in
objective-c court frames
your results you're a result ables they
get to suffer namespaces
a little background on that when you
type in LB expression command
the result that expression is stored
away in the debugger generated
persistent viable
which you're very welcome three years in
subsequent expressions
the results appear objective-c
expressions well get stored in variables
name dollar zero dollar wonder what you
you get the idea
and the results are a swift expressions
will be stored in variables name
dollar r0 dollar r1 and you get the idea
let's see an example of the whole system
works
we're stopped in Coco frame the aft
command Calif
South of the frame are recurrently stop
we type
and objective-c expression because we're
in objective-c frame just be self
and we got it viable dollar 0 that
stored away
South now was pepper on
a little bit and we'll and in a swift
freight
now we like to try and use the dollar's
here a persistent variable and would
like to ride in the check to see
expression that involves at
doctor of life so well
since we're in a swift frame those with
compiler is trying to compile your swift
your
expression we just with Pentax
but that house with syntax thats
Objective C syntax
and saw the compiler gets really a happy
any mentions things like and Nani more
scores argument not contain a click here
a care must be doing something wrong
here
well what's going on is you're trying to
use P R language
and as a way for you to do that but you
have to Cali be
don't automatically infertile and you're
my expressions from the language %uh the
freemen stopped in
use the language I CaL you to use
in this example we're using the bash L
or dash national language
flag expression command when can only be
use the Objective C plus plus expression
evaluator use the clan compiler
that is inside a view to actually parse
that expression
and then that works but there's a caveat
little with the caveat your locals
will not be available since you change
your language
as we said before locals are not
available
P always in a way similar to the
expression command
but it actually want to get the result
the expression
it goes back to that martin et
experience that the parable be leaves by
swift objects will display using data
for matters
objective-c objects will display using
their description method
much like they did for before Xcode sex
second cat funny real quick
I can have is with class that in our
tennis object
and I can actually override description
for that class
in swift but if I try to PO 18 LDB
how to be will not even look at that
description I'll be will use data for
matters
and that's when I'll get because that's
a swift object
prefect we want to use my description
what if actually want to you
CD objective seaside thinks it turns out
there is a way when there's a will
there's always that way
i cant far from there and I guess I have
to ride
an expression and I guess I have to ride
and objective-c expression since I'm
trying to get in objective-c behavior
came in for help for peole an expression
I can discover that the PO behavior is
actually triggered by a flag expression
command
the dash shopper CAISO flag for object
description
and so I can guess that I need to write
an objective-c expression to get an
object description
but not much change language now i cant
you as my object local anymore
I can resort to using its address I know
it live somewhere in memory
and PO told me why leaves a memory I can
use that information
to go across the language barrier and
bring my option along with me
but but I'm not using might
local type information anymore so that a
number
for all client knows I'm asking it pay
please show me that number
I need to tell the compiler that were
actually want to see
is not the number of black 2000
something
I want the CD object at that location in
memory
the simplest way to get there just got
through it
and after all these magic
a result shows up just like that
thank you thank you
left very quickly stopped for a couple
stabbing scenario s
protocols enclosures
let's say I set a breakpoint right why
I'm trying to use one on my
creature objects and I step incorrectly
wanna see implementation
up that coated step through it and see
what's going on
it turns out that that just works
Alnylam's right why would expect
but there's one extra frame on the stack
does for frame call prodigal witness
for creature dot speak on the stack that
frame
if the protocol is the prodigal economic
dispatch frame
it's the code that is with runtime uses
between where at my call
star someone my code a month the cold
cold start executing
tracker Lipper from the namic dispatch
LD be automatically
step through it right into my coat and
if I step out
say magic happens in reverse the product
awareness frame
just disappears and I get right back
into my code
transparently and have more good news
for you
you can set breakpoints inside closures
you can expect only be two year break
fight inside your closure even if it's
an inline anonymous closure
and that's what you'll see in the Speccy
that sister Khloe juries in line and
anonymous
it's called closure number one in my
call Mike calling function
you can also expect to see your locals
even though steps even those dollar
variables that are automatically
generated by the compiler
and you never declared good news all
over the board first app Inc
now this topic is really dear to my
heart
because thats what I usually walk up
data for matters
data for matters are weighing only be to
improve the way our data show
to hide implementation details and all
we focus on the core things that matter
to you when you get back
much like we do for c-bus boss in
objective-c
we automatically format type seen as
with full ivory
you don't have to worry about that that
will happen out a medical for you
but the good news is that the mechanism
is pliable
this caller in great detail in lost your
fashion
which are welcome to watch online or on
the Ltd website
will just quickly go through example to
show that you can roll your own suite
for matters
much like you couldn't ship of loss and
objective-c
let's say we have a structure represents
a person's address
and we try to be all my address card
represented in this track
I felt horrible display but it looks
nothing like an address would look right
I want to make these more handle up like
I won this little we'll be more like I
was drying my address
on an amp I can do that with the old
B-type summary at command
the type summary at commander's lol BBS
command to say
when you're showing me a viable a beast
type here's the
at a glance information I'd like to see
shit are presented
and so we can tell Debbie you should use
the
Dyeables name you should use that name
of the person
you should use the stadium September
separatist you buy a new line since
erratic
now bought a new one in there for me
will you
and riders zip code and then after a
call in the space
can you please but the state this is the
US address format basically
and we're saying you stop for the
address object
now only pee on me again
we got something that looks a lot more
like an actual address
data for matters mission accomplished
I told us all with caveats there's a few
more
when you actually tell only be buying
this for a matter to be
type you have to use the form qualified
name
that includes the name of the module
we'll talk about that a lil bit
if you're right I'm pie dough for matter
you want to use has been valued at some
are you when asked objects for a summary
even for staying studying see our
objective c- look like basic types that
have a value like an ant or float
in swift there's a legal more intricacy
going on under the hood
so what you want to show we want to ask
if the object summary
caveat to the Ka'ba except for enough's
when you have a swift enough and you
want to figure out which cases selected
you of the value
let's talk about game uniqueness
let's say you you guys are running an
awesome objective-c up
and as a really good framework that will
help make you so much more productive
its four-dot framework of course Ford of
framework has developers were
really good tasting class name Inc their
case Inc last name is so good that they
came up
we have a really nice last name
unfortunately this guys have to go to a
taste for their own good
a little while later the developer some
another great framework
bardot framework came up with the same
super
classname now the resolve this
if not nice at all the result of this is
on the fine
a few frameworks with the same class
with the same name
trying to correct this in the same up at
the same time that's not nice but on the
fun
you don't get to choose which class gets
actually loaded
is with that's got
smoke
thank you swift provides uniqueness
among function overloads and among
classes in different frameworks
the way to that all this good mashed
is a Fisher cold Mangal names family
only come from c-bus class
and may be familiar with that already
let's talk about it
distill guys and they're both runs with
colored better know about each other
but they bought think that my class is
the best name ever for a class
I don't agree with that but that's their
choice
they want the summit there go to those
with compiler
the first guy goes on and off it
as a result he gets a compiled version
of this code
war his class is actually called
something my mom you my class
we go back to that in a second when the
second I doubt that
the same thing to try to compile
his class actually gets called something
modern to my class
now they don't clash anymore Marshall
won my class model to my class
there's a little price to pay not if I
actually look at the screen and seal
what the name of the class became a
linkage time
it's cold underscore copper King St
lower case T copper Casey Saban
module one Saban Mike loss
and that's just for the guy in the class
now
the wall is actually a scary place
sometimes
what if you are out there in the wild
roaming through a dark straits
and out a little alley a mangle name
came right at you
that could happen while you're enough
you're just sitting there in Interface
Builder doing things and
orgasm angle named are or worse even
your app just crashed not all you're
gonna crash report a window
you're also got a mantle names and our
doesn't get much worse than that
X abt swifty mandel comes to the rescue
thrifty mando is a little told them
chips relax code:
the black sea bass is the input on the
command line one or more swift Mangal
names
and be magically provide to the mangled
version
so fear no more and congressman rangel
names in dark Alice
this is a magical modulus this is the
magical modulus
in the context all name uniqueness on
avoiding clashes
models can do a lot more for out
motorcycle he make debugging
alarm or of some why
how let's look at it I have
source code for my up returns with
I give it to those with compiler
the output up that process is an op
and Marshall information wife extreme
porn on the model information
while it turns out that much like it
contains a copy of Clank
only contains a copy of the swift
compiler inside
and that's yours of course a Sparta
expression evaluation for swift
but there's a little more for the story
now when I try to debug that out
the call dropped the compiler we'll
actually be able to in purple
to ingest the model information for
compiled up
wife that's so important let me give you
a legal perspective on what happens when
you compile a nap for debugging
and then to try to debug it when you
tell the compiler
any compiler a let's go we climbed
example
when you tell Clank police compile map
for the bike Inc
what clanged off is it ingests your code
as usual
it understands it recorded gets a man
told model on it in some sense
then you tell Klein gimme in formation
to hold me back my up
but that process stuff is generates
dewar
wharf is a format used specifically for
containing the bag information so clang
get an understanding of the type system
of your up it takes that understanding
it translates 8
into a different format dwarf
the debugger LDB than in Jaz
that dwarf information and hes still
recreate an understanding on the type
system of your app
the way LDB doubt that is it generates
climate types
outer door hold on a sec
so what your kalin me here is basically
that clan
generates client types outta my source
code
that it translates that into war that
LDB consumes the dwarf
and generates Klein pipes back
why only be really nice if
allenby could directly understand the
compiler notion of types
but only big crate if we didn't have the
intermediate steps
and the compiler part is your source
code understands it
create some representation of the types
it's all representation of the types in
your app
and the debugger get things that same
representation
that's certainly seems nice it certainly
seems that for our house
that have to actually ride the debugger
which keep one step we can directly use
the compilers notion of the trip
it's also really nice for you note to
users: up to the doctor
the reason well there's a couple of
reasons
the obvious one is that if we could do
that
never be no potential for loss of
information in different place from
process
week what we will go from source clan
types
dwarf clang types to source
types types while I stopped wearing
permission and your loss
that is what happens in swift
this rift compiler generates a Marshall
which is
the compilers understanding up the proof
over your program
at the time he was being compiled
I will debase copy others with compiler
in Jax that model information
and can use it to reproduce the type
system that the compiler was staying at
the time your program was being compiled
there's no law some information and
there's no need for the intermediate
step
on recreating the types from back from
nor
there's one more advantage
some of you every 10 see boss boss code
and you're probably years
generics for that situation
I'm sure a ball right into it you tried
to use some generic function
and ok you actually in the year starting
your source program
and now eileen is complaining are you
trying to use this function which is
really weird name
that is not present in the target
it turns out for that what happened in
swift
fish generics are actually typed that
the compiler understand nakedly
and since we have the compilers barry
own understanding of the truth
now we get Avery type and every function
through model information
even though she did not using your
source code and even generic once
there was a lot of ground cover today
if you remember one thing from the
fashion
well there's always comments but no luck
that's not the thing I wanted to
remember
you can choose your language and hourly
be will be there
every step of the way with helpful
investigation tools
what are your it up rather using use
with feature so you buy your existing
code base
the helpful fissures in the debugger
will be there to help you make your op
are some we talked about a bunch of
topics
we talked about Smith types that being
data for matters
much of and probably a more on that
be important thing years your feedback
matters a lot to us
I've been in the labs last couple days
I've read the blog spear last couple a
base
and I've gotten from I've seen from you
guys
some amazing feedback i've seen the
great things have started doing is
waived
included a floppy birds up in swift i've
seen that
we've got an email store people power
amazing things about how they expect
this new tools to change their lives to
make their programming batter
keep that coming your feedback matters a
lot to us
let us know what we're doing great let
us know what we can do better
and of course thank you everyone i win
thank you