good afternoon everyone are you guys
doing
now
battery go I could manage open so that
was on owned
but I want so I this session is called
I what's new in Interface Builder as we
were joking earlier maybe
what isn't new interface bowler we have
all kinds a great stuff you guys
today and so my name is Kevin Kathy and
one in Interface Builder engineers
and me in my colleague Quinn will be
joining us later I can be walking you
through
sum up what's new now we're gonna show
you some stuff that you
might not have seen yet Rossana go into
more detail about some other things that
you
have seen so far at this conference so
what we have
today is completely falls in a couple
themes themes that you really have to
and from the US so far in the conference
the first one is is live NIS now to know
about you but I like seeing
when I'm working on so as I work on my
code we have teachers to bring
your content your code your custom stuff
right into the interface for campus I
think we really want to help you guys
get to start your vision faster
and to have some fun while you get to
you next is adaptability
I'm love this about our platforms is all
the places
that your abs can run let's think about
we got iPhone iPad
Portrait Landscape OS 10 iowa's and then
throwing all the languages to you
you love getting those bugs that are
like hey this is buggin this language
and I look at my cup
I haven't heard that language I think
that some that's great about our
platforms as an
and as application developers reply all
well aware of this
third is power in parity
I O S and almost 10 if taken some great
step storyteller this year
and I think one of the places that this
is really illustrated best
is in interface polar and so we've got
some tools to help you
seamlessly work between a both of our
platforms using really familiar
technologies and workflows
so what's your plan for today how how we
gonna do this
well my coworkers are in an app and then
he conveniently
left for vacation this weekend so he
didn't have a chance to finish it so
were gonna finish perform on stage I'm
is there a nickname
the app is actually about going on
vacation and sharing your photos while
you're on vacation
and rating those and so we really have
to look at my coworkers photos as he
enjoyed a drink by the beach
and Quinn I give this presentation so we
have a list oversight see a little
ring and outside is showing the kinda
popularity
that particular destination Hawaii in
London
probably great places got never actually
bend you know those
but I New York prolly not the most fun
place to visit
must be that the peace that just isn't
as good a Chicago now by tapping on the
site in a slide over your slideshow I
can rate my photos
and then here's the iPad version and you
might notice a fuel differences here so
for one we have a caption
and into that ratings POW sheik moved
over to the side there
I'm also photo nerd so I love to know
how you took your photo
so if you capital detailed but you gonna
pop over with some location data on
things like
the shutter speed enough stop so
I think the best way to do this is just
a jump into a demo and start making this
app awesome
alright so I have my storyboard here
and I have a the mockup that I showed
you earlier from my designer this is
kind of a reference and will use that as
we go through our presentation
some terms a strategy and and Scott
starting your app that the thing I like
to do personally as I to get all my
views laid out first
and then kinda fill in the custom
content so let's start by adding
constraints for our table he saw here
this out this box this list is going to
be our that circle ty love you
that will fill in all that there's a
couple ways to add content and interface
bowler
why I can just easily controlled rag to
Avoca spacing constrain
for this view I can also use the
constraint pop over here
and this gives me some additional
features reno the pic concentrate on the
fly
pick a different object to constrain to
things like that
Southern art i love u has got position
and heights what about wit well we can
add an explicit with constraint but then
for real change that highlight he will
use of Google update in all these
different spots
so what I really want to express is just
that this view
should have the same with is the same
height this is not new since last year
which the military aspect ratios
with the towel you now in the in the
spot that we won it was working these
labels
sums gonna grab the labels dragging up
in a spot in my in the position here
and I can create multiple constraints
that one seizing control drag
by holding the Shift or the command key
in a sitting return
now if I look back at my mock-up you can
see that
the text is really not centered but I'll
be it's it's come at the bottom of the
taxes in the center
love this particular target you so now
we can do
new since last year's we can actually go
ahead and change the attributes involved
in my constraint
but is open up the attributes inspector
for my constraint
you can see now I can see the items and
their attributes
and I can just go ahead and changes from
center why to bottom
which is gonna move it down to the other
side but one thing you'll notice
is that didn't do exactly what I
expected so what's going on here
all the things that I notice is that I
was thinking about in terms of the label
not in terms the view so nothing that
our inspector gives us the ability
to reverse the keys to the constraint in
a way that makes sense to you
let me and you that change and if I open
it up again
icons like reversed first and second
item at this puts the constraint is
mathematically equivalent to the other
constrain but I can't express it in a
way that makes sense to me
and now i can say okay the labels bottom
should be at the views center why
now one field that you might have
noticed here is the multiplier
so this is what enables things like
aspect ratios and also proportional
sizing constraints
and as a couple different ways I can
insert a multiplier depending on my
situation
so I'm thinking it about it in terms of
an aspect ratio I could do something
like
124 and you can see that now that labels
bottom is one is in a ratio of one to
four with the center wire that
might i love you but you know what
fractions might make more sense to me
are you the fraction instead so good
just type in a fraction
or of course decibel numbers are also
Africa was well
so our title labels now in the right
spot close to the sublevel
sucking this track is in a position
aum's gonna do two more constraints
to get my views all a doubt and I can
show this by resizing my table you now
want things I love about getting to show
Xcode is giving you guys a few tips and
tricks for being even more productive in
Xcode so this is going to be
pro chip number one if I hold shift when
I right click
in the campus it'll give me a menu
everything into the mouth
at the point that I clicked Savannah
quickly get to my table view cell
I just do that and select the nominee up
if I resize my table view cell you can
see those constraints
budding exactly what I want I'm ahead on
be that change
alright so with our views in place for
ready to start filling in that custom
view
and you've already seen a our custom
custom views features are a couple
different times
but I'm gonna do now I'm gonna show you
the steps necessary
to have your content showing up in
Interface Builder from start
to finish and show you I mean really how
easy it is
the first thing we need to do you step 1
to 4 as recreate
a custom framework remarks on OS 10 in
our new and I last with I was
8 someone to jump my product editor here
and Melissa target on add a new target
we won a Cocoa Touch framework so I'm
gonna call this
site rate kitten ever Abbas the site
rate
am choosing to in but this in my eye was
applications in it two things one
it in a link my application against this
framework and 21 application built in a
copy that framework
into the Apple let's go ahead and create
that framework
and that's it I have a custom framework
and its already for me
now step number two and getting your
content to show up in Interface Builder
is to create
a subclass you I view more an issue if
you're on the Mac
sucking this right-click on my group ear
choose new file
I wanna coca touch class I'm gonna call
this
site tile view
so classy idea or any you Swift is our
language
so make sure this is add to the right
target will make you at your framework
target
and now our class is created so to step
down already
the third step is to tell Interface
Builder that this class
can display custom content and interface
bowler
and I can do that by Martin the class as
at
I B desirable if I Nana
in object if I'm in objective-c
the attribute this looks like that
so step three is done a class is
desirable our framework is created
and the final step is to simply tell
Interface Builder
that and instanceof a above you in my
storyboard
should actually be this class something
back to the storyboard
shooting the recent files here
and on the go ahead and select might our
view
I open the identity inspector and I can
just type in
that tile you class that I just created
you have a similar law to compete for me
and now that's
everything I have to do to get my
content showing up in interface polar
it's super super easy now for something
so not because they haven't written the
code
but were kept their so speaking at what
was actually
now go ahead and create some code for
our view so I wanna show the code for my
view side by side of my storyboard
and that's really easy about to open my
class
I'm gonna show you another Xcode pro
chip number to you
if I options like this file many be no
that'll
open in a new assistant or in a new tab
based upon how your preferences are set
but I hold options shift
and click I can watch user view
and this user allows me to pick the
destination up where I want this file to
open
I can target a new split a new tab a new
window I can even target
splits in tabs are even open so very
very flexible to get
to open the file
I'm integrated a new split side by side
with my storyboard
alright so there's a couple different
ways that you can create your custom
views
and when it burns at today's were gonna
create a custom view by composing at
I've smaller components in these
compounds are you there
sub use like you I label you an
ImageView or layers
morning use layers today if I were to
implement dry rack
that's ok I guess the best performance
whereas using some players and some
views is gonna get us
really good performance things go and
delete this code here
and we're gonna start trading our view
if we go back to market here
by working on this on these rings on the
outside
summer start with this this gray ran in
and fill it in with the colored one
what create a in New shape layer
comes for the property you can see if
the mean Erica need
import module for that contains the
coronation classes
an hour create this thing a really
convenient place to create this
as in a is an honest is an override love
layouts abuse
for someone to call super which will
make sure to on my studies have the
right size
and Anna by having created the
ringleader yet I'm gonna go ahead and
create one at it
Tulare my view then of course
wanna make sure that we position in the
right place
now have a Larry Watson let's do
something interesting with them my
clothes the
utility area to get myself a lot more
space
so what's crib is a path and we're just
gonna make this be a circle
animate set this as the shape I love my
shapewear and their interpersonal
they're showing me the result
have my code so far
response super fast which is great so
i'd
not only one a solid circle right on a
crater rim and sews
CA ship player has a feature that allows
minute to struck the outside
love the up the path and sauna and turn
off the fill color
that align with and set the struggler to
block now because my content is showing
live interface Miller
I can see that I'm already made a
mistake flows are you familiar with
Betty a path you know that
when you have a stroke happen that draws
outside the path unhappy the
inside the path so actually wanna inset
my path
by half for the line with now I know I'm
use my line with the lots with create
new property for
and now I can inset my rectangle
by that amount and make sure to use in
boss box
and now my shape is looking much better
the last thing I want to do is wanna
filled in with that
color that our designer gave us all feel
than an and
how it looks much really really light
mmm machines this to you .3
designers aren't always right certain
not hiring layer I I love all our
designers
another ring wear for the background
looking pretty good looks with autumn
autumn color
obviously the exact same thing pretty
much the only difference I'm gonna do
with other ring layer
isn't gonna rotated by 90 degrees so
that when we fill an R rating it's going
to come from
the top of the circle not other side so
I wanna drive my
reshape player now by an actual ratings
let's create a new property
which is the rating and now one actually
update or layer based upon its rating so
many use the feature apps
I've CA shapewear the Austin is set the
kind of the progress on the stroke
I'm gonna do a new method because I'm
gonna call the thrown up by two
different spots
so one of the spots that
I'm going to call is from its from
changing the rating itself
it couldn't be easier now to react to
property changes
with sweats new property observers so
all you have to do
is just say that when this rating
did did change I can just go ahead and
call that method
that updates my shapewear
and I'm also gonna call it and then if
you're just in case we have an actual
change those properties yet
and now my ship layers lookin
exactly how I want it so far now it's
really common when you creating
and different types I love custom views
on have properties that you expose
that people can change to defer your
code or even with Interface Builder
and interfacial to make that really easy
with a new feature called inspect ables
so if I got to mine rating
property here and market as IBM's
spectacle this is the flag for interface
better that says hey
this property I want you to show in
Interface Builder just like
all the other properties but you had it
on your views so I jump back to Xcode
and I open the inspector you can see
that rating is
is shown up and I can edit it and it
reflects instantly
in the campus you might be wondering
what can I use of Instructables you can
use
all kinda different prop different types
for Instructables
by the way in spectacles works is that
you might wanna we're we're just all the
data gets stored
and spectacle takes advantage up the
user-defined runtime:
attributes that we've had for couple
releases their Facebook her
you can see that the rating I just set a
showing up here
now it's important that we are using
user-defined on hand after beachfront
spectacle because it means that you
don't have to worry about where to store
this data
and how to encode it we take care all
that for you at design-time
and at one time the different types that
I can use sprint spectrum or anything
supported by user-defined runtime:
attributes
bullion strings numbers be
valuable like him points and sizes and
racks in
even images which is new this year
love it so instructive laws are I think
are great for exposing properties a view
that you can edit
but I think it's also really helpful for
helping you
developed your views so there's there's
two ways that I see this
the first thing as it helps you to
validate the changes that you're making
especially easy experimenter ng with new
types of things
so I wanna change the color my rating
based upon how good that rating is
red means you can better catch up angry
maybe
well done so let's go ahead and change
the
the the color a bar stroke based upon
that rating and I'm using a new
switch statement and swift to accomplish
this
and I can see the Interface Builder is
doing
the right thing in terms the color now
I'm a switchback interface Plus ICANN
edit the inspector bill and I'm gonna
show you Xcode project
number three I like to navigate summed a
lot of times without the mouse
and I can't jump around with in Xcode
and put the focus in different
editors using command J
if I had command J give me a little
chooser and I can pick which
editor I wanna have focused so in this
case I wanna jump focus back
to the interface with the editor so I
can just go ahead McMahon J
a pic to primary return and now you can
see I'm seeing my inspectors
from her face further I can jump to New
the attributes inspector with Command
Option
for not killed in focus and I can
tryout our colors and everything looks
to be behaving
as expected
now the the next place that I can a
that I can use in spectacles in terms of
in terms of a playing with my views is
is also in just
X spearmint thing with different types
the values
so I haven't decided yet on my on my
line with im
10 might work it might not be the right
thing so what smart that as inspector
Paul
I'm gonna jump back Interface Builder
using command J
that line with the showing up in my
service try new value 12 low then is
pretty thick
to assist known come back down here five
little small
not sex sickle pretty good to me so very
very easy to Xperia man
with your custom views when using them
with an interface bowler
now I'm also gonna show you just how
live these views are
gonna go ahead and resize my table you
again
and you can see as on resizing it it's
just
perfectly real redrawing my view its
interacting with that just like
any other view that's an inner science
and Interface Builder
may go ahead and and undo that change
okay so our rings are looking pretty
good let's go ahead and fill not image
someone to create a new
layer for my image montana declare
property that I can set from my code
update the image
now I wanna put in image in there and so
let's go ahead and set that on our lair
might come back down to our
lehrer properties here
and actually and on the thing I wanna
create this inside there are property so
what's actually go ahead and do that
enough create the lair for somebody that
inside a bar layouts abuse
it's looking a lot better as a better
place to do it blood update it down here
in our
our lair properties so you can see her
face bowlers
on doing as I'm just done drawing a
square and I'm drawing a circle masking
it
and now we can set image as the contents
up that squarely are behind
so what's getting image to set inside if
you're now
I don't wanna ship any images with my
actual
framework the images that I use for
testing right is that would just blow
the framework
what I'd like to do is be able to
reference an image it's in my project
without actually putting it
in a target and Interface Builder
provides
a great place to do this in a great way
to do this through prepare for interface
polar
so this is a method but it's called
after you your
views are initialized incentive
Interface Builder and allowed me to do
any kind design time setup
against only gets called the design-time
now I have some
images in my products and test images
unleashed onto you
over here in this folder and these are
in any target their descent images that
my designers gave me to help me test to
make sure that my app is doing the right
thing
wanna go on reference wannabes by owner
so I could I could pass a
you know an absolute path then generate
image but i wanna do in a way to make
sense for my entire team
so Interface Builder will actually pass
the paths
to your projects through the environment
and allow you to actually take advantage
have
the resources in your project
so let's go back here and let's go ahead
and look at what that looks like so
inventive our environment there's an IV
project source directories
string that's just a bunch of product
directories
concatenated with the colon and I can
split those up
and go ahead and actually get the
strings
so I only have one project path summers
gonna go ahead and grab the first one
and I can get the path relative to my
project
just by a pending that test images and
that that image name
and then we can go ahead and create the
image
and it should him it should show up
here any second hi well this isn't
exactly looking right to me i i think a
a
I think I musta missed something gonna
be great if I could do but my view right
McAmis
well with my views you can so I'm gonna
set a breakpoint
on my image here go back to interface to
learn slut might how do you
and from the editor menu I can to select
debug selected views
and this is going to attached to
Interface Builder
and allow me to actually debug might be
did
debug my custom you just like any other
debug session
so I can see here the the looks like I'm
getting inside here some I'm getting the
project path
let's go ahead and not let's go ahead
and sand step over
not see it but the images you can see
the LDB is automatically praying out the
fact that this is an optional tight at
the optional hide actually has something
in it
footsie with that images and yep sure
enough we got image
so what's going wrong here only put a
breakpoint
reaction center image contents and the
to continue
and hmm interesting
mother never actually gets call but I
must be doing is a must-have for Don to
actually
update my image property when are my
image layer when the image property
changes
if I stroll up now yup sure enough I
forgot to use
a property observer to make sure that my
image
prop layers and get updated when image
changed and there you go
so Interface Builder provides lot two
different ways
for you to be able to design your views
using my prepare for Interface Builder
knees I B project source directories
you can see your custom images you can
you can debug them
but there's even more you can do let's
go ahead and close the deal by Gary here
I'm gonna jump over to different view
controller now
and we have this rating view which is
showing us the number of stars
for are particular image now this
rating view has an inspector Paul it's
called star rating
I'm gonna go ahead and change this to
3.5
and when I zoom back out and zoom
instead on our rating layer
you can see now now that that that label
there's overlapping
our star well why is that well we have
this explicit width and height constrain
so that the rating he doesn't have a
chance to grow to whatever size it is
sotsass go and delete this we need 'em
so can delete those not Interface
Builder is hopefully telling me
that my views and the US it doesn't have
enough constraints
now for those you familiar with on a
layout you know that there's a method
called intrinsic content size which
allows reduced the fine
a size to fit size from my view why can
take advantage in that
right inside interface bother if we go
back to our
we got our rating view class and I'm
gonna ok not using open quickly
site rating view and use my little
option shift to target the assistant
here
most drawn to the bottom of the file at
our new could
sovereign are intrinsic on inside method
and now
Interface Builder is 12 recognized that
matter there it's gonna call just like
it normally would at runtime and now
it's showing me
that my view can grow to fill the size
the stars and the interns account in
size
my label and I can just put it right the
place
and it's also time with my view is now
no longer ambiguous
I'm all good to go its executing my code
and use in and turned the content size
override
to figure out which constraints need to
be there
now for those who are pixel
perfectionists you might realize
but that caption is actually one point
of
from this label on terms are being
aligned
I'd like to be able to align these two
things by their baseline but
my rating due to the custom you have
stuff inside the villa how to lie
aligned by the baseline what can
override another
method on an on you I'd even an issue
called you for baseline layout and I'm
gonna return the label
thats internal to my custom view and now
Interface Builder is showing me
that this view now has a baseline
running right to the baseline
my label and if I delete the centering
in three I might caption
I can this dragon here and you can see
it snapping right to the baseline
that custom view that I just created
entirely
in code
not go ahead and finish this off by
baseline
aligning these to you to these two views
so it'll look and see you using live
using some other things that you can use
to make some really cool he was I'm
really looking for to seeing what you
guys
what you guys do sup
the four steps that you need to do to
get your custom content and Interface
Builder
one create a framework wanted to create
a framework in the first place
the way that this feature works is that
when you define a class is designed a
ble
interface dollars going to build your
friend Mark target
to launch hopper process gonna
dynamically load your framework into
that whole process
and then interact with that and this
also helps
keep you from the mistakes that least
that I make while writing code
which is something like a crash that way
you don't have to you can see what the
areas were having to suffer from it
secondly you create a subclass a view I
view
either with objective-c or was swept
third you mark it as desirable I wanted
to say a quick note about
and spectacles well while desirable
is a feature of this custom views
feature you can use inspector balls
with out having a desirable class you
can add Inspector Morse to any of your
classes
but you interact with an interface
Miller and most traders properties in
the inspector
and finally you just hook up your custom
view with
the classic you just created live you'd
like to do all kinds of things you can
see your custom drawing
you can have custom John a tree interact
with that one that I didn't show you can
also provide
the line it wrecked insets that are on
both I was a nice tan
you gonna bite your views right McAmis
and you can also use several mechanisms
for interacting with your co design-time
I showed you prepare for interface
bowler but another one is this target
conditional
target interface bother and you can use
this with pound F
cue either opt code in or out of my
views
so for example you might have some
server connection code that you don't
wanna run when you're
incentive interface bowler sickness opt
out using the target conditional
out to show you some new our layout
features since last year
now we want to do is we want to add
iPhone support to our
our application my coworkers had time
for iPad support
and our goal is that we use a single
story board to do this and this is made
possible because it a feature called
size classes size classes the future I
was
a.m. Xcode 6 the largest specify how
your view controller near you I adapt
as the available size for your view
controller changes
well let me win it I'll walking through
an example what's the story with some
you control over some with some size and
it grows to some new size
what's important here is not the point
size
I love your view controller either in
the smaller bigger
configuration what's important is the
magnitude of the change
small verses big this magnitude is
called a size class
a size cost and have one of two values:
compact think small
a regular think bigger any given time a
view controller is gonna have to size
classes
one horizontally and one berkeley making
a
total number of combinations for saw
them in a concrete example
so I have are you I hear and when we're
in landscape on the iPhone I do like
that bottom bar
to tighten up a little bit to make more
room for those those images
so we can do is in the configurations
are four configurations
for where that bar are where the new
controller is in a more compact
Berkel environment we can to set that
constant the thirty
and the bigger one thing to 52 iraqi
right
well kind of if you notice I have to
specify the value twice
and this is gonna make it really hard to
make and it's in the future you make
hard to maintain my app is ever gonna
make a change and make it into places
so Interface Builder exposes a third
value in a size class called any
and any is simply as its name suggests
either on the size classes so I can say
that I want that 32b for
any horizontal class I don't care what
the witness
all i care is about the height which is
compact what the fifty-two
well I could also put it in any for
regular but we're I really wanna put it
is an any any this is the default
configuration
this says that it doesn't matter which
device or which
oren tation what the site in my view
controllers I want to use these values
and this from the really important
strategy is your divine that designing
your applications
you wanna do as much homework in any any
as possible
and then use branch out to those more a
more specific configurations as needed
and this is going to make your app
much more maintainable and much more
adaptable
now that's great if you can become
really familiar because this is a
actually exactly how we expose switching
between the different configurations
inside the tax code
and let me show you how that works
alright so we're back in our our lovely
story more here
and the first thing I'm gonna do in the
storyboard unable five classes
me go ahead and open up the documents
factor here and check size classes now
two things are going to happen
one if your document isn't using our
layout we're gonna try an all out for
your
and then secondly it's going to upgrade
all your segways to the new
adaptive segways nama talk about that
all that
sore enable size classes and immediately
we're seeing the result the designing
and it's great flexible adaptable
environment
are you can chars are showing a square
to help reinforce that you're not as any
for a specific
spur tickler device but rather for the
public their size
are magnitude of size a view controller
so the first thing that we want to do is
wanna take that bar and make it a little
sis
a little bit narrower or shorter I
when are height is one hour
sinus go ahead and put the canvas into
a configuration are gonna do that so
this is the first thing with size
classes
is transitioning through the different
configurations it's really easy
if I open up this control here in the
bottom of the campus
you can see was that grid that we're
seeing earlier in this lovely the pic
which configuration and adding
when I pick a configuration data its
gonna resize the view controllers
for that particular configuration to
reflect that and now
any edits that I make inside this
particular configuration
will be customized for that
configuration
let's go ahead and do that now further
the constant the high constant on our
bar
thank you handsome like this now I could
double-click to edit this constraint but
its element it is I'm gonna open a site
inspector
and you can see here all the constraints
for my bar
well I really just wanna see the ones
that are being defined by my parent to
composition and size this summer's gonna
filter the constraints down to those
and furthermore was gonna look at size
constraints
then to change the constant just click
once
type in 30 return and now I've customize
my bar
for any compact
you can see the result that if I switch
back to any any here
and jabar grew back to that taller
height so really really easy
to make customization between
configurations now the second thing
about size classes I want to say is
well what's customizable between
configurations therefore things that are
customizable between configurations
one that can change a constraint
constant to have to change the font
3 I can change the whole sets the
constraints I can turn off an entire
city constraints a
my portrait constraints and turn on a
whole other set say my landscape
constraints
and forth I can also customize sub use
turning them honor of this is different
from hidden
wanna do is just hidden it still
participating in layout
but when I uninstall the constraint
using soccer the using size classes
actually takes out in the view hierarchy
so I can have new supply constraints
forty an example that now what I don't
have a lot of
horizontal space I wanna turn off this
rating
so I'm gonna go ahead but the campus
into you
compact with an I don't really care what
I did is it can
not be as tall or short is is that is it
needs to be
and you can see for a while at that
looks pretty bad
so it's going internet caption of when I
wanna turn to subdue of a configuration
its really just as easy as turning off
the constraints that configuration and
then turn in the view of itself
when I use the constraint commands are
in this menu they're gonna apply again
for just this configuration
let's go ahead just clear the concerns
for this view and now we can
uninstall from this configuration I can
do this using the inspector on a per
view instance
or really quick shortcut for not done is
just
command early and command early will
just turn off in its configuration
delete will delete it and all the
configurations
I also wanna go ahead and remove those
constraints I can dislike the constraint
command early not turn it off and I can
add new constraints for justice
configuration
so I'd like to take this rating view in
a line it horizontally in my container
how many use the new are not the new
they had just the existing alignment pop
over here
much use horizontal Center in container
I'm not change when these
monitors update frames nice mind on
wanting what this is
this allows when you're adding you can
new constraints the
values that you're an ass constraints
for might not be the actual values that
are currently reflected in the canvas
for example I wanna adCenter
in my bottom bar but Mike view clearly
isn't centered on the bottom bar
so I can tell interface with her hey
when you add these constraints just go
ahead and put the views
and those new locations another these
options allow me to do
all frames just it update it for the
whole view controller and items at new
constraints
this is helpful if you're in the middle
of doing a lot of different constraint
surgery and you just wanna move one or
two news
but I do in this case menu all the
frames in my view controller
you can see at that constrain crushed
and it slides that rating view
right on over
and if we go back to any any wallach
with customized are interface across two
different configurations
very very easily and let's see what this
looks like at runtime
I don't build run my application
there showing up I can rotate it you can
see that bars automatically adjusting
and on iPhone because its compact you
can see that that caption isn't showing
now one thing I haven't talked about her
pointed out yet is it may be something
you guys are wondering you're saying hey
you headed
you have an iPad storyboard wait a
second I thought but you can sure in
there I saw that you had to replace a
great other you had a popover segue
how's that working on iphone what the
new adaptive view controller API
in iowa's 8 all the wonderful system
classes that you've come to know and
love
work on both iPad an iPhone and the way
that it works is that they adapt their
environment based upon that available
size:
so for example are split you controller
incentive showing side by side because
the environment is more compact
it's actually it's gonna push my detail
onto my master
when I'm in a more compact environment
like an iPhone
similarly with my popover segue
into being a pop over an iPhone it's
been turned into
a model without me writing any code and
this has to do with those new
adaptive segue types let's take a look
at those now
device like this popover segue here
and go over to the attributes inspector
you can see it when a new present as pop
over segue Smith won a new adapter
segways
let's take a look at other adaptive
segways we have show as a replacement
for example for push
and what show in show detail does is it
looks at the context that your end the
decide
what to do so for example a spot you
can't rely on iPad can actually replace
the detail if you have
Avery a show detail but an iPhone its
gonna push that
detail side onto the master now it's
really cool about this
at this is dead accomplished by using
two new you I view controller selectors
showed you control and show detail view
controller you can
override these for custom containers and
you can designers containers in
Interface Builder senator segways
and it's just going to work at runtime
dinner two types are present morally in
print as pop over
and these are using the present new
controller
API into the present model view
controller that was allowed to take
advantage of the new
presentation controller ATI
which is a new object when you use
present you control or you can do things
like
make sure that the custom transitions
that you have are all coordinated
along with the animations which is
really really great
sewer use profanities popover which will
allow
our presentation you controller
to automatically adapts now if I go back
to mine
storyboard here you can see there's
there's no button for closing this
and so I could if I had time I could go
ahead and add this
and you're welcome back on the labs and
I'll show you how to do this but with
the new adaptive you controller API
but I can do as I can take advantage up
some other overriding delegate methods
to do things like for example in this
case I can say when this pop over
segue gets fired go ahead unwrapped love
you can show that you're presenting
in a navigation controller at a bar item
and then just an iPhone its initial Mia
Done button
that I can use to close my close that
modal view controller
but one on iPad maturing as a popover
why don't need that so what show it
very very cool for being able to create
great gaps between both
iPhone and iPad
3 talked about size classes and again
size classes a
really great technology they'll make it
really easy for you guys
to create these experiences both for
iPhone and iPad
all within the same story board I also
talked about the new
adaptive segue types and we really want
you guys to use his new adapter segue
types consider make your application
be able to you hands as their name
suggests adapted very easily
between a different types of
environments them I run in out a point
that you can use
custom content you can create custom in
Tanner's and use those use those schoen
show detail view controller methods
to customize exactly how those you can
charge a mere presented
you have a sliding view controller some
might that you can build all that now
with an interface bother what I want to
do now is have my colleague can come up
you can show you even more stuff at noon
if it smaller and hopefully tell them
better job than I did
Quinn
cry thank you Kevin someone is Quinn
Taylor I'm also an engineer
on the Interface Builder team such a
fantastic team and I hope you can feel
how much hard work we've done to bring
to you guys will love these new features
and I can't wait to tell you about a few
more them
so first I for one talked about asset
catalogs we introduced asset catalogs
last year with Xcode 5
and they're fantastic way to manage
resources inside your application
both for I O S and 40 S 10 won the first
new features
that we've added to asset catalogs in a
2006 is support for size classes
as kevin has just been demonstrating to
you you can easily adapt your user
interface
for compact a regular height or width
now noticed that we have new field in
the inspector
when you've selected image yes a catalog
that allow you to customize the same way
now if you select on these for example
will customize on compact with
you'll see the new rose appear that
allow me to optionally specify
new images that will be used if I'm in a
compact with scenario
so any images that you don't actually
specify for a specific configuration
will be inherited
from a specific configuration just as
kevin was talking about with
any any so is a fantastic feature
die-cast mice
second alignment support so there may be
occasions where you have an image
provided to you by a designer
that doesn't fill the entire space if
the image for example may have a glow
effect
are some other padding that did that
because it to be inset
and now you can also the show that
information convey that
inside interface builder any asset
catalogs and this will correspond to the
alignment wrecked properties on either
an S image for you I image
and you can specify alignments from any
the four edges the fantastic
and next is image formats so when we
launched ethic headlines last year
we supported PNG images so we've heard
request first thing was added as support
for Jay pic images
from a you love you to take images this
can be really handy when you have
resources that might be large and
compress better with Jay picked in the
european chicks you can save space your
application
an effort that's great second is PF
vector images and he's a great as well
so this estimate value um this is a
fantastic way
tooth to to specify an image that will
scale automatically
to your different scales and resolutions
when you're building the an acid
catalyst for I West
those vector images we're asked arrived
to the correct resolutions and scales
at build time on the west end however
their preserved at runtime and I'll even
appear at scale
for printing which as a really cool
bonus and you're also able to mix and
match bitmap and vector images
for any particular asset and last to
support for template images
Matthew mention this a bit on Monday
template images allow an image to be
to be treated however the stencil in
your in your application
so you get kind of a highly a outline
effect
and traditionally this is done by
detecting whether the finance and
template
and now we give you the ability to
override this but default behavior
directly in Interface Builder and nasa
catalogs so
at suppressing catalogs next you've seen
a few new class and has had about
West End from it as visual effects you
is a brand new class
in Austin yosemite you've seen a
pervasively for the system by
Notification Center
behind your your menus and Manjinder
source list and so on
you'll see effects like blurring
translucency vibrancy
punch their effect in masking and you
can bring these own this
the same effect to your own applications
visual effects view is supported
completely in Interface Builder and you
can have your own
custom views participate in virus the
effects by overwriting
allows vibrancy method on an issue you a
view much more information about how to
integrate this
definitely check out the session on
adopting new features view I
and your semi on video next
you've heard where the new system
fundraise talk about this the great news
is for you
you have to do anything use the system
font it's going to work after next
couple take a review
so you don't have any worries on that
front speaking to finance
I was custom fonts many view you're
already excited
a share your enthusiasm for a couple
releases now you've been able to use
custom fonts
in your IRS applications you can put
them in your project and happened your
bundle
and now we're adding support for being
able to pick those funds directly in
Interface Builder
and have been shot McAmis life for you
so here I just miss fonda they look
pretty cool I was 10 brought it over
and I can see I can just the metrics and
make sure looks just right without
having to run my application over
as a fantastic time saver alright
a so pictures are worth a thousand words
I feel that
demos are worth a thousand pictures
you know I'm gonna I'm getting a step on
Kevin's toes just a little bit here
the this custom front ASSOCHAM I am i
how a story but he's been working on
Anna you know this looks fantastic he's
done such an awesome job
but the that thing is this is a vacation
happened to make no make it a little bit
more fun and vacationing
mean we just need a custom fun now I've
actually snuck a font and his project
here so I'm gonna go all right over
to the front picker and you'll see that
shows right up in here in Interface
Builder
and I can pick my fun to show for it up
and it looks a little smaller than was
expected to Megan
bump up the size diesel bitter 236 that
looks pretty good
and I could do the same thing here for
my sub subtitle my level
bumper set up to point looks pretty good
okay and now since those
the Fonterra just a little bit different
metrics I can adjust to update those
frames
okay South fantastic night can see right
on the campus what's gonna look like at
runtime
I've got information available to me and
gonna save a lot of time
when you're designing your I was
applications alright so now I'm gonna
jump over to
what I've been working on well kevin was
on stage I was working on the a
the Mac version of this is a pretty
quick workers South try catch up with
and is that
i've kind ever copied from his work here
you can see we've got a very similarly a
and 10 notices
I'm using West End storyboards which is
a new feature
you know if any of your family and if
you're familiar story boards will be
immediately comfortable to you we're
building up our interface
using scenes connected with segways and
we're showing our organization directly
here on campus
all the connections between them and how
my applications going to flow and this
can be incredibly convenient way
to a to see I have British works you
notice that my main menu is actually
still present here and I can edit that
just as I would
in files so all those YouTube you can
actually do your entire application on
it with an analyst in storyboard
so in addition to just being familiar to
I West developers
there's some great features within
storyboards that actually make your life
a lot easier you Mac developers
for example presenting a popover where
she
can be rather difficult when you have to
write code to get it to start an end
and this is a this is just a simple
screening a Segway
to present a popover you have seen the
has your view and while I it's right
there
and sending is is really fast media in
addition managing parents would use
here in fact we have a split view
controller now NS but you controller
and Aftab you control are also new in
your semi and you can use those
in either Sims or storyboards so I've
configured a split you control here with
to split the items
with my I'm with my master in my detail
summers as what I would do
iPad and you can see I can use the same
type of things here I've got in fact in
an official affects the dow bottom
anna & and it just works let me show you
run this application
on Mac using storyboards
okay so here's my application I've got a
nice looking source list in a
and I can click between them I got my
photos come in trading at the bottom
I've come a captions and it I've done it
with storyboards
I can see all in one place and it's
incredibly convenient so I hope you guys
will check this out
as you're working on yosemite in higher
the this can be deployed only tea or
something about
but they're fantastic way for new
application development to speed up your
development all right next wanna talk to
you
a little bit about gesture recognizers
you probably also familiar with these
from my OS
now in in Yosemite we've added five
gesture recognizers and have support for
them
Interface Builder as well so let's say
that I want to added just recognize our
filter object library you can see these
five the pop-up
I'm assay I want to go ahead and
put in a magnification gesture
recognizer wanna do some sort of pinch
to zoom
kind of action so it's a simple is
dragging from object library onto the
view
where you want to recognize the events
drop it right there you'll see it
appears in my document outlined here on
the left
and now all I have to do is connected up
to the source code so I have my
my view control here I mean option click
on my
site view controller to open it in a
split and the cloth
was this area for now I cannot use the
connector source feature
with in Interface Builder I can control
click and drag from my magnification
gesture recognizer
directly into my source code and have a
credit and outlet in action for me
in this case I want create an action
method that my gesture recognizer will
invoke
when events happened something select
action Anna
treble clef elections fun name sometimes
I'm in a car this big if I
and some mystique and excitement to the
code as a now you can see I've got this
yr
this connection right here to the action
method right from I just written as and
when I run this
this message going to be invoked and and
the code that are right here
what will be fired without me having to
do any event detection myself
it's a fantastically convenient way to
develop applications
okay you know I'm Rd kinda starting to
regret the choice
for that selection in big if I it's a a
human-like
my a coworker comes back to make it look
at how happy he is they're on vacation
where the beez
and he is trying to be too pleased to
find a name like big if I so
to reuse the new finding replace feature
nominees Command Option shift af
to make my find that a gator in find a
replacement
so I'm gonna get that horrible selecting
the man he ran a search for big if I
and something more reasonable examines I
hit return you'll see that detects now
in instances that selector both in my
source code enemy Interface Builder
documents
the fantastic time soon
Aikens I can select both these instances
replace them RC snapshot is trying to
get on my photo application here
want to take a picture to so we're gonna
we're going to just replace and you can
see
I've got a zoom right here for my
magnification gesture recognizer
the action has been a place to zoom I
don't have to destroy my connection
change my selector name and recreate on
this connection for MACO into so
it's a fantastic time saver fact for
fine replace in fact
fireplace also works with in document
find
so with command F I can bring up right
inside of my doctrine here and I can
search for all sorts of things you can
find strings that it would appear in
text
if I look for label I can find those as
well and a little highlight for me
where it may appear to select a name
where it may appear in text in a string
and so on on for example us look for it
another thing that you can use
fine for unexpectedly convene is to jump
between parts of your view if you like
so for example I have my site you
control and I have a list you can the
second type list
and going to show me here's my site list
table view controller
this can be incredibly handy we have a
large storyboard and you have your
scenes named appropriately
you can jump between them with with find
right in the document
so this is a a fantastic time shippers
well the last thing but I'd like to
demonstrate for you
is a little bit how Interface Builder
participates in your
localization workflow to help improve
that Simon open my
assistant editor again and I'm gonna
close made to the area
now I want to bring up my preview and
you'll see them I selected few shows up
in the preview
on the right side now if I have
it if I have localizations already I can
use this to preview
Kevin I have only been working on this
for for a little bit but we're pretty
sure this app is gonna take off
worldwide and we have all sorts of
localizations
for now all we have is English but even
when you don't have any translations
you see this entry in there double
length sooner language so I can test
this and see
how is my user interface going to react
are my I don't have constraints and
correctly to help those
those views you can clap you have a
fantastic
I can see without running my application
how my interface is going to react and i
cant I can see that as I select from the
review all my strings will be double
then I can easily see that
once you have translations you can
easily plug dozen as well
a new contest those in Interface Builder
at design-time which is a fantastic time
saver
alright so you've seen some
the great new features that we've been
working hard to bring to you this year
Interface Builder next good sex again
revisiting the three big themes
first is live NIS that more your view
spend your content and your application
are live in the IB design campus than
ever before
there's more power for you 3 quickly and
avoid
thus the costly build and run in debug
lips seconds adaptability
and greater dynamism being able to adapt
to change and configuration where your
view can appear
and third is power in parity great new
features
in the West End and I O S and within
Interface Builder itself help you work
more quickly and efficiently
than ever before any questions you have
should be directed towards will prevent
or Steve them on
with great documentation online
available there are quite a few related
sessions
they'll be fantastic for deeper dives in
the subject matter you can catch on
video
thank you so much enjoy the rest the
conference