well what time to a mall
welcome everybody to localization with
Xcode 6
my name is sold in forty Fisher and I'm
an engineer
with the Xcode team later my colleague
Chris Hansen will join me on stage
so you spend time on your
applications artwork you spend time on
your application's code
but you may yet have to configure your
Global Audience
the App Store is available in 150
countries around the world
here's a small fraction of them and
there are literally hundreds of millions
users shopping in the stores the
interesting thing is
there's no one dominant language around
the world
I O S is localizing to 40 languages
to reach a global audience to take your
applications to the next level
you simply must localize so if this
sounds like an interesting opportunity
you've come to the right place will
bring you guys up to speed
on Apple's award-winning
supports for I O S and Mac OS 10
and of course will details from the work
clothes in Xcode
to help you get your application
localized and for the old hands out
there
we have some new features that I think
you'll find very interesting
I want to take a step back for a moment
though and introduce a useful
distinction
internationalization isn't quite the
same
as localization I like to think I've
internationalization as a milestone
on the path to a localized application
internationalization
is where you structure your application
to be
language in region independent that
involves
corralling the store strings
using interface builders auto
layout support and then once the
application is ready
then you can proceed to the second step
localization I should be clear that's
users around the world see your
applications
in very different ways so here's an
English application in the US region
here's the same application in mexico
and you'll notice that in addition to
being in Spanish
it's also got a subtle difference in the
days
here's the same application running in
Spain
also in Spanish but again
with a difference in the dates and the
number formats
so your applications going to have to
handle
these subtleties I'm gonna show you how
first we'll create and internationalize
application
and then later we'll localize it and
getting started
I'd like to introduce you to Chris
Hansen think is also
so as alton said internationalization
is the first step on the route to having
a fully localized application
I'd like to show you how to prepare your
application
and how to leverage Apple spring works
to prepare for localization
so we have some excellent framework
support for internationalization and
localization
in I'll ask analyst 10 and it's
completely pervasive
throughout the system frameworks
otherwise
I don't think we'd be able to localize I
last
into 40 languages and what our system
does
is separate your localize double data
from
the rest of your application thus making
it much
easier to produce localized Burton
variance up your application there are
actually
all built into a single fun
and these localized resources these
localized data
can be images sounds and movies
and documentation in addition to the
user facing taxed
in your application and even the user
facing tax
in your source code and as I said
it's extremely simple to use
now the first step is to start with
NS localized strain
and of localized string lets you
internationalize
strains that are used in your user
interface
but that come from your source code
and the way it Anna localized string
works
it lets you keep nice strings in your
code
such as format strings you don't have to
replace all the nice
readable strings in your code with some
sort of
all uppercase identifiers pointing into
a resource file
instead with annus localized string you
can keep those strings
as they are and still have your
application
fetch localized resources automatically
and that's the important part there's no
explicit
loading our management a very localized
strings needed
at all and
we have a couple variants annus
localized string
such as annus localized string from
Table but you can use
if you do need to keep different string
tables
for different purposes what's just dive
into some code
here we have the kinda format string
little often appear in your code here
I'm just saying
how tall a particular Mountaineers so I
can assign that to a label
now obviously this string is in English
and it's completely on localized and on
international iced
so thats not really great for my users
who use other languages
fortunately all I have to do is wrapped
that
with NS localized spring and adding a
comment explaining what the string is
four
and I've made that code localized
well that comment is important because
it tells you localize urs
your translators just why you're using
map string
because different languages might use
different terminology
based on context so for example
a language might say that a person is
a certain height tall in a completely
different way
than says on mountain as a certain
height
of course that wasn't quite enough we
were using string with
for map we should actually switch
to localized string with format with
that'll do
is it'll insure that when we pass out
that height
as a number but that number is also
properly format
for the user's language and region
including such things as localized
digits because not everybody uses the
same
digit system the same Arabic numerals
that we ate use
in say the United States
and of course as with all of our system
frameworks
missus all available from swift as well
and in fact
I think you'll like how we've are how
we're handling
annus localized string in swept
now those localized strains when you
localize your application into another
language
Morcombe from a dictionary call the
local eyes will strings file
and this is a nice readable file with in
Xcode
where you can specify
all love your localize will strings a
course
salt and will show you how you don't
even have to offer these files yourself
how Xcode will take care of that for you
at the very beginning of a particular
entry in the file
you'll see that comments that you put in
your source code
and naps so somebody who is the
localizing up file
will know just what that spring is for
then the string exactly as it appears in
your code
will show up as a key in that file
and that's how are frameworks
localization system
will look up the string to use in
another language
and finally on the right hand side
you'll see on modified version of that
string
now hear this is Justin English file
but some languages actually use a
different word
order than English and instead of making
you
write some code to say well if I'm using
this language
then I need to pass my arguments to
string what format are localized string
with format in this order
and then in this other language I need
to pass them in a different order
you can pass them all in a stable order
in your code
and you don't have to right anything
language-specific
instead you can use this one dollar sign
in to dollar sign syntax
which Xcode will put in for you
automatically
to indicate what ordered the arguments
comin
and here's an example Justin English how
you might say the same thing
but in a different order and some
languages
world news one order some languages will
use another order
one order might be formal one order
might be informal
it doesn't really matter the point is
that Coco will take care out the heavy
lifting for you
now sorta but the next level of we have
NS formatter
a lot of what your app's do is present
information
from objects to users
an ounce human-readable tax and that's
exactly what for matters are four
for matters actually translate between
objects and human-readable taxed
not just from one to the other
and they can be used to bowl for
presenting and interpreting taxed
so if you're saying getting numeric
input from user
he'll probably want to use the formatter
just as much as you want to use a
formatter
to present numerical output
and for matters use the user's current
locale
the craft language region and other
settings
by default you don't have to do any
special setup or configuration
has hella formatter pay use the user's
specific language and region
so some very simple format or code
dates are actually extremely difficult
format properly for every language in
region in the world
and that's why we built support to them
into our system frameworks
so that everybody doesn't have to do
that work
here we are configuring the formatter to
present a medium-length
date string now that's a date string
that might not have the day of the week
but might present save them on and the
day and the year
only incense and in a state doesn't just
carry a day a year and a month
also carries a time
were telling this formatter that we
actually don't care about the time
that's in the date
we just care about the date portion
other
and of course what we have a formatter
set up we can just keep reusing it
so once we have a date we just need to
pass it through that formatter
using a string from date method in that
case than a state formatter
or in the equivalent method for any
other format urs and we can then
a sign up straight or label
and of course in swift this all looks
very similar
it's actually a little bit more concise
though thanks to Swift
in New Moon syntax now we have for
matters for dates
as I said but we also have for matters
for individual take components and for
time intervals which are also very hard
to get
right now all situations we also have
for matters for numbers and Ford
formatting and number specifically as
currency
which might have slightly different
rules and even for formatting
by counsel such as the number of bytes
or megabytes uploaded for download
that way you don't have to figure out
how to format that properly in your app
stumps out
and new in iowa say and OS 10 yosemite
we have support for for matters for
health related quantities
such as energy in calories in
kilocalories
we have for matters for length and
height we have for matters from mass
and this way you can present this
information consistently to user
with other APs on the system
now underlying all of this is the
concept of a bundle
your caps are actually built into
directories not single files
those directories are called bundles and
that doesn't just cover your caps that
goes here ap extensions and your
frameworks and everything else on a
system to
and NS bundle provides an API
that's the standard way to access
resources within those bundles
in when you use Ennis bundles APIs
they automatically get the most
appropriate resources for your current
language
and what's more building bundles is
directly supported by Xcode
so when you have localized resources in
your application
you don't need to write scripts to place
them in the right place
in your app just how Xcode that their
localize
and what language therefore Xcode what
automatically
include them in the right place
the INS bundle API is very simple here
we see
getting a resource that represent the
game menu
from our main bundle which represents
our out and then we're just creating an
image with it
and assigning it to I you I image via
now most of the time these are very
common operations
so we have some shorthand in our
frameworks for them for example you I
image
has the image names method and that'll
just
automatically go to and a fumble
for your main bundle and after that
image and it'll even handle differences
in things like the path extension for
you
but not everything is going to come from
one of those methods
for example if I wanna play a welcome
message when my application starts up
I'm probably going to want that audio
message
to be localized as well
but eighty audio player doesn't simply
have a
player with file method that's okay
we can just get for your health
programming bundle to that message
and then pass it along to AV audio
player because those URL's
are just a regular URL's there's nothing
special about them
requires any form translation before
they can be passed all swear
and as always we support this and swept
and in swift
when years following sort of a chain of
methods like this
you can actually use the let syntax so
you don't accidentally
reassign to one of these variables I
find out
really handy
now let's talk about walls
syntax could 5 which supported the
concept called
base internationalization in Xcode
that helps you internationalize your
interface
by keeping your strengths that are in
the interface files
separate from the from the you why
components
that are in those interface files
and of course in Xcode we also make it
very easy to localize your
other project resources as you need to
a new in Xcode 6 we have some powerful
preview features
that you preview how your application
will look in other regions
and in other languages both while it's
running
and directly within Xcode in Interface
Builder
but first let's talk a little bit more
about bass internationalization
as I said keeps
your strengths and your user facing
taxed
separate from your interface objects
so the placeholder text that you put in
to your
I V storyboard or your ZIP files
is only representative up your
development language
what this means is that when you have
other languages
added to your project you only need to
change the strings
you don't need to go through any more
and adjust every single zip file
every single storyboard for every single
language you support
and for other resources we just show
them
exactly the same way that we show
localized strings in Xcode
so as an example I have an app here
that house a stop sign icon and a yield
sign i cud what
those have text on them so
I'm probably going to want a different
stop sign icon
and a different you don't find icon at
least for the tax possibly even for the
shape
for English and for Swedish and you can
do this with
any kinda resource images sounds
movies documentation
and really any kind of resource that you
can put in Xcode and any project
Xcode knows about the structure bundles
so you don't have to tell it hey I want
these
over here no I want those over there
Xcode just knows and what automatically
put everything in the right place
in your app
now new in Xcode 6 we support
preview at runtime: this debug time
preview
is accessed through the and its schema
she where you can set
your application language from a pop-up
and this pop-up will let you pick the
system one which
it'll let you pick any language into
which application has been localized
and also pick a couple had let you pick
a couple of pseudo languages
that I'll explain a little bit later
but that's not all we've also added the
ability
ID's preview assistant to select
I'll language in which you want to
preview your nap
so you can preview your interface by
just selecting
any language in which your application
has been translated
from the language pop-up in the lower
right corner
up the preview window
now we also support a pseudo language
directly within I B for checking your
auto layout constraints
and I'll show you that a little bit
later too
and here it is im than a little bit so
you can read it
now the stages of internationalization
are simply to identify the strings that
you're going to use for your
translations
to make sure that your application is
properly using base internationalization
and auto layout and then it should
localize any other project resources
that you need
my like to show that to you now index
had sex
so here I have an application
that when I run it will show some
earthquake data
from the US Geological Survey its Web
data feed now I'm not actually using
live feed so don't be alarmed if you see
anything in there
on the other hand we also want to see
what might be going on
this is California after all
and you can see that in this app I have
a nice big title I have
a label indicating where particular
earthquake happened
I have a graphic indicating that mag and
well
indicating the strength for severity of
that earthquake
the dayton time with that quake and its
magnitude on the Richter scale
and then when I press her when I tap
one of these earthquakes
I also got action she allowing me to see
that earthquake
on the US Geological Survey website
and to see its location in maps
now there's a lot of strings a lot of
text in this interface
and where does it all come from well I
need to figure that out to make sure
that my application is properly
internationalized
so to start with let's take a look at
that action she
I happen to know but that's brought up
for my table views delegate
which happens to be my main view
controller to and I just have
a straightforward method called present
actions for earthquake
that shows those actions
and here you can see that to present
their work she I'm using the new in Iowa
State class
you wyler controller weren't adding
alert actions
but here I'm just passing the title
string directly to my UI alert action
that means that even if I am running
this application and Swedish or Hindi
I'm still going to see this English
taxed
cell I'm just going to wrap this in NS
localized string like it took them like
I showed you
and I'm also going to put in a comment
indicating what this string is for
and that's all I have to do
to ensure that this tax will come from
my localized strings
when running in other languages now I
also have the same problem
with my maps action title and even with
my counsel title
I could adjust those here but in the
interest of time
let's just pretend that I did now
there's
course a bunch more text here I should
be the turned the
the name up the earthquake or rather the
location at the earthquake
and the dates and the magnitude
up that earthquake now those are going
to be in my table view cell
ok because this is just a standard
tableview application
and when I select my cell I have a handy
configure with earthquake method
that pops up my interface for me now
finds him in here a little bit
you can see that I'm just passing the
location
up that earthquake straight over to my
location label
and that's just tax that comes from the
USGS datafeed
however I'm not passing the date
directly to that date label instead
I'm passing it through a date for matter
that I've configured as a property
and the same is true with my magnitude
I'm not happen it directly I'm not using
string.format
instead I'm passing through a number
formatter
I'm just going to command click that
property so that shows
in Xcode of scroll down just a little
bit here so this is more visible
up and you can see that this property
it's just only easily initialized number
formatter
where i'm saying the I want that
magnitude
to be presented in a decimal format and
because
earthquakes he's a logarithmic scale we
tend to
always want to present a fractional
portion
so I just tell my formatter
I always want to show the decimal
separator and then watch a show at least
one fractional digits
and actually so as to avoid overflowing
my label
I only wanna show one fractional digit
and for that date
I'm just telling my date formatter the
taiwanese a medium style
in for the time
I want to use a short style for the day
I don't really care
the earthquake happened on a Saturday or
a Wednesday I just care about the actual
day of the month and the month in the
year and for the time
I don't really care about the
milliseconds at least in this app
I just want to know the sure the minute
time that earthquake
so we've got a lot of work
actually make sure that we're getting
everything from localized resources
and or passing our data through for
matters know what does that actually get
us
well we haven't translated the app yet
but if I just stop it
and go to my edits scheme sheet I can
look under the options
and I have my application language
pop-up
in my application region pop up
now this is big menu sign going to zoom
back out and I'm going to choose
Sweden so I can see how r manager would
see this application
when he is back home in Sweden was going
to close the sheet
and rerun my application and you can see
but even know the text is an English
still a number of things about the
application
changed for example the date in time
are presented differently in Sweden
evidently
the day above the month comes before the
month
whereas in the United States we tend to
write the month
and then the day and Sweeney the is a
24-hour clock instead of a 12-hour clock
like in the United States
and finally one of the most noticeable
differences
in Sweden the comma is the decimal
separator
rather than the period and the system
frameworks
handled out for me just by using a
formatter
now let's take a look at our interface
in Interface Builder
I'm just going to select that earthquake
seen that i'm looking at in the
simulator
and I'm going to bring up the preview
assistant
that we introduce the next good pop
and here I can select the preview
and in addition to allowing me to
preview
the application in different
orientations down in the lower right
I kept also select own language in which
a preview the application
so here my move over a little bit you
can see that I only have my development
language
actually in this project however
under the separator I also have one
close to two languages I mentioned
a double length pseudo language so if I
select this
and zoom out what do I C
well all of my labels have had their
taxed
double in this is to simulate
running your application in a more
verbose language
a language that uses more tax to say
something
for example German tends to use about 30
percent more
space than English does to say about the
same thing
on the other hand there are some
languages that use even less space than
English to say the same thing
and your applications interface needs to
accommodate them
all fortunately auto layout
will do most of the work for you and
this preview assisted
lets you see that its actually working
for example I actually do help
all and auto layout issue in this
preview
you can see that the magnitude field has
an ellipse the Senate
indicating that its text is overflowing
the label
now the largest earthquake that ever
been recorded was a 9.5
so this probably isn't an issue
at least for this out however it is
something
that you'll probably want to take into
consideration
a course not all the text in this
preview was doubled
that's because this heading says
prototype cells
and thus are this background that says
tableview prototype contact
those are actually part up interface
builders user interface
and not your own text
now if I wanted to localize this graphic
because it uses color and color is
another
language and a region dependent
are piece of information network also be
very easy in Xcode
we just select the image I wanna
localize
and then open the inspector and go to
the inspectors
localization section and we have this
nice big a localized fun
that will turn any resource into a
localized resource
and that but we'll just bring up a
pop-up alert
asks where I want no what localization I
want that resource to be a part of
initially
now it can actually be a part on the
base
internationalization because it doesn't
have a place
as an image into which I can substitute
strings
however I can make it apart might
English
localization and let's talk about what
we just saw
we saw how the system frameworks
I last and OS 10
will really do a lot of the heavy
lifting
for you and internationalization and
localization
we saw how you can use the debug time
preview to check your region support
because after all even a few don't
localize your application
your users are still going to be in
different regions all over the world
and use different conventions
and we saw how you can take advantage of
design time previews
and bass internationalization to ensure
that your application is properly
reactive
when it comes to the length a text in
the interface
and of course you can localize other
project resources to
as you need to now to talk about the
actual process
%uh localizing and translating
application
I'm going to hand things back to Bolton
thanks Chris so you saw how Chris
prepared and internationalized
application
he structured it to be language in
region independence
and you saw how the frameworks provided
some of the
localize data for users around the world
for free
so what's left to do
well it turns out that the book and the
remaining work
is to translate your user facing strings
and this is still best done by an
expert's
in the language and not just machine
translation
so your challenge is to extract those
strings
from your projects then packing them up
from your translator
for your translator after they've
translated them you have to
integrate them back into your project
sounds like a lot work
well I'm pleased to announce an Xcode 6
we've streamline this process
Xcode will now carefully examine you are
I B resources and your source files
and extracts the source strings for you
who generates and open X left formats
now this is a mature standards that's
accepted by
a number of translation companies around
the world
and is compatible with the number
translation tools
so when translators insert their work
into the X left they would then
returned the exe file to you
and then you simply imported into your
project
and then Xcode will meticulously crepes
the resources are
update existing resources to put the
translations where they need to go
so you no longer have to run Jan string
so I B tool
in order to do this
thank you actually there now
so here's the project that Chris created
earlier
I'm just gonna navigate to the projects
where you find a lot of the
localization related details so here you
can see that at the moment
it's only gots English in this project
so
if I want to extract the source strings
from this project I simply go up to the
editor menu
and choose export for localization a
choose a destination
the home folder and then Xcode
generates the exe file based on what is
found in the project
I'll show you that quickly
it's simply an XML file and down here
you can see the
source strings the Chris localizer
internationalize earlier
and the comments to the added to the
translator
so now imagine that I
send that to my translation team I would
email letter uploaded to
their service and after they've
completed their work
when I want to import these translations
I go back to the editor menu and choose
import localizations
here some
prepared earlier now I've heard that
smorgasbord is
race in Sweden but personally I've for
curry in India
so we've got some Hindi translations and
Xcode
is inserting those translations
into the project now you can see that's
Hindi is added to the project's
and thats when I disclose the storyboard
very in Peru
there's strings files waiting for us
and if I choose to run this application
are used to you debug time
menu I'll choose Hindi
I'll choose to preview its
as if the user in India
and now
you can see that beautiful script in
place the dates have changed
the region the number formatter
is the same as in the US and this is one
of the things I like about the
preview feature it's immediately obvious
that
this is not in the right script the
title of this
events so in this case you would ideally
use
a localized feed I also like to point
out this is available on the command
line
so you can now use the export
localization
and import localization burbs to build
this into your
localization workflows and to automate
this process as you want
so you seen how
Xcode six will now streamline this
process
localizing your application how will
help you to communicate with your
translator
in this open X live format so now that
you've got to localize application
you'd like to keep it that way
and you'd like to build confidence
that it is going to appeal to a global
audience
so I'd like to invite Chris back on
stage
to show you how to best maintain this
application
and build confidence but it's ready for
a global audience
thank is often that's pretty cool stuff
so
of course you probably don't want to put
off
localizing application on children very
end up your development process that
sounds a lot like a waterfall
development and we really want to be
iterative these days and the
export and import workload results and
show you
allows you to do that it allows you to
do
when I like to think up as continuous
localization
because you can x4 and import at will
this what's your stage a localized
as you work and you can use previews
to catch missing or bogus translations
very easily and
week even include some tools that let
you prepare your application
for right-to-left languages like
Arabic in hebrew independently of
translating your application
into those languages that can make it
much
easier to actually experiment with your
user interface
even if you don't speak or read Arabic
or Hebrew
so I just like to show you that
right in Xcode so let's say
I've been working on my project for a
while and I've just received my spanish
translation
back from my translator to import
all I have to do is as all time showed
suck my project and then choose
import localizations and I'm going to
pullin
mine Spanish XLA file now what happened
here
unlike with salt and showed you with
Hindi there appears to be an
issue with this translation while
it turns out there it's missing
the show location and maps functionality
I must've actually exported the spring
localization
before I added that feature to my apt
but thats
okay I can still import this
incomplete localization and at least
see my application as it is right now
with all of the localization has been
completed for Spanish
so I'm just going to import that and if
I disclose my storyboard here
I can see that now I have strings in
both Hindi
and Spanish fort now for wanna see how
my application actually runs
as always I can just use my application
language
in this case Spanish now they've had
that localization
and also choose the spin region
so I can see me how somebody who speaks
Spanish
in Spain would see my application
now I run this
I see that earthquakes here
isn't localized that must have been
another thing that might
our translator missed and
if I tap an earthquake
I can see that one of my actions and the
cancel button
are translated but that button that I
called out earlier
has not been
now if I'd wanted to see this right in
Interface Builder
I could select my main story port let's
just select that earthquake seen
and bring up the preview window again
the preview a system I should say
and if I choose my Spanish localization
and Interface Builder
I can see that some of my place over
labels have been translated
however this birth quakes title
is not only all in English but it's
actually
been changed all capital letters
and that's actually the frameworks
calling out to me
that they will recognize this should be
coming
from a localized resource but it wasn't
found I can get the same effect
in the edit scheme she when running my
application
by choosing this new shown on localized
strings option
so if I just stop and rerun my
application now that I've seen
have set that I can see that
earthquakes is called out and all
capital letters
now I said you can export and import
Atwell
and one reason that you want to export
is because
you'll be adding features your
application as you go
and you'll want those new features that
you add to be translated
and you export in exactly the same way
no matter when you do it
you simply select your project and shoes
export for localization
but ivory added some localizations to
this app
so what happens or Xcode gives me a
choice
and whether I just want to export
strings in the development language
or if when generating the XLA files
I should already include the strings
in the translations that house
this way I can handle it was actual
files
to my translators and they concede from
work but they've
already done and won't redo it
instead they'll only do the work needed
for the new and change strings
so if I save this and replace the one
that was already there
I can see now in the home folder
that I have 3d
exported localizations in actual a
format
one in English one in Spanish and one in
Hindi
a finely I'd like to show you what your
app would look like
in a right to left language for
convenience
was gonna bring up the storyboard again
so we have something to compare against
start me up from running in the
simulator and
I'm going to edit my scheme once more
this time I'm just gonna set my region
back to the system region
but I'm going to set my language shoe
the new
right to left pseudo language
now when you're using a right-to-left
language
on and iPhone or an iPad or Mac
it's not just attacks that goes from
right to left
the entire direction other user
interface
is changed based on how the user
prefers to read
well just also turn off my shown on
localized string setting here
and let's see how auto layout reacts to
just changing the user interface
direction
well because we use the concept love
leading-edge
and trailing edge rather than left and
right
in are auto layout for this app
most of the app just flips right to left
just doesn't Arabic or Hebrew user would
see it
we have our magnitude all the way on the
left
instead of all the way on the right next
to it
is are graphic indicating the severity
of an earthquake
and then we have some text overlapping
that indicates that we probably still
have a little bit of work to do
on making this fully support right to
left taxed
now the frameworks do that but I
probably just have a bug in my
auto layout constraints and this preview
helped me find before I actually went to
the trouble of trampling my application
and I don't have to understand
Hebrew or Arabic in order to debug that
problem
so what we saw with how you can update
your translations
and as you go to keep your app current
and really continue to do
iterative development at the same time
that you're app is being translated
well so far how you can use the various
kinds a preview
to capture missing translations before
your users
and possibly even before your key way
ever sees them
and we saw how you can simulate many
different behaviors
between regional formatting and even
right to left taxed
to ensure your caps work the best they
can for
everyone because that's really what it's
all about
reaching a global audience are
frameworks for iowa's analysts 10
make that really easy especially
if you take advantage a Xcode new work
clothes
for axel F export-import and
for previewing localizations at debug
time
and at design-time there are some
related sessions
there is actually one earlier today
called advanced topics in
internationalization
the QoS in deep into what you need to do
in terms of formatting and
code to deal with all the subtleties of
internationalization
for example mixing right to left and
left to right: taxed
and that's actually the sequel to a
session that was held last year
that it also encourage you to check out
in the WWDC
ap and as always
the advanced topics internationalization
is going to be available for streaming
soon
there's also an caps for China get
together tomorrow
at work add up 4:30 for anybody who's
interested in tapping this
huge new market thank you very much