the morning
the debugging an ex got six so he got
say now debugging session last year you
have notice our quest to bring more
relevant ebuddy information to your
fingertips this year we look we're going
to continue with this mission
up quite forget my colleague reminded me
to introduce myself
but my name is not change from last year
some still hanging on
have stood by you I engineer sup
let's look briefly look at what we're
going to talk about
this year I'm gonna talk about a new
feature in tax cuts 6
that will help you with debugging y'all
use of Grand Central Dispatch
which is TCD its teachers call
cutie bugging makes up Tristano come up
show you amazing new way to explore and
you but your user interface
and then carries gonna talk in detail
how to integrate
y'all the criminal preview into your
custom class
I want to set the stage for a cutie
bugging
so that we on the same page my apologies
the
this is a vid love it too basic for some
love you but
is important that we get the
fundamentals right so
where and application hits a break point
a
the program pas the debugger will go
through a process known as
unwinding what it does is looks at the
method it contains a break point
and follows the prank 3-pointer back to
the call flight
in this case away from that it goes on
until they were just the beginning of
the threat
then contact with a series of stacked
frames
known as a back trace so spectrum is an
instance other invocation other method
now back to resign port because you
helps you understand the control-flow
and the state of the application so what
happens
all how does the city impact that traces
but first what is GCT it is a
technology that is introduced five or
six years ago
I it's not at the time frame as since
then has taken off like wildfire
because it is a very natural way to
create concurrent responsive application
basically you
evening bag a task up in the smaller
work items
call blocks and then UN cue the block
2aq using two weeks
synchronously or a synchronously
we're going to focus on the latter
because it poses a bigger challenge
when it comes to debug UN Cuate
synchronously using
the dispatch a sink ATI and then
what you're telling the system the OS's
at some time later
it can be Q ya block
and final work attracted to start
executing it
imagine that you've had a break point
your blog right now so let's look at the
back trace
of track 16 of the debugger
has finished unwinding the bottom all
spring
39 represents the start of the work a
threat
which corresponds to the deep healing
you that
so what do you have to do to understand
the control flow before the and healing
event
well what I used to do is to find the
math that that contains the and CUNY ban
in this case cash crop image pasted in
the session every year
search for all the calls I saw that put
break points there
relaunch the application go through all
the crazy you I gestures
to make sure I can repeat the up
something looks the same problem
the hit the break point and heaven
forbid save
North call sites also in another respect
a sink because them insight to wash
rinse and repeat
but Xcode is not lying to you when it's
giving you this limited
that trace that's because the trip the
thread that does and queuing
did it a synchronously in the past
in fact that threat is possibly doing
something completely different
on may be gone from memory so it's not
bad to
accuse anybody of not being being able
to unwind to the past
but in your head must be thinking well
this is accurate but
surely expert can present a more logical
back trace
and we agree with you saw
in the scenario that i described above
earlier we're going to splice in actual
sex is gonna splice in the back trace
of the ensuing event so they can show
them to you in a
in a more logical manner in the UI
any get one what one am more than one
including events
Xcode is gonna follow the chain so they
show you everything
so how do we do that while we work
through several years of the OS
down to the car West we try cause all
the factories is
of the ensuing events so when your
application has a break point
exco to us the debugger do we treat the
back trace
so that we can show them to you in the
UI
the life that frames they have colored
icons
the wreck on a stack frames the angry
icons but
just like the livestock friend you can
select
you get elected and effects but has the
buck symbols
it was you will surely the Southport
again this case
if it doesn't have the votes in Bali
will show you this assembly that some
among us can actually decipher
so what why and icons gray ball
a wreck on us that brings icon is great
because it is a visual cue
to let you know that its historical
and because it doesn't exist in memory
anymore you cannot interact with that
in the console he cannot run expressions
like peel
next call when I show you the its spring
variables because recording
the frame parables would cause the
application to plot out in memory
possibly causing it to be jetsam on the
device
so that wraps up the first part of you
debugging
lean on to the second part
axle body for shows you the back traces
in the threads view in the back have a
gator
as you can see here press five threat by
showing it
showing you respect race so that just
means that affect races all organized by
his parents
threats that's another equally
interesting views known as
Hughes view in the back navigator and
you pay attention to your top right
corner that's a little control known as
the process view options collector
it is a mouthful that is useful
so huge you toggle it to the Q view
experts which issue over to emphasize
the relationship between blocks
and Q's so
in this slight here you see that a top
he has won executing block
so what about the blocks that yet you
have thank you
but not executing it let's look at this
scenario
so I'm using a serial key US an
illustration but
this happens with concurrent use as well
we square is your currently executing
block
as long as it's not finished executing
blocks the summit's summit subsequently
to the key will get stacked up behind it
we call this great quest the pending
blocks
Sonex buttsex we're gonna show you
the pending blocks as well the Q
so in this case we have nine pending
blocks
the pending love select X unlike the
executing block in that you press the
down
it will show you the is Rep back choice
which by definition is a wreck on a back
trace
a bank unions so we hope that by so
facing this information you can answer
questions
like how many pending blocks have I
similar to the Q
MI over saturating the Q
and you can literally tens and thousands
a block spending blocks
out there some that are not needed
because you may be able to change all
going down all your
granularity so that you do less work
i doing that's what is important because
that would mean saving battery life on
your customers
devices on top of that will help us
solve
a class of programming problems
that I'm going to go into a
demonstration now
so running on a simulator is an
application called jogger
which helps you track your runs in San
Francisco
and keep said while you at you doing
this to be the BBC
by know about jogging in keeping fit we
can all dream
out live a time I get that tracks the RI
time
annual velocity and
a map of all the route that I've done
and I've done exactly one this year
which is one too many gonna
if you click on the date you selected
date you all flight into detail page
of my velocity crop some notice that
it takes a little time to the slide into
detail page
and I'm sure you have learned from Apple
and develop help customers that
the one you any nation to be sloth small
like butter so this is not
and I want to figure out why so since I
know to cook really well under
just gonna jump straight into Xcode to
the class known as
graph you crap you is the class the draw
the graph
and I'm gone James I'm gonna jump
straight to a week from net by going to
the implementation feel of the John Barr
and start typing awake bag up
and i've a method jail here that creates
my velocity path
and I know that is doing a lot of
heavy-duty work so let's jump in
to the definition by doing a command
click on it
but I see here as is spending time
fetching the velocity data from the
database
and that it takes a lock to protect it
and subsequently go through each data
point that velocity data
to draw that the path and when is done
releases the lock
so doing all this work on the main
threat so is impeding
detail page from sliding and this
looks like a good candidate to use
artist a defect a sink
so let's do that going back to away from
that
and I'm gonna pacing that place in a
chunk of code
which I don't have alright
alright I'm gonna move the line that
creates the the path
into the dispatch facing block I'm gonna
dispatched to block to a simple Q
of the graph and i'm don calculating the
path
our updated on the main threat but usual
so this is a free doesn't pretty simple
change
that's three run by clicking on a run
but in to see that works
ok am going to go to the
date second selected so this time
when I when I select the date
detail page the slide in very quickly
Richard us
but my graph is not drawing
cell that them anyways don't you can
try to figure out what is the problem
but one of my favorite way is to look at
the speed up the application
and to do that and you know I will look
at the back traces
of the application by clicking
be pause button in the debug bar and I
know that
want for my grad is down on the grass 0q
site farm
found a threat which is threatening to
interested open
and is it
you name it may not be this year to back
but frame to
shows that I'm trying to wait for lock
looks like it
minutes like bring three to come from it
and indeed I'm waiting for the lock so
those of us who have faced
this situation before half have a pretty
standard
following path: as that which is to find
a thread that has the lock
so let's do that Michigan if the way to
show all the back to recess which which
is due first
collapse be a process item and by
holding down the option key
you can twist it open Sonam than a
visually just and through
to look for the threat that has the lock
well this is interesting because the
sites that
threat 22 which is trying to acquire the
lock
I cannot find a threat that has the lock
so this is a head-scratcher but what do
you know I'm just learned something that
may be able to help us
summit is situated cutie bugging by
going to the
that control and here I'm going to use
the
filter bach to focus on lie crop sale Q
so that s cell
is safe here I'm one running block which
is
my the law the block waiting for the
lock
and I one pending block
to show my pending lock I'm gonna go to
ninety Batman widan
about workflow and turn on I wish
opening blocking cues
by out pop my pending block
minute twisted open and select the first
frame
which espy sauce court subplot a
celebration drop kar
is a method which enhanced this morning
as well to use dispatch
a sink so that can to work of the main
track
and looks like in my haste what I did is
I acquire the lock before I did the
dispatch
a sink so what's going on is this
I had an execution block waiting for
lock
and SPECT right after it is my pending
block
which unfortunately has the lock so
the pending block cannot move because
has to wait for the execution block to
finish
so this is the kind of a deadlock
albeit in and non-classical way so
thankfully the solution is pretty simple
I just have to move the line that does
the locking
closer to the place ways protecting
its data which is full of the media to
this ensures that it doesn't try to get
the lock
and killers dq and start executing
cell with this second round of simple
change
receive this works
okay let's get to the point where I can
select the date again and walla
everything looks correct now so
without it cue debugging what you would
have to do what I would have to do is to
such follow the places where I
my velocity did a lot of issues and
usually look at them and
reason really hot about house used and
that error prone and tedious
in summary you're gonna get cue
debugging an expert thinks
which has two parts: record a back
traces gonna get you
show you back trace all me and healing
if and when you're using effect you
think
and pending blocks Bice hopefully bicep
basing this
information you all can optimize the use
of GC
with that many bring up try to talk
about unibody
here
hi my name is Troy and thank you for
coming to our
debugging and Xcode 6 as you may know
Xcode is a fantastic tool
for discovering things about your
application they may be hidden
through the debug humming just should
have two new features through the
pending blocks and recorded I stack
traces that are
hitting pieces of information about your
application that Xcode X 160
we all know that not all the bugs
in applications are hid some of them are
extremely visible there staring us right
in the face
from the user if a server applications
and since these are visual bugs
wouldn't it be great if we could do but
then visually as well
and now an extra tix you can so it kinda
bugs in my talking about
these are the bugs were you have I miss
position viewer clipping is wrong
he's a very squish through the stretch
news
and these are the views that are missing
entirely because the visibility or
is hidden attribute is set incorrectly
in your application but
that's not all that this I knew aspect
to the debugger an extra helps with
you can use it when you're not even to
bucking it's an application like this
and I would like to add a new button
down here
and
I don't know maybe its new code base to
me maybe it's been awhile since I've
read this
I don't know what this view is behind a
wouldn't it be great if I could just
click with the mouse and find out what
that you it's
well now you can't this
YouTube under featured integrated all
throughout exco
so let's take a look at the expo window
and figure out where the different
pieces are
so we know what we're talking about
where talk about this
YouTube and the future here's the Xcode
whenever we all know and love
we application is running down at the
bottom there's
body but by this is where you fine I you
familiar items such as baked pies and
continue buttons
well now there's a new button here which
is the debug
you hire keeping right here simply click
this
and exclude is going to import the user
interface if your application
into the main editor window X ca but
it's not just
imported as a static image if imported
separate pieces so that exco can
actually exploded out into three
dimensions
and rotated around if you want senior
your application in this 3d view is very
illuminating and allows you to
at traverse the hair DC with a parent
views RC with the siblings are
but if you want a more concrete
representation I V view hierarchy
we turn to the debug navigator this is
as high maint at about the place we find
your threads on your tears
at available here in this
I process few options selector if you
select
the view option in there now is three
excuse abuse down below we have
the your view hierarchy in the
application which is right here
down below we have some filtering
options to help you
team that list we have a show only
primary views and we have a show only
displayed here from a stop on earth
second one because this was important if
you have a view that's missing in your
application
maybe the day is hidden and sat on it
and so Xcode is also going to hide in
the next to you why
but Xcode knows about it could show it
to you so
I use can simply turn of this option
an external show all of your viewers
even the ones they're hidden finally
there's the
bass string comparison there which will
do an exact match at that list in the I
navigator to help you drill down T
exactly the item you're looking for
now let's turn our attention over to the
right hand side
at the Xcode window this is the
inspector area
and you might be familiar with this if
you've ever used interface because these
are very similar
we have a Object Inspector and there's a
site inspector as well
here we see the Object Inspector for you
I am HBO
and not only that this is the specific
you I am at you
because we're selecting we're clicking
on 1/8
in our application so we actually have
the address for that object as well
which is resident in memory on your Mac
or on your I was device
we have thumbnail and all the other
interesting actually to that
about that view listed in this inspector
finally we have a site inspector this is
gonna show you the size and position
as you might expect it's also going to
show a list
I V auto layout constraints that are
affecting that view
with two exceptions down at the bottom
ec2 constraints which are deemphasized
these are not affecting the layout have
you currently but they're still attached
to the view
and I still have meaning in this case we
have felt that with
I have too high 320 and in the print the
CDC that's content size that's because
the system at it this
implicitly to this view to represent the
content size
to de-emphasize cuz up above buried
ended with two explicit constraints
they were added in Interface Builder and
is also have a with the 320 in this case
but they
might not always match so this is a
great place to check
if you're think you're having constraint
issues as we're gonna see
and a demo which I'd like to show you
right now
alright here we have the application
that humming started with
and if you have superego eyes for maybe
not you'll notice that
there's a pretty bag visual back down
here I wonder if the beauty fucking
in Xcode can help us find that
something to switch over to Xcode find
this
debug you hire key button and simply
pressing
what's happening now is Xcode going
through all the news in
the application and pulling them back
into the Xcode window
now we see user interface right here
and already you're getting at better
look at what might be
issue and its application you see some
other views summit
images in this you I collection view are
outside
the view where they're supposed to be
contained
that's a that's a pretty interesting
fact to help diagnose the problem but
it doesn't help us solve the problem
sorin have to dig deeper
to explode the view hierarchy I've your
application all you need to do is simply
click
and drag anywhere in the congress
this allows us to see the the
parent-child relationship between
somebody's views
I have open on the right hand side the
assistant editor which is an automatic
mode
this allows extra to track the
file that I click over here in their
view to bugger
with a source code file that matches
with it
so if I click here I get the source code
file for
you energy I manage
traverse backwards update higher pitched
tell you get to the custom self it
has been written for this class the pair
to the issue I am to you
is the UI view and this is the content
view that sell
and the one behind that is the run
details collection Buechel
which is custom code in my application
mother going to open up the inspector
here
and check out some other positions I
these views as it gets
it looks like is probably a position
back here the traversing
back up the stack starting with one of
these
user id has a missing image I am going
to click here
and see the position is 160 45
its child is 4545
because the position is relative to its
parent
but where is this final view I'm gonna
go over to the navigator
and find love you have selected is this
your way you live you
and I can simply find where child is I
don't know where it is in
special space but I know where it is and
real
hierarchy of the view so if I click here
I see that the position
is a 160 45 and remember that's based on
the parent
so what I'm actually looking at is this
view over here I thought there was a
working one
but view has been shifted of a
cell and its that's the reason it's
missing
so let's go back up to the the cell
class and take a look at the
implementation class
I mean idk man click on the class name
here to dive into the implementation
and here you see a red a fairly simple
implementation
for cell view all it does is it
overrides the unit with frame
it creates a new UI ImageView and then
add that
as the cut isometric view of the content
the right down here
are thinking about p information we
found earlier
we know there's a position issue and I
can see that were passing the frame
wrecked
befell to this subview
that's not what I want I want this the
sub you to have the same bounce as the
cell
so instead a friend req I'm gonna tape
self that bounce
the should be enough to fix our problems
I'm gonna build and run
switch over to the simulator
and Jack back into you are friend
details view
sure enough we have the out fully
functioning
you I collection do with dollar images
tightly spaced
as expected now that bugs fixed
I do see another issue see this I
this label up here San Fran is sketchy
keen a camper San Francisco but this is
a serious
running app this is an app for those of
us that go every morning and we don't
call
this fair city San Fran is a San
Francisco
isolates let's go back to bed have if
you go back and see if we can understand
what might be going on there
I mean it take a moment to admire the
fully functioning
you a collection view looks great I mean
it then turn back to you
two-dimensional know this button down
here allows us to reset the View Rd
and I'm going to cook on this label
alright I know that I'm using auto
layout and miss
application so let's go ahead and see if
there's anything having to do with
constraints
there might be an issue down here is the
fasho constraints find this shows all
the constraints
and it also dims out the views that are
not currently related to those
to that new or its constraints this
allows us to really focus in on the work
at hand
when I zoom in
it's plain to see that there are two
constraints attached to this label
and if I look over here I see the
witness 95
there's any explicit constrain have 95
down at the bottom the contents I've is
a hundred and 9.5
so clearly somebody added a complex was
a constraint and Interface Builder
and that clipping me implicit size
a that label so I'm just gonna switch
over to
my storyboard find that label and
delete that explicit constrain
if I had the time to show you guys I
would had a constraint-based
properly limited that label 13 go beyond
the bounds on the screen but
I'm sure you can find in Interface
Builder section for example
this afternoon at 3:15 that will at
go into more detail about out allow
constraints
and I we have the full string that label
so we've seen it the view to biker is a
fantastic way
to both look take a look at your your
application and I invite you to do just
that
go back today just after the session
open up your computers just try hitting
the view bigger bang on your application
I think you'll find it eliminating
and the integration with Xcode is
fantastic
now I'd like to turn it over to carry
was gonna teach you a little bit more
about quick look
previews
think it right my name is carrying and
how is everyone enjoying the conference
so far
great I know that we are very excited to
be here as well
to show some great new debugging
features in Xcode set
but first let's take a step back
last year Xcode 5 debut with
is getting feature whereby as you are
running and debugging your application
you can get a live quick look preview
above your data simply by clicking on
the quick look icon in the debug bar
you can get those pop over that will
show you a preview you could even
simply by hovering over the source a
variable
in the source editor get a quickly
preview right from there
just by clicking on the quickly icon in
the paper that appears now
but X good five debuted with the fault
support for
a number of important and common object
types
like images and busy it has
and even things like map locations
well we've got a lot of great feedback
from this feature and I know that it's
been
very useful to number developers
including myself
so to build on the success index had sex
there is support for to new object types
the first is views
so wetherbee you i've you are in an
issue
you can get a quick look preview %uh
that
simply by clicking in the variables you
and clicking on the
quickly icon or my favorite is just hit
the spacebar
and it'll bring up a nice preview and
considering how
common views are in most applications I
think this will be a very powerful
feature
now this second object-type that was at
is well I honestly don't know
that's because it's your own custom
class
so now for the first time if you have a
that does some custom drying and perhaps
returns
a I'm an image or a busy a path or
something like that
you can now get a preview that as well
before now there wasn't great support
for that
so if you were to try and get a preview
you would get this
default view which had some pertinent
information like the name and the
address and the type
but no preview so
I would like to show you how to fix that
there's a simple method that you can
implement in your classes implementation
and it's called debug quick look object
now in this class you can either call
your drying code or implemented in there
but the important point is from this
method you return something that Xcode
knows how to show so wanted the default
supported types
should be returned from this method and
then you'll be good to go
and I would like to show you that now
so here we have the jogger application
that we've been seeing in previous
jammers and I'm gonna click the routes
button
and we'll see on things around from this
morning
if thats indeed the case
and okay so this class has a
and object class called route half
overlay
which accesses the run data to
generate this busy a path that then gets
overlaid onto the map
so let's look at that a little further
I'm gonna click on the map
and I'm gonna hate this a well scrolls
really fast
gonna hit this breakpoint and the same
trying to debug
some issue here now down in the
variables view we can see we've got a
number of local variables like this
point
and if I click on the quick look icon I
can see
a preview of the point this is our route
path overlay
and if I click on not I'm gonna hit the
spacebar and what it just comes up with
is just some generic information but we
can do better than that
some gonna stop here
gonna go to our route path overlay
and I've got the method that I was
talking about debug quick look object
it's a sort of a long title but
try and remember okay and if I i'm
comment that
and what this method does it's not
really important because it's going to
be different for
every custom class but what it does is
it it accesses
each of the 360 for some odd points
a map location the for that Ron
and then generates about as a power
skills in a little bit and then returns
from at
does a path because Xcode 6 knows how to
render or quickly preview a busy a power
so the now that we've implemented either
an able to
I'm gonna run and bike again
go to our routes click on the map
and if all goes well we should see and
ice
detailed preview a each of those point
today to from
the start until the ambulance picked up
on me when he collapsed
I
attack so when everything today
we've she we've seen humming show us how
we can vary easily and more effectively
debug Hughes and blocks
with the new cute a bug in future and
then trace showed us how
we can more a effectively or easily
explore
our applications view hierarchy I've
used this
very effectively myself I several times
been very helpful and then I showed you
how to add
quick look previews for your own custom
classes
on and remember you can also now preview
any view so for more information you can
contact
are great developer tools evangelist a
bill on I also got a link here to the
documentation for
quick look previews which documentation
will show you
will a full list of exactly all the
default supported types
in Xcode sex and then
don't forget the developer forms
there's a lot of great debugging
sessions this week so be sure to check
them out
thank you very much