good morning
alright happy to sing that's good a
earnings will Turner and with my
colleague Brooke
cal and we'll be talking to you about
testing in Xcode 6
and let's get started so we're gonna
cover several topics today
start of just kinda motivate this think
about the benefits attesting white why
should we bother in the first place
then we'll get into what it takes to
had test to a project may be a more
projects that don't have test
and they will talk about some new
features
annex good sex which allow you to test a
synchronous systems
and that also testing features that
allow you to catch performance
regressions so
why should
we test obviously every high moment we
spend developing as an investment over
resource
our resources time and our colleagues
for maintaining
maintaining the code base that we
created so the obvious thing about
testing
is it helps you find bugs in as many
classes about its that you find the
testing
they are regressions so cases where you
ship your product
you make a code change data feature and
in the process
something breaks and now you're 1.1 or
1.2
has a bug where customers are unhappy we
hate regressions
pasar fantastic way to ensure your code
ships without regressions
also bugs where performance changes you
make a change in your code and now
suddenly something
taking a lot more time to execute and
maybe that only on some devices not
others
so pass again can be a great way to
catch
performance regressions the other sorta
less
talked about unless obvious benefit if
testing is it codifies the requirements
a your project so especially if you're
sharing code with engineers you create
classes classes have
API's and a lot of times because
objective-c in script are great
languages for expressing
the API semantics in the API
the theirself document we think okay our
job is done
but in truth they don't really account
for all the possible permutations have
inputs to those functions so if you
write
test those tests help beautify the
requirements as API's another engineer
come along
they can make code changes that area and
it has helped them understand what the
expected behavior is
so to get started with us
you may have a project that doesn't have
tests already
so you want to add to this that project
and then the obvious thing to do is
make sure that those test pass
alternatively you may start with the new
project
and that case you have the option to a
different workflow where
you create test first and then you write
code that passes
us and that sometimes referred to as
test driven development
so now you're set up you got your test
their passing
you can go into work load we talk about
we consider
a continuous integration workflow and
you start of a green state where
everything is working
and you're making code changes you're at
it features fixing bugs
at some point 110 these code changes
introduces a bug and so now your
continuous integration because you've
written test
identifies a bug and you know right away
right after that first code change
you know that the bug has been
introduced so then you can take the
necessary steps
fix a bug and return to Green State with
you i think is a green state represents
no
quality and having tests and have a
continuous integration ensures that your
projects remained unknown state of
quality
all the time so to get started let's
talk about how testing works
and Xcode Xcode ships with the framework
called
XE test and this is framework for
testing provide the Senate API's
let you create tests run the test
express
expectations passes and failures as the
it all starts with the base class exceed
test case
and to create test you subclass exceed
space and then you add test methods and
test methods follow a naming convention
they return void their pre-fixed
with the word test in lower case and
they take no parameters
the remainder the method name is at your
discretion it should be
sure to what a name that conveys the
purpose the test
inside the test methods you can use
assertion API's we provide
to report failures for example Xeta
assert equal compares to scare about
scaler values
and if they don't match it outputs a
string and reports a failure to test
harness
so in Xcode we manage a lot of different
parts of our projects their targets and
we have test targets for managing tests
test targets build bundles and these
bundles
contain compiled test code and also
resources you want to use in the test
may be a
data files driver test these go in your
test but you don't really wanna shippers
with your application
you gonna ship them with day on a ship
them at all you want them to be with
your test bundle
so these are pest targets are
automatically included in new projects
if I go today and I create new
application
you'll see there's a test target test
class already there to start me off get
me writing tests from the beginning
you can also and test targets to
existing projects
and this may be something you wanted to
to project that has not asked for it may
also be a step you take to help
organizer test because you can have as
many test targets as you want
and this useful sometimes he'll run just
this test target that test target
or you can run them all together
so let's think about moment about how
pass
run because their bundles these are not
execute oppose it can be launched
themselves
so instead we need to host them and
execute a whole process
generally we inject the singer apso your
test can be written
against her application can access all
the code in your application
which means when we run the test we run
it in the context
your application alternatively
you can run a minute hosting process
that's provided by exco
resources for tests as I mentioned
before are not
in the main but no there in your test
bundle cell
when you go to load them don't use and
aspen domain but on this is something
that
trips people up I think a lot of us just
kinda have and its Mandal main bundle on
autocomplete in our heads but instead we
want to use as bundle bundle for class
and passed your test class that ensures
that you're going into the test bundle
to locate that resource
some running tests Xcode lets you run
tests number of ways
the simplest way is command you and this
takes your active skiing
and runs the tests that are associated
with that skiing
you also have but and the Sorcerer's got
her
next to the test method that let you run
just that passed
or the class and all the tests in that
class
see in the summer set up buttons in the
test navigator
you can also run tests using Xcode built
so if you have a setup scripts
you've used to create your own kinda
automation setup
you can use Xcode build and you passed
the test action
paths your project tell it which scheme
this is essential because your project
may have many schemes
and the destination and you can have
multiple destination so if you are a
multiple devices
you can pass is all with distinct that's
just a nation flags
XO bill will run
when your tests are done where do you
see the results again there's a number
of places where we display the results
with us
the first is a test navigator we'll see
green checkmark
or red icon indicating failure
also and the issue navigator as if you
had a test failure
you'll see not only the failure but the
reason the failed and so if you use our
search in macros this is where you'll
see that air
string that says you fifty with an equal
to 0 or or whatever the
the assertion you were testing
they also shown the source editors got
her and then finally
most useful is the test reports where we
saw all the tests that are Brian
and the logs associated with them and
some additional data
that will get to you later in the
presentation
so let's get started see what it looks
like to add test
to an existing project
let's take a look at how this is put
together um
to simplify this for the demo II tweaked
a little bit from the sample code its
online
but I basically the the got service
ap is this NS operation subclass that
parses
the XML data and this operation as you
know is is
designed to provide concurrency and be
run in the background
this class has a delegate the calls back
with certain events when parsing is done
when its parts certain number of objects
orbiting counters any kind of hair
I so we have this property here
parsed earthquakes and that's something
you can access safely at any time to see
the array a parched earthquake objects
so I like to write a test that validates
the sparse operation behaves correctly
so let's
let's start clean we have
not a clean slate here we're gonna
reset this little bit so you can see
what it looks like to had test to an
existing project
cell we have a project
and at this point there's no test target
so
to add a test I'm going to go to File
menu and was like new target
and you must select under
other Coco test testing and your name
this target
Miller caught two just a be safe and
now we've noticed a few things we see in
a group here
inside that we see a template test file
and if we look if we look at the scheme
will also notice
that under the test action we have this
one that I removed but more importantly
we have this new one that just got added
so this theme template methods and ham
just gonna remove these so we can start
clean build our test out so the first
thing
to recap what I want to do is write a
test for this operation subclass
so I'm gonna import the header so that I
can access
the API's the next thing to do is a at a
test method
and just to reiterate from earlier this
method returns void
this prefix with test and there are no
other parameters
the rest the name is just a name that
I've come up with
that to me represents what this test as
for
now I like to sometimes go through an
outlined
the steps I'm gonna take his comments
before I write the code help me organize
my thoughts.
so just here's a summary what the test
is gonna do
we're going to get the URL to a resource
and that's going to be a resource in XML
data that's in the bundle
willow that into memory we're going to
create the parse operation
then will run the operation directly and
finally
will check the number earthquakes and
see if that's correct so
I'm gonna get a resource to that to the
bundle I need to add the file
well I've had this file here that
is its
the when it
copy this file into my project as a
resource
or copy it in and this is just
some data that I downloaded in advance
because I wanna take the network
out of the equation when I write my test
there's nothing wrong with testing the
network but in general if you keep your
test some poor
when they fail it'll be easier to figure
out why they failed
so in this test I'm not interested in
validated the network works
about dating the parsing works so by
having this
in my bundle I eliminate that as a
concern
so to get the URL ok I'm going to go
into the bond ok
and galleries resource URL
ok and then the next thing we do is just
know that
as in in this data the next step
is to create the parts operation so
that's that's up
that is the class that we are trying to
test here and I'm gonna
create it with this data and I'm not
going to set a delegate because in this
test I don't need to
the next thing is to run the operation
directly
now we know that in this operation is
designed to be run in the background
but operations allow you to invoke them
directly and synchronously
by just calling start that means when we
call start
it was gonna run and your return its
finish running
so at that point I can check the results
and see if they are what I expected
now I had zero here
actually know that there's more than
zero but I'd like to run this and let
you see what a failure looks like
before we go any further so I'm heading
command you to run the test
ran quickly and you can see here's this
message
parts operation 0
failed visit 55 is not equal to 0 okay
so there are 55 earthquakes
in there so let's run this again
and now with passed our test again you
see that same
pass indicator there and the test every
Gator
and we see id here in the test log
that we parsed and succeeded so that's
what it takes to add
has to project would create a new test
target and we go and then we added the
test code would create test methods
we use this sir since to validate the
state that we expect
so will switch back to slide up
okay so what's going on to what's new
and Xcode 6
we have new API's and improvements to
our tools
surfers aorta mention is we've added
some
improvements that help with the
compatibility story
and I'll get into more detail but this
basically means which versions have
Roos as you can target easy actually
test
we've also added instruments integration
for tests and
book will talk to you more about that
later ok
finally we've got new API's as I
mentioned earlier
these are both for a synchronous testing
and for performance testing
so first XE test on older OS versions
originally exit has shipped and it was
part of the IRS release itself
so I meant when we ship to you could
only wanted
on Virgin's ViaWest that hat we've
changed now that worse now worship EXE
test with Xcode itself
so this means that as we add new
features taxi test you don't have to
worry about
whether or not they're going to be
available where you're running your test
because you're always going to be
testing with the current version it's an
Xcode
and this also means that we can
targeted older versions a while so
anywhere that Xcode supports
exit has to also support and this means
I was six
and later
so that's probably good time to just
mention as a unit which is the the tag
the legacy technology that exit house
was derived from
in a Xcode 5.1 we deprecated a CNN
we're not adding new features to it and
we really think the time is now to move
taxing test because we've added new
features to it
integration is better and
as he is no longer where we're focusing
our energies
if you have existing targets that you
want to switch alexi test
we recommend using my greater in Xcode
to do so
the reason for this 022 to do this he
just go to the Edit menu and select we
factor
convert taxi test and it will update the
project settings
and also all here test classes will get
updated
the reason for this is some other build
settings that are so stay with us
are not accessible and the Xcode you I
so
some people in past have tried to do the
migration manually
and the you end up you not able to do it
100 percent by hand
if you are if you really do wanna do it
yourself
there's a different way which is just to
create a new test target which is
guaranteed to have
exactly the right settings and just move
your existing test into it manually
so now let's talk about a synchronous
testing whenever new API's
Xcode 6 some or more API's on our
platform
themselves are a synchronous they have
blocking locations when they're done
that make it run different cues they a
delegate call back that may be deferred
by the run the
they may make network requests which we
absolutely no should be handle a
synchronously
or they're doing background processing
like Rs operation here
so this creates a challenge because test
themselves
run synchronously and sell to help you
with that
we've added API's the allow you to
create a synchronous
control flow that manages a synchronous
activities
and we do this through what we call
expectation objects and these describe
events in your test that you expect to
happen at some point
in the future hopefully not too distant
on with these objects exit s has a %uh a
few I don't wait for them to be
fulfilled
and that takes a timeout and the
completion handler that's called either
when the time out
its or when all the events are fulfilled
and you can be waiting on multiple a
synchronous event at the same time
so let's look at the code example your
document as you may know
has a open with completion handler there
is in a synchronous opening and that's
that's great because it a large document
might take a little bit time to open and
honest all
users interactive experience while
you're waiting for that
so let's write a test for that the first
thing I do is I created an expectation
and these expectations will creation
weapons take string which is simply a
description for your benefit
it tells you if we had a timeout
it tells you what we were waiting for
and so the more descriptive you make
that
the easier your life
then we create a document which I not
showing here we call the open with
completion handler and you notice I
haven't filled out the completion
handler it's just an empty
block at this point on will get back to
that moment
and then finally I call way for
expectations with a five second time
probably a little on the long side but
just to be safe here so what we have now
is a synchronised
what we have create expectation set up
the document
open it and then wait and this is a
synchronous flow within the test
a synchronously later that walk will be
called back
inside the handler I'm gonna do two
things and I use one of our certs
to validate that opening was successful
on top of that I'm gonna call
expectation for Phil
which will cause the wait for
expectations to return because now all
the expectations that created
have been fulfilled so
let's see what that looks like if we add
that to our
seismic smell test
okay so we'll go back to protest injury
here
and for syria do
is going to just rename this
to let's say parsing
and the background
because that's closer to our actual
real-world usage anywhere
so the first for the test is the same
we're still going to use that same
resource file
loaded into memory now before we create
our
parts operation will need to were in
this is where things are going to change
a little bit
so if you think about it we have here
were running the parts operation
directly instead of that
let's run it in an operational cue
so that looks like create an operation
cue
and add the operation to it that means
the operations going to start running
immediately but it's going to do so in
the background
now if I leave the test as is because
that running this happen in the
background
there are passages continuing on its not
stopping
waiting thats it's it's ready to go if
we run this test now
what we're gonna see is that we fail
because at the point where we're
evaluating this
person isn't done its it's often the
background somewhere and we don't
we don't know whether it's been a shit
so what we want to do
is way for to be finished before we
check
then just use it to second time out here
his timeouts are largely
at your discretion on if you make them
really really small
then you may have cases where something
takes a little longer to run and you get
a failure that's
not really failure so those are just
kinda at your discretion
um so now we can wait but before we wait
we also need
expectation that describes what we're
waiting for
so think about the operation how do we
know it's done well it has a stellar get
API
with call backs let's look at what those
were like again so
parts operation the dog call backs we
had
tit Parus did finish that fail with
their
well did finish looks like exactly what
I want so
going back into my test if I'm gonna be
the delegate
I need my test itself to conform to the
dog protocol
and then need to implement the did
finish method
now inside that I'm going to operate on
some kind of expectation and report that
its fulfilled but since we're here
and we're not in the same context here
will need to track
that operation as a property so with
this ad
an expectation property to our test will
set it up
before we create the parse operation so
we've created a expectation pursing
finished as what we're calling it here
and then inside our operation
we will for Philip so let's just run
this
now secret this is actually gonna fail
because I left something out
intentionally
but i wanna what you see what failure
looks like when we had the time
and a synchronous wat
failed exceeded timeout after two
seconds with unfulfilled expectations
parsing finished cell we never fulfill
our expectation
well the reason is pretty simple I
forgot actually say that this object is
the delicate so once we hook that up
we run again this time
everything passes because we get the
call back we fulfill the expectations
we unwind from the wait and then we
evaluate the number parsed earthquakes
its 55 so just walking through this
again
we use an expectation to describe future
event
we wait for the expectation
here and then when that event occurs
which in this case is in a dog called
back but could be inside a block and
there are some other contacts
we fulfill it that causes wait to return
so this allows us to handle a
synchronous activity
in a synchronous fashion it's fine for
testing
I wouldn't recommend you do this on the
main thread if your application code
okay so let's switch back so
that's what looks like to write and I
think earnest test
with the new API's annex at six
now but to talk to you about performance
testing
o'clock now
me easy to introduce performance
russians and you go
and historically finding these issues
can be time-consuming expensive because
you need to manually user applications
fine
Apple has some great tools for
investigating performance issues
and perform assessing is just awaited
tell you want to do an investigation
so we'll look at some new API delete my
dad to hope you
measure performance in detecting
russians and also see how
those met measurements these APIs make
are surface next with you I
including others test failures to do
progressions
and nothin ex-cons gonna be reporting
performance issues
as failures got to give you an easy way
to do that investigation so you can now
profile you test with instruments
the easiest way to do this is to use the
new measure BOC India
mistakes a blocker code and runs a ten
times
measuring the duration each time
and showing the result an ex-con
so for example gonna test here that I
I'm writing that I want to measure the
forms and using about handle
saw call cell measure block and the code
I want to measure
it's creating a file handle using it and
enclosing I'll
now that I've got this test I wanna
profileid
in the case that expert tell me
something went wrong and you can do this
from
tax cuts or senator protest navigators
and from the context menus
and is also a command for this and other
pokémon
it's important to keep in mind that when
you profile your test
misuses settings from skin profile
action
the was obvious difference here is that
when you're just running a test that use
the debug configuration my fault
but profoundly sorry release
configuration and maybe some difference
in behavior
let's take a look at them so here I have
a Mac version the project that will show
you earlier
and according a couple test that use the
measure lucky PI
I'm scar on my chest now
on if you can see this but experts on me
this test is doing
four thousand percent worse than before
so
at that's not so great on
so how am I gonna figure out what's what
what's gone wrong here I can look at the
test itself the sea
now is there anything obvious that ass
is doing wrong outside Press billowing
this
far from the spinal parsing its
and then validating that the earthquakes
alright
I can look in see other any local
changes in on
my project know there are I can look
and see how this test compared to all
the other tests in my project
ands actually this wonderful that
a this one's going bad it was a lot
better
so looks like I'm just got to profile on
I can do that
by right-clicking on the spot in the
store Center and sucking profile
or can also do that from the I
test navigator by right clicking on my
test and talking
profile
house like time profile for instance
al click Record
now and services want my application and
its run my test as done
so all zoom in and it's even see this
I'm just gonna in Britain the call tree
and expand this and from here
I can see my my test is being called
excesses eventually on the block but
I've given it and congress dali
properties which is causing some really
expensive function
well that's that's find out what I want
so
on let's look into that I'm right click
on down the properties
and use reveal an Xcode
you now yeah it is expensive
okay let's let's just get rid of this
was gonna to lead that and run my test
again
at a packed great
so we just seen as you can using a
measure walk if the IQ
measure performance and detector
aggressions
you can use results and sore center and
its report
and you can also profile your test with
instruments
so you just gonna taste how performance
testing works with Xcode
let's go into details for small sending
baselines
for exit asked to report a test as
failing due to a regression
needs a fix points compared its and the
bass anglers do that
miss an aviation exhibition only
important performance regression when
something's actually gotten worse
access use a standing ovation to
determine the spread in the measurements
to tell how reliable they are
and by measuring precisely we have some
additional API's
will you be even more precise about what
you want to measure
so it's a good baselines the baseline is
the average from previous one
you specifically selected for comparison
once you set a baseline exits will use
this
to detect would russians it will fail a
test
if he new average has increase from
baseline average by 10 percent or more
and it will ignore regressions less than
a tenth of a second
missus to eliminate a source a false
positives
the baselines are stored in source where
you commitment to your positive for E
and show them a good team members
and the store per device configuration
so when I run tests on my iPhone 5s
they're gonna be using the same
baselines that one will run the same
test
on his iPhone I guess I'm are you
but at the same time if I were to run
these tests I in the simulation
assimilated iPhone 5s
I would not use those based on because
that would be a different device
configuration
so it's talk about how you said
baselines affects
the first time around test I'm gonna see
an aunt is like this
with us grey diamond but the white dot
net
telling me there's no baseline to test
now let me know that it didn't do any
comparison
all and it's showing me the average but
that
time and the test took
I click on the application or get the
performance with a pop or
I get this from the store center or from
that new test report
from here I can see the current average
from test I can also see how the
individual measurements
that were taken differ from that urge so
here I can see that
i'd measurement number eight was the
longest one
now when I'm running to and clicks at
baseline an external
used I will copy the current average to
the baseline
I need to set this again I can click at
and either accept the new current
average
or taken whatever I want as as the
baseline
I can also edit the max from Sandy Asian
from here
now nurse at the baseline the next
summer on my test
all see a different allocation with this
great time with the check mark
at telling me that this test is doing
four percent worse
in the baseline that's compared against
if the tests were to do a lot worse
the test would fail I'm getting out is
like this telling me that
now it's sixty percent worse in this
case
I can also see the results from that new
test report
on also from the test report again get
the
performs look hop over by clicking under
the time call on those measurements
if you want to get at the brawl values
that I i
exco gets from Exodus those are
available on the Logs tab on this report
so what to talk about how exit s uses
the base on average
here's here have a dataset from one run
a test
there are 10 measurements for the 10
indications walk
and the whole culture on that one sec
mark with a one-second average
all set the baseline for my test which
fixes that in place
and the next time I ran my tests already
got to do said like this
the average be one second I wanna have
seconds
and the test would fail because that 1/2
seconds is
well outside the bounds the allowed
tempers Russian
so acted as an appellate s if the
new average has increased from the
baseline by more than 10 percent
but it's getting or regression what and
attend a second
but is is damage in a
let's look at that same decide again on
values Kontron one second
one second average
it harder on this test again and get
their stuff like this
hasn't really regrets the average is
still one sec but there some values
over wanna have seconds and some under
half a second
so it isn't a true regression in terms
of the average but something's gotten
worse
something that are you gonna do
something like this I want investigate
so the other just doesn't tell the whole
story and exit acid used an aviation
to indicate the spread the measurements
if we look at that first dataset more
time we see that it's any Asian said
for these numbers helicopter on one
second six-percent
while sanitation for the much more
spread out dubstep
is 40 percent
and awaited decision is this is
if the sanitation for the new dataset
is more than 10 percent in the current
average which you can adjust from that
job
poor will fail but again just like the
average
warden or sanitation less than a tenth
of a second again to
avoid potholes
so what causes excess a standing ovation
wall one thing is if the market you're
measuring is doing network I our file
I'll
that at Penn said barrier pretty wildly
and I think they can cause hi San
deviation
is if me
open what this isn't trying to do the
same work each time so for example
if on the block is being measured does
some expand
submit expensive global state the first
time through and then never again
one block might just be affected by an
initial very
and lastly and I think calls can cause
high syndication
is if the system is just busy with other
processes and short running tests are
specially sent into this
so how does exit s detect issues
for saw if there's no baseline average
it's done talking trying
and do anything else s on the
measurements if they're is
a base on average personal check to see
if that Sandy Asian
is more than 10 for the second and more
than 10 percent
the current average it is will fail for
that
otherwise don't check to see if the
average has in increase by
more than 10 tend to the second and more
than 10 percent of the baseline
and if it is a bill for that and
otherwise it'll pass
so how can we minimized and additional
one way is
and only measure the code it's important
to you
so let's look at how we can do that
without previous example
here this test is doing the work of
setting up
filehandle using it and closing I'll
handle
each time we want to block but if I only
measure the time using handle I might do
is just
move the set-up and tear-down work
outside on the block
but what I can do that sometimes the
work that you want to measure
require some setup work needs to be done
each time before the measurement
and for that we have some additional API
measure metrics
on a map to start measuring with block
you can use this matter just
are the block that that incall
the city I expect an array of metrics to
measure
I'm currently only time is supported
will also need to mourn can I start
measuring and stop measuring
uses isolate what apart what you want to
measure
you call these once per block indication
and you're gonna call start measuring
you need to pass a No for automatically
start
measure
salty how that would work with our peace
example
first I G we change the method to calm
measure metrics passing time as the
Metric and no problem at the start
measuring
call start measuring right before you
file handle and stop making immediately
afterwards
so now this block is doing the work
outstanding up the filehandle
and Tara down each time but it's only
actually
manning the duration spending useful and
let's look at this impacts so this paper
name in this project actually thinking
about
adding AI Jason partner to a I've got
a test them right here that's a
loading his file from on the web
and partner with industry consultation
I think and actually like to turn this
into a performance test
just my own sake and do that now
con by calling measure block
and pasting & Co and I'll click
to my test
so here we can see that it took I says
on average
1.91 seconds with a hundred fourteen
percent sanitation
as long as no based on average for this
test all that's
that's not bad but I know that its
senses doing is expensive work going
this far from your
from the the way each time actually
don't wanna measure that I just wanna
the time spent in Astrakhan shows Asian
so all do is all delete this call
measure time
measure metrics which is passing time
as biometric and no from a quick start
measuring then on to do is call
start measuring right before
industry consultation I can on my test
great so previously it was taking 1.91
seconds
and now it appears to be taking no time
at all so it's pretty good
I
which I might get a quick arm
but actually wanting this to measure
something
you know something that Xcover report
something significant so
wanna do with a change this to use a
larger file so we actually get that some
values here and sent a couple little
longer cuz
was actually doing is it's gonna Kong's
block
ten times loading file from
the web each time and parsing so now the
test is taking it looks like
1.21 seconds and its gonna very low
standard deviation which is pretty good
sometime click to set this as my new
baseline
and since that seem to take a while I
was gonna
move this out the block since the
the data that's loading is actually
immutable I don't need to do this every
time
sums can do that once on a test
initially starts
click through my test again and still
got a
a result around the same ballpark and
still got a pretty reasonable San
deviation
on other not actually doing any work
before start measuring on need all this
summers and delete that and
changes back to call mister block run it
again
Michigan similar results
and at what I can do so the last thing I
like to do with this
is like will show its earlier we become
our test to be self-contained we don't
want to
be link all some network so
I miss can change this said actually are
you going to copy this file my project
news asthma model for classed to love
this
on one file from my test target
run it again and every go
so now I've got a new performance tests
measuring
the time that takes to run this and if
something were to change
I find out the last thing I want to do
gonna commit my changes so here we can
see
the changes I made so far cover that
really expensive function
change my test two be a performance test
and we can also see the baseline here
so I can tell from this but this is
actually a file that store inside the
pocket on lots of
talk about that and out same their
for next time next time
so what you just saying is that you can
use new measure
walk API's to measure performance an
attacker russians
you can telex code what the baseline is
to specify what constitutes or russians
for your test
I'm and it won't exc actually test will
use a standing ovation
to inform you spend the measurements
and finally won something does go wrong
you can always use instruments provide I
like to invite will back up
okay great so
22 ago back to everything we talked
about today
a we start off with thinking about help
why should we test in the first place
what are the benefits
you know it helps us identify bugs
before we ship
it also helps as described and really
think about the
impacting the API's representing project
and then we talked about how do you add
tests and and also had an organized
person to targets
in your project test methods loading
resources from the test bundle
and using the assertions insider test
and then we talked about the new a
synchronised SAPI
which allows you to get synchronous
control flow
around a synchronous past and then broke
talk you through
performance testing and also the
instruments integration that lets you
profile your test and that's a really
powerful feature
because your test code is going to be
executing critical paths in your project
and then to easily be able to hoppin
instruments and analyze
time profiles object dollar profiles
I is really great to appear to have and
if you have questions we encourage you
to contact data logger
tools evangelist and there's a few
related sessions you know early on I
talked about this continuous integration
workflow
and exit ask combined with Xcode server
make that possible where you can set up
server that will
on commit our schedules check out your
code
run all your tasks and report the
results so there's a
session on that later this afternoon
right here in this room a better
thanks a lot folks