good afternoon everyone welcome to you
our session continuous integration with
Xcode six thanks for being here this
afternoon
my name is branching come a softer
engineer army Xcode team
today we'll talk about my favorite topic
which is of course continuous
integration
so just a show of hands how many people
are using some kind of continuous
integration system out there
alright our son okay expression
how many people are using Xcode server
okay okay
good well well we hope next year when we
ask that question
that's going to be everyone so if you're
not familiar with continuous integration
we're gonna teach you all about it today
we're going to talk to you about
are continuous integration product which
we call Xcode server
we're gonna tell you about all the great
new things we built into
Xcode server if I wanna see that slide
are
at three months a great new features in
Xcode server in Xcode 6
going to be a lot of demos because it
really shows well
on the screen so first if you're not
familiar with
continues electorate integration what is
that all about
more fundamentally it's all about
improving software quality
and there a lotta ways it does that a
continuous integration system a cat has
problems quickly
and automatically so you don't have to
worry that when you make a change at the
end of the day
and you'll even introduced a bill there
a warning not to worry about that not
being caught
until the next morning because the
system like this is gonna cut it for you
quickly and automatically and for me
that really enhances collaboration
because you don't have to worry
about a blocking your team members
and let's face it when you're writing
code you taking lotta risks
you doing interesting creative things
you can introduce problems
and a system like this helps you I got
helps catch those problems quickly
another key thing is a system like this
helps problem
run on your test coverage because you
have your code running on a server
the server can support lots of different
testing configurations would be a big
pain to do on a client
so not a great thing about
a server product that's building your
code the can gather history so
build history in Test history for your
product overtime
this is actually really interesting
because at the beginning of
are product development cycle as I'm
sure you know there's a lot of change
there's a lot to turn and there's
probably you're probably introducing a
lot issues
here to sing warnings and static
analysis issues and you probably don't
have a lot of tests
at the beginning and it towards the and
love that cycle
you don't have any issues anyone a lot
of tests and a system like this
will help gather that history and show
it to charities such a great indication
where you are
kinda been your product development
cycle and of course a system like this
makes it really easy preview distribute
builds to your team
so hopefully have testers I hope
everyone does
and if you do a system like this makes
it easy to distribute those kinda built
so terminology
bear with me here so there are three
terms that we're going to talk about
over and over again in relation to
exclude server
term number one is a scheme so I'm ok
with anyone but I'm sure if you've used
Xcode for a while
you've seen this term and it's really
simple all the scheme is
just a recipe for building your product
it contains
the targets that you want build on the
target intern
contains the source files in the
resources and everything else that make
up your product
so why this important for export server
it's important
because the scheme is to be shared this
is not a big deal
excavated really easy to share schemes
but when you first create a scheme
were next to a greater scheme for you
that scheme was injured water how to do
it it's not a big deal
to something to keep in mind so turned
over to you
bought answer from the Bach and I
it's just the thing that we the word we
use to refer to the thing that builds
your software on schedule and
when the bot runs we say that it
integrates that makes an integration
so these are the three key terms scheme
bought and integration
so let's take a look and a little more
depth
at are from the bot so
what defines a bot so
up
fundamentally there to keep this
information one is the property want to
block
to build that's pretty basic the second
is the SCM information or the source
control information so where does your
product live
so if your product lives and get
repository or a Subversion repository
and Xcode can check out your project
been incredible
for your project that's really simple on
next part about about
a bot is the schedule so when do you
want the bot integrate the lot possible
options here
you can choose discover your bod
periodically so every hour one today
your you once a week if you want are
there's also on commits bar
on commit parts and it's a very popular
option because it means whenever anyone
commit source control
to repository about a fire of
integration
and of course there's also a manual
scuttling to
cell how to build
I'm so the solution scheme comes into
place the shirts came to the bar
how to build the project and you can
also configure three other option so
you want about to run static analysis
join protests
and you want to go archives and finally
about won't be a whole lotta good I
wouldn't tell you when something went
wrong
so we have a great system for
notifications and you can set these up
the fire before about integrates
and after about immigrants so that your
you and your team know the results in
the generation
it's like I said
been we call our continuous integration
product Xcode server
and their to you parts mexico server
actually there's the
Xcode Park apart within the expert
application and there's a part that
lives in the Austin server application
this is important to know if you try to
set this up with just Xcode you not
gonna get very far
we also need to get Austin server you to
get partisan
a new preview not be a warning about the
website this week
and when it gets released are to the
public it's also available on the App
Store
so there are two parts to it instruments
features
that integrates very easily with the
Apple Developer Program and this is
really important
because in order to run any of your code
on devices we need to do all the
provisioning and certificate stuff
arm and that is to know your Apple
Developer information in order to do all
that
apart the product we make it really easy
to get started without
in a course occurred to rebuild any I
was a Mac products
the Facebook and all that ex-con served
and when the really great features
about exco server is that it can run
your tests on multiple devices in
simulators
so think about it before we have this
product if you want to test
on a couple iPhones in a couple iPad's a
couple iPod Touches
you have to plug each one of these and
here your development system
separately and run the tests on them it
was a big pay but I can plug all those
devices and to an expert server
you can configure bought to run tests on
all those devices
and it's great you have is that really
brought has covered are talking about
before
the course expert server can produce IPA
in pkg files
seeking to more easily distribute these
products and his great
integration in Xcode it looks pretty
good too like I said I was 10
server is the other com part of this
equation said it was really easy has got
great features like Coast repositories
and this is where you you configure the
device is that you wanna make available
for testing your software will show you
them about in just a minute so last year
extra five major tax cuts over for the
first time
we're really really proud of its up its
features at
when we took a look at the product and
we took a look at what features you
wanted to build
in this release and future releases is
pretty clear to us that there were parts
are the foundation that we really need
to improve
so we're happy to say we have a shiny
new foundation for Xcode server in Xcode
it's much better in all ways it's faster
more reliable
super scaleable and its largest at our
sport for all these great features like
support for swift support for
performance testing a new feature we
call issue tracking
and probably the most requested feature
from the first version
was triggers thank you
thank you just wait just right up like I
said we have a great new foundation
Superliga super reliable and it's really
skillful to
so I decided to do a little test a few
weeks ago attacking all Mac Pro
I was sitting in my office a 25 year old
Mac Pro it wasn't doing anything which
is
was a nice for rest for me on a set up
ex-con server
on Xcode 6 on and I decided to add a few
boats
so I started with a small app it started
with the but the DC up
you have today new devices a credible
for that that went pretty well
I decided to just keep going so
at a bar for Xcode that went really well
at a bot for games under that went
pretty well again these are parts are
running on this one alzheimer
Hyderabad for the maps project for you I
K miles all going well so I threw up
getting there too
this is a very old piece of hardware its
billing box for all these products both
small be given a really big and is doing
just great
so this is something that just wasn't
possible with the first version Mexican
server
triggers okay so we heard you you ask
for this loud and clear
and we're really a really great story
for traders so we support triggers
both before an immigration starts and
after an innovation runs
and there are lots of interesting
reasons for supporting both of these
on their number of conditions you can
specify
determine when a trigger runs and their
two talk two triggers
there's a shell script writer and at
Notre so it's really cool
about shell script triggers that you can
do anything you want to do
right should the shell script and we
provide a number environment variables
that you can leverage in the shell
scripts
and we'll see a few of those in the demo
in just a little bit
are that your reports that we provide
you can configure them to you
show you just the minimum amount
information which is just like the
builders and warnings
are or you can customize those and make
them really rich
and out all the issue tracking that we
do
speaking issue tracking what is this
what an issue an issue with either a
built-in warning
build their static analysis issue
or a test failure and issues are
important
you don't wanna ship software with
issues the fact we have a policy
really good policy on the X codeine
waters there's a build
morning or static analysis issue are in
the store space
that's a p1 and that's what we work on
it's important we can ship with these
things
and you should check with them either
and by having a great issue tracking
service in Xcode server makes it really
easy to know when those issues
get introduced and we can do really cool
things like a contract that issue all
throughout its life cycle
so the issue still exists we mark that
as an on resolve issue
and then when an issue finally gets
resolved we service that in reports to
and because it's got server tracks all
this history over time it's really great
easy to see when an issue was introduced
are and even who introduced were we can
be pretty smart about that
so has a lot of stuff there um butter
really
bring the point home I think it's better
to show and mrs. like to bring up Matt
number one
is gonna talk about these things
alright thank you so much brent
and as you heard we got a real a lot a
really great new features in
experts-- German experts 6 are but in
case you've never used before we're
gonna start from the very beginning
which begins in server cell we have West
End server
installed on this machine which you can
get from developer that Apple that com
you need the preview to work with Xcode
6 beta that you all got this week
I we've already set it up on this
machine you can see our servers called
pop art
I and it's ready to start integrating so
what we're gonna do is set up
Xcode server so we select Xcode
on the left hand side in the services
West and the first thing that we ask you
to do
is choose which version of Xcode you're
going to be using so you do need
Xcode installed on your server machine
in order for X whatever to work because
that's what actually does all the
building
arm but we give you choices which ex
could you use
in case you want to try out a new
version of Xcode or in case you need to
support multiple versions RBIs SDK or
something like that
so we're gonna select the Xcode that you
all have a copy of right now
and when I choose that its gonna start
setting up our database
it's going to generate Klein SSL
Certificates and its gonna start all
over processes
so that we're ready to start doing
integrations with tax cuts are and after
a few seconds
that set up and it's ready to go now if
you're doing Mac development only
that's all you need to do you can stop
right there all set
good to go are because gonna be testing
on devices and everything that we do and
I always need to be code signed
we also need a way for Xcode server to
be able to do that Kodak
and for that we're going to join Apple
Developer Connection team to do that
we next to the developer teams label
there's an Add button
so will choose that and then you sign in
with your Apple ID
and once you've signed in that's going
to give you the option to become a
member
all your developer team so when I click
add what is actually going to do
is add your server as a new person on
your Apple developer team gets its own
set of certificates
private keys signing identities and it's
also going to download a copy of all be
provisioning profiles that work with the
app's that you have registered
4ap ID's on your developer team and it
can take a few seconds because it does
go out make Ubuntu Certificate Signing
requests
and then pour does all in once it
finishes you'll see that you are now a
member
all the developer team that you signed
up for now
said going to test the devices I do have
an iPad Mini right here
you can all see 30 I am when I'm gonna
do
is plug it in right into my server
machine
and after just a second in the devices
West
back shows up so you can see it's ready
to use and it shows which teams it
enabled for
if this devices never been used before
you also get an option right here to
choose use for development and that goes
out to the port on attitude albertine
so really easy to do from the screen
you also have the option of configuring
who can use your server so
by default orkut this at a button here
you can see that but can be created by
anyone who can login
I and anyone can view those box once
they've been created
we want to lock it down just a little
bit more so I'm gonna choose
only some users can create parts
administrators is fine for me
but I'll turn view only access for
everyone back up cell
that's pretty good for me i think thats
a good good centre-backs controls for my
server
from OS 10 server you can also set up
hosted repositories if you like IX
conservative host your pocket or spore
you can do that here
you can also set that up directly from
within Xcode but that's all we need
from server for right now so I'll close
server and will head back over into
Xcode itself so when she wants tax code
the first thing you're gonna need to do
is set up an account for your server
and that happens in the Preferences
window on the accounts to
you can click the plus button in the
bottom left hand side
and choose ad server and you can see my
server bobber is gonna show up right
here saw select proper
choose next and log in with my username
and super secret password and there you
offset
our wedding new features that we've had
in Xcode six which we think is pretty
useful ways down at the bottom of the
Accounts window
we do show you which version OS 10 OS 10
server
and Xcode your server machine is using
so if you've got multiple servers and
something starts going a little funky
you can look right here and it'll tell
you what your server machine is running
that's not a bad place to start when
you're trying to diagnose the problem so
that's all set
we're gonna close the account went up
ever gonna open
our project and it's a project called
coffee board
so our team from time to time
we make mistakes we're only human II
don't make that many mistakes but some
people on our team do
I and when that happens it's a mistake
happens that causes someone
to spend more than happy day fixing a
problem we think
retribution is in order so we britain
nap that keeps track of when that
happens
and assigns debts of coffee and ice
cream
to the members of our team and we call a
copy boy so that's the separate here
idea to Matt's gonna show it to you a
little bit later ob you can see it's got
a lot of tests all setup guide is
written in swift which is pretty cool
so incredible for that project a switch
over to the report navigator
and I'll choose from the product menu
great pop
now the first choice you get is which
scheme your project is going to
integrate with I'll use the IRS one you
get to choose
what the name of your project within a
mere bachche is going to be such as
coffee board
are you also choose which server your
pockets created on and whether or not
integrates immediately after creation so
I'll leave that set
now one of the issues that some people
ran into in the first generation X good
server
was that you go through the process of
creating a body would all look like it
was all fine
and then your but would go to run its
first integration and it wouldn't be
able to check out your project
which wasn't fun is that wasn't all that
easy to fix so when the new features
without an Xcode 6
is the concept love source control
pre-flight
so what's gonna happen when I click Next
is it's going to scan your entire
workspace
find all the source control working
copies that it knows about
gather up the credentials the tax code
knows about that goes with those
repositories
package them up in a nice secure with a
bundle and send them up to the server
so that the server can determine right
now if there's going to be a problem
when it's time to check out the
repository
so I'll click Next tactical future
so I click Next it tells us that all the
repositories that it found
the coffee board repository it could not
indicate and that's because I was
recently a victim of identity theft so I
change my password
so what I can do now is correct this
issue right away so click the Change
button
enter my user name and my new password
click Next and this time it says my
credentials are verified
so it knows that when it goes to check
out my but for the first time it's going
to work which is a really comforting
feeling
cell now we have an option to choose how
frequently we want are brought to run
which is great by default it's going to
be a periodic bar
that runs hourly on the hour but because
we want this to be a little bit more
alive
for our demo we're gonna choose on
commit so that every time we make a
change the bot
it's going to kick off a new immigration
you askin choose which
actions about will run when integrates
and also how frequently it cleans
by the fall we always do incremental
bills but because I really like squeaky
clean box
I'm gonna choose always now depending on
which scheme you select
if your scheme can build targets that
have products that run on
I O S or on Mac you have a choice out
where your targets
will run for testing cell since we're
doing
and i OS target we are going to you use
I West
but we do have an option to specifically
which devices are tests will run on
so I'll drill down into that and shoes
the iPad that a correct collect
connected
earlier on and then you get the option
to configure triggers and I'm gonna talk
more about that in just a minute but we
will show you that by the fall
we create a trigger that will send an
email notification when something goes
wrong
and you can choose if you'd like that
email to be sent to all your computers
and you can also build another West up
email addresses if you'd like to send it
to more people
you can choose what goes into that email
message where do you want issue an
analysis issue summaries
the commit message is if you wanna hide
those because they might that contain
sensitive information
or you can turn both off if you just
want people to know that integration is
completed
are you asking choose when they see this
when that you know will get sent whether
it's on success
test failures bill there is or any
combination of the three
so we could create are but will get
created
and after a few seconds it'll start
integrating
and you can see another great new
feature we have an expert 6 is alive
progress information
right down to the cops source file
that's being compiled by a pop
see you can really keep close tabs and
exactly what's happening while
integrating which is really cool so so
take a few seconds to compile
and once that's done it'll start running
tests on the iPad that we have connected
right here
and I know you can't see it but it's
unlock the iPad
the app is launching
and the Tessera
and you can see we have been result for
integration that has completed
are you can see that because multiple
people have committed
a to the repository for this integration
we have a nice break down
all the chametz and we have these nice
little circles which indicate
relative to each committer how much
about integration Bay
own so to speak it's the number files
that have been changed
and if I click on a computer I can see
which commits were made
by those commuters which is pretty cool
but because a single integration
isn't that exciting we're gonna switch
over to our other machine
which has bought that's been baking for
a few days
Sep you can see this but has been
running for quite a while
I've gotten taller next this file has
been running for quite a while and it's
got a much more interesting history
arm which is a great way for us to show
off another new feature that we're
really excited about which there
issue tracking feature sofa select
integration number four
you can see that shows we have no errors
one warning one analysis issue
and six tests ran successfully but these
warnings and issues
our new women in this integration and
you can see that Xcode server smart
enough to notice that because it puts a
plus-one
under each in those circles so that we
know that these were just recently
introduced
and you can see here in the issue
summary it also says new issues
one warning one out this issue well I
came along and fix that warning
so an integration 5 you can see that it
says
resolved issues morning on use variable
and knows based on the file location of
these issues
and the message that the issues
generated that this is exactly the same
issue
and we can safely say that this issue
has been resolved so that's really great
way to keep an eye on the health of your
store space
really really cool we also have here
logs just like you would see for local
projects integrated in Xcode
and you can even drill down into them
and see the same kinda view that you
would expect from looking at these
from a local product which is really
cool
but now I wanna show you probably what
was be most requested feature from
the first person experts Arbor which is
triggers
triggers a really cool and we're really
excited to show you what they can do
so we'll start by talking about how we
work with them on our team
we have a friend his name is Jeeves
and he sits in our messages chat room
all day long answering useful
questions for us like what's the weather
like
for instance you can see in Cupertino it
seventy 70 degrees and partly cloudy
I of course here in the beautiful city
of San Francisco
it is a good 12 degrees colder which is
to be expected
are but Jesus really helpful we really
like having him around and it's very
helpful to our team to be able to get
that kind of information on the fly
but we want to supercharge this with
information from Xcode server
and the best way to do that is with
traders
so we'll switch over and Xcode have put
that up so you can see it side by side
I'm gonna at the bar and most in the
settings I'm going to leave the same
because we're not really changing much
about the Bach
and you'll see as i click Next it will
re validate those credentials that
except earlier to make sure nothing is
broken in the meantime
will leave all that information the same
but when we get to the trigger screen
I'll choose at trigger and select run
script
now I've already got some triggers
written down here this is a ruby script
bare shell script by the fall but you
can put a little
I should bang at the front here and run
using whatever interpreted like
and all this does it hits a NAACP and
point that we expose
on Jeeves I and it uses things like the
integration number
and the bot name to build a message that
we're showing our chat room
so all select all of that and paste into
a trigger
I'm gonna do the same for post
integration trigger
and these are just a little bit
different you can see I actually use the
failure count
our account warning count said we can
provide even more information on our
chat room
and proposed integration triggers you
get a choice up what condition under
what conditions your trigger will run
whether it's only on success
only when something goes wrong or any
combination house
so I create the triggers arches update
and then to kick off a new immigration
ever bop
so put the status here and you can see
we gonna message in our chat room
immigration 49 coffee board is now
starting
and that message ran after the source
code check out happened
so that way if you'd like to for
instance inject versioning information
into your bill product
you can do that right from a pre
integration trigger which we think is
really cool
you can see the innovation completed and
we got yet another into
in job information message in our chat
room because want to take it
just one little step further we had
another little feature we can say
Jeeves ok not whether Jeeves
integrate coffee court
and you can see is kicking off another
integration exco which we think is
pretty cool
so that's just one of the many things
that you can do with triggers where sure
you have ideas about how you want
integrate them into your own workflow
are we have a lab right after the
session come see us come talk to us
and we can help you make sure that you
can make triggers do whatever you would
like
I thanks so much Brent back to you
so of course the big news this week
switch support
so how's execute server deal with swept
well deals with it just like it deals
with objective-c
it as complete feature parity with
objective-c projects so whether you have
pictures with project
with you have a mixed swift in
objective-c product there's good server
in every box other projects no problem
all the features work the same
this is true testing supports whether
you write unit tests in objective-c
or your item in swift all the testing
support just works
the same goes for performance testing an
expert there is always had great
assistant editor integration in Xcode it
still doesn't of course that works just
as well for swift code
as it does for objective-c code
we'll talk about performance testing
this is another great thing we released
this week and if you haven't heard any
the talks yep
I recommend to go out go back in
washington there's a session this
morning about testing
and processing is is pretty great its
and what we've
minute really simple arm
the great thing about it in the context
of Xcode server is that when you write a
performance test
you can have expert server run that test
on multiple devices
so this is this is really great so you
may be surprised to find that your code
runs a lot slower on one device
11 operating system and you expected it
to
and server it's really easy to see this
the key thing about performance testing
is that they work great on the box you
can just write your code in a measure
block
I you don't have to set a baseline but
if you set a baseline you get a lot more
value out of them
anything with baseline does he have to
set them on a protest heard about per
device
basis so that looks something like this:
we have this report you can see all the
tests here you can see I have a couple
different devices that these tests are
running on
and I in order to get more value of
these need to set a baseline
for each test which device this is the
UI that does that
we'll see more about in a minute so case
this is new to you
this is this is what a performance test
looks like it's really simple
this is what it looks like in
objective-c any code in the metabolic
here's gonna get executed
ten times sarisi and swift
we have
also a measure block
factory closure but its so called matter
block that's the API
I it's the same thing so to show you all
this in action I'm gonna bring up my
office mate Matt number two
was allowed as keyboard I have ever
heard to show them a
mama
thank you brent so I'm really excited to
be here today to share
new Xcode server in Xcode sex with you
guys I'll
support for swift art brand new
programming language
an awesome new performance testing
features right so we have the eye with
anywhere open with our coffee board
application
ago list were here with me Matt Brent
and some of our friends
and our balance is so looks like I've
got a negative balance
I guess they are some people some coffee
and here we see a list with exactly what
I own each person or what they owed to
me
I think I remember brain causing me a
bad issue earlier in the week
that cost me sometimes I forgot to add
that transaction
I can do that right here and it'll get
added to the list
now I'm worried bed as we keep adding
transactions we have
some back and forth a on our team I'm
worried that as this grows
that condensing these down into a nice
list for the UI
is gonna get more time consuming so I
want to test the performance about make
sure
it stays good as I keep adding to the
application
and the performance testing feature next
good sex make it really easy to do
to make with the simulator and switch
back to exco
so here got an exit SK some class with a
buncha test making sure that
the function I have for condensing down
these transactions works correctly
I think we all know there's more to a
great application just working correctly
customers expect great performance they
want your apt to be fast and get out of
their way
and performance testing feature will
help you make sure that that's the case
some to add a new performance tester
application
and I'm gonna go ahead and commit that
to my repository so that tax cuts are a
concert integrating that
push that up while it's doing that I'll
take a closer look at what the status is
actually doing
so it's just like any other unit assets
just method on your test exit SK some
class
starts with the word test takes no
arguments returns a value
first thing we do is created mister
transactions that were gonna emerge
and then I don't want to waste any time
measuring thats I do it outside been
the measure block and Nathan except here
we call this measure block function
and passionate closure and whatever code
inside there will run multiple times
and measure the time each iteration and
average this together
report that to you so I think our
integration is finish completing
some can go take a look at that now
we have a this lovely test report that's
new in Xcode 6
breaks down exactly what happened in
each test I can see I'm
performance tests is here in the list
I've got this new column for Time
reports the average time that
generational a test set
looks like this: 2.15 seconds on average
that seems pretty good if I click that
time
that I can see a breakdown by device
only got the one device plugged in right
now but I can have several
they would each have their own time
measurements
max could stymie something here telling
me that that we have no baseline
for the time performance metric and
that's because when you first had a test
a performance test
excuse not to make any assumptions about
what's good performance and what's not
because every test is unique and every
device is unique
and we don't wanna make any presumptions
so we report the time for you
but we won't try to fail your test based
on how performs if you have any
assertions and your tests
or fail based on that but that
but when I keep working on this
application
I wanna know if this performance get
gets worse i won X considerate to notify
me
when that happens by failing my test and
to do that
I can fit a baseline for this test
to do that I click the time for this
particular device
I can't hit the set baseline
and what happens when I click that
button is that Xcode
updates its project file with entries to
say for this particular test
for this particular kind of device like
iPhone 5s
iPhone 4s iPad that me that this is the
performance standard
that if we significantly regressing get
slower than this
number that should fail a test
and the interesting thing about this
getting added to the project files
is that they get committed source
control I'm gonna go ahead and do that
now because I want our
about to be able to use them you can see
these are just
property list you can edit them by hand
if you want but we've got a nice UI and
that s report for managing the space
I'm gonna push that up Latics conserve
start integrating
and while it's doing that we can look at
the test report here
weekend we have a lot of filtering
options here like we can
show only failed test which I don't have
any of which is great
if we want we can just focus on the
performance test like the one I just
added
if there's a particular test I'm
interest in looking at I can search by
name
fell to just SMS that name
or if I'm interested and what I happen
what the code is for specific test
I can click the Follow button here and
jump right to the code for that test
now see what what's happening with about
we can see exactly which tests it's
running america's
and healthy what happens when a test run
when we have a baseline for
so now I can see that this time our
tests ran a little bit worse
and little bit longer than the baseline
that I set by testo passes because it's
within a
acceptable range we understand that
there's going to be fluctuations between
each test run
and we don't want to fit fail over
zealously
so let's see what happens when I
actually do introduce a significant
regression
some you switch back to the code that
handles merging these transactions
now what I have here is clearly working
my tests are passing
the performance tests are succeeding
but I'm worried that later on when I
come back to look at this
I'm not really gonna understand what
this was doing I think I have an idea
for how I can rewrite this function in a
way that makes more sense to me that I'd
understand better later
I'm just gonna be a little reckless
hearings committee right away because I
know Xcode server has my back
if I break the application are fine make
it perform significantly worse
X cancer is gonna tell me and my entire
team
I'll push that up let that start
integrating I'm really excited about
this performance testing feature
but they can make your tests were close
lower
so Xeon server give you a great way to
I speak keep your speedy workflow but
still take advantage of these
performance
s now that bill run slower because were
running several iterations
ways on ideally significant work
otherwise and when the test
so you can set up an one scheme Xcode
server runs
that runs all your tests including your
performance tests and another one to run
locally
just rancher quicker once to get the
best of both worlds
I think I saw gf's tell me that my
integrationist on
on our looks like I have some failing
tests
I guess that new merge function wasn't
as good as the old one
looks like it is performing a hundred
and thirty-seven percent worse
that's pretty bad I don't wanna ship bad
when we
when we ship our application but I'm a
little busy to fix a renowned
busy giving at WWDC presentation so
I'm gonna trust that our notifications
let my team know and that someone else
will take care fixing
I
Matt go ahead and high tax code have one
more thing
I wanna show you guys so last year when
we introduce expense over
we gave a great way to give high
visibility to what all your box we're
doing
inside your office and we called the big
screen and we have a new
beautifully updated version a big screen
I'd like to show you now
so this is a new big-screen
along the left side you can see we have
a list about
these are all the box configured on our
server we got a little punny
on our team ICANN fee that below each
but name
we have icons indicating what kinda
issues we might have on those pots
so coffee board is clearly has test
failures in a performance regression
about it looks like someone started into
at started new integration on their out
somebody came along and fix my mistake
now when we focus on each pot
show account so airs warnings
analysis issues test or test failures
that some are failing
even show the change in that both
numbers from the previous integration
along the bottom you can see both the
committers
and you can see even if they we have
issues that we've attributed to them
how many those might have they might
have and looks like coffee board finish
integrating our tests are now passing
which is great looks like somebody came
along affects my mistake looks like it
was the other Matt
so applause for him but
and that's the new big-screen
that I've got to show a are handed back
to Breck thank you
thanks Matt
mother great demos by two great guys
both at the same name
sup in summary
we've got a great new foundation in this
version: second server
got tons a bug fixes and other
improvements please keep sending us your
feedback we are listening
and we've got great great new features
like
in flight progress notification so you
can see exactly what your body is doing
when it is raining
we have issue tracking so conservative
tell you when issue was introduced
if it still exists who introduced the
issue and finally when it was resolved
this gives you a great sense of the
overall health of your project
we have a great new testing
are test result are you why including
support for performance testing
a really easy way to set baselines for
tests for individual devices
and of course we have awesome support
for triggers
so I've got lab right after this here's
more information if you need to come to
the lab
and maybe even try to out to address and
write something even more awesome than
our friend Jeeves comment so that's it
thank you
have been weak