I
good afternoon thank you are welcome to
what they tell me a session for 16
modern frameworks
to me. talking a lot about mostly I'm
the mechanics setting up modern
frameworks on IRS
some the API design principles that we
use it up on
and we recommend you guys use if you
were here for and Ian Collins talk
just before this I they really delved
into a lot of the
deep architectural components
apart build your application me to cover
some the higher level stuff and then
we'll go through a quick tour of Xcode
and talk about how some of these things
get built directly into your apt and
just a mechanic to getting all about
setup
so I'm how many of you have actually
used
I am static libraries in your
application you get from a third party
that everyone okay if you're doing it
without one of those things you're
probably using the target management
mechanisms in Xcode
right you download a bunch of source
code files you put them someplace on
your drive
you hope you remember where you left
them I
and you're messing around with this near
shifting things in our targets
you maybe even taking them wholesale
dumping directly in your applications
when I've got
six or seven copies across all the
applications are working on
things like that I the next step up from
this is
the static library right the coca
touched attic library
2.0 a you start to put it someplace
you're probably checking in your sources
I the died a separate header seen you
put a header someplace
you can't carry assets along with it so
you don't get to do things like
have a bunch a nice pictures or
customized
controls and things like that in your
application so
this is good but not great
and I was a so actually me back up for
second or ten dollar purse
you guys are here all six review now
okay
I am how many you've actually ship the
framework
while okay
a good number great I O S users you can
do it now too
there are some restrictions that so
we'll talk about that
one of the reasons that you're going to
use frameworks is
to be able to package absolutely
everything up that you need is a single
unit writers can include headers
conclude
images asa catalogs you name it throw in
the free market goes along as a single
unit
you'll be able to put this framework
someplace on your drive cue track I'm
Xcode will take a removing those things
in the right place in your application
bill writer lot a really neat features a
built-in for Iowa State
especially the faces from the new
features to be able to make
the workflow for frameworks really a
factor for Euro essay taps
but why do you want to use remarks well
all the packaging stuff is really nice
but all the features that are now I say
take advantage
are frameworks so the first thing you
prolly wanna try using is live you
should live rendering views and
Interface Builder
so you're putting things into framework
all the custom rendering on a custom
drawn becomes available Interface
Builder for use
directly next code as your editing unit
your storyboard
I guess I chose my age were also reports
now right
not kids anymore I if you're using
extensions
right you're gonna want to use framers
because you can be able to share code
between extension
and the application without having to
duplicate stuff in each place
way to you won't be putting things in
the in the target the extension the
target for a friend to the free app you
put in the framework and link the two
against the framework itself I
if you write multiple applications
and you're using either a third party
framework you're getting from someplace
else are you have a bunch of your own
tried-and-true tested code that you like
all your
categories on a string because I you
know who does that but
okay categories in a string and things
like that for sharing code between
multiple applications
you're gonna want to use frameworks and
obviously also if you're going to be
publishing a free market remaking all
over your code available
as a framework you want to get a package
that up
in a single distributable thing that
everybody can download music and
versions
so let's talk a little bit about getting
set up
Xcode makes it really easy to create
a new framework the new template right
insider the
a new file dialog where the project I
logged it says
Cocoa Touch framework right you can just
a click on that
we're gonna go to try markets can walk
you through the same form get a bundle
ID
things like that David someplace you're
off to the races
this also works if you have an existing
project you create new target one the
new target template is
a Cocoa Touch friend I
what was it once you decide you can use
frameworks
when you put your
if you're using live use if you're
interested in a framework for live use
your gonna wanna put
the views in there and controls and
anything else that goes along with
giving your out that custom apparent
right to review all the assets
interviews will be offered wrong code
the control so again if the assets
things like that they all go in the
frame
that way now when you make it for for
using with your application
or giving out to all your friends
neighbors and
trying to use it within exco try be all
its up two starts to work
right what goes in if you're using
extensions
where to put all the same stuff you
would put in for live use the views in
the controls because my parents because
your extension probably has all about
you're also going to put in things like
you control a class
write a custom view controllers at your
writing you wanna make available its API
to everyone else or to your
expansion into your application those
are gonna go in there as well
you're probably also gonna put the
service API to using down there so if
you doing that working code things like
that
all that's what's gonna go down
resources
again assets I'm
configuration files to my peeps
particular to your service
go down there anything that goes in
common
two-year extension your application so
that's also true if you're going to be
sure using primer contents between
multiple applications
right you got two or three application
from the store users are going ahead and
download iOS applications from the store
you're gonna wanna put all the stuff in
common right the idea here is your ideal
change the source code once building new
version of your framework
make it available call your applications
on your machine so that when you ship
marxist or
all those changes get picked up and
when you're publishing framers again
it's the same thing
so really what you gonna wind up doing
is
refractor your application using along
the architectural things that any in
column were talking about
in the previous our point goes into 8 an
organizational unit
like the framework in order to make your
development a lot easier
I'm
the app right now if you're using
extensions for instance
got an application its gonna have to
part can have
the app and the extension that nifty
little
building brick there is the extension
writer
they sit next to each other inside the
application bundle you can think the
extension as basically a little tiny
application
for got a buncha source code in there
and it probably share some source code
from swift files may be subject to see
files
those things are all gonna be a party
the targets
right rather than have the object code
generated by those who think those
things getting
duplicated into each of those targets
what you do is just pull the common
stock down into the framework
and lengthy application extension
against the framework
how do you decide workers down there as
far as code goes
if it looks like it's showing up more
than once in a target or more than once
your application
probably cousin framework I'm
we do this at Apple we look across all
the applications that were developing
we start seeing patterns you start
seeing things they're ripping themselves
we take those patterns are pulling down
in the framework either go from
the action you I can't really go to me
absolutely at Kitano H 10
we go down and foundation the wind up
going down the core OS there are a lot
of different places
where we start pulling common code
autographed and make sure they wind up
at the right level out abstraction for
use everywhere else
i'd so a really good technique in terms
of separating out everything you're
doing in your applications is
doing the same thing figure out what's
in common put it in the framework
use the framework is the unit
distribution for pulling a lot stuff
together
premature API you heard and in Karnataka
little bit about it
a yes I'm yesterday earlier today
I identifying the responsibilities
figuring out who should be doing what
within your classes
right some guy in the internet wrote a
thing about being rufus with your object
to make sure there is clean bright lines
between
where those responsibilities go
is a great technique and will make a lot
to develop an easier
to take the same kinds a framework
approach to
developing your application because now
you get really separable code could
easily testable code
you get very very good abstraction
layers
once you decide they're gonna be
offering frameworks to your application
or anyone else for the publisher
framework is API for your service
you know providing all those you argue
controllers to go along with it
the key word there is its API the key
thing is to make sure that you get
papi right we spend
weeks arguing about things I mailing
lists Apple about how to develop the API
with the architecture should look like
what things should be named
all that stuff there are some cocoa go
our guidelines that we use
I'm gonna run through some of them here
one of them is that it's much better
to be clear than it is to be brief
right so a method like this in
objective-c insert at
three Bree very terse
when you insert when
at you're inserting it to
don't do this it's not clear enough it's
not specific enough
it doesn't help you because you know we
all write this code what once twice
gonna read thousands of times I'm gonna
hand a whole bunch of code of to some
kid was younger and smarter than I am
he's got to figure out what I was doing
right so be clear expressed your intent
Insert Object at index
right what you inserting some object
where's it going
at an index right now you got a very
specific for
guarantee you gotta readable readable
chunk of code
this is the kind of thing that we will
literally spend
a week an email arguing about to get
right
API design is a contact sport at our
company
so if you're not if you're not really
throwing some elbows in the mailing list
with your
with your friends and neighbors in in a
in during a TI you're probably just not
having enough fun with it
so I'm so do this
be really specific don't abbreviate
right don't make your selectors look
like line noise
except occurred color we have code
completion it fills out for you can get
a couple keystrokes and do it it'll tell
you
0 work you know set background color
right long tells you exactly what's
going on
do that a
don't be ambiguous right there lotta
words that can be used
differ for now on here's one the ones
that I actually proposed in managed to
get by
now regret display name
right you see this in a couple places I
think it's a nice File Manager these
days
we try not to do this anymore it display
a downer for
might only thing to show the name to
somebody
or is it a name intended for display
right what we do these days in the
in the kit mostly is anything that
intended for the display to the user is
is
a localized name even if you're getting
is input from the user because you're
going from input
as input from the user it's pretty much
is localized as its gonna get
right coming from that if you're showing
it to the user
and it on your strengths while some
things like that it's the localized name
is coming out of
the bundle system to have the right
localization
right or intent was to be able to say
you wanna show you something in their
language
it's for display and everybody went well
why I'm calling
explaining why isn't a strong group your
let's not do that
so be clear
also don't take advantage or some other
things that
objective-c in this case what you do for
instance you could declare send action
like this
and you don't necessarily have to give
names to the parameters
so this produces a call so I
that looks like send action callin
callin in fed action object Cohen
but production selector colon object
Colin plaque it's not
specific enough what the object intended
to be what is that flag action me
right fill the hole selector out
send action to object for all cells yes
or no
butterfly could but I think about
animated it could have been
you know stop transmitting the method
message after you find a hit or keep
going
those kinds of things have to be spelled
out again you're going right at once
somebody's gonna come by later and curse
your name because they have to read it
a thousand times after that don't be
that guy
do this on swift no brings us some
really interesting opportunities to be
clear to be expressive and still try to
maintain some in the church miss in the
West typing in things like that we'd
like to do
and something to talk about as far as
what goes I'm
our little bit different because for us
we're still trying to figure out what
some the the really good API
idioms mean and we're really not sure
what it means to have a language in EM
for language it has had about 200 native
speakers for less than a year
so trying to figure out what some of the
stuff is going to wind up looking like
a little bit of a challenge is actually
great opportunity for all you to be able
to provide us feedback which swept
in terms of what the ATI looks like and
how your experiences in using it both
as a native language into the mix and
match pits
a with cocoa and Cocoa Touch and let us
know
exactly what you'd like to see in and
what makes it easy to use with with all
these things worse is what makes you
feel like there's a there's a little bit
for chin
right so please make sure your filing as
Raiders on how you like it to work
I'm fickle a quick look at it and that's
what function are
I pull this out over the example to in
the book but I'm gonna serve work
through those animal extend it to
to something else so contains character
string character so
a swift function has named parameters
in this case these names are the are the
very willing to use inside the function
to describe the variables
rights which produces a call so it looks
like this compares character body
you writers a string there's a a
character
if you tackle hash mark in front of it
this is not a social media construct you
don't get to find out what's trending in
your code
although it might be an interesting
question how often he use hash tag
character
I'm this allows you to be able to
use unnamed parameter at the call so I
can be specific about what is this
produces a call so it looks like this
contains character string
character right Java code
you got method overloading you can wind
up with a method
thats one word and it has 19 different
set the parameters some have
you know for arguments 6 arguments 12
arguments 9 argument summer the same
summer different
what arguments are they his name
parameters are great way to be able to
actually tell it the call sites
which ones you're using a long way to
way to be expressed in a two way to be
specific
right one other really nifty things
about swept
is the mix and match feature being able
to take code
that already exist you've already got a
$200 check to see Co
interparticle terms and shipping
applications and things like that would
be not to throw that away and try to do
it all over again swept
be fun if you have the time you probably
don't you're trying to ship
right mix and match what you do things
like this this is
the popular presentation API from you I
kept
it gets converted into something that
were too big we like this
by the mix and match system for swept
I so function present pop over from
wrecked
wrecked view our directions animated
that produces the Call site that works
like this okay
again not specific enough not a really
good
description of what's happening right
what any their
I have no idea what is true me I'm some
reckon some you are at least descriptive
enough
but it doesn't really help me out those
aren't my variable right
if we read a clear oh and then we've got
present from bar but night I mean that
just throws the other wrench into it
right which is okay well I apart on item
but are directions animator still there
we can be more specific about these
things
we can take advantage a function
overloading method overloading and say
call both present pop over what the heck
right now we've got this really neat way
to be able to separate out
the other API from I
you know Coco and Cocoa Touch
and make me too different so we had a
rough cut
from rec to rec writer from rick is
gonna wind up being
external name to use at the call so I
records can be variable inside the mat
the implementation variable you're using
for parameter it's the name to use for
cramming
pastor in Huehuetenango hash marks there
again
that makes you that makes it possible to
use the same name as the externally miss
the internal main news produce call
sites that look like this
rights not to present pop over from
recon view our directions animated in
prison pop over from bar button item
her directions animate Creek I can tell
the difference between that
awesome
while typing completions nice but
experts stole a buncha typing Swift has
some really nice features
for default arguments your API
so let's go back and take a look at just
the present popover method
okay if we read a clear like this
what we've got is you're probably right
direction is the type and
dot any there is the default value
rights with when it goes through the mix
and match bit takes the common prefix
offer the norms for the options and
makes them
the shortened version at the end which
is one really nice thing about when we
went back to ruin and started
normalizing all the names again a pretty
common prefixes allowed us to do this
so dot any as passed into a popover air
direction tight is
that particular entry out of the NFC
numb
are argument and bought get through
there is a a way to say that yes
if there's no argument presented you
want to be able to have this thing
be true all the time so that turns these
call sites
which are nice for descriptive
into these call sites
right won the patterns were you seen
foundation I'm
is you'll see a really long method it'll
have probably an hour
anywhere between six and a 212 argument
I think you'll see versions are that are
shorter your general you'll see the
and arguments have an object to seize
order starting appeal walk go shorter
versions are calling in the longer
version with the default values
writers are all generally one-line
implementations a call back out to
the big guy with all the switches on it
right
this is where you can provide all those
switches without having to provide all
those methods all the time
put in the same default values
this provide you with some really good
opportunities to be able to clean up
your code
be really clear in swift and doing this
in swift talking
to objective-c API's you can store
really
sending down the API surface so you
don't have tons and tons and tons
methods to keep track of you got one
place to these implementations
the default value should go in the right
place
was really good documentation online the
coding guidelines for Coco developer
Apple dot com
I just go to to developer Apple com
login search for this document
it's the same coding guidelines that we
have up on our internal wiki
for how to get started with developing
API right so the rules that work trying
to put down there
do the same things that we use that
Apple so another good reason to go in
and and look at these is
all the check to see if your gonna write
if you're
not just can't talk it over and go for
swept entirely a hump
all the API will work well in be fit in
with
the idioms we already have for are
existing cocoa frameworks
the other docking a primary don't
revolve download it already
this with programming language I
wouldn't be surprised if all you
suddenly have more experience with an
idea by this point
I'm drilled on I but it also available
online
developer Apple com it's got all ok the
information about swift in it and they
do make some API
recommendations in there as well again
we're all sort of just figuring this out
so if there's something that you see
that makes a lot of sense
great call it out tell us because we'll
make sure we try to keep it
if there's something you see that you
don't like or that you like to make
suggestions are
sentiment I'm take advantage a bug
report outlook.com get the radars in on
swift because this is really your
opportunity to have a lot of influence
on how all the stuff develops if you're
publishing a framework
whether it's for your own applications
or whether through application for other
people to use in their own applications
you gonna run into a problem this is a
problem that we run into every time you
release a new version the operating
system and that's
framework version right
to user has gone down a whole bunch
about
darn well and good for you guys
issued on what all your abs but I all
those applications
what's a used the latest version of this
new framework that just came out
and Virgin 1 so for a while at least
you're in good shape everybody's got the
same code running if an application
sends information to another one be an
extension or via the open URL calling
things like that
hey all the object work together
no problem right awesome
and then you come out the new version
the framework
and some applications update to in some
applications don't
or some the applications just got
developed in an abandoned unknown never
update
right for some applications on the
user's device are going to be version 2
blue ones some versions or conversion
what
and now suddenly I'm trying to send an
object to that other application from
aversion to frame it to a version one
free marker from a version 1 framework
to aversion to framework
not everything's the same was object
grow new capabilities the dated you're
passing back and forth may have
new keys in right 1i think you're gonna
have to do if you are going to be
publishing a framework
is be very careful about the versioning
so a number of things that you can do
you
but dealing with framework versions
first
you're gonna have to put a framework
version in there anyway
the the framework mechanism in creating
target when you create a new
project for framework because the
entropy list for the short version
string cue track at
use that that information you can use in
order to figure out
what's happening what version free
mckree went against what version
is the data coming from you can send
that data to something else to see him a
version one thing a reversion to print
the other thing you should do probably
should take advantage acute archiving or
key archiving like behavior right so if
you are doing key-value stuff is as part
of your archiving
her partner document format make sure
that your key value pair meanings
are consistent right don't suddenly for
for version one key that might be
background-color: don't suddenly make
zero mean white instead of black
conversion to
because then suddenly the developing
your the users to come along and you're
gonna get sent from Sunday dinner gonna
say well this this completely run don't
walk
what happen right so once you committed
to what a key/value pair means
or what our relationship between two key
value pairs mean
inside this archive you're sending back
and forth a different version to your
cell
you really kinda have to stick with
right we do this in apple also there's
this whole set of keys that that have
that a ser come along to make sure that
when we open up
archives from older versions in the
system that we can continue to read that
data
you do get lotsa interesting
opportunities at reading right time to
be able to deal with that so
one is missing key should return or the
equivalent in the face is getting back
nil
you probably want to do something saying
right if you're looking for a key in its
not there
maybe it's a great opportunity for some
default value get injected in
at the time the Huron archive and that's
really the opportunity able to do that
because the the encoding and decoding
are your chances to get that interface
when you're writing that data out
you can be rented out for consumption by
somebody else when you're consuming that
data
you can have to look at it go well not
really sure where this comes from so I
should at least be wary of
right if you're encoding things in you
know that there's a bug back they really
need to fix
back in version one you can do it by
encoding something different you might
do that
if you're looking at situations where
polling new keys in
the old code isn't gonna go looking for
those new keys that can ignore those
things are probably pretty say
the new stuff you wanna make sure you're
not
stomping on all keys you not interfering
with the relationships between
use when you encode and decode that your
interface
I know I'm writing out for something's
gonna pick this up and I don't know what
version it's going to be
for I'm getting data back in I have no
idea where it came from
right make sure your keys unique right
is somebody subclassing your stuff and
they're sending stuff back and forth but
they're depending on your framework
you don't want to actually stop on their
namespace
right to keep the keys
you know we're getting some some names
beating behavior in sweat the keys in
these kinds of things
aren't our art namespace it also make
sure the unique use the prefixes
if you are really defensive use your
bundle ID prefix it there
I'm won the ways you can also a
mentions I didn't put in a sly one ways
you can also work with this is is by
conforming to en a secure coding
right secure code to make sure that
you're only getting the object on the
archive you're expecting to be there
also start looking for future
availability right
classes responder selectors for reason
if you're in some code you're using
somebody else's framework you wanna make
sure that that
your code is gonna keep functioning if
something gets updated check to see if
it responsible actor
check and its class from string do those
things in order to make sure
that when you're working with all the
stuff
you don't wind up at actually pension
user and killing a rap because with an
exception of sending something to it
sending a message to a stringer
ferryboat doesn't respond to a message
except conversion to
okay so awesome great
what households work
I pretty well actually
if you follow me on the social networks
up today
you probably know that I have a dog
this is my dog this is buddy
he's got a sixty-pound barking a
thirty-pound bodies about the stall
I'm he's cute and I put a lot of
pictures my dog because I
can't really post anything about work
I
so a lot of people like to say hey Chris
dogs awesome
i'd you know can I borrow your dog might
want to meet your dog
your dog be a great party my life I'm
not giving away my dog sorry
can't happen but I am
I am pleased to to talk a little bit
about a prototype that working on
I'm it's called the
it's called but the gramm and it's a way
that you can take your pictures and put
my dog
into them
so
what we'll do is a I'm gonna take a
quick tour through Xcode
both on for for what I've done so far
with with this
and just to walk through the initial
setup love
an extension application framework I
but you're gonna be able to do this kind
of thing the idea is a
with the terrible pictures at this is a
beach in Corsica went biking trip a
while back
our ride bound up here was absolutely
gorgeous
we're gonna try and stay a couple days
but they were going let's do it this is
a great picture but I really missed body
got about ten days by this point
and it's a great picture but now now
it's even better picture had a min photo
bombed
by my dog itself
we're gonna take a look at three things
but the Grammy application
its order the iconic the user sees the
place for gonna start
right it's going to allow posting and
editing your photos
and as long as there's a picture body in
there it'll post
a we'd like to allow some comments on
existing photos in sort of a feed kinda
mechanism
you may have seen up like this before
somewhere I'm not sure
I and we're gonna have a share a posting
view controller with the extension right
wanna share the code so it winds up
in both places the extension is going to
allow posting adding photos with another
aP's
but not allow comments on existing for
trucker buddy feeding the extension
that's the business for the application
and that's actually one thing about this
architecture in the framework and stuff
like that you wanna be really careful
about
right you know one wind up with your
entire application suddenly living in
the framework because
not all your applications can be
appropriate for the extension or not all
your applications to be appropriate for
Publishing's a third party framework
there's the things that are common to
your service
inner things that make your app unique
rights you want to keep those two things
separate and it's going to share the
post do you control the application
obviously the framework
is going to contain a shared hosting
view controller and
shared networking code for posting
things like that and the model code
right all the stuff that makes up the
common things that the extension needs
to know to be able to deal with the
object
the applications also deal so we have up
the but the grant application here I'm
and
a tap on it there's Biden course ago
this is the feed
here I and we're gonna post something
here this is
a picture my parents backyard in
connecticut a
in and looking very new england and
falling three pretty and I can't bring
but there cuz he doesn't like the flight
we've got this app you got the extension
they work together you gonna be able to
take data from the extension throw it in
the application
and the code to your gonna share between
the two you're only going to use
in the framework so you not to be
jockeying target United shuffling stuff
around things like that so
we'll take a look at Xcode so let's
let's take a look at a new Xcode project
will start from scratch here
mostly to give you sort of an
orientation before I start jumping
around
and touch the ground to show you what I
did so what we've got here
is the start a say it had application
error page based application what's
let's go with a single view application
here just for the basics
will call this I framework example
because I'm not particularly creative
and we've got a a language choice here
I'm gonna stick with objective-c for a
minute
and we'll just a 0 I am NOT an
organization on to myself
so will call that happen corporate id
desktop or create this
so we've got here now is just an
application
prime and there some
different things here too to build
settings and build phases and
all the stuff you're familiar with
you'll see the the link binary with with
libraries bit here
I if you're just gonna have an
application should be fine you work with
this new put all your
your code in your tabs in the menu to
work with your target some things like
that
but we're actually gonna go ahead and
create a new target here more will
create a new
framework in library target a Cocoa
Touch framework
will call this a it's called what's the
cat
and you'll see two new things here it
says here front leaf project is the
framework example here
and embedded application framework
example so we're creating this new
up premark and we're
Xcode also gonna set up so that when a
framework build and then you when you
going archive it all the time winds up
in the right place
as we can do finisher and now we've got
to the link binary with libraries there
but the kid framework is required
and %uh let's go ahead actually create
the extension here to our here's an
application extension
a will use a share extension
okay and %uh this will be the but still
posting
extension
okay now we've got but the kid
but the posting but the posting
bits had to share view controller in
here
and a storyboard for that
C
we pause for station identification I
there's nothing but the kit right now
there's nothing in the butt so there's
that
the certainty share view controller in
here I and we've got
this view controller for the free market
example for the application
one of the things I mention before what
I want to be able to had to share view
controller be part of the framework
right someone use that both in but the
gramm itself
and in the extension
but for posting is the extension I'm
all this stuff if we go look what's take
a quick look at the Finder here
actually if we go look in the framework
example folder
right Xcode organizing all the code in
a director is here but the
directory obviously directory hierarchy
is not necessary reflected in
in how Xcode shows that in its
and it's a youthful files in groups
thing here but we're gonna just move
these guys up into
here some I'm just making sure
this your view controller part the bus
ticket group it's not actually moved
outta
the the directory the 10 behind the
scenes but
you know if you feel like you want to do
that go ahead and move in with your
version control system over into
to the right spot here in the bus ticket
header I'm gonna go ahead and
it says here in this are you should
import all the public enters your
framework
using statements like import but stick
it public header so it's too
import
but the kid share you control
poker completion
and we need to make sure that we change
these to be parlor right targets over
here on the on the right hand side
sure you control diagram is part two but
the posting target we actually wanna
make up our the but the kid target
anything you're gonna do it Fri Mar is
different than what you probably aren't
doing before
is within a framework there are some
designations for what a header means
so you're actually gonna wind up adding
the header to be part of the target a
framework
which isn't necessarily something you've
really done before right usually use the
headers the
the daughter Angelina Torres is a party
the framework for the target
the headers are just loose you never
wanna can distribute so this is a free
market gonna handed out to people are
gonna be heading out other developers on
your team you're gonna wanna tell us
whether this thing is a project header a
private header
republican right so
the prosecutor means that only things
within the project can see it
the private header goes anything it's
market a private here goes into a
private headers directory inside the
framework
when that free markets bill right
the public portion of it is obviously
the public attitude
if the haters they're just in the
headers directory there make this a
public header
I'm you might use private headers
because just like us you've got SPI
you don't want people to use but it's
really handy to be able to use it
internally
or across to project and maybe the SPI
something you want to publish later but
it's not quite bullet proof enough to be
able to papi now
you put on a private header if you
publisher framework
don't forget to remove the private
headers directory from the framework
because then everybody can grow ball
over so I'm
and then down here in the butt for
posting thing well we're gonna have to
edit the target
so go back up to this framework example
here
and if I look at but step but the kid
but the kid is linking with no libraries
the framework example is linking with
buds ticket I need to make
but the posting link with but stick it
so I can do is
just drug this guy here now okay will
pick the plus
will choose but the kid from the project
and now all those things
will link together not sure view
controllers now part of the framework
its live ill but since but the posting
extension
links the framework in the Apple Inc's
the framework they can both use sure if
you control let's go ahead and build
that
for the simulator and then let's take a
quick work here at what actually got
produced so if we go look at I i move my
build directory appear on the desktop so
be easier to find
up Africa looking product here we've got
a couple different products based on
on our on our tarde configuration and
our target
here's a certain everything spread out
right so here's but the cat that
framework years the
the app here's my but the gramm
application I was building earlier
for the free market example inside that
is now
a couple different directories this Fri
Mar directory has the but forget
framework inside a bit
and what's what's good old school and go
work in the terminal here
the old church in the past and a bus
ticket free merck has incited this
headers directory and module
models are generated for for use with
swift and and for the module
a in at import director for objective-c
there some nifty things to go along with
that but those are those are things we
should read about the actual
documentation
I'm so the free market built into the
applications that actually one thing
to to be aware of is you're gonna have
multiple copies the framers on desk at
the time we're not sharing frameworks
across
sandbox boundaries right things inside
the same sandbox get access to the same
framework but
we're not letting you use the framework
out some other applications installed
even if it's one of your own
right all the things getting better
directly applications here after still
completely stand-alone items so what's
the
go back to this and take a quick look
here I because the extension is its own
little applications from things you need
to be aware every things like and its
bond Old Main bundle isn't gonna work
exactly the way you think you're gonna
have to go work for assets
by bundle identify using a bundle API
know there is no but I ran into myself
that I introduced
why you ask so
and the share view controller has the
standard extension stuff here for things
like is content balloted select
these are these are I'm peculiar to the
to share a few Control orbiter
there are other API and all the other
extensions that are specific to those as
well
both actually take a look and see how I
sort divided up
but stick it and buds to gramm I'm
so
there a lotta really similar things here
to the way
everything up broken down I'm
not really tall enough to point up there
but
you'll see that the I'm we got to feed
you control or any posting view
controller which is it that
two things to use on the tab view in a
demo or earlier
and then the main story board contains
those two things and then
there's a buncha model code is down and
bites ticket but the kid has all the
stuff like
a the public umbrella header
right to just like you just type import
you I can you like it I date you should
be selling your umbrella her up in your
framework to do the same thing for all
your public API in there
so you'll import but the kid that age
/url easter hope you will some I'm and
also all the model code down there so
the thing that manages a post is there
and the post view the displays a post
with the
the the dog a resizable there in the
sheriff you control and things like that
mean
done here in about 3 poster again it's
the same thing it's just the main
interface story where the anti
storyboard which says when you call up
one of these things
this is a storyboard to launch into on
right now an extension
that's it writers other logic that lives
in the framework that does all the other
work thus ending at the data and the
medical asiana the other photo and
things like that
so making sure that you're pulling all
these things down in the right place
is very very important most to the
thirteen years I spent doing Fri Mar
I work a lot a really talented framework
developers a lot of this stuff
is tremendously hard one lessons from
shipping software
right being clear being explicit
having the right amount of API having
expressive API
distributing things in the right way
being careful with your versions
making sure you're working with data
safely getting the right abstractions
right all those things make our lives
much much
easier taking a free market approach
even the applications if you look at
most or applications on the device
you know Maps has mapped it right
and I would say health has health care
right
all the things that make an the ap
function and useful to the user live in
the apt all the heavy lifting
all the shared code all the interfaces
that allow things to work with your app
going those frameworks right it's a
great separation for us that's what
helps
ship software can be a great separation
for you as well
there are some related sessions that
happened earlier in the week honors one
tomorrow are creating extensions for OS
and first-hand parts 1&2 were
earlier go watch those for breaking up
things into the extensions in in the
character setting extensions up
right and then apply from the stuff he
got here are some stuff you got from
from
and Ian Collins talk previously in the
previous our
to all that and ensuring code between
Iowa snow ice 10
allotted you I'm work on both platforms
and a lot of the model code and things
like that
is actually share a bowl and much of the
extensions API
was developed specifically with an eye
to being able to write
as much cross-platform code is possible
with
as little as the pound it's for target
OS is we could manage
right for you will be able to do a fair
amount a code-sharing
even for extensions Iowa snow attend
that's right here
tomorrow morning at 9am brayton early
K so 37 actually fantastic remainder the
week enjoy the bash
thank you very much