good morning welcome
like to see a number folks out I'll
Brighton early to talk about
all the heart-pounding excitement in the
world compilers
and i'm jim crow spock
and I'm really happy to be here today to
share with you
all of the new things that we have
Italian a VM
when we normally talk about
LOVE am and what first comes to mind
when we think about it
is the Apple LLVM compiler itself
is what we all used to build our ouch
and that for real really first encounter
LBM
but it's much more than that ela via
misused
in a wide variety of products and tools
that we all use every day but this
developers
and as end-users over the years
Albion has grown to be a really key
technology here at Apple
for building tools for performance and
for modernization and that has been
no exception this year as we have moved
swiftly along
with a broad variety %uh new
improvements
start with back in September
we introduced the Apple 87 processor
which has been just absolutely
magnificent
and what it allowed us to do bring truly
desktop class performance
to your mobile device and I will be in
place
a key role in that's and now
we're encouraging more view to use this
technology in your outbox
so building for 64-bit in iowa's is now
the default
as record 5.1 carrying on into Xcode 6
when you rebuild your app do using
standard architectures
arm 64 will be included this does not
impact your deployment store you can
continue
deploy back to Iowa 4.3 we still build
for RB 7 for 32-bit all
the development work clothes that you're
familiar with for the simulator
the debugger profiling all these things
continue to work transparently just as
you're familiar with in a 64-bit
environment now one thing to be aware of
is that because on 64 is an entirely new
architecture
your entire application must be built
64-bit
not just a few libraries here are a few
files there
but the whole app so if you're relying
on third-party libraries
and those libraries have not yet adopted
64-bit please work with your vendors and
encourage them
to update and support 64-bit development
so that your app can
then migrate as well and get the
benefits
during migration there are few things
that we'd like to
bring to your attention that might come
up a few
advancements we've made a few things
that we've tightened up in the
specification
and what possible impact about P rappers
to start with in 64-bit I allows
all functions must have a prototype this
has been good style
cents time immemorial
I and it's been required for c plus plus
since
start its ban highly suggested in C
before any modern version not using
prototype is deprecated
and has been for very long time now
so we're taking advantage of this
in arm 64 to generate more efficient
calling convention code in particular
for periodic functions like print out
but be
number of arguments the function varies
by call type
talk when you have order code that
you're using that may not use prototypes
what is normally a warning has now been
promoted
to an hour so the compiler will
highlight to you in your code
exactly where this is happening so that
you know
porch prototypes to go and pure header
files to move on
one place that this does sometimes come
up in a little bit more
subtle way is Reina C++ and objective-c
interworking code with direct
indications objective-c message send
to help find this we have a new Xcode
setting
to enable strict tracking a bob see
message sent
this is a recommended setting and when
you first upgrade your projects helped
code six will
encourage you to adopt the setting
and what's tricky is that every
indication about
message sound effectively has a
different type
it has the type up what the final
receiving method
is going to be for example here
trivial piece of code that's a invoking
method foo with strict checking in a
bowl
the compiler will now tell us that we
need to tell
yet what the final pipe is
there's a straightforward to do too
little bit verbose but very
straightforward we simply at the tight
up the final receiving method done it
here with the pipe daft this could be
done with the direct typecast
on all on one line if you prefer just to
make sure that the compiler knows
what the final receiving type up the
method is so that it can generate
the right code to get the final result
correct
another place that we have tightened
things up
and taken advantage of our new baby I am
is the objective-c boolean type
dorm any if you are at doubt stump the
experts last night this topic actually
came up as a question
I've rather amusing like I have tried on
that will be great
so ball is basically now a blowpipe
previously its ban assigned character
and sometimes our code our code as well
not just
I in yours would put values into the
billion pipe that work
strictly Boolean now the compiler
is going to be taking advantage of the
striper definition
so what can happen is that if your code
does that the results between 32 and I
laugh
and 64-bit iowa's may differ
so if you start seeing some odd
behaviors with Boolean
this is something to look out for
we also have pointers and for now 64-bit
architecture this is kinda the core of
what this is all about the pointer to
launch an app 64bits
so old code would often do horrible
things like hasting
integers two pointers in back and forth
and hopefully we don't write code that
does hurt anymore but we all have this
legacy code we have to live with
and now this can bite us if we're not
careful
this is very similar to what we've all
dealt with on
the 32bit to 64bit Intel transition if
we went through that
that she'll probably haven't magically
just solve that the compiler
to for example here forecasting an
integer
which came from a point or somewhere
else for casting that too
avoid star but now the compiler can help
a little bit it can at least
inform us that the problem is coming up
and tell us that well we have a problem
here that
we need to look at make sure that this
is really what's happening
now if we ignore this warning the
runtime
in the kernel is going to be a little
bit more forceful about us
if we had dereference that pointer we're
going to get a hard-fought
because the page 0 is mapped to always
give a fault so
if we miss any of these through other
mornings for still getting error
paying attention the compilers can be a
lot friendlier little be
night unfurling tell you the line number
source file for the problem is
the Colonels just gonna tell you did
something bad
to address this we use the C language
type toughs that are 64 and 32 bit claim
that we say we have we won a signed
integer unsigned integer
there is an appropriate height for
saving a pointer value
or poor indexing into an array for
comparing the differences between two
pointers
for example we would modify our previous
code simply use the int punter
hi which one are compiling for 32-bit
iowa's
we a 32-bit signed integer and for
64-bit iowa's
will be a 64-bit signed integer
slightly more sharply this can come up
in structure layouts
when we use a longer pointer these now
bro
which change but the size and sometimes
the alignment the offset other fields in
our structures
we have to be careful that this is done
in a way that's safe
the most of the time this is going to
work transparently because the
structures were used
entirely within our application and
everything gets the new definition and
works fine
fight if we're doing something like a
representation oven on disk file format
communicating across a network to
another process
that is going to rely on the exact
layout of a structure
that can go bad so again on any of those
data structures
we want to use DC
fixed type fixed size types to make sure
that we get what we want
whether we're building for 64 bit I'll
ask corporate 32-bit iowa's
so in summary building for 64 bit I'll
ask is easy
it's their fall the compiler will help
find
and resolve any issues
this isn't the only thing that we've
been up to we've also been making
advances
in objective-c
and the compiler can help here too the
language has continued to move forward
so love this one really helps with
interoperability with swift as well
she may be seeing in that pocket highly
encourage you to check it out
not happening at the same time as this
one took a look on the video
when that comes out on the BBC ap
and where we write new code
we've been using all of these
advancements in the language
to get modern best practices more
expressive code
but then we have all this older legacy
code
the would like to adopt all these
features and as well but
that a lot a code to go read through and
manually find all these things
so we have a tool that will help us
identify the opportunities
where we can use these new features I
think the best way
to talk about that is to show you with
the demo
now rather than use some contrived
example code here I thought well maybe
look at something that we all are
familiar with at least as users
and our WTTC ap
that code has been with us for a while
we updated every year
and what the modern eyes are we wanted
to use that to look at it and find out
if they're
perhaps some places in the code base
that we missed for opportunities
to use new objective c- features so
let's look
and see what a few those things that we
found our
we go under edit to re factor between
convert
our project modern Objective C syntax
begun a dialogue box telling us what
we've just selected to make sure that we
got the right thing
we can select whether to which targets
in our project to modernize
from this in this case for looking at
the BBC app itself
in a previous version the tax code to
modernize would go through and just look
for
objective Singh liberals and
subscription but now we have
more options now personally I prefer not
to do all of these at once that tends to
be
a little too much to swap back and forth
so I tend want to select
a few things by to look for instance
type
here that we can get our initialization
weapons more strongly typed
going to try and find if we missed any
read/write properties for recon Burke
up explicit getter setter methods
Android ebook to use in ASCII new
foreign racin value so the compiler
can cooperate with the run time to give
better results
click Next the compiler will run
over our code and turns out we do indeed
have a few more suggestions for what we
can look at
but do keep in mind that these are just
suggestions
that we need to go through and look at
the side by side death here
we have the new code on the left the old
code on the right
we look to hear this work fine
everything looks good here we're
converting to Ian's
secure our next one this looks a little
bit
different because we still have this and
I sent a juror over here
that what I could be straightforward
cleanup but
I brother come back to this later I just
want to deal with the things we can do
automatically right now
so I tell the monitor to discard that
change
it mounts make sure that doing that yes
I'm absolutely sure
can do the same here we could also tell
it to ignore all the changes in this
file
this check button here
and out also found a place where we can
use an instant
type not all looks good so we tell it to
save and Xcode will now tell us that all
we can
update our project as well take snapshot
that sound great but what it do that as
backup for good
now our project to save its been rebuilt
and the objective-c modernize our works
tuber update our code and help us find
places for we can take advantage
up new features that isn't the only
place
that we've made advances for objective-c
had for interoperability to tell you
more about that
I'd like to ride up my friend coworker
Bob Wilson
the clock
thank you Jim so modulus
are another way that LTM can help
modernize your code
we produce models just last year but in
case you missed that
let's start with some background
so be four models we had precompiled
headers
which are often ineffective way to speed
up the compilation of your code
but they do have some limitations you
can only have one mod
one precompiled header at a time and
more importantly
the whole approach abusing a textual
inclusion of a header file
as a way of importing framework is just
fragile
we have a deal with the issue where a
header file get included more than once
in a single compilation we have also
problem have headers being fragile
and what I mean by that is that the
meaning up the header
can change depending on the environment
where it's important
and let me show you that with an example
so here I've defined macro count to the
value 100
and I'm port the foundation framework
now
inside the foundation had her there's
and include for the NSR a definition
and an SRA has a high bar count
so the macro Scout get substituted
as literal taxed in that place and we
end up with
completely broken code where instead of
the I Heart name we have a value of 100
this is what I mean by hatter's being
fragile
modules solve this problem by replacing
the model
textual inclusion with semantic import
there's a lot more detail about models
in the advances in objective-c
presentation from last year's WWDC I
encourage you to watch that if you're
not familiar with modules
until now models have only been
available for the system frameworks
new in Xcode 6 you can now define
modules
for your own frameworks as well for C++
and objective-c
besides fixing the problems we just
looked at this also gives you away
%uh importing your own framework into
your swift code
and as jim mentioned there's another
session on integrating swift with
objective-c
I encourage you to watch the video to
learn more about that
so if you want to do this how
it's really very easy for most
frameworks it's possible to define
a single umbrella Heather that imports
all of the framework API
and this is what we recommend that you
do as
is the easiest way to adopt a module
once you've done that simply go to the
Xcode build settings
for your framework and in the packaging
section
set defines Marshall TS and that's it
it really is very easy now if you have a
more complicated framework
where that that single umbrella hat er
is not sufficient you can use a custom
module map
and there's more information to describe
how that works on the LVM website
after you've created a Marshall you want
to use it
how do you do that there's a an at
import keyword
followed by the module name that tells
the compiler I want to import this model
if you haven't had a chance to update
your code and you're still
have a pound import to include the
umbrella header
compiler smart enough to know that this
is now a modular framework
and it will go ahead treat that has an
implicit modular important anyway
so just as a guideline though we do
recommend you use at import
when you're importing your framework
into a separate target within your
project
just because it makes it clear in the
source that you really intend for this
to be a modular import
one exception to that his within the
implementation have your framework
itself
it doesn't make any sense to to import a
framework into itself
and so in that case you really need to
use pound import to textually include
the framework at urs
just within the implementation of the
framework
and beside those guidelines we have a
few other rules about models that you
should be aware of
first don't expose any non modular
hatter's in your framework a PI it's
fine to import another module like cocoa
but if I have an important something
like post crest at age which presumably
is not a model
you can put that down inside the
implementation your framework
but don't expose in the API
one other issue is that models can
change the semantics
up your code we saw earlier the problem
a fragile Hatter
where macro definition inadvertently
broke the code
sometimes you might want to do this on
purpose and I'm showing here an example
arrived to find a macro debug as a flag
to enable additional debugging API in my
framework
by switching that framework to be a
module the debug macro
defined in my source code no longer has
any a fact which is not what I wanted
now that limitation only applies to
macros that are defined
in the source code so if you really want
to do something like this
one alternative is to define the macro
on the command line
or in the Xcode build settings
so that is user-defined modulus it's
really pretty straight forward in the
common case
had gives you fast compilation clear
semantics
and away in our operating with swift
code
so far we've been talking a lot about
ways that LBM help to modernize your
code and adopt
modern objective-c modules but
let's turn now and look at performance
which is the other team up this
presentation
profile guided optimization or p.geo
is a new feature in Xcode 6
penny gives you away getting even more
performance
out of your code me give you to
overall high-level understanding of what
this is about
one at the inherent challenges for the
compiler is that
it has no way of knowing what the input
to your program is going to be
the only input to the compiler is your
source code
so the compiler have to assume that all
inputs are equally likely
there are some cases where it can gas
that certain code pass will be more
common than others
for example it can assume that going
through a loop
is gonna happen more often than cold
outside and that will
but those are just gases and they're a
lot of things that is simply can't now
if we provide a profile has an
additional input to the compiler
he can now try to optimize for the
common case
hand do a better job optimization what I
mean by profile here
is simply account how many times each
statement in your apt executes
in a typical run if you're out
you may be wondering how do I get a
profile like that
again we can use the compiler here to
generate a special
instrument it out that as it runs is
gonna count how many times
each statement executes and then when
you're out finishes
with the special instrumental version he
will write out that profile
which the week and then use for p.geo
so how does the compiler use that
profile information
there are an awful lot away so many
optimizations can benefit from this
but I'm highlighting just three here
that are particularly valuable
want us to the in liar if we know that a
function is really hot
and by that I mean its its run a lot
over and over
be in water can be much more aggressive
about inlining
when we're generating the code we can
try to lay out the the comment passed
through your code
so that they're contiguous which makes
it easy for the processor to run
fast and the register allocator can also
try to keep values in registers
throughout those most common paths
let's look at an example just to give
you a better understanding of this
this is some C plus plus code this going
to iterate over a set of colored objects
and for each one is going to update the
position of the object
so the top I've got a loop over the
object
and freaked when I'm gonna call my
update position function
and update position is gonna look and
feel if the object is red
it moves in a very simple horizontal
lines to the code is really simple
but if the object is blue let's assume
that that the movement is much more
complicated
got a very large block of code here
now the compiler has no way of knowing
whether red objects or blue object
are more likely so it just assumes there
them both equally likely
but with PDR I might be able to know
that rat object
are form far more common some I'm
highlighting and read here the hot code
which is the code to generate over the
set of objects and then to handle the
rat object
I'm gonna color code the cold code in
blue
which is blue object which are rare for
some reason in this application
and then let's look at how the compiler
would handle this code
here's kinda that the fall code layout
that matches
roughly the original source or order
gotta
the hot loop outside and an update
position function down below
with a little bit of hot code in it
inlining is one of the most important
optimizations
can't would really like to in line at
update position function
but the compiler can't in line
everything
for the code would blow beyond point
where it would be useful
but in this case I the the update
position function is big because all
that cold code for handling the blue
object
and so it wouldn't normally be in line
but because p.geo tells us there's some
really hot code here
be in line or can be much more
aggressive about that in this particular
case
so we take that the loop iterating over
the object
had split that half and movie in
the update position code right in line
so this is much better now we've got a
lot of the hot code
right together but we've still got a big
chunk of
book this cold for blue object the cold
cold right in the middle of our loop
AP geo can help this as well opt by
changing the code layout
it knows that that code is called and
can move it down below
out of the way and we end up with a nice
tight loop
can run really fast and it also I'll
typically enables other optimizations on
that hot code
so obviously this is a simple fighting
sample but hopefully gives you feel love
the power
p.geo and just how much you can help the
optimizer
so you may want to use it when does it
make sense
the compiler does a really good job
optimizing by default
with p.geo if you do just a little bit
of extra work together the profile
you can do even better so obviously if
you're
if you're happy with the performance
you're already getting you probably not
motivated to do that
even that little bit of extra work but
if you need more performance
by all means give it a try
and let me show you some examples up
just how much it can help
this is a graph showing the the speedup
compared with p.geo compared to a case
I'm just a normal optimized bill
and I'm looking at four different
applications here the Apple LLVM
compiler itself
applying p.geo to to the compiler itself
sq like database
up the Perl interpreter Angie zip file
compression
mpg ok if the speedups ranging from
about 4 percent all the way up to 18
percent
so not all out for benefit this much it
really varies depending on the app
but clearly there's a lot of potential
here
so if you want to try it how do you go
about that
p.geo is really easy to use the first
step is to collect the profile
I'm gonna come back and talk about that
in just a minute
what you've done that simply go in the
Xcode build settings for your project
and
find the use optimization profile
setting and set it to yes typically
just for the release configuration and
that's it you enable p.geo
once you've done that as you continue
developing your app you make changes you
fix bugs you add new features
the code becomes gradually outta sync
with the profile you collected earlier
and when that happens the compiler will
will simply fail to use that profile
information on break anything it did he
just gradually lose the the optimization
benefit
when that happens it will give you a
warning
so if you see warnings like this saying
that your profile may be out today
as you see more and more of them it's a
good indication she it's time to go back
an update your your profile
so let's turn now and look at how do you
generate the profile
Xcode 6 has a new command generate
optimization profile
when you run this command exco will
build the special
instrumental version if you're out and
then right and you can then
interact with the running app to
generate the profile when it finishes
running will write out the profile and
add it to your project
has your running a route keep in mind
its important to exercise
all the code that's important for your
performance
if I V game with three different levels
and I only play the first level
my game the compilers can assume that
that's the one thing that really matters
and not
work as hard on other levels
now you may be wondering if I if I've
been really hard game
it may take a while to play the whole
thing to completion
up that could be a problem right so X
could have
another option which is to use your
performance test
as inputs to drive the profiling
performance test our new feature
in Xcode 6 if you'd like to learn more
about them there's a session right here
tomorrow morning
on testing in Xcode 6 and
white shoes if if you care about
performance you want to set up
these performance test anyway to catch
regressions in your co just to keep
track of how you're doing
and what you gone to that trouble to set
them up
in most cases they're pretty good inputs
for driving this profile
again though keep in mind it's important
that your test
cover the code in a way that's reflects
a typical usage if your app
going back to my my free level game if I
write lots a test for the first level
and only a few for the second and third
level
again the compilers gonna end up
optimizing more heavily
for that first level another benefit of
using test is it gives you a great way
evaluating how much does p.geo help me
can just run your tests let me show you
that with a demo now
so with the release of the swift
language we thought it would be fun to
make it a demo app
that would celebrate that and so rather
than this with language we thought of
this with birds
we made an application that uses the
Boyds artificial life simulation
to simulate of La Crosse Wis
and I can create a whole bunch of them
here and let them fly around
and the way this this boyd's application
works
his that each bird are buoyed compares
its position to all the other ones on
the screen
and it calculates the distance between
them to find that
the flock up the birds nearest to it and
then
each boy has a competing urges on the
one hand it wants to move
closer to the center of the flock the
same time
it doesn't want to get to close and so
if it gets too close to another one
it will move apart and the performance
if that is we add
more and more of these boys could become
a problem
so we set up a performance test to track
that
and this is a a really simple
performance test
on we set up a scene with two hundred
boyd's
and measure the time it takes to update
their positions a hundred times
and that's our performance just so let's
run that because I care about
performance
I'm gonna edit my current scheme to make
sure that my test
step is going to use the release build
configuration
so that we get optimize results
and I'll go to the product test menu
can run my performance test here
all right and now because I have to run
the test before I don't have a baseline
so let's go ahead and set the baseline
based on that first drive and now let's
try adding
p.geo into the product menu perform
action
down at the bottom here's this new
command I told you about generate
optimization profile
I get two choices I can either run the
application
or I can use my performance test and I
I'd like to show you how it works with
the performance test
I just click building run and Xcode
very helpfully warns me that I haven't
yet enabled
p.geo in a build settings and it offers
to do that so let's go ahead
and let it enable that it's now building
a special instrumental version of our
apt
and running it using a performance test
and when those tests finish
II gotta I got a warning here in fine
air
let me just explain what's happened here
is that because we've run the app
with a lot of it instrumentation code it
runs more slowly
but this is just been used to generate
the profile so that's not a problem
when you go back to the project
navigator minute and show you
that expert has added this new
optimization profiles
holder an insider that if you can see it
there's my profile data so that's great
p.geo is enabled we have a profile let's
rerun those performance tests
go back to run product test and see how
much does it help
tests are running now and while we get a
21 percent improvement just like that
we don't have to change the code or do
anything else
so that is p.geo hi it's a great new
feature
to help you get even more performance
when you care about getting every last
drop out your code
continuing on this team up performance
I'd like to
turned the stage over to not approach
him my colleague to talk about
advances he and vectorization
thank you bob I
so I last year with Xcode 5
we've introduced a new optimization
called look victories Asian
and I would like to remind you with
lifters asian ex
so modern processors have victor is an
issue Victor instructions
these instructions can process more
posts killers at once
and the victory station is the compiler
optimization
that accelerates loops using these
vector instructions
and let's see how it's done you keep if
you can see the cold and the screen here
you'll see that a simple program
that accumulates all the numbers India
rate into one variable into some
and the natural way affects King
executing this code
is to load one number at a time and save
it into the variable some
min load another number and save it into
some but there's a better way
above excluding this code what to look
back to rate does
for you automatically is that each
introduces a new temporary variable
temp for this is a vector register
vector temporary
bearable and this allows us to load
for numbers at a time and ad for numbers
that time
and we do it for the entire right so
this is obviously much faster because
we're processing
for numbers at once as data processing
one number at a time
and when you finish scanning the array
we need to take the four numbers from
that
$10 pre-reg stir and add it together but
it doesn't matter because usually are
arrays pretty big
so so this is how look pictures Asian
accelerates
loops and makes you could run faster so
that you don't have to change your code
so in Xcode six with improvement
fertilization
in a number of ways were first the ball
we've improved and now says have
complicated leaps
this means that that they'll p.m. will
be able to analyze
more complicated loops and vectorized
more loot in your code
just great we've also integrated to look
back to either
with p.geo the Bob just just mentioned
so this means that when p.geo is
available
to look back to either will be able to
make better decisions
when Vick raising your code we've also
Inc improved
the x86 and ARM 64 coach in support now
this means two things:
first ball the loop vector Hazare has
better understand
processor so it can't predict better
when
it is profitable perfect riser coat
and the second thing that means is that
when it across your cold
ill generate better more optimized code
sequences
so that you called would run faster
and the last feature that i wanna talk
to you about his specialization
a blue parables
so most variables in your code
are only known at runtime these
variables can be
arguments or computed a
more expressions and and compiler
doesn't know the values of these
variables
at compile-time only at runtime
and in many times the fact riser cannot
picture as your code
unless the value of these variables is
known to be constant
so let's take a look at the example they
showed you earlier so this is a simple
loop
and I modify I modified it a little bit
and I introduced
the step purple so now instead of
consecutively scanning
all the elements in the array we jump
and skip some elements and
we we going to step up variable step
know kept that rises code because these
elements are not consecutive in memory
we can't use these vector
registers to load few elements and then
added together
it won't work unless step is equal to 1
well in many cases step is equal to 1
so what we do well we've introduced a
new optimization
called specialization what we do is
would create more people versions of the
loop
in one version of the loop we assume
that step is equal to 1
and then went back to write the code and
make the code run faster
but in another version of the loop we
don't assume anything
and code runs as is scaler
and them we had cold for selecting
at runtime which version of the loop to
run
if that happened to be one them fall who
that will then we go next YouTube Akris
version
but if step is not equal to 1 then we we
execute a regular version
and this compiler this new I am feature
allows the new pic dresser
to back rise: a lot more looks means
great
okay so this was looked back to his
Asian but in Xcode 6
we've also added a new kind of the trees
Asian this is
this this new pic riser is not to affect
riser it's called
SLP pics riser which which stands for
super word level parallelism
and it extracts parallelism beyond oops
with this Zazzle perfect riser does it
take looks for
multiple scalars in your code and glue
them together into a vector instructions
let's see how it's done saw on the
screen you see a very simple struct
destruct has two members X&Y
their consecutive in memory and we have
a simple function
that converts unit from feet 2
centimeters
now this is a very simple conversion all
we have to do his load
the ex member multiplied by Constantin
do it again and we do something for why
and of course the natural wave executing
this code
is to get consecutively load variable
axe
more quiet 7 back load verbal why
multiplied and save it back bet again
there's a better way of doing it and
this is what the Hasselbeck riser does
we can load X&Y together because they're
consecutive memory
multiplying together again
and seven back to memory and this is
ethyl be victors Asian
acid privatization is a very beneficial
for some kind of application mainly in
america applications and we see
great speed ups it may not speed-up all
programs
but it definately speed up a lot of fun
to make Lee
com complex applications
so to summarize I we've improved look
for clues Asian
in Xcode 6 and we've introduced a new
kind victories Ishant
called SLP victimization
now in Xcode 5 when we introduced to a
pic dresser we did not enabled by
default
and you have to go into one of the
settings and select computerization and
then
love kisses Asian worked well in Xcode 6
you don't have to do anything because
both the new SOPA Victoria riser and
improved load factor as ur
are enabled by default when you build
your application
in release mode this means they don't
need to do anything just compiled
application
in release mode and improved LVM will
make your code run faster
okay so we talked about number of
performance features
in Eltham we talk about PJ we talk about
the Tories Asian
which are but but both of these features
are features of a static
see and and seek with a compiler but LVM
is a central technology here at Apple
that's used by many projects
norm the project that I wanna talk to
you about today is accelerating
JavaScript code
well WebKit is another
is another important technology it's the
heart the Safari web browser
and WebKit needs to execute JavaScript
code because JavaScript is everywhere
and every web page and WebKit has an
interpreter
so when you load your Facebook page or
any other page WebKit start excluding
your code
with the interpreter but what kit also
has
to JIT compilers to XLR to accelerate
your code
when WebKit sees that you execute the
same function the same JavaScript
functions
over and over again to top let's take
little bit of time
to compile it real quickly so that he
will run a little bit faster than the
interpreter
so this is the fast jet in WebKit sees
that you execute function many times
then says
alright that so that's also take a time
and optimize this function real quick
so that people run a little bit more
faster little bit faster
so so we have the interpreter
we have Fastjet and we have to
optimizing jet
and there are trade-offs then there's
the trade-off between compile-time
and the quality of the code and this
works really great
accept that JavaScript is evolving
people start writing
large compute-intensive applications in
javascript
people can compile C-plus bus programs
into JavaScript
can run them in the in the browser you
can even compile
a quake three and run it in your browser
today which have
but some people like it it for I
dads it's great I
Beitenu you taste and we need a new
compiler
to support this use case and this is
where LBM comes into the picture
so we're adding LBM as the fourth tier
compiler
to WebKit
functions that run many many many times
are now compiled with LVM and they'll be
amnesty
tuned for making the most out of your
code for really trying hard
to optimize your code and to generate
excellent up
code quality and again there's a trade
up from compile-time
and quality of the code so WebKit really
wait for you to execute that function
many many times as you do in computing
test applications that run in the
browser
but compiling Java Script with LVM
is very different from compiling see
your objective c-
because JavaScript it's a great language
tutor
it's a dynamic language and if you look
at the code on the screen you'll see
that
there are no types there's this am
argument here but what is n YouTube
integer
is a double the class can be a lot of
different things
tile I recompiled well luckily
WebKit excluded dysfunction many many
many many times before
with the interpreter so it knows that in
the last thousand times
and was an integer so now we can compile
this code assuming that and his mentor
accept that someone may decide to pass
in and that's not an integer someone may
decide asa a double
for class and then everything will break
and can't allow that
so what do we do we'll technique that's
very similar to what we did with the bed
riser
we had checks will make assumptions and
we have checks we assume that n is an
integer
we assume that and does not overflow
and then we verify our some chance at
runtime
okay that's great but what is the fall
back what we do
when are some options fail we have to go
back to the interpreter
because only the interpreter can handle
all these cases
all these extreme cases
but moving back to do interpreter is not
simple because we started executing the
code in function may change as we can
just start executing it from the
beginning
so we developed a technology that's
called on stack replacement
which is the connects the that is used
to migrate to state
up the program from the jetted code in
LVM
back to WebKit in LBM needs to track
all the variables in your program and
someone may be in registers
something maybe on the stack and now
we're able to migrate them from LBM
into web to WebKit and continued
execution
in WebKit now this doesn't happen arm
all the time to very extreme case but
when it happens we have to handle these
cases
okay novak now I compiling code with LVM
is very beneficial
especially for compute-intensive
applications and especially
for these c plus plus applications
compiled into JavaScript wrong in the
browser
and we're really excited about Scott its
script
so now I we use LVM socks on rice
I we use LVM as the fourth beer compiler
and
in Safari both for x86 and I'm 64 on I
wesson
I was 10 and get excellent performance
pickups
summer as the stock today we talked
about modernizing objective-c code
and we also talked about a number or
performance features
if you have any more questions you can
contact our our developer tool
evangelist they've too long
or you can go to the Apple website or to
the LBM website
I am there are few related sessions and
I'm and I encourage you to attend these
sessions or to watch them online
thank you very much and the have a good
week
I