howdy
and a dildo in and I'm excited to
welcome you to section 418
improving after the instruments got a
lot of fun stuff to cover today
so let's get started so there are 5
items on our agenda today
but really only one goal and that's to
give you the tools you need
to go out and proactively profile your
app's looking for
memory problems at CP problems in
overall to increase the efficiency have
applications
so I'll start by talking about what's
new in instances here and then we'll
have three sections
and memory management time profiling and
performance cars
each with Associated Emmaus and
hopefully so that whether you're a
a new profiler our platform or
experienced handprints veteran you
should be able to take away some
tips and techniques from los demas and
finally what sessions complete without
covering dietrich's until talk about
some new at the trace improvements
and West 10 your city so
to get started what is now an instrument
is here well
you get to a major theme and
the first theme is a new UI and so
I am NOT if it looks quite a bit
different than before
but this is to match the style Xcode
and I was 10 you so many and we think
that you really like it
at the top like to point out the toolbar
am a particular note is the path
controller
allows you to quickly select both target
device
and process and one gesture which we
think will really speed up past your
work clothes
and on the right we've got
am a centralized place
for all over your configuration options
so whether this is recording options
before you run
viewing options or extended detail at
stack traces
is one place now to go and that's called
the inspector now the reason we did this
is mainly for your content and
we all spend a lot of time looking at
statistics incall trees
and having more real estate more space
to clearly ass
dive into your problem is really what we
did this for
so that's the first them what's the
second thing
well as you may have noticed swept
is a pretty big deal was here and we're
really excited about I'm what it offers
but as you go out and adopts with your
application
and whether its by adding news with
classroom converting from here
on the current code is swept we want to
make sure
that you have the confidence because you
can measure and you can
understand what's going on with the
technology into instruments has a
support for swift
and this will run across all over demise
today so we'll be using
both hybrid and your sweat taps for
those now there's
a host of other features and instruments
ass a move which will get to today
and that the demos like simulators
behaving as devices and strengths now
and some counters improvements and I
like but Dad
those a to serve high-level and
things that are new so
let's dive in and talk about the first
problem
they may face when developing
application and that's memory usage
so how can you reduce the memory usage
if your app
well we're talking about here is
persistent memory usage
so that helps narrow it down a little
bit but we also need to find out like
what what is your app using and for
doing that
we can think I have the marine
application its Rev
and iceberg you get the heap memory on
top which you
know about because these are the objects
you interact with view controllers
I ask images I managed object context
these are the object to your code
directly interact with
and under the surface there's everything
else there's the lair memory
I'm backing those images I warrior
here am managed object context as a lot
of
as objects as well and so if
you manage the membrane serve on the
surface
and you manage it well it turns out that
you actually
do a pretty good job managing the whole
usage the application
so how do we manage those objects that
we deal with
well for that there's ownership model in
objective-c ownership some
objectives his ownership model is pretty
ass straightforward it's there reference
can model based on retainer release
and you know when that after drops 20
the
the apt just read at these rules are are
well-known
their rules are documented and
the key point here is that it's
deterministic simple and pretty fast
so what about arc well
this makes it so much easier because it
manages to retain release for us
and so it transforms a problem from
dealing with retains releases
to dealing with your object graph and
managing
I relationships at a semantic level
so what about swift worse with such
model a
understandably is a lot like a objective
sees
although I i should point out that there
are a couple
differences namely that the and
that the retains releases are inserted
for you and
there's really no need to worry about
them
if you're working with objects either
you do still have to manage our lease
polls
and for that there's a nice dinner
library function I which
accepts a a closure and really easy to
use and so on
just make sure that that the urine
sorting out early spores as makes
sense with the a check to see because
they're using
so if these are the ownership models
what tools to have available to us
well while the heavy lifters we have is
the allegations instrument
and this provides I'm back traces and
information for all of your heap
allocations so good few things like last
names
I can dismantle ray after dealing with
script objects
at important to note that your I S swift
objects will be
pre-fixed with the module that at their
contained in
and so for your application this may be
just your app's name
but for us what topics be the heap
only will contain your reference types
and so I
if you're thinking about this at a a a
colourful easier classes that your
strikes
I'm but once you you identify these
ideas
allocations allocation from provide you
the and the reference histories for them
so retains releases an even lighter
parodies
at it also provides a lot of information
for anonymous BM
usage and see you can use a call tree
and track it back to the source
so I would actually like to shoot-em-up
abusing
ap allocations and profound nap
extension
so I have here simulator an iPhone 4s I
want instruments
and you immediately notice that we have
a new template user
and the template user allows you to
select at the top
I your device or even mention devices
for simulators
we can go ahead and choose to watch
different simulator
and allow you to choose the target the
one profile before leaving
miss liking your eye your template
matches the workflow ferment
from Xcode a lot better and so if you
use to
choosing what you want profile and then
the tool you can do that
or you can just go ahead and select as
always the tool
and configure first so I selected
the leaks ad template which has two
instruments
allocations in Lexington and for the
style
a pull up the at the listed aP's
installed on my simulator
you notice it behaves just like a device
to give me install the app's
and now new and I was 8 because map
extensions as well
if I select say sharing extension in
pop-up will also let me flight what app
it's hosted in
& Sons up extensions I'm are accessible
to multiple laps in the system
even system maps I can have
I'm behavior provided by your
extension you may want to select a
process
other than your main affects you
excludable
when your profile in your you're sharing
extension
now for this demo I'm actually gonna
slights a two-day extension
and since we know what he was going to
be
appear in there's actually no need to
flex AI housing app
so actually launch map in the simulator
and
it's a an app extension brain to debut
and what I have
is a I'm extension that
allows the quick access to my game and
so you know maybe I'm playing
a move very slowly a player move every
other day and I just one up or down in
make a quick move but it's a wave me
guessing
what the the pattern is tells me how
many I get right
coming up misplaced or wrong a couple
random guesses
you notice the memory usage in
instruments as I'm going up slightly
but I'm what I'm really interested in is
finding out how I'm doing cleaning up
memory
when I act creating new game and so I
can just create a few new games here at
the end
and instruments you notice we detect
quite a few weeks we'll take a look at
that
so first of all and allocations and
showing me all the
categories that I recorded and things
like see if string
and I can type in for my example dot
and we see four different categories
see the colored button and the dot today
you controller are prefixed by my module
because these are switched classes
and the other two higher objective-c so
they're
running together working fine
if I select one of these switch classes
and I've been even more I can even see
their 10 release history
paired or or not and if I go back to the
summary
up quickly notice that the persistent
number which is the 1i wanna check
if i'm looking for. memory growth is
well ok a hundred percent now
this is where your expectations as a
developer come into play
I expected my color buttons to
you know be reused so there's a few and
persistent a few entrance and
but my games I expected there only to be
one active at a time
so this and immediately and identified a
bug
ash ago at this point and fix fix it
now there's a couple other ways to find
my growth family s show you
two more first without leaks
and lakes will tell me all the the
memory that I could find was
unreferenced missus type of personal
growth and so we've got now it blocks
ac a couple of colors and those games
again
and what comes to persist McGrath
there's really three types leak memory
there's abandon memory index cache
memory
leaks will tell us the first to those
three if I want to investigate all three
I can use a technique called
generational analysis
now normally use this March generation
button
while you're running and set down some
flags
fitted then later no when you were doing
certain actions
but in this case actually know when I
did them and I can add them
after the fact which is a really
powerful technique
suffice like martina generation it
creates from the baseline snapshot
and what this is doing is categorizing
all the persistent memory in my
application
by where it came from on the time line
to anything before this flag
is grouped into generation one anything
between flag one flag to
generation I guess be as a playable
I can keep markey's I can even actually
choose to move them around
just by dragging them and updates the
the generation information
immediately sofa turndown
a generation be here will notice that
I'm
how well we have those dots games again
and we also have
equal number have asked not blocks
have kind of interesting I wonder if
these are coming from
perhaps we've got over 10 cycle
involving block
cell on the right in the inspector area
taken with the stack trace and on notice
that here we have a swift RAM
calling new game action I'm
on my my view controller let's take a
look that real quick
a jump tax code here's my new game
function
and it's just creating a dots game
assigning it to my I've air and
then it's registering for state changes
on my game
and passing an what looks like a black
this is
actually is for closure we can take a
look at the header
and we see here the register for state
changes take the dispatch block
and here we are providing it we just
give a very natural Sendak's
well if year shrill your with
blocks in 10 cycles it's very easy to
capture
the game in the block registered on my
game
and so we really really need to do here
is actually declare and that we would
like to capture
new game and well probably safe to
capture self quickly as well here
now swift offers a really good
am technique for doing this and its
capitalists
so we can just saying that we would like
to capture self
and new game weekly in this book
now we get aka compiler a quick that's
because we would clear something week
idk implicitly converted to optional
well
a time itself is now we really don't
care to call that method
so go ahead and add Sam optional
chaining
and every opera Don
so have to show you and Smith's now
supports
ap extension profiling you can specify
your host ap
either in the menu and instruments or in
your
scheme and tax code an app extensions
while they are transient
processors Mary doesn't matter because
they and
if the crash if they they flicker it's a
very bad experience for users and you
wanna make sure that
when they're running and other people's
applications running on a system
that you get the best user experience
possible now like to direct you to
had two other sessions if you're
interested in learning more about
abstentions
I R Us Austin so
afar briefly by memory management was
swept
objective-c code can still mismatch
retain release
especially if it's I'm code that you've
you've hand
hand-written and you have uncovered art
so when you're using and swift objects
and passing them to objective-c code
you may need to do some retain really
sparing and attract on the problems
also more important is that you can
still form cycles and swept
likely their side to great tools
language tools
available to us add to manage that graph
and not have to I and break this the
cycles
the person's week and this I
actually converts your type are required
to use an optional type
is what it does is returns you the type
Cornell
depending on whether the object that
references is still alive
at the time you you attempt to use a
variable
now for a noun you may think this is all
I can say
entertained an art and it's actually
safer than that I would what it does is
it returns the type
always but the object doesn't exist you
don't get
a unknown selector by or
a internet crash later actually dollar
needs to be object still there and then
gives you a deterministic crash
so some very powerful tools
at your disposal when dealing with swept
as a show in the demo on with what
captures this is a really easy way of
creating retain cycles
and something you should be aware of I'm
and check to see if I reference self
like this
it's going to capture it strongly as
well as new game
and I would have to use these week
typeof typeof
I'm have decorations
and then use them inside the and the
block
and swift like a show you it's very very
easy
using capture list to quickly change the
memory at type have your
the variables within the closure and so
just by declaring them
week and the capital S we can use them
and
and no problems inspectors also a really
powerful here and that
if you reference a property it will
force you to declare that you really
do intend to you I capture self by using
self
top property to learn more about swift
we gotta lotta sessions this week
and swept in our ability and DAP advance
weft
and if you want to learn more about the
generational analysis
and I did during the demo I'd refer you
back to last year's talk on fixing
memory issues
so with that I like to turn it over to
my colleague
Chris markle for telling you about time
for filing
time profiler at a high level as a tool
within instruments
that helped to make your apt faster
there a question
being faster in and of itself probably
isn't your real goal
why is it that you actually want to use
time profile
every answer I think a lot of cases is
depriving
great user experience what does that
mean
I mean you have faster app launch times
you if it's important to your frame
rates there 60 frames per second
time profilers a tool that can help you
do that
buttery smooth scrolling time profilers
great at finding pick up two years
growing and help you get past those
problems
and you know kinda meh more general
category all issue 1 have a responsive
UI
the user does something in the app they
need to see
a the Apple respond as quickly as
possible you don't want them to click a
button and wait
way happen so what exactly
is time profiler time for a player is an
instrument that samples
stack traces at creed describes:
intervals addicts
goal is to give you an idea of how much
time you spend in each method
there's an important distinction here in
that time profiler is not actually
tracing
through every method in function calling
rapid measuring how long it takes
it is capturing stack samples and
recording
how often frames appear in those samples
and others can be important if you have
a function or method that doesn't get
run enough to show up in air samples
ours too fast to show any samples
this isn't an issue most of the time but
it's an important distinction to keep in
mind when using time profiler
when should use time profiler well
there's
a couple different situations
if you have a specific problem that you
know about time profilers great
you know if you have stuttering a frame
rate slowdowns
some portion of your app is taking too
long parsing up by all
or something of that nature but it's
also find you some profiler
to identify and fix hot spots before
they become problems
you don't have to wait until you have a
problem before firing up instrument
season time
feiler actually it's a good idea to keep
my eye on the CPU Ganesh
inside Xcode if thats Eunos spiking in
ways you don't expect it just seems
higher than you want
that's a little clue you know something
should go off in the back here has
maybe I should look at time profile and
see exactly what's going on here
and so now I'm gonna show you a demo how
you can make you happy faster
with time profile and what I have here
is a hybrid ap
it's got some sweet files it's got some
object to see files
and I've been working on it for a while
and I want to get an idea of how well
it's running
for you know I don't know very specific
problems but i wanna gonna take a look
and see
maybe there's some hot spots in there
some gonna go ahead and time profile
this out
and to do that I am going to press in
click a hold on the Run button in Xcode
and choose profile
this guy launch instruments into the
template user
and once it's done building I'll show
you a nifty little trick
in a few me with this mess in the past
what would happen here
is would give you the temperatures are
what you see here and you would choose
you would go down to the button down
here
and you would click it in time profile
are or whatever
actually choose that now I'm thinking
about it
whatever is to your chosen would
automatically start running in recording
for your app
with the new instruments
it gives you a chance to change your
configuration before it starts running
now if you want all behavior it's still
there if you hold down the option key
you see the bun changed her profile and
that'll launcher app
and start running an immediately in my
case I don't want to do that i'm gonna
go and go to choose
I'm actually gonna make couple
adjustments and actually I'm here
on this is you can't quite see all that
but the two changes I wanna make unwise
can become clear soon
as I want to choose to record rate
waiting threads
and this means don't only collect
samples from the friends that are doing
work
but collect samples from the threads
that are I know as well
I happen to know that I want to do that
because I for hearst the stock before
I if you choose that option another
really great option to choose in the
view options is just disliked running
sample times
and what this means is even though
you're collecting idle samples
don't use them when computing time spent
a because Dave release or to water down
the result you have a lot of idle time
you get some very small numbers you
don't expect
so with that I'm going to zoom out
gonna click the record button to start
my app
and see here so here's my app
got a set of pictures over on the left I
can select them in
at the time they get the big view and
I'm gonna go ahead and click Apply
button
and well haw that's awesome
let's go through years or more one thing
I notice is that
between the time i click the button
below Haus before the eyes actually show
up
I don't like her my my app is supposed
to be I'm easing
as if you can read that I'll let's clear
and having to wait for your googly eyes
is not and I'm amazing experience
well fortunately I was capturing a time
profile
let's go and see what's going on here so
now we look
at the track to you we now have new
gestures
for working attract you and to select a
time profile
all I have to do is click or dislike the
time filter all I have to do is click
and drag
and then apply the time told so it's
much simpler
support hopefully hopefully far more
intuitive than
I was before and actually zoom in you do
the same thing
you hold down the shift key so do that
now I can zoom in
go back a and so now I can see if I come
down here
I can see that most my time is spent in
the main thread
and in the start method in this Aug
you're not here to watch me
click disclosure triangles all day I'm
gonna go over and I'm gonna use command
3 to bring up the extended detail paying
and this over here getting my heaviest
act race and what I'm looking for is in
this column here
i'm looking for big drop in the numbers
I can see right here I go from 120 to
I can give me ideas where my problem is
and when I selected in the stack trace
its lights on a call to review and
there's still a lot of stuff in there
a lot of which I don't really care about
so I'm gonna head command one
actually commit to go to my view options
one-on-ones I'm gonna choose over here
is too high missing symbols
no I'm gonna choose height system
libraries
and this narrows it down to just my code
it's kinda nice if you're looking here
you can see um
will expand this one more 0 you can see
here's an objective-c call
here's a swift go I got that backwards
right this is this what this is the
objective-c call
this went on here's a SWAT call us at RC
is
the bridge between them and if using a
hybrid app you'll see those
just so you're aware that there there
they're not from causing any harm or
anything exciting
another thing I want to do is I want to
convert the call triggers this makes it
a little easier to kind of see
frequently the most expensive calls in
your app
are towards the end of the call tree so
I can help to narrow in on that
and another thing that exercises I can
see per thread
really quickly what egypt what's think
expensive
calls so I'm here so I'm spending a lot
of time
in this method right here some double
click on it and it brings up
like this when do a little bigger I can
see
my swift code who
and it scrolls really quickly and thanks
to
this big red far I can see that most my
time is being spent on this particular
line of code
when Cisco doing well I'm using the core
image face detection to find faces
and then to find eyes on those faces
from most my time is being spent
warm what are my options here well I can
either change
think accuracy level the detection so it
doesn't find faces as well
I can maybe turn off the blink detection
those two things might make it faster
but I don't think they would provide as
on as in I'm amazing experience
as having high fidelity face detection
and getting you know the googly eyes
need to be on closed eyes as well
I I could maybe write my own face
detection
and maybe that'll be faster than what
provided in the Cape probably not
so are my choices here well actually
noticed using the app
that even if I can't make this faster
maybe can change where the work is being
done
and to do that I actually am going to
change its so
that when you click on
the app in the sidebar we click on the
thumbnail in sidebar
well go ahead and build the I the googly
eye image then
and by the time you click on the button
it'll be you already ready for you
and so I'm gonna scroll down to my
did select still use election to change
happen are to be cashing my googly eye
images
but I'm now doing I'm currently doing it
when you click the Buy song is that a
little code here to generate that
on when the selection changes we're just
move the work around here
and I'm actually Chi cheating a little
bit here I want to point this out
I'm using a mutable dictionary
as my cash and so instead of having to
deal with the mutable dictionary
and multiple threads I'm actually
dispatching this back to the main thread
so that all of my dictionary access
happens on the main thread
I can do this cuz is fairly simple app
it's not now are dreading going on
on but if you're doing more complex stop
you're gonna need a more
involve solution but this works for me
and if we scroll up to the actual
this is when you click the button you
can see here we basically
get the selected row which we see if the
images in the cash
if it's not we go ahead and build it and
put it into cash and then we
display so let's go and see this makes a
better
got the Profile button you see profiling
if you keep your eye on the track to you
you'll see that
it still does work you still see the
spike ranked but by the time actually
going to click the button
the workers are teamed up salyers all
spy
click the button scrub down here
this one ha love this app I could do
this all
ok but what's going on here where's my
scrolling what's going on of
thus stuttering of this is not I'm
easing
I need to fix this okay let's see what
we can do
this this is really terrible fortunately
I'm still running time: profiler so I'm
going to go ahead and select someone is
little spikes in here
and apply it I'm filter hold down the
shift key
go and zoom and I'm in NFL locker still
have
this a invert call to reserve expand my
main threat against his most expensive
I calls in right here the thing that's
really hurting us is the scaling the
image
that's where we're building thumbnail in
making it smaller arm
but the other thing I happen to know up
that's I can see the CPU spikes
and there's a few of them but it doesn't
really quite explain that much studying
and circus if you to be doing a lot more
work requires
stuttering like that so nothing I'm
gonna go check
is I'm gonna go up here in the toolbar
to our new strategy buttons
I'm gonna check out the thread strategy
which is fine over here
this is gonna show me what each strategy
wattage thread is doing
was about so you can see the whole thing
each of those little stopwatches
represent a sample that was taken on
that thread
the ones that are solid are ones where
the thread was doing work
and the ones that are translucent or
where the threat was I'll so if I go and
click on one of the news
and kinda see if you look up at the top
it says I'll call stack sample
not running on CNG users and I'll case
now I wanna make one thing clear here
because again estamos well-rehearsed I
know exactly what you need to click on
if i my problem
when you're dealing with your app
there's thousands of the samples
you're gonna have to use some detective
work to really narrow down where an hour
after seeing the stuttering are you
having the problem you're probably going
to have to click through several of
these
a to find out exactly what's going on
but in my case I can look through
interviews I can see and hear
what is this NS URL connections send
sickness request
well that's a big red flag synchronous
requests
bad idea figures are based on the main
thread
what the heck is going on here
so let's go back to ap I know there's
something going on here
actually no you know the season
associate with building the thumbnail
so I'm gonna go into my photo class
go to where the fall there's little
comment here with us read on the
internet Chris from six months ago
I don't even need to read this whole
thing that guy is a fool
if only there were some to our show you
a tool okay
I'm just deleting all this code we don't
need knew you'd
to using URL request too low to local
resource
I happen to know that that's good bye
that image we're looking for that we're
looking to create a thumbnail for
if you look down here in my initial
either actually have a property that
already contains that image
so instead of doing whatever that guy
from six months ago was thinkin
I'm still use them as I already have and
I'll free up my black thread
now I also have you know this is well
rehearsed demo that doesn't quite solve
the problem
it helps a bunch but still we'll start
stuttering and to fix that
we're actually going to another little
cheap we're gonna move some workaround
I'm actually gonna go in pre generators
thumbnails when the app starts
am going to the here at this a mine
swift class here
has a load photos method and this just
goes on
polos the photos on the bundle and
creates a list in here and ask some code
actually goes through
just simply touches each photo eSports
thumbnail
and neck its the that causes the
generational thumbnail
network happens we're doing this on a
background thread
basically as soon as you load all the
photos next thing we do is we don't
general
thumbnails the actually technically make
my out more fish in it just moves the
workaround
but I think for the user from the user
experience they won't really know
so now go ahead profile my app again
we take a look you can watch at the
beginning I'll the threats you can see
it doing more work
on if we actually use the app should
have some nice
buttery smooth scrolling here
this is a good one ha
fun at the park Fire Department googly
eyes so now my app is great it's super
responsive buttery smooth scrolling
as just up so much better
and that's an example I'll time profile
so to real quickly her I don't know
maybe we'll be back with quincy
our review what we've done we talked
about the new track
you you can I define zoom in on the
problem areas
you drag and select to apply a time
range filter
shifter exams and and controlled ragle's
and you're out
we also talked about the new inspector
paints
I there are some new keyboard shortcuts
so you can quickly move between them
I if you're familiar with a certain idee
mission kinda ring a bell I
command one is a record-setting this
these are the settings that apply to the
next
recording session command to is display
settings so it
alters how you see things either in the
detail an extended details are in the
track you itself
and then command three is the extended
detail
so you can see basically its details on
whatever selected either in your
detail you like the call to review or
and the actual instrument tracks itself
we also looked at
to love this strategy views the one we
didn't look at is the CPU strategy
and this will show you what work each
core on your machine is doing
we did see this from a strategy review
instruments at all you're probably
familiar with this strategy its track
shows you what what an individual
instrument is recording
and then finally the thread strategy
which shows you what each thread is
doing
and I'm just a quick reminder if you're
in time profile or
you can enable record winning threads in
see any block trades you have
and then you can go through them and see
maybe there's something your code it
preventing your thread from doing work
when they should be
we also talked about a few call tree
settings
I sense expensive calls are frequently
hear that ended the call stack
you can turn on environment for call
tree is also a great way to see
what each thread is spending its time
doing
and then you can hide system libraries
to help you focus on your code
and not really you know what the framers
are doing
you probably can't do a whole lot about
and I want to discuss
a couple tips I in the context menu
on the call to review you can choose
a to focus and prune current settings
a charge moves the associated cost
based on which option you select I
prune remove the associated costs so
those things aren't even for
part in the calculation anymore and then
focus you can think about is
a prune everything bot I am finally
our talk about two more Kyle I some
things you always do when you're using
time profiler
first you should always profile release
bills
the performance characteristics
aveda bug bill versus a release build
are significant
and profiling the bike builds could
cause you to
fix problems that aren't actually there
naked optimized away
the default in Xcode is to
profile release builds arm but this is
not
necessarily the best option for every
instrument for example
a the allocation instrument when using
objective-c code
the debug information provides extra
data it can use to
to a report on your allocations
and you can change this in the scheme
editor in Xcode you just choose the
profile by me you can change it from to
bug
to release and finally for Iowa's
it is really important for you to
profile on the device
I the simulator I for some things that
is much much faster for many things for
some things actually
much slower than the device really is
not a good use of your time to run type
time profiler in the simulator and with
that I'm going to head off to my
colleague jokers rack
was gonna show you what after you
haven't I'm profiler is not quite
enough a curse
my name is Joe Grice work we're talking
about a few things starting with
what are performance counters each other
processors
in your machine contain some small
number the 64-bit hardware registers
now you have to be like 48 some very
small numbers a very limited resource
and these are separate from the regular
floating point intended to register the
me think of when
you talk to your program actually
executing and doing work
know what can you do with these
registers well the good for counting
some small a small number of events
things such as a number instructions
have executed
l2 cache misses branches taken you
low-level Cebu specific things
alternatively you can have them take a
call stack every time some predetermined
number of events occurs
so what does that look like the cold
performance monitoring iraq's
or PMI's for short so say we have
our programs executing here over time
and the blue bar represents the
number branches we're executing and so
higher means we actually did more in
this period
with time a sampling which is on time
profiler rittick samples at a regular
periodic interval one millisecond by the
fall
this is true for time profile as well as
the colors instrument
but for release in water problems doing
well as being very branch E
we can do is set up what are these PMI
so that we have to get more samples
during the periods we care about
so we do is say every 10,000 branches or
so
but actually take a sample and so we get
more and there's we care about
fewer ever else because that's just
noise to us Angeles hone in on the
problem
application just a little bit quicker so
what else can you do with performance
counters
well you can get more information about
your app's performance beyond just time
that we saw
so sorry but I'm profile on steroids and
that's why we considered
maybe a little bit more in advance
instrument but it's something still have
in your toolbox
so what can you learn think about how
you're utilizing your CPU resources
things like the various levels and cash
is in a machine the execution units
translation look inside buffers if you
know what that is so you can look at all
so too little details that might be
bottlenecks for your particular
application
you don't learn more about your
application itself for instance how
often are you branching
often does branches miss predicted you
can even look at your instruction mix
you know how many integer operations are
you doing
how many floating point operations are
you doing these are things you can only
determine statically
by looking at your program because
you're depending on some user input or
something from the internet and that
sort of thing
so we had counters for a few years now I
this year we've added a few new things
first you know specify formulas
so you can get those Robinson but
actually apply some basic arithmetic to
them
on top of that so you can see we can
generate I PC which instructions per
cycle
at so measure how much work you doing a
given clock ticked generally a higher
number here
injured or more work im and performing
better incorrectly branch miss
prediction rate or things like your l1
cache miss percentage
take the total number of loads 01 kasam
est Adam to the total number of stores
and missed
and then divide that by the number of
total loans pasta number at all stores
and multiply by 100 for miss percentage
now
we've had x86 support for a few years
this year with I was 8 you can get
64-bit ARM devices
tap colors as well
and then the even profiler in Smith if
you're familiar with that that's where
you use to go for any kinda PMI based
information
for that kinda sampling you can just do
that right within the colors in sermon
now
and is actually no need to go to to
severance miss a thing counters related
head over to counters whether
as you build a move I was performance
colors
so I'm a little basic a matrix
multiplication at so
if your linear algebra is a bit hazy up
to a major
mobley cation about to end by and
matrices for each
elements in alchemy trixie you have to
multiply piece by piece an entire row
up the input matrix a times entire
column on the input matrix B and then
adding to those parts together
so in pseudocode it's just basically
just this trip Lee nested for loop here
for all the work is really the summer
products happening here so in swift code
Scopus a alright so we have are
basically is our trip Lee nested for
loop
and with all that work being done again
and that some Asian on the majors eight
times matrix P
and so what I want to do is go ahead and
profile is instruments
thousand gonna run on my device I use
the
option profile so it is going to launch
time for farms to start recording on my
device
and I can tap a button and it starts
when matrix multiplication
else is gonna take a little while
multiplying to 1000 by 1000 matrices
each one contains a double so it's a
fight so it's eight megabytes per matrix
twenty four megabytes in total and so
takes us here about
we talk about what twelve seconds to do
that
calculation someone stop
click track to time filter to the
regional interest
me just player and
what I want to see is where with map
spending time
so proves to me here on our extended
detail view
where we can follow that and that really
big number that so many samples are were
gets really small as we drop down here
so a problem is most the samples are
actually occurring this matrix multiply
routing
and if you double click on that routine
you take you to the source code to sleep
before
we'll see just like Specter ninety-two
percent my time is being sent right on
that summation life
I don't have much codes all being spent
on the one line I wrote so
kinda and other overtime profile I mean
I think I've done as much as I could do
well we can actually doing a little bit
deeper for willing to go look at this
assembling
and what we have here is these Hill Dr
instructions that are taking
a bunch of time an LDR asbestos loading
a register from memory
and so we can see these two ltr
instructions 1 a.m. loading major today
wanna blow the majors p and they're
taking a long time so now I can use the
counters instrument actually going to
figure out why
so what are a new template select
counters
you
and i wanna add some interesting offense
to record using
counters and so if we choose
at an event we can see the list of all
the events that this
device supports I'm interested in my l2
cache
so many as the number l2 cache loans
and I have a favor so creo l2 cache
loads missed
the number of stores and the number of
stores that missed
so havel's offense I'm gonna create a
formula using them
sewn together or one number the kinda
represents those four things
and what I'm gonna do is actually
generate a miss rate
saying the number of loads plus the
number of stores that missed
divide that by summation of the total
number of loads
which is loads
plus stores
K if I multiply that by 100 now I have
my miss percentage
that's a little negative for me I prefer
to think in his percent it's all just
take one hundred minus that number
and given a mail to head percentage at
that event
and as a matter before I PCs while those
hand you guys to have as a predefined
formula for IBC
go ahead and add that as well and so I'm
gonna start by recording again
and this time we see the cold 3 view as
well as
attract new has a bunch more things
being drawn and overall my events
so I start my matrix multiplication
again we'll see all those events going
by
has been calculated
and as this wraps up we can actually
start looking at
information and details so just finished
and we have here
is the number a bill to cash loans was
at $462 million
okay that's a lot 124 million in the
mist
and there's a much more in significant
numbers stores our overall had
percentage was 72 percent or so
okay that's not too bad alright BC was
points6
my means we're doing less than one
instruction per clock I think that
sounds kinda bad about computers to do
multiple things for clock is this
but the number that sticks out to me
most is that l2 cache low number
knowing $462 million loads two-mile to
cash
when my input matrices are only $1
million elements eat
to go to back the envelope calculations
as I should only probably do about two
million
so why is it so big well it turns out to
go online and search is actually much
better ways to do matrix multiplication
they're a lot more cash friendly for
today's processors and one of those ways
is actually go
and block up your matrix multiplication
as they're trying to do an entire row an
entire column at once
will do in smaller pieces because as
major too so big trying to do it all at
once we were gonna loading a lot today
to
and then kick it back out to memory and
unload a back in again kicking back up
that's very inefficient slow so have
another implementation or actually
while this matrix up into like 50 by 50
pieces
so much smaller we can see XQ here and
they're already finished
so we did this in about let's see time
filter down there region
and we could see were running time now
that
three and a half second so we are just
put it up about three times
and it took about three lines of code
very straightforward
and our l2 cache low number is now at
$24 million
so went from work $450 million down the
24 million slept much improved
cast or still somewhat insignificant
over growing in size
relative to Lowes RL to hit percentage
interestingly enough has come down we're
in the low seventies before an hour at
64 percent That's
a little bit odd r.i.p Cee Lo harbors a
much better
1.6 are actually doing you know one and
a half instructions per cycle some
that a lot better so this is where we
kinda considers a little bit more
advanced instrument because
you can generate a lot more these
numbers we have to know how to interpret
the results
as r.i.p CEE got better so that was
great our cash hit rate went down
was that a problem well no because we
actually did hundreds of millions in
loans
less to the cash to the fact that the
hurricane down a little bit
not really that big of a deal
the kinda wrap-up miss me to smoke
occasion thing you could continue
he by entering try to write a better
version however we've already done that
for you
there's an accelerant framework that has
that done and if I tap
on that version it actually finished
here in about two hundred milliseconds
and it's one line of code and it works
and that optimize for multiple cores
multiple devices
piece a cake please don't go right here
on my matrix multiplication
now last thing to point out the demo is
yeah I spend a lot of time over here
down here
your adding these offense adding these
formulas a really useful
I'm gonna come here since many many many
times I don't want to type a min again
so be sure to go to File same as a
template
give this some interesting name l2 hit
rate
counters something like that
and then say but of and the next time
you go to the template user
use the custom filter load up this
template you have the type that in
again and again and again
so what did we see a with counters
you're basically click data by default
similar to time profiler
it's a statistical sampling and
application this is an important point
the basic for the past no one
millisecond by the fall
were aggravating the time at all the
events and then we can attribute it to
that one moment I'm we take a call stack
sample application
this means you want to get a lot of CPU
samples to get really inaccurate picture
what your
applications doing if you're not very
CPU intensive this isn't the instrument
for you
you can tweak that slightly by using the
performance monitoring interrupts
so this allows you to very Libre
sampling rate based on the number of
events are happening so if you're really
interested in branches
or l2 cache entry you can actually
sample based on how many of those things
are occurring
and get more refine results on what
you're looking at
note that the PMI instructions can be
slightly a little bit imprecise
in that by the time the into requires us
to take a call stack
a small number instructions may have
gone by which means
you'll be on the precise instructions
because thats buy you a beer in the
neighborhood and it will get you to the
problem a lot more quickly
be sure to use formulas you can gather
always relevant but a lot of times
larger to
Jerry one metric metric it makes it a
lot easier to see the problem at hand
so jericho's formulas and save them
inside
over template so that you can get back
to him quickly in the future
changing gears entirely dietrich's
if you're unfamiliar with teachers I
recommend you go online
%uh display information about it
basically it's a kernel-based
recording technology little let you get
more information about your application
especially how it interacts with the
kernel
zeroing out talk about what's new with
OS 10 you're so many
first there's a dynamic trace ma'am so
close memes away the actually
print out the contents of your memory so
previously you had to know the size of
your
array at compile-time and the happens to
work a lot of the times but not always
now to work with variable size arrays to
say I want to trace the CG contacts phil
recht sky
hard-won is a variable size rectory and
art
to is the count of how many things are
in there
cigarette this tea tree skirt that on
upon entry into CG context still Rex
we're going to do is copy in hard-won
which is the array
and the size that array is a size a
single CD wrecked times are
to which the Cal so to have the copied
into the kernel
Oracle Trace my mom that to pass the
array the past 5 12 which is the maximum
size we are expected to be
for our application and then again we
pass I think Council trace them works on
your variable size
race the next big improvement is urs
histograms that have been approved
basally as a number of new options
too many discuss here but they see you
get much better
improved histograms usury better ASCII
art
under terminal when you're generating
these things are free to that
excellent blog post on teachers .org
obstruct all the options
and always will be helpful to you
there's a few other new features
previously if you wanted to make sure
you got
every single probe firing from det race
you might have to
so your application is root now you can
actually St traced to wait for the
process
start with the SW so you fire up the
trace
and then you start your application and
with a little help from the kernel
stopping application
letting teachers come in and installers
probes the talks
than your application will be released
by the kernel to run annual Miss Annie
the probe firings at the beginning
is also a more advanced feature which is
to animal variables so if you run the
SIS cattle turned out to be traced
you list them what variables your
current Carl supports things like
maximum buffer sizes are enabling
additional static colonel probes
some pretty advanced features you can
now toy with that you couldn't before
column or bottom all the documentation
has been updated
soldiers run man that Mandy trace and
get all info
so some rice so it was a lot of things
we saw allocations
leaks time profiler counters so there's
a lot of tools in the toolbox
and you can use them on swift and
objective-c code alike
it'll just work I want you to be
proactive
use these tools throughout the
application development process
I'm even while you're debugging
something maybe a sea of the corner I
wanna low CPU or memory gauges spikes
the unexpected
go ahead and profile application in
strength right then
and actually try to improve your
application right then and not just at
the end
and while you're doing that number don't
assume go ahead and profiler ap
make a change in actually think we'll
fix it and then profile announcement
again
a coupon generating until the problem
has been resolved
if you have any more questions you can
always contact a bit longer evangelist
are we have documentation on developing
outlook.com
was excellent forums that you should
know about where you can talk to
other instruments users post question
for answers and Smith developers will be
on there from time to time answer your
questions as well
as a few related sessions
we saw some stuff about extensions today
to you'll see that
others I can talk tomorrow some swift of
course all throughout the week
he was mentioning switched to buying
stuff for the world to be on Friday
with that thank you for coming have a
great week