Hyatt hello and welcome to the advanced
graphics animations
why what's up
ok I'm actual up next with that he will
take over in the middle of the talk
and was to less talky going to cover the
following topics:
the first part will be talking about the
quantitation pipeline and how it
interacts with the application
after this I'm introduce a few rendering
concept that are required to understand
our new two classes you I blow effect
and you haven't the effect
and after this Michael takeover and
walking through existing profiling tools
and demonstrate a few case studies 228 a
framework to be looking at and at a
distance talk
from in the fourth but a top you looking
at coordination and told in taxes OpenGL
on some hardware was metal with the
graphics software and then
in the second half of my part ever talk
about you I blow effect on your lap and
the fact that a part of you like it
so let's get started with the
coordination pipeline
so it all starts in the application
the application with a few high keep
either indirectly with you like it or
directly was cool animation
wanting was not a thing now is that the
application process
is actually not doing the actual
rendering work for coordination instep
this
if you are a key is committed to Reynoso
up which is a separate process
and israel also has a server-side
version of coordination that receives
this your lucky
if your keys then rendered visco
animation
miss orange elemental a obvious to you
few accelerated
and then one secure key is being
rendered we can finally displayed to the
user
so do things interesting part is now
haha doesn't look like time by
submitting the application so therefore
I would like to introduce the flow
Ingrid
the vertical lines represent a vertical
blanking interrupts
and Cynthia rendering at sixty have are
you I the distance between doors were
declines
16.67 milliseconds so
the full thing that happens in the
application be receive an event
probably because the touch and therefore
the usual case
but anything to him in this case is that
the 12 update a few hockey
and this happens in the face that we
call the contraction faces in
is no application at the end of the
faith
if you are accused and and called and
sent Reynoso
the full thing that are in the summer
and the house is difficult to secure a
key
the end the summer then have to wait for
the next piece Inc
in order to made for bus that we get
back from a state you can actually went
to
and then it finally stopped issuing talk
of
to for the Jeep you with OpenGL metal
again then want this is completed
hopefully teach PDP resources not
available he can finally start rendering
and soldier accused of doing is
rendering work hopefully this rendering
book
finishes before the next we think
because then we can
swap in the frame buffer and showed if
you are key to the user
as you can see this very steps spent
over moves for frames in this case it's
three frames
and let's say we would now lost continue
with the next 10 leavin to commit
transaction
after-hours played that we would only be
able to her and that's when he heard not
at 60 Hertz
so therefore what we're doing is BR
overlaying
the stages so in parallel with the drugs
that you can see here people
do the next 10-20 vent and the event
commit transaction and so we end up with
following step diagram in next few
flights I would like to
focus on commit transaction stage
because that's what effect application
developers the most
so let's take a look at commit
transaction
commit transaction itself consists of
all fails the first phase this delay of
faith
does that he set up the fuse then the
next phase is to display faced as they
draw to fuse
the sub faces steep repair commit face
heavy
to some additional 20 mission work and
the last phase
is maybe actually pick it up the Laos
and seventh-rounder so
in the committee let's look in detail at
those four phases
first then they'll face and layout faced
the layouts a fuse alright I invoked
does the few creation happens does the
BF left with short he was that's a few
and is very popular content and to some
lightweight database lookup something
like this because we don't want to stall
here too long
like this could be for example localized
strings because we need him at this
point in order to put
to a labor layout because of this the
faith
usually Cebu bond oil about the second
phase of the display 5
disadvantage or contents the store
activity overridden audio stream drawing
one thing what both noting here is that
this
faith is actually Cebu on a rebound
because the rendering is so for us to
rise to use your
cool graphics was rendering and Soviet
leaders rendering with
CG context so the point is here that we
want to minimize the work that we do
with call graphics to avoid a lot
performance in the stage
next faithful to prepare faced this is
the image decoding image conversion
happens
image tickling should be straightforward
the 75th and images and if you are a key
and
this trip XO PNG's I getting the call it
at this point
image conversion it's not quite so
straightforward what happens here is
that we might have images that I in a
format that has cheated on
that is not supported by the GP you and
definitely need to convert
his images a good example is could be
indexed bitmaps leave want to avoid
certain image formats
in the last faced the cliff face the
package up the layers and send them to
run the server
this process is because if you have to
trade with really a tree and is
expensive the latter is complex or do
that's why we want to keep the left rear
strut as possible
to make sure that that it's part of the
faces is efficient as can be
so let's take a look how this works
animation animations themself
three-stage process I'm two of those
happen in fact application
at the last eight happens on the in the
summer the first they just let me Chris
where we create animation update of your
key this happens usually was the
animators duration:
animations Meffert then the second stage
is every
prepared committee animation this is
where earlier a few
been called and direct and that promise
of familiar
and it is because is out for fails we
are just looking at
the only difference here is that with
the committee don't just committed if
you are a key
recommit as well D animation and it's a
reason because we would like to hand off
the animation booked Reynoso so that we
can
continue to update your animations
result using inter-process communication
to talk back to the application of
awesome backed with the application
so look for proficiency reasons
saw let's take a look at a few rendering
conflate the required to have
understand and you visual effects that
yet providing you with what I was eight
for his part of a talker I'm covering
three areas first time it's pandering to
this whole or GP was work
then I'm going to introduce the concept
of render passes because on the effect
for use with for in the path of
and then I'm doing a fourth example by
showing you home asking works is when a
passive
so let's take a look at times rendering
with famous rendering the screen is
split into title and I and pixels
have put your screen shot together and
all it to the grits bacon he actually
bought it has
thanks would be like the time for the
children so that it fits into
into the SLC cash and the ID is here
that the geometry split 2-2 tie back its
and I would like to demonstrate this a
by using the phone taken as an example
as you can see the full I can spend much
but I'll and
before i cant others when it is he a
layup and the CLA NCAA israel's
two triangles and if you look at the two
triangles
they're still spending multiple
triangles through to the tiles
and thought if you were doing now it
will not stop splitting up those trying
of
many committed but I'll so that each
type can be rented individually
the idea fear the beard do with process
novel who geometry so at some point we
have to geometry for each to collect
that and then we can make decisions
on what pictures are visible and then
decide but pick such a two-run three-run
each pixel shader
when he wants public's home
obviously if you do banning this doesn't
quite work that we still have to you
problem overdrawn
so let's take a look at what type up
when Rick passes I'll
so let a few applications has built a
few her keeps coordination
it's committed to render so and comic
when mission you call it it
and now it needs to end it and it will
use OpenGL metal
and it's like I'm just saying metal for
simplicity Tremlett
and it will generate with hope your
comment but that is then submitted to GP
you
at the Jeep Europe received this command
before and stop doing at work
the first thing that you do is what text
processing those that about action
around
and ideas here that would transform all
about this isn't a screen space at this
stage
so that we can do tend to the second
stage with his bitches get retailing
actually tell the geometry fought
advocates
and this part of the state Scott but I
left side you will be able to find
in the instruments in the open OpenGL ES
driver instrument
and %uh palo utilization
the output of the state's is written and
something called the parents about from
and the next stage is not starting
millions that
the leave made no answer or geometry is
processed and sits in the family to
buffer
or into the pan with a purpose for
because the problem is if the problem is
full we have to flush it
and it's actually performance it on
because they meet with automatic
processing
and gets front load the pics a shift
work
and except to say that status as a set
up extra stage
the stage is actually call to render a
stage and you can find again in the
instruments or your structural
a and that the name ring writers Asian
and the output of the stage is written
to something called
you in the buffer K
South take a look at a practical example
by looking at masking
let's assume of your keys way to go the
command buffer is
sitting miss the few and you can stop
processing
for the full thing happens in the fourth
pastors that be rendered the
delay I'm off to a texture in this case
that this camera icon
them in the second pass P render the
their content with extra
and in this case with this kinda blew
material
and then in the last part that he called
it compositing possibly apply to master
the content texture
and composite to rate the result a
screen and up is dis light blue camera
icon
saw let's take a look at you I'd love a
factor for those that don't know
you I blow effect can be used with you
as a visual effect few and
does not public API since I was 8 it
basically allows you to use the broth
that introduces I was having and be
providing you with three different law
stuff that I want to demonstrate your
to piss regular I O S wallpaper and
apply to three blocks that that you have
to it
extra light light and dark a
so let's take a look how does look
performance wife
I'm using Google Docs time as an example
for rendering process the doc style
actually using the law was the model for
an apostle and
the I think your mind number in the past
depends on how to be difficult to other
nations
for certain pop pop up
for the fourth past year end of the
content that was going to be blood
then in the second part of be captured a
confident on scale it
the downscale depends on the hardware so
in disc fly to cap it at a certain size
with the readable
then in like the past few play the
actual blog arisen which
separated so we do for the horizontal
and vertical blom
there's actually a con brio optimization
because do with anything a pass but
let's assume our
blower car would be eleven by 11 this
would mean we would need to read how
twenty-one samples per pixel
by separating it to be or need to read
11 samples per pixel
cage bus so after the 4th path we have
to love
horizontally and vertically blot small
tiny area
and so what's left in the last part is
that need to upscale display or intended
in this case we end up them to sell a
doctor
so that looks fine but let's take a look
how this looks like performance wise
so what it as a test I critical full
screen layout and
applied to your bluff effect to it and
measure the performance and a staggering
can see three roles
the first rule group effort I'll
activity second-rower interactivity
and to the last row I put in the black
interrupt you can actually see you
what friend boundaries are and again be
running at 60 votes are you I
so time you have as 16.67 seconds
so let's focus on on a single frame
as you can see a first look here the
first Tyler path is happening before the
first when their paths and that's
because
the Thailand the process all geometries
with emphasize what we just saw on a
previous life
so let's go quickly what passes against
the footpath if the
content past the time for this penance
really depends really on if you are a
key
in this case it's just the simple image
so it might take longer in use in
real-world
you I'm then in the second panel 3
downscale
and capture the content it's actually
fairly fast
at his pre-match consul cost then
the surpasses yours on two brothers
again constant calls for two pretty fast
because the
only played on a very small area and
then in the fourth piles
me to refer to comply or again very fast
and
we end up with a blow to region and then
in the last past the upscale
and tint people are
the one thing you will notice now others
gaps between those passes left my time
here in Orange
and those cats I actually did you idle
time and to happen because we do here
rent a context switch
in on this John a jeep you and this can
actually quite
at up quite quickly because the time
spent here and at other times per
possible to your point want to
your point to a few seconds so in this
case was four passes we have bought at a
time of 0.4 to 0.8 milliseconds
which is a good thing if you can track
of our 16.67 milliseconds
let's take a look out a book performs on
the various devices from
so again this is the full screen blow to
use that I used before and
measured as well on iPad 3 such
innovation
and as you can see the iPod Touch
generation performs much worse than the
iPad app
in the interest in the in the case of
text the lead lawyer the timing
is 18 point 15 in the second for the
country and that 60% of the type of
wrong about him
and polite and actually around fourteen
point five milliseconds
which leads us about 20 seconds for you
i've which is not really enough for
entering any compelling you I'm
so the decision be made on I was seven
already was that we would is able to
bring on certain devices
and the iPod Touch generation is one of
those devices and with this
the former on the iPad situation changes
to this
you basically just apply it in play on
top so that we can actually do believe
he is the same as
with possibly effect
saw and to either it on what devices we
don't want to be only 22 tinting
on the iPad 2 and iPad such generational
be just the private in Danby skip the
blow steps
on iPad 4th generation iPod air iPad
Mini iPad Mini
was richard is playing or iPhones and
iPod Touch do both the Bryant attending
soul in summary for the you I visual
effects few with you I play fact
you I blow effect it would have to ask
impasses depending on the style
when he died two weeks redrawn so it's
actually fine if you have
a large blur area and you don't have
that content behind it because they only
apply to blow one's
effective very costly so the United can
be easily Jeep you belong to
so therefore you should keep the balance
of the few a small as possible
and therefore as well he should make
sure to put it for defect
saw next let's take a look at you I
violence effect
you have aren t affect the city is in
effect issues on top of the blender from
interviews for content which can make
sure that content thanks out and doesn't
go unnoticed the broth
so let's take a look how does look like
at this hour three blocks that again
and let's assume the bonds to render the
camera icon from
I'm asking example from before on top
and this could look like this if you
don't use any balance effect and as you
can see was the light style
there might be too large booty issues
because the great stuff leading
out so what decided to us that we edit
some
if I'm into effect and the primacy
effect and at the pump through and then
you end up with nice private look
saw let's take a look how does affect
performance
so back to or in the past agro
the first five passes are in this case
for the doctor or the broadcast
and then in a six pack of beer another
their content to a texture
and then in the final compositing pass
we take the
their content and apply filter and
composited on top of the block
don't be fooled here from the for the
cause actually quite expensive and I
wanna shoulders and next couple of
flights
so this is our order and I come from
before the South the the steps what a
blow and lets at on now the steps for
the vibrancy effect
so in perfect a meeting in here from
content that is ok mr. Aiken
and damn obviously the cost for this
past depends on what you're entering
their
what very few very few have key looks
like
and then last past the apply the filter
and as you can see the for the cause
actually very expand the fifth
actually the most expensive path we have
here
one thing to keep in mind here is that I
apply to balance the effect of which can
carry on
the recommendation is to not apply to
pharmacy effect with with Marion stat to
only apply it to us more content areas
to avoid to tissues performance penalty
about time for life a the did you have
no spam or caps because you have more in
a pass a Saudi g2 I'll a time
has increased as well if not six caps
and this can add up to 0.6 pool 21.2 mi
seconds
by the time about you
saw let's take a look how does look on
my putts a generation and iPad a.m.
does the base cost from before 4.59 many
seconds for the iPod Touch I actually
don't blow
and a different times for the iPad and
depending on the blast I'll
solitaire on and what we can see is for
the fourth been effective therapy is
spending on iPad saturation about 27 to
26 many seconds just
for applying the vibrancy effect on the
iPod
air we spend about 17.48 me second
flexalite style and
around 40 milliseconds for light and oxo
you don't have a lot of time left on a
gp2 any other rendering
I mean 22nd from the best case here
sought to emphasize again we should
really restrictive RNC effect on a small
area to avoid is huge
keep your head so in summary
the UI vibrancy effect at to a screen
pass earth
you i havent effect use expensive
company is an expensive compositing for
the full content
therefore you should only use the
vibrancy effect on the small regions
arm again like the blonde only to return
to read wrong
and you I'm into effect is very costly
on all devices
so with less was the Blue Earth you I
can the BG view bound
keep the bounds of the fuse as small as
possible I make sure to
budget for defects so
next I would like to give a couple of
optimization techniques take the
techniques on the way I
ones with relation authorization can be
used the composite which once was the
Jeep you
this can be neighbors they should trust
their eyes property on a clar and
a few things to keep in mind when doing
this first
extra of composite a creative MB update
the content foolish only used it for
static content
secondly you should I use it because the
cache size for us relations limited to
25.5 times of the screen size
so if you stop setting dress dress
property of on last part of your
few hockey you might lower the cash over
and over and end up as a lot of
additional
ski passes last
up arrest was impressed with images I
because from the cash
if they are you someone how many seconds
so you wanna make sure that use this
only for image that conversely you stand
up for
in Tripoli's them just because then you
working through every time a mosque
impasse
so typically use cases are to avoid
ridge or redrawing expensive
effect was that the content seek redress
rice for example a blow
and the other thing is to have what we
doing a complex you are key so we could
breast rice for few are key in composite
is on top of a blur
wonderbra so the last thing
I have here is capacity capacity can be
disabled was the last capacity property
I see a layup
a capacity but actually in terms of
capacity for Laos not a pixels means
your past the property is not equal on
points year old
and for last long trip the content that
means that China Laos
or a background image and but isn't on
the status of your account to be
composited
before it's being blended and if America
nations was told of its not need
be very careful with this was this
I would like a plan talk to Mike 42
so I am i crossing software engineer on
the island on Steam
and the first thing on talk about are
tools so
before I get into tools though I do want
to mention prompt investigation might
so basically what are the questions
running through my head when
I encounter performance issue want to
start tracking down the source about
so first thing I want to know is what is
the frame right
you know it's always good to know where
you're starting performance wise so that
you can gauge how the changes you make
are affecting performance
so our goal is always 60 frames per
second we want to ensure that we have
smooth scrolling and I smooth animations
to provide a good user experience so our
target should always be 60 frames per
second next up
I wanna know are we see peerage if you
down you know obviously the
slow realization the better because will
let us had our performance targets
and also give us better battery life
netting 10
other any unnecessary is there any
unnecessary CP rendering
so basically are we overriding for all
right somewhere where we really
shouldn't be
you know kind understanding what
rendering and how rendering
we want the Jeep you do as much with us
as make sense next thing on a No
is do we have too many offspring passes
as actual pointed out previously
of green passes basically give the Jeep
you idle time because I have to contact
switches
so we want to have fewer offspring
passes fewer the better
next up I wanna know is there too much
blending in the Y
on we obviously want to do less funding
because blending
is more expensive for the Jeep you to do
then rendering
as normal a player so responding better
necks I want to know is are there any
strange image formats were sizes
basically want to avoid on-the-fly
conversion image formats
as I 2.0 previously if you are
rendering an image that is nice in the
color format is not supported by the
Jeep you
then it has to be converted by the CPU
and so we want to try and wait anything
on the fly like that
next up on an order any expensive user a
fax
learn vibrancy are awesome but we want
to make sure that we're using them
sparingly in a way
that will give us the sprawling
performance that we want and lastly
oh noes or anything unexpected in the
View Park on you know
if you have a situation we are
constantly adding removing views you
know you could introduce a bike
accidentally that's a
you know insert a nation forgets to
remove them or you know your
adding use your parking forgetting to
remove them you wanna make sure that you
only have the views that you really need
mom you know in your heart key because
you want to avoid excessive CPU use a
back forty
so now let's get into some other tools
that will give us the answers to these
questions
so first up on talk about instruments
and particularly will talk about
are the coronation instrument in the
OpenGL ES driver instrument
then I will say a few things about the
simulator that you can do with colored
about options
and I will briefly talk about a new
feature in Xcode
for life you debugging device so first
up
if you want instruments and select the
coronation temple
that will give you a document that
contains
a coronation instrument and a time
profile learns from
if you select the coronation instrument
you can then choose which is the six you
wanna show
in this case its only frames per second
so will choose that and then when you
take a trace it will show you your frame
rate so you can see in the column here
shows you the frames per second for each
interval that this
trace was running for you see this in
sample intervals likewise
wanna see what the CPU's doing are you
can select the time profiler
instrument and so you slept and you can
then see an aggregate the call stack
what the CPU was doing while you were
taking a trace
so this is where you would look for you
know I am i overriding drive rack too
much spending too much time in a
threatening
thread doing things that I shouldn't be
next up let's talk about some other
color debug options that are part of the
coronation instrument so if you select
the coronation instrument
you can see the color debug options over
here on the right
so let's go through what those are first
up
we have color-blind a player's and so
this will tent this will 10 players
green better appcake and two players red
have to be planted
as we said previously you know layers
that have to be blind it is more work
for the Jeep you
and so you ideally want to see less red
you know and more cream but there are
gonna be cases where you can avoid it
on for example in this particular case
we have a white people view
with white people who sells and we
noticed that our labels
are you know having to be blended here
so if we made our labels in this case
opaque then we wouldn't have to worry
about doing the blind
on so that would be one opposition we
can make in this particular case
next up color hit screens and missus red
this shows you how you're using or
abusing
on the should Rasta rise property on see
a liar
so what this will do is it will it will
tense cash it's green
cache misses red so you know as a 2.0
previously keep in mind that your cache
size is only two and a half sine
times the size of the screen and items
are affected from the cash if they're
not used than a hundred milliseconds so
you know it's good to use this
particular coloring book option to see
how the cow you're utilizing the cash
with
you know what you have such a rush to
respond
when you first launcher app you're going
to see a lot of washing right because
you obviously have to render it once
before can be cashed
but after that you don't wanna see a
whole lotta flashes red because
you know as we have previously you know
any thing you're doing is going to incur
offering passes you have to render a
and then stick it in cash so
next item is color copy images on
you as we said before if an image is in
a format as in the color format
that the chief you can't work directly
with it will have to be converted by the
CPU
so in this particular example you know
this is a simple
far photo browsing arm were just getting
images from an online source more not
really checking her size
or their or their color format on its
own if it were case we're getting images
that are 16 bits per component
and so you can see that they're tutored
sign here that is telling us that these
images had to be converted by the CPU
and commit phase
before they can actually be rendered so
you know for this
particular case we don't wanna do this
on the fly because I will fax growing
performance
on with so you can beforehand
you know convert your images to the size
and color format you're expecting
and it's best to do this in you in the
background so you're not eating up time
on the main thread while you're trying
to scroll or doing other things
so the next option is color misaligned
images this will tent
images yellow that are being scaled
until images purple
that are not pixel on you know as it had
previously it's always good to make sure
that images are in the color format the
size that you want
because the last thing you want to be
doing is you know doing conversions and
scaling
on the fly while you're scrolling so the
same prince will be applied
in a previous life who also apply here
to get rid of the scaling
fly so next up is color of green yellow
so this will 10 layers yellow based on
the number of green passes
that each layer occurs so be more yellow
you see the more of green passes we have
if you notice the NAP are and the
toolbar are tinted yellow
that's because there are players with
these layers that are
actually during the concept behind it so
we expect those but I do find it curious
that the images
are having offering passes so we'll take
a look at that later on the presentation
and see how to work around this issue
so next is collar Open GL fast path blue
and so what this will do is this will 10
layers blue that are being planted by
the display hardware
on this is actually a good thing you
wanna see because if we have content
with being bent blinded by the display
hardware
the Nets less work for the Jeep you have
to do so in this case if you see
something show up in blue
that's a good thing on
last option is flash up the two regions
and so what this will do is it will
flash
her to the screen yellow that are being
updated on this particular example is
with the clocks out the ship's
in I last are you notice that the yellow
regions here
are the second-hand ideally you only
want to see
part to the screen flashing yellow the
you're actually updating again because
it means less work for the
GP you must work the CPU so if you turn
this on you don't want to see
a lot a flashing yellow unless you
actually are updating
that much of the screen so in summary
some other questions that the coronation
instrument will help you get to
I will help you figure with from readers
is there any unnecessary CP rendering
because
it does include the time profiler
instrument
on panel also with the colored by the
options you can see are things like
other too many offering passes how much
when things going on
and you have any strange image format
your size is that not expecting
and so one additional point on color and
options some
love the color and options are available
in the eye with simulator so you can see
the example here
a few things to point out with this the
colors might be slightly different
because the version CA that's running
inside the simulators actually person at
the aid atlanta with 10 on iowa's
so if you see any discrepancies always
trust what you see on device
because that your customers actually
gonna be using home
so this is a good future because you can
have you like for your testing team go
off
and poke around your app and see if you
have any unexpected offering passes or
any conversion or anything that looks
suspicious
so next topic on talk about the OpenGL
ES driver in
so if you watch instruments and select
the OpenGL ES driver template
that will give you a document that
contains the OpenGL ES driver instrument
and and and the time profiler instrument
so if you select the OpenGL ES driver
instrument
you can choose from which the CITIC
Pacific's you want to actually collect
when I'm investigating things I tend to
go for
advice realization which will show you
how much the Jeep use in use during the
truth
i render entirely realization does
correspond to the renderer
entirely phases that axles I talked
about previously
and then of course the coronation frames
per second because I want to know what
the actual frame rate is that we're
seeing
so if you take a trace
and then select the coroner the OpenGL
yes driver
instrument you can then look at the
statistics
and see if approved for example in this
case you know we are getting 60 frames
per second
and our device utilization is in like
the mid
lower 70's so you know depends on what
you are your rendering so you know you
may want to investigate this
gold like that all boils down to what
you're actually rendering for this case
and likewise since we have the time
overall arrangement here you can see
with the CPU's doing
so if you select that you can then again
look at an aggregate cost tax
what's going on in the CPU during this
time to this is always useful because
you can highlight certain regions
you know if you notice that you're
dropping free in 3 knows a lot of
activity you can zoom in and see
what the CPU was doing during a
particular time
so in summary with the OpenGL ES driver
instrument you know this will give you
answers to questions like What is your
frame rate
are you can see what the CPU and CPU
were doing and you can also use the time
profiler instrument
to see other any unnecessary CPU
rendering going on
so next up is a really cool feature that
was added Xcode
for live you debugging on device so if
you open your project in Xcode
and then run it and then click the
Follow button on the bottom here
on what it will actually do is it will
grab the view hierarchy of the device
and you can then go poking around the
view hierarchy in C what exact use are
in your
you why so this is always good because
you can expect to see a better if
there's anything unexpected there
you know maybe something is building up
you have a legal thing animations or
something
or constraints so this is good to
actually see what the view hierarchy is
on your device
versus say what you conceptually think
it is when you're writing your co
home if you select an individual item
arm
or noonan individual view you can look
at the properties for its ok in this
case we selected the UI view
and you can see details about what
property in image is currently being
rendered by that you
so summary for Xcode you debugging this
will let you poke around in your view
hierarchy see what's actually being
rendered on device
you know which is helpful because you
can see if you have any expensive use
are you looking at their properties
you've seen with the Browns are what not
and it also good to see if you have
anything building up unexpectedly
you are key
so next up was talk about some case
studies so what I want to do with this
is i wanna talk about a couple different
scenarios
and measure performance across different
devices and then we'll figure out how we
can work around these performance
problems
and keep the same visual appearance but
you know get the performance gain
we want so first up was talk about a
fictitious photo application
so this is just a simple application
with the table view were each table view
cell has
image and a couple lines attacks and
there's also a small shadow
behind each image so if we take this to
me
measure the performance on an iPhone 5
us using your Julius driver engine
you know we can see that we're hitting
50 frames per second so
that's good 60 frames per second or
target so awesome
ship it not just yet arm
we you know actually love all over
customers and we wanna make sure
everybody has a good user experience
regardless of what device they run
so let's take a look at some of the
other devices that
we support in Iowa City see how to
perform it stacks up
so first off let's look at the iPod
Touch
so I'm curious what's growing feels like
iPod Touch
so you know again we'll take your iPod
Touch and will use the OpenGL ES driver
instrument
and you know sure enough we notice our
frame rate is in the mid-thirties
which is nowhere near our target so that
would be a lousy scrolling experience
and if we look the device utilization we
see that
you know this is like mid to high 70's
home
this strikes me is really kinda odd
because all we're doing is we're
screwing around a couple
image thumbnails and syntax so I don't
really expect this much
GPO activity so was sleeping figure out
what's going on here
so first in 10 is you know
what's in my view our keys or anything
unexpected here so
we use the X could be bucking feature we
grab the view hierarchy
I don't really see anything surprising
here so we've got unity will you sell
with an ImageView
into labels nothing on nothing out of
the ordinary here so
receiving figure out something else so
if we use the coronation instrument
you know remembering that often passes
are expensive what if we have any of
being passes are unexpected
and sure enough this is the slide in a
reference previously
so you know we have of green passes for
the images
which again strikes me as curious let's
take a look at the code and see what
we're doing how are we setting this up
so as I said each each
image from now as shadow how
regenerating
so in this case we were asking for
animation very shadow for us
and we're doing that just by sending
shot a radio show to offset
you know and other properties on
basically what we're doing this
coronation have to figure out what the
shapeless shadow looks like
I mean when it does this it has to take
of green passes to render the content
and then look at the office China love
which is rendered to figure out where
the shadow belongs
and then go through all the actual work
doing the the shuttle itself
is there a better way you know what we
can do to avoid this and it turns out
there's
on if we add the following line to
there's the Shining Path property
arm you know were only scrolling image
from Nelson just basically racks various
sizes
we can usually figure out you know what
the shape of the shadow needs to look
like because again they're all just
you know various sized rectangles are so
if we take advantage of the shadow power
property and at that to our code
then coronation doesn't have to eat up
any offspring passes
to actually generate the shadows so
let's play let's make this change will
add this line
and mystical look with the coronation
instrument to see
if this really did get rid of are often
passes in sure enough it did
so this is great less often passes means
you know left idle time on the Jeep you
so let's take a tray since you were
strong performance looks like
so again looking an iPod Touch will use
the OpenGL ES driver instrument
and we noticed that we are indeed
hitting 60 frames per second
that's great and check out the device
utilization
you know we are now in like the
mid-thirties as opposed to
you know both mid-seventies before are
so this this is great you know less
chief you work means we're hitting a
performance targets
and also means better battery life so
that's a good thing
so awesome can we ship it now arm
not just yet we still have one more
device: we should look at
so with take a look an iPhone 4s and see
how
scrolling is with her new changes now so
we are in fact in 60 frames per second
that's good
and again device utilization seem sane
me a 30 percent is a lot better than
mid-seventies
so to summarize when we had coronation
doing in figure 100 shadow for us
are you notice there's a drop of when
you look at older devices
so the iPhone 5s can handle this no
problem
but as you look at the iPhone 5 the
iPhone 4s the iPhone iPod Touch
you notice that performance drops off
because again all the devices can handle
the amount of green passes the newer
devices can
and when we make this change in take
advantage the shadow path property
you know notice we're hitting our target
everywhere for 60 frames per second
so this was good we can ship this and
happy covers so
after we can finally shipped so
in summary of screen passes are
expensive
you know you always want to use
coronation instruments to find out if
you had any unnecessary
our screen passes and no the API's in
the view hierarchy that you're using
to understand first thing you can do to
avoid in this case
it was using shadow and as always you
know measure performance across multiple
devices
you know you can see what the Jeep you
utilization is by looking at the OpenGL
ES driver internet
and you can see with the CPU is up to by
using the time profiler instrument
and as always you know again know your
view our keynote any hidden costs for
what your
for what you're trying to render and
this is especially true for things we
have inside a people who sells
because we want to ensure that we have
smooth scrolling so it is particularly
important with York you build up in the
people who saw
so next case anyone looking at is a
fictitious contact application
so again this is just a simple table
view we have
you know around from now and we have
online attacks
so not a whole lot going on here so
if we look at performance across
different devices we notice that you
know the iPhone 5s the oven vibrating 60
frames per second
that's good but the iPhone 4s the iPod
Touch
are quite there so you know again we
want everybody to have a good user
experience regardless if the hardware
that are you think so
let's take a look at this and see why
we're not getting the target frame rate
on these devices
so first thing I want to do is take an
open field museum delia's drive
arrangement
and take a trace you know it's always
good to know where you're starting to
the you understand how the changes you
make are affecting performance
so take a trace notice there are
strolling
is you know only in the mid-forties it's
not good
and look at the device realization that
way she was asians really high here
arm thats rather interesting again
because we're just rendering a couple
you know images and syntax so that that
that that would that look suspicious to
me
so we'll take a closer look again you
know we use the coronation instrument
and see if there's any unnecessary or
unexpected of green passes
so you know we noticed the images here
are
incurring often passes so kinda curious
let's take a look at how we are
rendering
and how we are setting up these round
thumbnails
so basically what we're doing is we're
starting off this particular case
we're starting off with Square
thumbnails and we are on the fly
asking for a donation to round them off
for us and we're doing this by using
corner radius unmasking
on so this is worthy of being passes are
coming from so
you know again anything that we can do
to avoid on screen passes
you know will improve performance across
all devices
so is therefore is there a better way to
do this I
ideally if you can't regenerate your
family else round
then that would be great because and you
just be rendering images and you
wouldn't be trying to do all of this
masking having all these often passes on
the fly
so you know if you can pre generate them
that's great
if you can then another trick you could
do is remember this
you I was just away table view with
white people who sells and just you know
white background
so we could fake it in this case you
know we could render the square content
for the square from now and then render
a waiting for to circle on top a bit too
kinda
you know in essence cutaway the rest to
the image on
this will be reducing our on screen
passes but the increasing the amount a
blending
you know but it still turns out to be a
nap performance when because the Jeep
you can plan
a lot faster than it can do on screen
passes so
let's make this change %uh just doing
the
you know faking and see how that affects
performance
so will take an open to release driver
will take tracing your
she leaves driver instrument to refrain
readers and sure enough we're getting 60
frames per second
and notice how much last the device
utilization
so again we're 30 percent verses you
know mid to upper eighties
on one quick word on this on you notice
before
you're actually keep you down but we
weren't actually a hundred percent for
Jeep you time
that's because you know when you have
%ah screen passes there is a idle time
when the Jeep you have to change
contacts or do you switch contacts
so you know you still might be cheap you
down but not quite
hitting 100 percent CPU usage because
the situation with fostering passes so
that's
something to keep in mind so if we
summarize performance across
all the devices you know before we were
just using masking
we notice that there was a point drop
off on all devices
on after we made this change you know
and we made the trade offer doing having
more blending for last on screen passes
we are now hitting 60 frames per second
everywhere which is which is good this
is what we want
so in summary notice there's a theme
here
I often passes are expensive so you know
again you can use coronation to find
where you have any unexpected
of green passes and you know it's always
good to know your API
and what you using do to avoid them on
and of course you know
always measure performance across
different devices you know OpenGL ES
truck OpenGL ES driver instrument will
give you GPUs
activity and time profile arrangement
will show you CPU activity
and again you know always know what your
view hierarchy is you know if you have
any kind of strange
or those are looking performance issues
so overall summary you know what were
the questions below our original
questions and what will be used to
to actually find these answers so here's
a nice little table
you know it that shows what we actually
used to get down to the question so
this is always a good starting point for
figuring out before you start giving new
code
try to figure out what's going on is
good to see what's actually happening on
device
so overall summary on axle
talked about the coronation pipeline and
talked about some rendering concepts
and then talked about new UI kit
features for blur and vibrancy a fact
and then I went over profiling tools and
then this an example
case studies so if you have any
questions feel free to contact you to
the apt remarks evangelist or the
developer tools Angeles
so feel free to contact Jay per day if
you're curious about coordination
documentation
that available online as well as the
devil performs as a great resource
and other related sessions are happening
at the BBC
you might find this interesting so these
might be worth checking out
so thanks and have a wonderful