Hyatt hello and welcome to the for
advanced graphics animations
fly with
ok I'm XO up next over there he will
take over in the middle of the talk
and was to less talky going to cover the
following topics:
the first part will be talking about the
quantitation pipeline and how it
interacts with the application
after this I'm introduce a few rendering
concept that are required to understand
our new two classes you I blow effect
and you have RNC affect
and after this Michael takeover and
walking through existing profiling tools
and demonstrate a few case studies 2282
framework to be looking at and at a
distance talk
from in the hospital to top you looking
at coordination and how to interact with
OpenGL
on some hardware was metal with the
graphics software and then
in the second half of my part I will
talk about you I blow effect on your lap
and the fact that a part of you like it
so let's get started with the
coordination pipeline
so it's all starting the application
the application with a few high keep
either indirectly with you like it or
directly to score animation
one thing was not a thing now is that
the application process
is actually not doing the actual
rendering work for coordination instep
this
few Arceus committed to UN a suburb just
a separate process
and israel also has a server-side
version of coordination that receives
this your lucky
if your keys then rendered visco
animation
miss orange elemental on this trip you
few accelerated
and then one secure key is being
rendered we can finally displayed to the
user
so do you think interesting part is now
haha doesn't look like time by
submitting the application so therefore
I would like to introduce the flow
Ingrid
the vertical lines represent a vertical
blanking interrupts
and and surrendering at 60 Hertz are you
I the distance between doors
article and 16.67 milliseconds saw
the full thing that happens in the
application be receive an event
probably because a touch and therefore
the usual case
but anything to hell in this case is
that the 12 update a few hockey
and this happens in the face that we
call the contraction faces in
Mizuno application at the end of the
faith
if you are keys then and cold and sent
Reynoso
the full thing that are in the summer
and assist is the coldest you are a key
the end the summer then has to wait for
the next piece Inc
in order to made for bus that we get
back what state you can actually render
to
and then it finally stopped issuing draw
calls
to for the Jeep you with OpenGL metal
again then want this is completed
hopefully teach PDP resources not
available we can finally start rendering
and soldier accused of doing is
rendering work hopefully this rendering
rock
finishes before the next we think
because then we can
swap in the frame buffer and showed if
you are key to the user
as you can see this very steps spent
over mood for frames in this case it's
three frames
and let's say we would now lost continue
with the next 10 leavin to commit
transaction
after-hours played that we would only be
able to her and that when he heard not
at 60 Hertz
so therefore what we're doing is BR
overlaying
the stages so in parallel with the drugs
that you can see here we will
do the next 10-20 vent and the event
commit transaction and so we end up with
this following step diagram in next few
slight I would like to
focus on you commit transaction stage
because that's what effect the
application developers the most
so let's take a look at commit
transaction
commit transaction itself consists of
four fails the first base this delay of
faith
does let me set up the fuse then the
next phase is to display faced this is a
draw to fuse
the sub faces steep repair commit face
levy
to some additional 20 mission work and
the last faces
maybe actually pick it up the Laos and
seventh-rounder so
in the comet let's look in detail at
those four phases
first the layout faith and layout faced
the layout the fuse alright I invoked
there's a few creation happens doesn't
let me at least
sure keep stats a few and is very
popular content and to some lightweight
database lookup something like this
because we don't want to stall here too
long
like this could be for example localized
strings because we need him at this
point in order to put
to a labor layout because of this the
face is usually Cebu bond oil bound
the second phase of the display faith a
disadvantage or contents the store
activity overridden audio stream drawing
one thing what both noting here is that
this
face is actually Cebu on a rebound
because the rendering is so for us to
rise to use here
cool graphics was rendering and Soviet
leaders rendering with
CG context so the point is here that we
want to minimize the work that we do
with the quad graphics to avoid the
large performance in the stage
next faithful to prepare faced this is
the image decoding image conversion
happens
image tickling should be straightforward
the 75th any images and if you are a key
and
this trip XO PNG's I getting the call it
at this point
image conversion it's not quite so
straightforward what happens here is
that we might have images that I love
politics cheated on that is not
supported by the GP you
and definitely need to convert these
images a good example is could be
indexed bitmaps leave want to avoid
certain image formats
a in the last phase the cliff face the
package up the layers and send him to
run the server
this process is because if you have to
trade with really a tree and is
expensive their trees complex or do
that's why we want to keep the late
response as possible
to make sure that that it's part of the
faces is as efficient as can be
so let's take a look at this works
animation animations themself
three-stage process two of those happen
in fact application
at the last eight happens on the run the
server the first eight is very crickets
where we create animation update of your
key this happens usually was the
animators duration:
animations Meffert then the second stage
is that we
prepared committee animation this is
well able to fuse been called and
direct and that promise of familiar and
it is because
is out for fails we are just looking at
the only difference here is that with
the committee don't just committed if
you are a key
recommit as well D animation and it's a
reason because he would like to hand off
the animation work to render so I'll so
that we can
continue to update your animations
result using inter-process communication
to talk back to the application of
awesome backed with the application
so that's what the efficiency reasons
saw let's take a look at a few rendering
conflict the required to have
understand and you visual effects that
yet providing you with what I was 8
so it is part of a talker and covering
three areas first time with mentoring is
how or GP was work
then I'm going to introduce the concept
of render passes because on effects use
mood for in the path of
and then I'm doing a first example by
showing you home asking works is when a
path
so let's take a look at times rendering
was famous for entering the screen is
split into title and by and pixels
have put your screen shot together and
all it that the grits bacon he actually
bought it has
sites would be like the title virtual so
that it fits into
into the SLC cash and the ID is here
that the geometry split 2-2 tie buckets
and I would like to demonstrate this a
using the phone taken as an example
as you can see the full I can spend
smokes but I'll and
before I can tell has read it as a
seattle-area and the CLA NCAA israel's
two triangles and if you look at the two
triangles
they're still spending multiple
triangles earth in with the tiles
and thought if you were doing now it
will not stop splitting up those trying
of
many committed but I'll so that each
type can be rented individually
the idea fear the beard do with process
novel who geometry so at some point we
have to do a tree for each to collect it
and then we can make decisions
on what pics a visible and then decide
but picks a chair to run three-run each
pixel shader when he wants
pics obviously if you do banning this
doesn't quite work
then we still have to you problem
overdrawn
so let's take a look at what type up
when Rick passes I'll
so little few obligation has but if
you're keeping score animation
it's committed to render so and comic
when mission you call it it
ans now it needs to end it and it will
use OpenGL metal
in this light I'm just saying metal for
simplicity trend it
and it will generate with openelec
amount of it is then submitted to GP you
at the GQ oops receive this command
perform and stop doing it work
the first thing that you do is what text
processing is that about the chat around
and ID issue that could transform all
about this isn't a screen space at this
stage
so that we can do tend to the second
stage with those bitches get retailing
many actually tell the geometry fought
advocates
and this part of the stage is called but
I left side you will be able to find
in the instruments in the open OpenGL ES
driver instrument
under tell you to as Asian
the output of the state's is written and
something called a parent about from
and the next stage is not starting
millions that
the leave made no answer or geometry is
processed and sits in the palatable for
or into the pan with a purpose for
because the problem is is a public bus
will be have to flush it
and it's actually performance it on
because then we need to start over text
processing
and gets front load the pic social
network
and next set say that stages as a set up
extra stage
the state is actually call to render a
stage and you can find again in the
instrument so popular private school
and the name when the rate was Asian and
the output of the stage is written to
something called
you in the buffer K
so that's take a look at a practical
example by looking at masking
let's assume of your keys way to go the
command buffer is
sitting mister review and you can stop
processing
so the full thing happens in the fourth
pastors that be rendered the
delay I'm off to a texture in this case
with this camera icon
them in the second path P render the
their content to a texture
and in this case with this kinda blew
material
and then in the last part that he called
it compositing possibly apply to master
the content texture
and composite to rate the result is
green and up is dis light blue camera
icon
saw let's take a look at you I blew a
factor for those that don't know
you I blow effect can be used with you
as a visual effect few and
does not public API since I was 8 it
basically allows you to use to growth
that introduces I was having and be
providing you with three different law
stuff that I want to demonstrate your
took this regular i worth wallpaper and
apply to three blocks that that you have
to it
X the light light and dark a
so let's take a look how does look
performance wife
I'm using Google Docs time as an example
for rendering process the doc style
actually using the law of the model
friend apostles and
the I think your mind number in the past
depends on how to be different not
imitation
for certain puff puff up via
for the fourth past year end of the
content that is going to be blood
then in the second part of be captured a
confident on scale it
the downscale depends on the hardware so
in disc fly to cap it at a certain sites
with the readable
then in like the past the apply the
actual blog arisen which
separated so we do first horizontal and
vertical
does actually a con brio optimization be
quick to listen thing a path but let's
assume our
blower car would be eleven by 11 this
would mean we would need to read had a
twenty one samples per pixel
by separating its we only need to read
11 samples per pixel
cage past so after the 4th path we have
tooth
love horizontally and vertically blot
small tiny area
and so what's left in the last part is
that need to upscale display or intended
in this case we end up there with our
doctor
so that looks fine but let's take a look
how this looks like performance wise
so what it as a test I critical full
screen layout and
applied to your bluff effect to it and
measure the performance and a staggering
can see three roles the first role we
present a tile activity
the second row interactivity and to the
last row I put in the black interrupt
you can actually see you
what our friend boundaries are and again
be running at 60 votes are you I
so time you have 16.67 milliseconds
so let's focus on a on a single frame
if you can see a first look here the
first Tyler path is happening before the
first when their path and that's because
the Thailand supporters all geometries
with emphasize what we just saw in the
previous lights
so let's go quickly what passes against
the footpath is the
content past time for this penance
really depends really on if you are a
key
in this case it's just a simple image so
it might take longer in use in
real-world
you I'm then in the second panel 3
downscale
and capture the content it's actually
fairly fast
at his pre-match consul cost then
the surpasses yours on to blow it again
constant calls for to pre fast because
the
only played on a very small area and
then in the fourth past
me to refer to comply or again very fast
and
we end up with a blow to region and then
in the last past the upscale
and tint people are
the one thing you will notice now others
gaps between those passes left my time
here in Orange
and does get I actually did you idle
time and to happen because we do here
rent a context switch
here on this John a jeep you and this
can actually quite at up quite quickly
because the time spent here as I times
per possible to your point want to
your point to a few seconds Saunders
cases for passes we have got at the time
of 0.4 to 0.8 milliseconds
which is a good thing if you can track
of our 16.67 milliseconds
let's take a look out a bill performs on
the various devices um
so again this is the full screen blow to
use that I used before and
admitted as well on iPad 3 such
innovation
and as you can see the iPod Touch
generation performs much worse than the
iPad app
in the induced in the in the case of
text the lead lawyer the timing
is 18 point 15 me second full week and
render 60% of this type of Braun iPad 2
a.m.
and polite and actually a around
fourteen point five milliseconds
which leads us about 20 seconds for you
i've which is not really enough a
rendering any compelling you I
for the decision be made on I was 7
corey was that we would is able to blow
on certain devices
and the iPod Touch generation is one of
the few bystanders this
the former on about situation changes to
this
basically just apply it in play on top
so that we can actually do believe he is
the same as
with possibly effects
saw and to elaborate on what devices we
don't want to be only 22 tinting
on the iPad 2 and iPad such generational
be just apply the tent and be skipped
the blow steps
on iPad 4th generation iPod air iPad
Mini iPad Mini
was richard is playing or iPhones and
the iPod Touch do both the Bryant
attending
soul in summary for the you I visual
effect few with you I play fact
you have no effect it would have on
screen passes depending on the style
why don't you weep sorry drawn so it's
actually fine if you have
a large blur area and you don't update
content behind it because we only apply
to once
effect is very costly so the United can
be easily Jeep you belong to
so therefore you should keep the balance
of the few s smallest possible
and therefore as well he should make
sure to budget for defect
saw next let's take a look at the UI
violence effect
you haven't the effect is a is an
effective use on top of the bro and it's
meant to be useful content which can
make sure that content than out and
doesn't go unnoticed Bros
so let's take a look how does look like
at this hour three blocks that again
and let's assume the bonds to render the
camera taken from I'm asking example
from before
on top and this could look like this if
you don't use any balance effect and as
you can see with the lights style
there might be too large booty issues
because the great stuff leading
out so what decided to us that we edit
some
if I'm into effect and the primacy
effect and at the punch through and then
you end up with nice private look
saw let's take a look how does affect
performance
so back to or in the past agro
the first five passes are in this case
for the doctor or the broadcast
and then in a six pack of beer and other
their content to a texter
and then in the final compositing pass
we take the
their content and apply filter and
composited on top of the blow
don't be fooled here from for the cause
actually quite expensive and I wanna
shoulders and next couple of flights
so this is our order and I come from
before the the the steps for to blow and
lets at on now the steps for the
vibrancy effect
so in perfect a meeting in here from
content that is ok amer-i-can
and damn obviously the cost for this
past depends on what you're entering
their
but very few very few have key looks
like
and then last past the apply the filter
and as you can see for the cause
actually very expand the fifth to
actually the most expensive path we have
here
one thing to keep in mind here is that I
apply to balance the effect of which can
carry on
the recommendation is to not apply to
pharmacy effect with with Marion stat to
only apply it to us more content areas
to avoid to tissues performance penalty
about and his life a the did you have no
spam or caps because you have more in
the past us or the G two at a time
has increased as well if not six caps
and this can add up to 0.6 pool 21.2 mi
seconds
by the time about you
saw let's take a look how does look on
my part such innovation and
iPad a.m. does the base cost from before
4.59 many seconds for the iPod situation
we don't blow
and a different times for the iPad and
depending on the blast I'll
solar at the on and what we can see is
for the fourth benefactors step your
spending on iPad saturation about 27 to
26 milliseconds just
for applying the vibrancy effect on the
iPad
air we spend about 17.48 me second
flexalite style and
around 40 milliseconds for light and oxo
you don't have a lot of time left on a
gp2 any other rendering
I mean 22nd from the best case here
sought to emphasize again we should
really restrictive I'm into effect on a
small area to avoid is huge
keep your head so in summary
the UI vibrancy effect at to a screen
pass earth
2 I'm into effect use expensive company
is an expensive compositing for the full
content
therefore we should all you survive into
effect on the small regions
arm again like the blonde only to return
to read wrong
and you I'm into effect is very costly
on all devices
so with Les Mis the Blue Earth you I can
easily be G view bound
keep the bounds of the fuse a small as
possible I make sure to
budget for defects so
next I would like to give a couple of
optimization techniques take the
techniques on the way I want is worth
relation
isolation can be used to composite which
once was the Jeep you
this can be neighbors they should trust
their eyes property on a clar and
a few things to keep in mind when doing
this first
extra of composite a creative in the
update the content solutions
only used it for static content secondly
you should I use it because the cache
size for us relations limited to 25.5
times of the screen size
so if you start setting dress dress
property of on last part of your
few hockey you might lower the cash over
and over and end up as a lot of
additional
ski passes last a
arrest was impressed with images I
because from the couch if they are you
someone how many seconds
so you wanna make sure that he used is
only for images are consciously use them
up for
entry please let me just because then
you will Inc you every time in a screen
pass
so typically use cases are to avoid
ridge or redrawing expensive
effect of that the content so you could
rest rice for example a blow
and the other thing is to have what we
doing a complex Trk so we could
breast rice for few are key in composite
is on top of a blog wonderbra
so the last thing I have here is
capacity
capacity can be disabled list the last
capacity property ICAO
a capacity but actually in terms of kim
possible a it's not a pixels means
your past the property is not equal 1.0
and for last long trip the contents
that means that if China Laos or a
background image and
but isn't on the status of your account
to be composited before it's being
blended
and if America nations with turn it off
it's not needed
be very careful is this was this I would
like to rent or to Mike
so I am i crossing software engineer on
the island on Steam
and the first thing on talk about are
tools so
before I get into tools though I do want
to mention prompt investigation lighter
so basically what are the questions
running through my head when
I encounter performance issue and want
to start tracking down the source about
so first thing I want to know is what is
the frame right
you know it's always good to know where
you're starting performance wise so that
you can gauge how the changes you make
are affecting performance
so our goal is always 60 frames per
second we want to ensure that we have
smooth scrolling and I smooth animations
to provide a good user experience so our
target should always be 60 frames per
second next up
I wanna know are we see peerage if you
down you know obviously the
slow realization the better because will
let us had our performance targets
and also give us better battery life
netting 10
other any unnecessary is there any
unnecessary CP rendering
so basically are we overriding drummer
somewhere where we really shouldn't be
you know kind understanding what
rendering and how rendering
we want the Jeep you to do is much add
this as make sense next thing on a No
is do we have too many offspring passes
as actual pointed out previously
of green passes basically give the Jeep
you idle time because I have to contact
switches
so we want to have fewer offspring
passes fewer the better
next up I wanna know is there too much
blending in the Y
on we obviously want to do last funding
because blending
is more expensive for the Jeep you to do
then rendering
as normal a player so responding better
next I want to know is are there any
strange image formats were sizes
basically want to avoid on-the-fly
conversion image formats
as I 2.0 previously if you are
rendering an image that is not in the
color for me that's not supported by the
Jeep you
then it has to be converted by the CPU
and so we want to try and wait anything
on the fly like that
next up on an order any expensive user a
fax
learn vibrancy are awesome but we want
to make sure that we're using them
sparingly in a way
that will give us the sprawling
performance that we want and lastly
oh noes or anything unexpected in the
view hierarchy on you know
if you have a situation we are
constantly adding removing views you
know you could introduce a bike
accidentally that's a
you know insert a nation forgets to
remove them or
you know your adding use your harking
forgetting to remove them you know you
wanna make sure the only have the views
that you really need
mom you know in your heart key because
you want to avoid excessive CPU use a
back forty
so now let's get into some other tools
that will give us the answers to these
questions
so first up on talk about instruments
and particularly will talk about
are the coronation instrument in the
OpenGL ES driver instrument
then I will say a few things about the
simulator that you can do with color
debug options
and I will briefly talk about a new
feature in Xcode
for life you debugging device so first
up
a if you want instruments and select the
coronation temple
that will give you a document that
contains
a coronation instrument and a time
profiler instrument if you select the
coronation instrument
you can then choose which is the six you
wanna show
in this case it's only frames per second
so will choose that and then when you
take a trace it will show you your frame
rate so you can see in the column here
shows you the frames per second
for each interval this trace was running
for you see this in sample intervals
likewise wanna see what the CPU's doing
are you can select the time profiler
instrument and so you slept
and you can then see an aggregate the
call stack
what the CPU was doing while you were
taking a trace
so this is where you would look for you
know I am i overriding drive rack too
much spending too much time in a
threatening
thread doing things that I shouldn't be
next up let's talk about some other
color debug options that are part of the
coronation instrument so if you select
the coronation instrument
you can see the color debug options over
here on the right
so let's go through what those are first
up
we have color-blind players and so this
will tent this will 10 players
green better appcake and two players red
have to be blinded
as we said previously you know layers
that have to be blended is more work for
the Jeep you
and so you ideally want to see less red
you know and more green but there are
gonna be cases where you can avoid it
on for example in this particular case
we have a white people view
with my table who sells and we noticed
that our labels
are you know how many people ended here
so if we made our labels in this case
opaque then we wouldn't have to worry
about doing the blending
on so that would be one opposition we
can make in this particular case
next up color hit screens and missus red
this shows you how you're using or
abusing
on the should Rasta rise property on see
a liar
so what this will do is it will it will
tense cash it's green cache misses red
so you know as a 2.0 previously keep in
mind that your cache size is only two
and a half sine
times the size of the screen and items
are affected from the cash if they're
not used than a hundred milliseconds
so you know it's good to use this
particular coloring about option to see
how the cow you're utilizing the cash
with
you know what you have such a rush to
respond
when you first launcher app you're going
to see a lot of flashing red because you
obviously have to render it once before
to be cash
but after that you don't wanna see a
whole lotta flashes a red because
you know as we have previously you know
any thing you're doing is going to incur
of green passes
you have to render a and then stick it
in cash
so next item is color copied images
on you as we said before if an image is
in a format as in the color format
that the chief you can't work directly
with it will have to be converted by the
CPU
so in this particular example you know
this is a simple
far photo browsing arm were just getting
images from an online source more not
really checking her size
or their or their color format on its
own if it were case we're getting images
that are 16 bits per component
and so you can see that they are tinted
sign here that is telling us that these
images had to be converted by the CPU
and commit phase
before they can actually be rendered so
you know for this
particular case we don't want to do this
on the fly because I will fax growing
performance
on with so you can beforehand
you know convert your images to the size
and color format you're expecting
and it's best to do this in you in the
background so you're not eating up time
on the main thread while you're trying
to scroll or doing other things
so the next option is color misaligned
images this will tent
images yellow that are being scaled and
10 images purple
that are not pixel on you know as it had
previously it's always good to make sure
that images are in the color format and
size that you want
because the last thing you want to be
doing is you know doing conversions and
scaling
on the fly while you're scrolling so the
same prince will be applied
in the previous light will also apply
here to get rid of the scaling
why so next up
is color of green yellow so this will 10
layers yellow
based on the number of green passes that
each layer
occurs so be more yellow you see the
more of green passes we have
if you notice the NAP are and the
toolbar are tinted yellow
that's because there are pillars with
these layers that are
actually learn the concept behind it so
we expect those but I do find it curious
that the images
are having offering passes so we'll take
a look at that later on the presentation
and see how to work around this issue
so next is collar opened your fast path
blue
and so what this will do is this will 10
layers blue that are being planted by
the display hardware
this is actually a good thing you wanna
see because if we have content with
being bent blinded by the display
hardware
the Nets less work for the Jeep you have
to do so in this case if you see
something show up in blue
that's a good thing on
last option is flash up the two regions
and so what this will do is it will
flash
her to the screen yellow that are being
updated on this particular example is
with the clocks out that shit
in iowa's are you notice that the yellow
regions here
are the second-hand ideally you only
want to see
part to the screen flashing yellow the
you're actually updating again because
that means less work for the
GP you must work the CPU so if you turn
this on you don't want to see
a lot a flashing yellow unless you
actually are updating
that much of the screen so in summary
are some questions that the coronation
instrument will help you get to
he will help you figure with free
murders is there any unnecessary CP
rendering because
it does include the time profiler
instrument
and also with the colored by the options
you can see are things like other too
many offering passes how much when
things going on
and you have an East strange image
format your size is that not expecting
and so one additional point on corn
options some
love the color and options are available
in the eye with simulator so you can see
the example here
a few things to point out with this the
colors might be slightly different
because the version CA that's running
inside the simulators actually person at
the aid atlanta with 10 on iowa's
so if you see any discrepancies always
trust what you see on device
because that your customers actually
gonna be using arm
so this is a good future because you can
have you like for your testing team go
off
and poke around your app and see if you
have any unexpected offering passes or
any conversion or anything that looks
suspicious
so next topic on talk about the OpenGL
ES driver in
so if you watch instruments and select
the OMG oh yes driver template
that will give you a document that
contains the OpenGL ES driver instrument
and and and the time profiler instrument
so if you select the OpenGL ES driver
instrument
you can choose from which the CITIC
Pacific's you want to actually collect
when I'm investigating things I tend to
go for
device utilization which will show you
how much the Jeep use in use during the
truth
i render anti realization does
correspond to the render
entirely phases that axles I talked
about previously
and then of course the coronation frames
per second because I want to know what
the actual frame rate is that we're
seeing
so if you take a trace
and then select the coroner the OpenGL
yes driver
instrument you can then look at the
statistics
NC throughput for example in this case
you know we are getting 60 frames per
second
and our device utilization is in like
the mid
lower 70's so you know depends on what
you are your rendering so you know you
may want to investigate this
gold like that all boils down to what
you're actually rendering for this case
and likewise since we have the time
overall arrangement here you can see
with the CPU's doing
so if you select that you can then again
look at an aggregate cost tax
what's going on in the CPU during this
time to this is always useful because
you can highlight certain regions
you know if you noticed that you're
dropping free in 3 knows a lot of
activity you can zoom in and see
what the CPU was doing during a
particular time
so in summary with the OpenGL ES driver
instrument you know this will give you
answers to questions like What is your
frame rate
are you can see what the CPU and CPU
were doing and you can also use the time
profiler instrument
to see other any unnecessary CPU
rendering going on
so next up is a really cool feature that
was added Xcode
for live you debugging on device so if
you open your project in Xcode
and then run it and then click the
Follow button on the bottom here
what will actually do is it will grab
the view hierarchy of the device
and you can then go poking around in a
few Archaean see what exact use are
in your you why so this is always good
because you can expect to see as I said
if there's anything unexpected there
you know maybe something is building up
you have a legal thing animations or
something
or constraints so this is good to
actually see what the view hierarchy is
on your device
versus say what you conceptually think
it is when you're writing your co
if you select an individual item arm or
noonan individual view you can look at
the properties for its ok in this case
we selected the UI view
and you can see details about what
property in image is currently being
rendered by that you
so summary for exclude you debugging
this will let you poke around in your
view hierarchy see what's actually being
rendered on device
you know which is helpful because you
can see if you have any expensive use
are you looking at their properties yes
in with the Browns are what not
and it also good to see if you have
anything building up unexpectedly
you are key
so next up was talk about some case
studies so what I want to do with this
is i wanna talk about a couple different
scenarios
and measure performance across different
devices and then we'll figure out how we
can work around these performance
problems
and keep the same visual appearance but
you know get the performance green
we want so first up was talk about a
fictitious photo application
so this is just a simple application
with the table view were each table view
cell has
image and a couple lines attacks and
there's also a small shadow
behind each image so if we take this and
we
measure the performance on an iPhone 5
us using your computer yes driver engine
you know we can see that we're hitting
60 frames per second so
that's good 60 frames per second is our
target so awesome
ship it not just yet arm
we you know actually love all over
customers and we wanna make sure
everybody has a good user experience
regardless of what the bikes there on
so let's take a look at some of the
other devices that
we support in Iowa City see how to
perform it stacks up
so first off let's look at the iPod
Touch
so I'm curious what's growing feels like
a iPod Touch
so you know again we'll take your iPod
Touch and will use the OpenGL ES driver
instrument
and you know sure enough we notice our
frame rate is in the mid-thirties
which is nowhere near our target so that
would be a lousy scrolling experience
and if we look the device utilization we
see that
you know this is like mid to high 70's
home this strikes me is really kinda odd
because all we're doing is we're
screwing around a couple
image thumbnails and syntax so I don't
really expect this much
GPO activity so what sleeping figure out
what's going on here
so first thing I want to know is you
know
what's in my view our keys or anything
unexpected here so
we use the X could be bucking feature we
grab the view hierarchy
I don't really see anything surprising
here so we've got unity will you sell
with an ImageView
into labels nothing on nothing out of
the ordinary here so
receiving figure out something else so
if we use the coronation instrument
you know remembering that often passes
are expensive let's see if we had
any of being passes or unexpected and
sure enough this is the slide in a
reference
previously so you know we have of green
passes for the images
which again strike me as curious let's
take a look at the code and see what
we're doing how are we setting this up
so as I said each each
image from now as shadow how
regenerating
so in this case we were asking for
animation to generate shadow for us
and we're doing that just by sending
shot a radio shadow of that
you know and other properties on
basically what we're doing this
coronation have to figure out what the
shapeless shadow looks like
on me when it does this it has to take
on screen passes to render the content
and then look at the office channel
footage is rendered to figure out where
the shadow belongs
and then go through all the actual work
doing the the shuttle itself
is there a better way you know something
we can do to avoid this and it turns out
there's
on if we add the following line so
there's the shuttle Path property
on you know were only scrolling image
from Nelson just basically racks various
sizes
we can easily figure out you know what
the shape of the shadow needs to look
like because again they're all just
you know various sized rectangles are so
if we take advantage of the shadow power
property and at that to our Code
then coronation doesn't have to eat up
any offspring passes
to actually generate the shadows so
let's play let's make this change will
add this line
and let's take a look with the
coronation instrument to see
if this really did get rid of our
offering passes in sure enough it did
so this is great less often passes means
you know left idle time on the Jeep you
so let's take a tray since you were
strong performance looks like
so again looking an iPod Touch will use
the OpenGL ES driver instrument
and we noticed that we are indeed
hitting 60 frames per second
that's great an check out the device
utilization
you know we are now in like the
mid-thirties as opposed to
you know both at the mid-seventies
before
so this this is great you know less
chief you work means we're hitting a
performance targets
and also means better battery life so
that's a good thing
so awesome can we ship it now arm
not just yet we still have one more
device: we should look at
so let's take a look an iPhone 4s and
see how
scrolling is with the new changes now so
we are in fact in 50 frames per second
that's good
and again device utilization seem sane
me a 30 percent is a lot better than
mid-seventies
so to summarize when we had coronation
doing in figuring out 100 shadow for us
are you notice there's a drop of when
you look at older devices
so the iPhone 5s can handle this no
problem
but as you look at the iPhone 5 the
iPhone 4s the iPhone iPod Touch
you notice that performance drops off
because again all the devices can handle
the amount of green passes the newer
devices can and when we make this change
in take advantage
the shadow path property you know notice
we're hitting our target everywhere for
60 frames per second
so this is good we can ship this and
happy covers so
are so we can finally shipped so
in summary of green passes are expensive
you know you always want to use
coronation instruments to find out if
you had any unnecessary
our screen passes and no the API's in
the view hierarchy that you're using
to understand first things you can do to
avoid in this case it was using shut up
and as always you know measure
performance across multiple devices
you know you can see what the Jeep you
utilization is by looking at the OpenGL
ES driver internet and you can see with
the CPU is up to by using the time
profile arrangement
and as always you know again know your
view our keynote any hidden costs for
what your
for what you're trying to render and
this is especially true for things we
have inside a people who sells
because we want to ensure that we have
smooth scrolling so it is particularly
important with the park you build up in
a table
so next case anyone looking at is a
fictitious contact application
so again this is just a simple table
view we have
you know around from now and we have
online attacks so
not a whole lot going on here so
if we look at performance across
different devices we notice that you
know the iPhone 5s Nov 15 reading 60
frames per second
that's good but the iPhone 4s the iPod
Touch are quite
there so you know again we want
everybody to have a good user experience
regardless of the hardware that are you
think so
let's take a look at this and see why
we're not getting the target frame rate
on these devices
so first thing I want to do is take an
open field museum delia's driver
instrument
and take a trace you know it's always
good to know where you're starting to
the you understand how the changes you
make are affecting performance
so take a trace notice that are
scrolling
is you know only in the mid-forties it's
not good
and look at the device realization that
way she was Asian is really high here
arm thats rather interesting again
because we're just rendering a couple
you know images and syntax so that that
that that would that look suspicious to
me
so we'll take a closer look again you
know we use the coronation instrument
and see if there's any unnecessary or
unexpected of green passes
so you know we noticed the images here
are
incurring often passes so kinda curious
let's take a look at how we are
rendering
and how we are setting up these round
thumbnails
so basically what we're doing is we're
starting off this particular case
we're starting off with Square
thumbnails and we are on the fly
asking for a donation to round them off
for us and we're doing this by using
corner radius and masking
on so this is worthy of being passes are
coming from so
you know again anything that we can do
to avoid on screen passes you know
will improve performance across all
devices
so is therefore is there a better way to
do this I
ideally if you can't regenerate your
family else round
then that would be great because and you
just be rendering images and you
wouldn't be trying to do all of this
masking having all these often passes on
the fly
so you know if you can pre generate them
that's great
if you can then another trick you could
do is remember this
you I was just away table view with
white people who sells and just you know
white background
so we could fake it in this case you
know we could render the square content
for the square from hell and then render
a waiting for to circle on top a bit too
kinda
you know in essence cutaway the rest to
the image on
this will be reducing our on screen
passes but the increasing the amount a
blending
you know but it still turns out to be a
net performance when because the Jeep
you can plan
a lot faster than it can do on screen
passes so
let's make this change %uh just doing
the you know faking it
and see how that affects performance so
will take an open to release driver with
a trace using your purely driver
instrument to refrain readers
and sure enough we're getting 60 frames
per second and notice how much
last the device utilization so again
we're 30 percent
verses you know mid to upper eighties on
one quick word on this
on you notice before we were actually
keep you down but we weren't actually a
hundred percent for Jeep you time
that's because you know when you have
%ah screen passes there is a idle time
when the Jeep you have to change
contacts or do you switch contacts
so you know you still might be cheap you
bound but not quite
hitting 100 percent CPU usage because
the situation with offering passes so
that's
something to keep in mind so if we
summarize
performance across all the devices you
know before we
were just using masking we notice that
there was a performance drop off on all
devices
on after we made this change you know
and we made the trade offer doing having
more blending for last on screen passes
we are now hitting 60 frames per second
everywhere which is which is good this
is what we want
so in summary notice there's a theme
here
I often passes are expensive so you know
again you can use coronation to find
where you have any unexpected
on screen passes and you know it's
always good to know your API
used to using do to avoid them on and of
course you know
always measure performance across
different devices you know OpenGL ES
OpenGL ES driver instrument will give
you GPUs
activity and time profiler instrument
will show you CPU activity
and again you know always know what your
view hierarchy is you know if you have
any kind of strange
or was are looking performance issues
so overall summary you know what were
the questions below our original
questions and what will be used to
to actually find these answers so here's
a nice little table
you know it that shows what we actually
used to get down to the question so
this is always a good starting point for
figuring out before you start digging
your code try to figure out what's going
on it's good to see what's actually
happening on device
so overall summary axle
talked about the coronation pipeline and
talk about some rendering concepts
and then talked about new UI kit
features for
blur and vibrancy a fact and then I went
over profiling tools
and then this an example case studies
so if you have any questions feel free
to contact either the app framework
evangelist or the developer tools
Angeles
so feel free to contact Jay per day if
you're curious about coordination
documentation
that available online as well as the
devil performs as a great resource
and other related sessions are happening
at the BBC you might find it interesting
so these might be worth checking out
so thanks and have a wonderful