good morning everyone and welcome the
session 5
what's new with core audio I'm the first
MC on the mic today my name story
and a we have been very busy we have a
lot of interesting things to share with
you today
we're going to start off by talking with
about some enhancements that we've made
the core MIDI
and how that affects you and your app's
and we'll move on to entrap audio views
and then we will have a large section on
the new improved and enhanced
a V Foundation audio and that will
include
talk about our unit manager AV audio
session
some utility classes and at last bullet
point there AB audio engine is such
a large topic that it gets the session
all to itself directly following this
one in the same room starting at 10:15
a.m.
so without further ado let's talk about
what's new with core MIDI
if you have a studio a music studio
that you use to make music it may look
something
like this so maybe there's a Mac in the
centre ovett or nihilist device also
very capable
be the center of her studio and
connected to it may be several USB MIDI
devices
controllers breakout boxes that are
connected by a5 pendant a legacy
quit met miss questions musical
instruments
and also you may have a network session
going well beginning and I O S
8 and Mac OS 10 yosemite your studio
can start to look like this so imagine
after making a very quick
Bluetooth connection sitting down on a
couch on the other side of the room in
your studio
and controlling all your music that's
what you'll be able to do
with MIDI over Bluetooth so starting I
was a
and an Mac OS 10 yosemite you'll be able
to send
and receive MIDI data over Bluetooth Low
Energy connections
on any device or Mac to his native
Bluetooth Low Energy support
the connection to establish a secure
meaning the pairings and forced
no one can connect your device is
without your explicit consent
and after the connection is established
it just appears as an ordinary MIDI
device any application that knows how to
communicate with the MIDI device
can talk to so to talk a little bit more
about how this connection works over
Bluetooth I want to talk about the two
key roles
involved in a Bluetooth connection
there's the central
and the peripheral you already have some
familiarity with this
maybe not with these names you can be
your central is like your
iPhone and your Prof role is like your
Bluetooth earpiece the peripherals job
is to
become discoverable and say hey I can be
something you can connect to me
so for Bluetooth many peripheral side
will advertise the many capabilities
will say hey I can do maybe you can
connect to me now and then that side
weights
the central can scan for device
that says they can do many and then
establish a connection
after that Bluetooth connection has been
established
MIDI data can be shuttled by
directionally between both cities
now in order to have a Bluetooth
connection you have to have one central
you have to have one peripheral
and we allow max anti-western my sister
play i the role
so you can connect Mac to Mac I West I O
S
Mac Diallo s and vice versa so
what does this mean for you and your
application if you are writing a Mac OS
and application the good news is
you are already read a already ready
this is the MIDI studio panel from audio
MIDI setup with some
sure you're all familiar with if you
look there you'll see a new icon
the Bluetooth configuration icon you
double click that icon
you're going to get a new window and
this window
will allow you to play either the
central Upper for all
if you look at kind of the top third out
the window you'll see where
there's a button this is advertising
click advertise to become discoverable
as
fresh air that's a name that you can
modify fresh Air's the name my
Mac Book Air because it's fresh then
the bottom two-thirds ovett is the
central view if someone is advertising
hey i can't. MIDI
it will show up in the bottom you click
Connect to establish the connection
the parent will happen and then a new
MIDI device will appear in the setup
the any application that uses many
devices can see and communicate with
now on I'll West there is no audio MIDI
setup so how do you manage your budget
many connections
you be using Newco radio kit view
controllers
there are two new Corradi ok if you
control it that you can adhere
application
one of them that allows you to play the
role the central which means use can
connect
and another that allows you to play the
role of peripheral which means you
advertise and wait
if you establish a connection between
two devices over budget meeting
and they're not communicating for a
while on their unused by the application
after several minutes we will terminate
a Bluetooth connection to say
our so what is all this look like and
practice
I'm gonna show you a short UI demo how
users
would use this and their studios
okay I've got my demo machine ready here
and what I'm going to do is I'm going to
launch Audio MIDI setup
this is the audio window will close this
and we'll go to the many wonder
up you notice your name anyone know
there's this new Bluetooth configuration
panel so if I double clicked this then I
will see
that they're currently no advertising
that is many devices
I want my Mac to play the role a central
so I'm going to wait for someone to
become available to connect to
and I'm going to use my iPad for that
so here's my iPad and this is a little
test application that we wrote to
implement the
did Corradi ok if you controllers that
talked about earlier
I'm going to get advertisement set up in
this will give me the peripheral view
you look at the top has to the name this
iPad areas i pair MIDI
I want to change its name like it at the
eye but I'm okay with that name
and then I will say advertise in any
service
now after I am advertising the MIDI
back on a Mac OS 10 missing you'll see i
pair media showed up here
by click Connect after a few moments
you'll see a new device appear in the
MIDI setup
and when to launch main stage because
mainstage Cana
receive MIDI notes and playback audio
go into performance mood
okay so be confessing her I don't like
he's
but I do have an application the place
he's really well
called arpeggio non-pro so I'm going to
launch that
and I'm going to use it to send MIDI
data
over to the main stage 3
okay now one thing I want to do really
quickly here
is check my connection status that debt
left it
inactive for quite a while here so I'm
going to
go back and make myself advertise on
more time
so now
this is live many data being sent over
Bluetooth
I can get there by a little louder
please thank you
so from want to do this preset Scott
epic fall
and it is epic you
so that's Bluetooth being sent over MIDI
and also descends not only the
controller data
but it also sends the sec stated that
you may have
or any other type of MIDI a few final
words
before I turn the mike over this
Bluetooth that
being able to connect bluetooth many
connections will work on both West in
Yosemite
NIOS 8 using those view controllers that
I told about
net told you about and will work on any
Mac iPhone or iPad that has native
Bluetooth Low Energy support
so now I'm gonna tell you which ones
those are from Max
any Mac that was manufactured in 2012 or
later
and a mixed bag max that were released
in 2011 also have native Bluetooth Low
Energy support
for the iPhone the iPhone 4s and greater
have Bluetooth Ellie
for the iPad the first iPad with Retina
display has Leen the ones from that
point and all
iPad Mini 780 Bluetooth Low Energy
support so this will work on all other
systems
also the connection is really low that
low latency it's very sensitive
and the Bluetooth belly band with
greatly exceeds the minimum maybe ban
with requirement for media for 1000 12
bytes per second standardization is in
the works were working with standards
bodies
to standardizes so more people can get
in on it and the key takeaway for you is
if you're making I O S
applications please start adding the
sleep these Bluetooth you I
you controllers immediately to your
applications
so that users can manage can manage
Richard many connections using your app
and a person is going to show you how to
do that is my colleague and homeboy Mike
Hopkins
and I'll turn the mike over to him thank
you very much story
I'd like to talk to you this morning
about
a new framework for I a less called core
i do. cat
this framework provides standardized
user interface
elements for you to add to your
application to do things like
show the many over Bluetooth Ellie
you I that Tori just demonstrated as
well as some new reviews for does the
view that are doing and trap
audio we've designed a so the
we do all the heavy lifting so that you
don't have to worry about rolling your
own UI
and you can just concentrate on what
makes your app unique
therefore they're very easy to adopt
with a minimal amount of source code
and they work on both iPhone and iPad
looking specifically about these
inner interface elements for media over
Bluetooth Ellie
as story showed you we have
why we have separated these into two
different view controller so that you
can choose which one is
appropriate for your own application or
you can use ball
for example of using you I split view
controller
you can have those both visible at the
same time the first one is the Capt many
local perform you controller
that's quite a mouthful this early in
the morning I am
if you want to advertise your OS device
as a per for all he is this class the
source code for adopting this is a very
straightforward
you create a new instance in that view
controller
get the navigation controller object for
your app
and push that view controller onto the
stack the
the Capt many central new controller is
required if you want to discover and
connect
to Bluetooth peripherals and you use
that in the same way
you chretien view controller and push in
on to your view controller stack
now I'd like to switch over and talk
about
enter up audio for those heavy they
weren't present last year WWDC we had a
session talking about this new
technology that we released with Iowa 7
in Review intra-party allows you to
stream audio between
one or more APs in real time a host
application
can discover available no naps even if
they're not running
and please refer to last year's session
what's new in core idea session to a sex
for further details
but looking at how this works with the
host appena connected no tap
know that can be an instrument in effect
or a generator
and her staff and no doubt can send
audio back and forth
in the case and an instrument the host
at can also send me to that
instrument ap and receive idea back
the two user interface elements that
we've that we provide
and I O S 8 are firstly the entrapped
idea switcher view
which provides an easy way to see all
the and trap i do. absent are connected
together
and switch between them using a simple
tap gesture
we also provide a and trap audio
host transport view this displays the
transport in the host you're connected
to and you're no doubt
and allows you to control the transport
playback
rewind and record in addition to
displaying where
and their transport you are by that
numeric timecode
night like to show a demo this in action
I have three different applications here
that will be using together in a wrap
ideas scenario
the first of which is garage band which
is the current version of that
application that I've downloaded from
the iTunes Store
and I also have a delay application
and an a sampler let's take a look at
the sampler first
this allows me to trigger sample
playback play the keyboard
for now let's go ahead and connect this
to garage band
middle and grunge band gonna connect to
that
sampler ap in and now this is connected
to garage band
so the first thing I'd like to
demonstrate is that entrap idea switcher
view
an action which this application is
implemented
as invisible by a button i press to and
you can see now
that we have two nodes show on the
hearst as well as our current
application and I can switch over to
grudge band
simply by tapping I'm going to add an
additional
enter up i do. ap the delay effect
and now if I was to switch over to this
application
without using the switcher view aka
double tap on my home key
the look can try to find an application
whereas it it's it's difficult to find
I mean that's why we've provided the
entrapped switcher view
and this application the delay you can
see that in the lower right hand corner
and now that is showing our host
this sampler as well as our current a
fact
so it's very easy to switch back and
forth
and you can see that just showed up
there so that's the first you'd like to
demonstrate
and if I play back on my keyboard we can
hear that we're now getting that delay
and this is interesting because we have
I'm
or sending audio from the host tour
sampler and then
through an app attacked the plane that
delay and then back now the second you
the transport view you'll see in just
about that you
we had that for you and that allows me
to control the transporter the host
I can do recording
sorry I'm no doctor jerry it's too early
in the morning for that when she get the
idea
and and these are the views and we're
providing for your benefit
so please add up the stat this
functionality tier application
okay said the goal between these user
interface elements are to provide a
consistent
experience for your customers and you do
have some flexibility in controlling
some other than
visual appearances and those controls
and they support a number different
sizes so if you wanna join our mass
I'm you are you can have that if you
want them very small you can do that
and the source code is I'm gonna show
you is very easy to add to your
application
and because these are some classes and
the UN view you can choose to create a
view controller if you want to add them
to a UI pop overview on your iPad
or if the example demonstrated if you
want to embed that directly in the
content in your app you can do that as
well
let's take a look at the code we a.m.
we import the umbrella header and this
case I'm demonstrating had
the switcher view from a nap file see
going to a be a drag out your UI view
assign that to be the class and the sea
and trap idea switcher view
create an outlet for that deal and then
and that you didn't load method in
and we specified the visual a parent's
that deal and then we need to associate
in our DNA with that view so that it can
automatically find the other APs
interconnected
and that's all there is to it
and creating them transport view
programmatically is this example shows
we create the view specify initial size
and location in that deal
configured some visual apparent says
associate and output idan it with the
deal
and then finally we add that transport
view as a sub your main contact
okay now I'd like to switch gears a
little bit now
back to a V Foundation and the rest my
presenters including myself will be
focusing on this framework
and some the new enhancements and
ability that we've added 38 at
to add to your application the first to
feature
is for ID again at management and
actually in the idea
component manager this is
a Mac OS 10 your sanity an API
be a deck to see based and it's
primarily designed for ID and a host
applications however as you'll see we do
have some end user features as well
we provide a number of different coring
methods which enable your host to
find the audience and the system given
some criteria for example
number supported channels we have a
simple API for getting information about
each individual idea net
we have some new tagging facilities that
out the mystery
in a moment and finally we have a
centralized
ID in it cash so that if you have
multiple host applications on your
system
when someone hostess and idan at and for
a lot of people there know what large
number them so this can take quite some
time
all the other hearst on the applique and
the system
share that information so they don't
have to perform that exhaust and scan
again
let's take a look at the API and more
detail as I said the username the
foundation in their new
the first class in the AVI Deanna
component manager
and this provides three different search
mechanisms for
for finding ID and it's the first time
which is based on the NS predicate
we can use a sec a sequel base language
to provide strings
which russia and damn and a source code
example later
for finding audience matching a given
criteria
we also have a black base mechanism for
finer programmatic control
and for those are you using all their
her stabs
with our current idea component API we
had a backwards compatibility mode as
well
each in the search and one methodologies
return
and an SRA adid and components
and that class can be used to get
information about the idea yet
now using our prior API if I wanted to
do something like
find Osteria fax did support to channel
and plan to channel output
I have to rate a great deal with code
I'm
that's okay but now at this new API we
can reduce all that to this
simple well again four lines of code the
first half which is retrieving an
intense
and a shared idea unit manager
and here I'm using the block-based
search mechanism to find
all components that pass a specific test
and in this block I'm checking to see if
that tape name
that I i dnt is equal to the
I'm preset string8 didn it a perfect
and then furthermore we're checking to
see if that ID and supports
stereo input and output you on the
tester is a
stop parameter so if you wanted to
return
I'm only the first 10 cents and the idea
component matching this criteria:
you can return yes and the stop would
would and it would stop immediately
okay now I'd like to move on to talk
about tagging
a lot of people especially doctored rate
and studio
has a large number a body in it so
finding the
to rate my and can be a bit challenging
because they're sorted alphabetically or
by
manufacture and there's a lot easier way
for users to find these ideas now
attacking
very similar to a be done with a finder
the previous Mac OS 10 release
users can now specify their own tags
with an ID and in order to create bride
categories remained specific
categories and how they want to organize
their audience
they can apply one or more tags into
different categories the first two which
is a system tag
this is defined by the creator and the
idea at
and for example with them and maverick's
excuse me and the assembly
have to get that name my head I
personally like to win but
I didn't get to go and mister some tags
aren't are defined by the creator and we
as Apple
have added standard tags: told the
audience that we feel would be useful to
my summer users
and you can also have user tags the user
specified by each individual user on the
system's at the end
3 users they can each have their own set
of tags
a tag is a localized string and the
user's on language
sweeter so he doesn't matter they can be
arbitrary
or they can be a predefined type and
these are all in audio component that
age
they can be either based on the tape a
body and
for example a filter or distortion
effect or they can be based on the
intended usage
for example I'm and idan it useful and a
guitar vocal track
now I'd like to show a demo and tagging
and action using them
a modified version and a lab so an A in
lab
in and you we can look at all the tags
associate with all the built-in audience
and here you see that for example the a
time pitch
had to standard tags: that are sissy
with that time effect and pitch
and those are defined by I S and in
addition
you can see that this distortion effect
has to user tags
when specifying this useful for a drum
track and another one for guitar track
and the API also provides developers the
ability to get a list them all day
system defined tags localized in their
language
the running hearst as you can see here
and I can also see all in the user tags
and
that the users assigned to all the ideas
on this system
adding tags care as simple as typing a
new one
now that's been added to that I D and
and I can do a search using this I'm
predicate base and other search
mechanisms
and it will search on the audience
looking for that particular tag
so this is something that's really
exciting and we hope that your
add use this API dad tagging
functionality to your own test
application
let's take a look now at papi
to find an ID in it with the specific
tag in this example for me is the INS
predicate
and filtering mechanism Hey Ram defining
a predicate
said that I'm the the
component past due had the alt tag
name's property
containing a particular string in this
case my favorite tag
and this is the identical searching that
she just signed my demo
when seem to find the predicate you get
a instance they shared a deal
manager and then call components
matching predicate which returns
an array
to get a left and the tags associate
with this
particular adid a component me is the
zyrtec names property
you can assign to that as well and in
this example I'm adding two tags to the
idea net
we can get all tags for specific
component in these law include the user
tags as well as a system tags:
all tag name's property we can get a
localized list them all the standard
system tags by getting the component
manager and then calling the standard
localize tag name's property
this is what I was just playing and a
pop-up and my demo
and finally I can get a list them all
the local a stag cities user has
assigned across all the ideas on the
system
and that again Nissan my demo
for those are being that ship idea units
and you want to add your own built-in
text does it. in its
I'm you need to go into here audio
component banned all
and in your info dat P last look at your
audio component dictionary and add a tag
section
these first two items are examples
abusing standard tags:
and the third item is a custom tag
see you can have that be something if
meaningful two-year
on company for example if you have a
sweet like this over affect package you
can add that tag
if you do so you can also I'm localize
that tag by adding an audience tag
that string volunteer banned all and
then adding localization screech
language that you wish to support and
please do not localize in Amherst and
I'm system tags: we've already done so
for you
so in summary if your'e if you're a host
developer please
adopt the AB i do. company manager API
so users can tag all their IANS
and and if you're not an end developer
please add some tags to your audience
so without further ado i'd like to
turnover this session to Eric Johnson
whole be discussing
temps and chicks in new functionality in
abit a session
Eric of
good morning so I'll be continuing on
with that a V Foundation framework
and this time we're on ISL s only with
abit a session
answered today we're just gonna spend a
few minutes talking about some
best practices focusing on managing your
sessions activation stay and then of the
talking about just a little bit anything
and I was a before we dive n
I wanted to call your attention to an
updated I efficient programming guide
that's available
on developer not Apple DICOM Athens with
all you all last year at this time
at this guide has been updated so
desperate
have been rewritten in terms of AV audio
session so it's no longer referring to
the
deprecated capi at a really great up day
and and for those of you who are maybe
not that familiar with
audio session hatteras a talk from two
years ago
where Tory talked about idea session
and also multi route idea and I'll
art so let's dive into you talking about
at managing your sessions activation
stay
so there's there's your application stay
and then the
there's already a session state and
their their separate things I managed
independently of each other
so if you've been doing development for
I'll ask you're probably familiar
with ap States so this is whether your
app is running or not
whether it's in the foreground in the
background it's been suspended
here audio session activation state is
binary
it's either an active or active
once you've made your session active you
do need to be prepared to handle
interruptions
and we'll talk about what that means so
let's look at an example of how
an audit session state changes over time
so here have were or on an iPhone we
have our
our application on top our audio session
I would say that we're developing a game
app
and then on the bottom we have the phone
buddy session
and right now the users not in a phone
call
and have a launcher app yet for both but
sessions are idle
an active now the user launches are up
when we first came in the foreground our
idea session is still an active
and because we're a game app we want to
make our session active
when we're in the foreground so that we
can be ready to play idea will do that
and we're going to just play some music
so we're for now happily playing music
in the foreground with an active idea
session
said then a the phone
phone starts ringing we get interrupted
by so
the system friendless an interruption
event
I'm the phone Friday session becomes
active in
plays the ringtone and the user decides
to accept the call
so the phone Friday sessions stays
active and
are on his session has been interrupted
so were inactive
and then the the user and call thing
that says goodbye
and now the system is going to deliver
an end interruption event to our audio
session
and we're going to use that has a a
signal to make our session active again
and resume playback and we continue in
the state
so this is a a typical example how
I'll something like a game application
interacts with the phones
at the phone app Sunday Session on an
iPhone
so the way that you need to manage your
applications
I efficient stay is actually going to
depend on how you use audio
and we've identified a number of
different types of applications
that commonly used audio on iowa's
and we don't have time to talk about all
these this morning and you probably
bored to death
we did after it is going to talk about a
few the if
so let's continue on with the idea that
we're developing a game app
surfer game app usually what we
recommend is the
when you're in the foreground you want
to have your own decision active
so a good place to make air I session
active
is in the App delegates application to
become active nothin
so that will cover the case when you're
being launched here
coming from the background into the
foreground or if you're already in the
foreground
and the user had have swept up the
control panel and then dismissed
to be covered in each of those cases so
once you've made your session active you
can leave it
active but you do need to be prepared to
deal with interruptions
so if you get a begin interruption event
you should update your
internal state so that you know that
your paused
and then if you get in and interruption
event that's your opportunity to make
your session active
answers and audio playback and this is
just like the example that we looked at
just a few minutes ago
media playback caps need to manage their
recession state a little bit differently
so i'm talking about. applications like
the built-in music app
or podcasts are streaming radio and
these are the types of applications that
we usually have
a play/pause button and there what we
refer to as non mixable meaning
that and I'll interrupt the audio other
NYMEX IPL
idea sessions suffer these types of
applications we recommend
that instead of making your session
active immediately when it for granted
that you weigh
until the user presses the play button
and the reason that we give you that
advice
is sometimes the user brings you happen
to the foregoing just to see if they
have a
a particular podcast episode downloaded
or see if they have a song in the
library
and they don't necessarily wanna
interrupt other audio that was playing
that's going to wait until they press
play
so like in the case of a game app once
you've made your session active you can
you can leave act in but again you need
to be prepared to handle interruptions
so if you get it began interruption
event you should update your UI
became a play/pause button thinkin good
time to change that stay
and also keep track of your internal
states that you know their powers
I one thing you do not need to do is you
do not need to make your session
inactive because the system is already
done done that for you
that that's what the interruption is so
then
if you get in and interruption event we
ask
that you honor the should resume option
so this option is part iv: the in for a
dictionary that's part of that
notification
that the first inning giving you head
that it's okay to make your session
active
and to immediately resume playback if
you don't see that option
has partnered occasion the nation way
user press play again
okay so we've talked about Ag for gay
maps and media playback abs
when you would make a session active
what about making your session inactive
so if you were something like a
navigation
or fitness app here typically going to
be playing
short at short prompt the body 0
and you're going to be using the duck
others
category option which will lower the
volume other
audio applications on the system so it's
important be
when you're done playing short prompt
that you make your session inactive
so that the other audio was able to
resume it for long
if you're Voice over IP at at her cat
app
or maybe one of these abt that has like
kind of a bright
a kind of like a browser view we're
playing short videos
then and you're usually going to be what
we refer to as non mix well meaning that
you're gonna interrupt
other audio and so it's important that
when you're done
playing idea that you make your session
inactive so that
other sessions are able to resume
and it's a good idea to use the notify
others on
deactivation option when you make your
session act inactive
and that way the system is able to and
tell and interrupted on a session that
it's okay for them to you
resume
alright so now with shift gears a little
bit and talk about
managing your secondary audio in
response to you
other audio on the system playing so
first let me explain what I mean by
secondary idea primary idea
so at what they were developing a game
application our primary audio
is going to be our are sound effects are
explosion
beeps and boops short but the dialogue
and it's the kind of idea that really
enhances the gameplay
and if of a kind of idea that if the
user
was listening to music when they launch
app he still wanted to play
and suck it and make something with the
other music
by secondary audio I'm really talking
about your soundtrack
missus audio where it also enhances the
gameplay
but if the user was previously listening
to their music for the podcast
you just the same have your soundtrack
be needed
and then if they're at the user stops
their music playback in their podcast
and
you'd like to have your soundtrack
resume so
and I was 8 we've added a bit of new API
to help you do this we've added a new
property and a new notification
the property is called secondary audio
should be silenced hand
as the name implies that the hint but
the system is giving you
that is a good time to new secondary
idea
so this is meant to be used by abt there
in the foreground
and we recommend that you would check
this property and application to become
active going along with any property
is our new notification this is the
any idea session silence secondary idea
and notification another mouthful
after this early morning at for this
notification will be delivered taps
there in the foreground with active
other sessions
and it's kind of similar to our
interruption notification that its
it's two-sided there's a begin events
and there's an end to that
how all wrapped up in the same
notification
so when you get to begin I'm found
secondary idea health and education
that means that a good time to meet your
secondary audio and if you get the end
event
thing in time to resume soundtrack so
let's look at what this looks like an
action
so on the far right we have the built-in
music app hand it's currently in the
back and it's not playing audio
on the far left we have our game app
that we're developing
so we're playing our primary audience on
a fax and we're also playing our
soundtrack
because there is no other music playing
and in the middle we have I was hoping
to negotiate things
so the user a has his headphones plugged
in
any precedent that middle button and the
music app
response remote-controlled answer is
that as a signal to
begin playback a music app also
informs I last sentence using its audio
output
and for then the system is able to pass
and to begin notification to our apt
that's in the foreground and in response
to that we can meet
soundtrack so are our app is still the
foreground the only thing that's really
changed is that the user
use their middle button 10 to play their
music
and we've responded to the notification
that we got from the system
for now some time passes were in the
state for a while and the user presses
the middle button again for music app
response by
pausing its playback telling the system
that is positive value out but
and in the system is able to send the
end
notification to our apt its own for
gramm
and in response to that we resume our
soundtrack
so hopefully miss will be pretty easy to
use
am there's a won the property and then
the two sided notification that you can
use to manage your soundtrack
so I'm kinda wanna similar thread and in
the past we've given advice
about how you can manager your secondary
audio
based on the is other idea playing
property
and we had given advice about and
choosing between the
me. category or so and yet based on
the state has property what we're
recommending now
is that if you're the type of
application that you just use the ambien
category
and the news the new property and the
new notification to manager soundtrack
arianna and things over to the quiet
he's gonna talk about new utility
classes
may be finished thank you good morning
and acquired I'm an engineer in the core
idea group
and I'd like to talk to you about some
new idea classes in the 80 Foundation
framework
are getting will start out with some
background and tell you what we're up to
and why
I the most are looking through this
class is one by one
and all type things up at the end with
an example
so in the past our car audio in audio
tool box API's
they're very powerful but they're not
always easy for
developers to get their hands around at
the beginning
we've tried to work around this by
providing some C plus plus utility
classes
an RS 2k and that's helped to some
extent
I but example code gets copied around it
evolves over time
and with we think it's best in the long
run if we sort of solidified these
things
informal API and that or providing now
with these classes in the V Foundation
framework
starting with Mac OS 10 Tan Tan Tan Tan
and
Iowa State
so our goals here we don't want to make
a complete break with the past
we want to build on what we've already
got
I'm so a we're going to
in many cases wrap our existing
low-level see structures
inside objective-c objects and in doing
so
these lower levels his structures become
easier to build
but we can also extract them from our
objective see objects and passed them to
the low-level API might already be using
and this is a philosophy we is also with
the the Audioengine
which will beat examining and more
detail in the next session here
and I should also mention an overriding
goal here is for us to stay
real time say which isn't always easy
with objective-c
we can't access methods
or properties on the idea rendering
throwed
I'm so we've taken some great care to do
that in our implementations
and as we go I'll give you a couple took
samples a
places where you need to do this to be
aware
real time issues when you're using these
classes
okay so sure the classes will be looking
at today
and the session I at the bottom there
with in green we've got a the audio
format
which has an AB idea channel layout I
in blue we have any idea PCM buffer
which has an audio format
every buffer has a format describing up
and finally we'll be talking about abe
audiophile which uses a the idea PCM
buffer for i/o
and as you would expect to file also has
format object describing
the files data format
so first let's look at it the audio
format
this class describes the the actual
format of daily might find an audio file
or stream
and also the audio you the formidable
they are you might be passing to and
from API's
so are low-level structure here for
describing an audio format is an art
history in basic description
which in retrospect might have been
called audio stream not so basic or
audio stream complete description
occurred there a lot of fields there and
it can be a little challenging to get
them all set up consistently especially
for PCM format
I'm but you know the beauty of the
structures that it describes just about
everything
we would want to use to describe
an idea for map but again it's a little
challenging
but in any case you can always create an
AV audio format
from an artist reinvested description
which you might have obtained from
low-level API
and you can always access stream
description:
promenade the audio format
but now we can move on to other ways to
interact with the idea for map
on so in the past we've had this concept
of canonical format
and this concept goes back to about 2002
and Mac or standpoint our time point one
or so
so this format was floating point 32-bit
the interleaved but then we got along
tile ass
and we couldn't really recommend using
plot everywhere cuz we didn't have the
greatest floating point performance
initially
so I'll for a while canonical is aimed
at 24 fixed point
but because it that's cuz I'm we want to
reunite under
something new now with deprecated the
concept of canonical
formats now we have a week all standard
format
we're back to not let her leave 32-bit
plots on both platforms
so this is the simplest way to construct
a navy audio format now
as with I you can't create a standard
format by specifying just a sample rate
on channel count:
you can also query and hear the audio
format you might come across and find
out if it is a standard format
using the standard property
we've also I provided for
using common formats with AV audio
format
and with we define common formats as
format to it often is and signal
processing
such as 16-bit integers that people use
and that I last saw her other platforms
we also provide for 64 bit parts it's
very easy to create maybe audio format
and wannabes formats by specifying which
one you what
the sample rate channel count whether
it's interleaved you can query any
format to see if it is some common
format
or something else using the comment form
at
property
okay so that's it the audio format let's
look at the the idea channel out
briefly here this describes the ordering
or the roles
multiple channels which is especially
important for example in surround sound
you might have left right center we
might have left center right and so on
I it's important to know the actual
order the channels
so every AB audio format may have a navy
audio channel out
and in fact when constructing Navy audio
format
if you're describing three or more
channels you have to tell us what the
layout is
so it becomes an ambiguous to anyplace
else in the system that says that AB
audio format what the order
the channels are so I
the underlying audio channel layout
objectors pretty much exposed the way it
is here you can go look at that and
party a types that age
but we have wrapped up in the audio
channel out for you
okay moving on
now let's look at it the idea PCM buffer
so I paper can be a sort of funny term
when we're dealing with D interleaved
idea because of the audio buffer list
structure
but that aside hi you can pick up that
some players memory for storing your
audio data in any format including
on it early formats compare the
low-level structures
which obvious ones in particular can
also be a bit
a bother to deal with because idea but
for Leicester's variable-length
so you can simply create an AB idea PCM
buffer
will create an idea but for list for you
above the right size
and you can always touch it back out of
PA the idea PCM buffer
here's the initializer so to create a
buffer you
you specify the format and a capacity an
audio sample frames
can always touch back the buffers format
and the capacity with which it was
constructed
and unlike audio buffer list which has a
simple
bite-size for everybody for I'm here
we've separated the concept of capacity
in like
so there's the fixed capacity risk
created with
and the frame length which expresses the
number of currently valid frames in the
buffer
some more methods here to get to the
underlying samples
we provide these simple type safe access
service
and this is good time now to
say a word about real time safety
because bizarre properties and as useful
as they may be for actually getting to
the data
since their properties they may involve
about the lookup
which can in-principle take a
a mess on lookup and
cause you to block so up if you're going
to be using
in the idea PCM boppers on audio
real-time threads
it's best to catch these members and
some say
contacts when you first looking at the
buffer and
I and is does cashed members on the
real-time trade
okay that's piss him but for now we can
look at audiophile switched
perhaps all these other classes together
so here we like to read and write file
so many core idea supported format this
ranges from
m4a mp4 wave cafe I A
and why can't pick up right now I'm so
in accessing the file here we give you a
single act single way to
I'm reading right the file completely
independent the files actual data format
supper 29 Corp encoded format like a
senior at the Los lesser and
mp3 if there's a cut back on the system
in most cases there is
we will transparently to you decode from
that
format as you read the file
similarly when you're running an audio
file we will and code from PC I'm into
that encoded format
if we have an encoder so to do this
the file has this concept of the
processing format
and the processing format is simply the
PCM format
with which you or interact with the file
so you specify that the PCM format when
you create the file
and it has to be either a standard a
common format
the only limitation here is that we
don't permit sample rate conversion as
you read from
or write to a file your processing
format needs to get the same sample rate
has the file itself now after familiar
with the
our little box extended idea prolly PI
this is functionally very some more
that's just a bit some thirty years
so looking now at the initializer is and
some accessories for the audio file
here's initializer for reading from a
file if you don't specify a processing
format
is simply I are I you get the
default behavior which is that your
processing format will be a standard
format
very similarly to create the audio file
for writing
the only extra information you need to
give us as a settings dictionary
this is the same settings dictionary
past to AP audio recorder
and and there are there are keys which
specify the file format you want to use
and in the case a example for example AC
you can specify the bitrate and any
other encoder settings those around
the settings pictionary
so once had you've got a file you can
always
access back the actual file format on
desk
so that might be for example AC 44 kill
her sister channels
but you can also query the processing
format
with which you created the file and in
the case and these two
simplest initialize urs does would be
a floating-point 32-bit same sample rate
is the file
same channel count as the file
okay so to read and write from if the
audio files
there's a simple method read into buffer
that will simply fill
the AV audio PCM buffer to its capacity
assuming you have you don't at the end
of file
right from buffer is a little different
and that it looks like the book looks at
the buffers frame length
rather the compact and the capacity so
writes all about the ballot frames
from that buffer to the file
and you can do random access I when
reading from audiophiles
so this is like the standard C++
libraries seek
and tell functions absecon of top
you can query the frame position to see
where you are when reading an audiophile
and I you can also seeks a different
position in the file by setting the
frame position pointer
before you read and the next three to
four percent sequentially from that
point
occurred like to tie all these classes
together now at the short example
in about four screens here we'll see
what it's like to
open an audiophile extract some basic
information
from at and read through every sample in
the file
secretary happen at for reading
simply pass a URL I I'm using the very
end here that's percent but I'm passing
PC employed 32 anyways I could have left
those often gotten a standard format
I'm going to fetch some basic
information from the File and Printer
including the files on disc format
and the processing for map I can query
the audio files like 10 frames sample
friends
and I can convert that Mike than friends
to a duration by dividing by the file
separate
okay next time when you create a PCM
buffer to read from
sense the file might be large I don't
wanna try to read it all into memory
wats
so I'm gonna live through 228k sample
frame set a time
someone to create a buffer with that
capacity
Anderson to screen the past the audio
files
processing format when when allocating
this buffer and that ensures that the
boppers the same format
but the file will begin me and
here I'm start I'm I'm ready to start
reading through the file
and I'm going to read one buffer at a
time until they get the and
second query the current prime position
and see if it's like
last stand like five discovered earlier
I can read into buffer which will look
and feel
told the buffer to capacity I can double
check to see if I'm done
by saying if I got a0 like buffer and
is a lot of code that but it boils down
to
24 loops the outer one is walking
through all the channels on the buffer
for multi-channel file
and than the inner loop
will look at every sample in that proper
so given every sample
I can look at its absolute level and see
if that's the loudest sample were
if it's louder than the latter sample I
found so far enough so I can record that
level
and where I found it in the file so
there in about four screens have code
I open an audiophile I read through the
whole thing one sample at a time
okay so moving on a bike to just sorta
foreshadow
abuses of these classes iraq in the
hi if you're Audioengine session
which will follow this one so at the
bottom with CAD audiophile maybe idea
PCR buffer
and those are both used by something
called a the audio player narrowed
which will be your basic mechanism for
scheduling audio to playback
baby audio player notices is a subclass
a more generic if the idea and no class
which is some
unit a body a process I'm and
we'll see how it the audio formats are
used one describing how to connect if
the audience
so that brings us to the and a bisexual
the stock
we saw the AB audio format channel
layout PCM buffer and file classes
you can use these without it the ideal
engine
using your existing code with the car
audio audio tool box in our unit C API's
if you're careful to stay real time say
and you can use those accessor methods
to I extract the low-level sees
structures
and again we'll be seeing how these are
used in more detail in the next session
on eighty Audioengine
and thats Genivar are here
we've looked at many over Bluetooth
intra-party are you ideas
lots of features a baby foundation idea
and we hope you'll stick around for the
next session on AB Audioengine
if you need more information call it
preserved Angeles
from there the developer forms hers the
next session I keep talking about