good morning everyone my name is couple
Christian movie
and I work in car audio I'm here today
to talk to you about
a new API call AB Audioengine but we're
introducing
for Mac OS 10 years somebody and I USA
as part of today's talk
will first look at an overview of core
audio and then we'll dive into a the
Audioengine
look at some other goals behind the
project features of the new API
the different building block should be
using and finally will do
a section on gaming and 3d audio let's
get started
for those of you who aren't familiar
with core audio
koran your provides a number of capi ice
as part of different frameworks on both
bio s and Mac OS 10
and you can use these different APIs to
implement audio features and
applications
so using these APIs you will be able to
play and the car sounds
with low-latency converts between
are different file and data formats read
and write
audiophiles work with many did %ah and
also play sounds like get specialized
several years ago
we added sum up simple objective seek
losses to eighty foundation
and they called AV audio player an AV
audio recorder
and using these process you can play
sounds from files
or a card directly to a file now while
these classes worked really well for
simple use cases
a more advanced user might find
themselves a bit limited so this year
were adding a whole new set of API to AB
foundation
call AV audio engine and my colleague
Doug
also spoke about a number of abou
utility classes
and Section 501 so using this new API
you will be able to write powerful
features we just a fraction
abiam on of code that you may have had
two previously right so let's get
started
what will the goals behind this project
one of the biggest goals
was to provide a powerful and
feature-rich API said and were able to
do that because we're building on top of
our existing core audio AP ice
using this API everyone and developers
to be able to achieve
simple as well as complex stuff and a
simple task could be something like
playing a sound and running it through
an effect
a complex task can be something as big
as writing an entire audio engine for a
game
we also wanted to simplify real-time
audio
for those of you who are not familiar
with real-time audio
it can be quite challenging you have a
number for on your call backs
every second and for each call back you
have to provide data in a timely fashion
you can do things like cable locks on
the IO thread
a call functions that can block
indefinitely so we make all of this
easier for you to work with by giving
you a real time on your system
but one that %um tracked with in a non
real-time context
features on the new API this is a
full-featured Objective C API said
on you get a real time audio system to
work with meaning that any changes that
you make on any of the blocks
take effect immediately using this API
you will be able to read and right
audiophiles play and record audio
connect different audio processing
blocks together
and then while the engine is running and
audios flowing through the system
you can't act the output of each of
these processing blocks
you'll also be able to implement 3d
audio for games now before we actually
jump into the engines building blocks
I thought I'd give you to sample use
cases to give you a little flavor of
what you'll be able to do using this API
so the first sample use case is a
karaoke application
you have a backing track that's playing
and the user singing along with it
and real-time the output at the
microphone
a spot through a delay which is just a
musical affect
and both the bees audience change a
mixed and sent to the output Harbor
could be speaker headphones let's also
say
that's you tak the outputs at the
microphone and
analyze that raw data CB users on pitch
he's doing great job a few years play
some sound effects
SodaStream also gets mixed n and played
out
the output hardware here's another use
case
you have a streaming application and you
receive data from a remote location
you can now stop this data in two
different buffers
and schedule them on a clear day you
can't run the output at the player
to any Q whose you why you present to
the user
so that they can tweak the EQ based on
their preference
the output a BBQ then goes to the upper
harbour
so these are just two sample use cases
you'll be able to do a whole lot more
once we talk about abe Audioengine for
let's get started
the two main object to going to start
with I V
engine object and the note of che and
that she specific types of nodes
the output node makes unknown and the
piano
we have other nodes as well that will
get to but these are the initial
building block notes
so the engine is an object that
maintains ago of
audio notes you create nodes
and you attach them to the engine and
then use the engine to make connections
between these different audio notes
engine will analyze these connections
and determine
which ones add up to an active chain
when you then start the engine
audio flows through all of the active
change
up of a feature that the engine has is
that it allows you to dynamically
reconfigure these notes
this means that while the engine is
rendering you can add
new nodes and then why the mop and so
essentially a adding or removing chains
dynamically so the typical workflow the
engine
is that you create an instance of the
engine create instances up all the nodes
you want to work with
attach them to the engine so the engines
now aware of them
and then connect them together start the
engine
this will create an active vendor to
read an audio will flow through all of
the active change
so let's not talk about a note unknown
is a basic
on your block and we have three types
and notes
that a source node which one knows but
generate audio
examples abyss other player on the input
no
you have notes that process audio so
they take some audio and do something to
it
and push it up and examples of this our
mixer
are in effect you also have destination
nodes
that receive audio and do something with
it
every one of these notes has a certain
number of important out but bus
I and typically you see that most notes
have a single input and output bus
but an exception this is a mixture known
that has multiple input buses
and a single up a bus every but
now has an audio data format Associated
so let's talk about connections
if you have a connection between a
source node and a destination node
that forms an active chain you can
insert
any number processing notes between the
source node and the definition not
but as long as you why %uh every bit up
this chain up
it's an active chain as soon as you
break one of the connections
all the notes that I upstream of the
point disconnection
going to an inactive state in this case
a broken the connection
between the processing node and the
destination node so my processing known
and my source known
I'm now in an inactive state the same
holds true in this example
so let's now look at the specific no
types
the first know that we're going to talk
about is the output node
the engine has an implicit destination
node and it's called the output no
and the role in the output node is to
take up the data that it receives
and hand it to the output hot this could
be the speaker
you cannot create a stand-alone and soon
to be out but no
you have to get it from the incident to
be engine let you create a
let's move on to the mixer no make some
notes
a processing notes and they receive data
on different input bosses
which he then makes to a single out but
which goes out on the output bus
when you use a mixer you get control
over the wall %um of each input bus
and he had an application that was
playing a number of sounds
and you put each of the sounds in on a
separate input bus
using this volume control you can
essentially blend in the amount to be
sound but you wanna hear so you create a
mix
you not have control over the output
volume
as well using a mixer so you're
controlling the volume
the mix that you created
if your application has several
categories of sounds
you can make you some concept called sub
mixing to create some mixes
so let's say that you have some UI
sounds and you have some music
and you put all the UI sounds 21 mixer I
love the music to another mixer
using the output volumes have each of
these mixers you can essentially control
the volume up
each of the sub mixes let's take that
concept a stepfather
and put all the sub mixes through a
monster Mixr
the output volume up the masa mixer with
essentially control
the volume to be in time mix in your
application
now the engine has an implicit mixer no
and when you off the engine
for its mixer node it creates an
instance of a mixer
creates an instance of the output node
and connected together for you by
default
the difference here between the mix
unknown and the output known
is that you can create additional
instances and then attach them to the
engine
and use them how you please mixtures can
also have
different audio data formats for each
input bus
and the mixer will do the work of
efficiently converting
the input data formats to the output
data format
so now that we look at these initial
notes
let's not talk about how this works in
the context of the engine
so let's say that I have a nap that
creates an instance of the engine
I can now of the engine for its main mix
or node
so it's gonna create instanceof the
mixer can instanceof the output node
and connect the two together I can now
create a player node
and attach it to the engine and
connected to the mixer
so at this point I have a connection
chain going all the way from a source to
a destination
so I have an active chain when I then
start up the engine
an active render thread is created a and
data is pulled by the destination
so I have an active flow day to him
the app can now in track with each one
of these blocks
and any change that makes on any of the
notes will take effect immediately
so now that we've talked about an active
render
red how do you push you on your data
on that end up thread you use a player
to do that
let's look at player notes clear nodes
on notes that can play date up from
files
and from bob Foose and the way that it
happens
by the way that it's done is by
scheduling events which simply means
play data at a specified time that data
at that time could be now are some time
in the future
when your scheduling buffers you can
schedule I to multiple buffers
and as each boffo is consumed by the
clear you get an individual call back
which you can then use as a cue to go
ahead and schedule more day
you can also schedule a single buffer
that plays in a loop fashion
and this is useful in the case when you
may have a music loop
are sound effect that you wanna play
over and over again
so you load the data and then you play
the buffer and it'll continue to play
until you stopped the player are you in
shopping
with another buffer we'll get into that
you can also schedule a file or a
portion of a file called a segment
so going back to a previous diagram we
had an engine that was in the running
state
to now I can create an instance of a
bottle and load my data into it
shown by the red at all want to do that
I can schedule the spot for on the
player
and when the players playing the play
over consume the data
in the buffer and push it on the end the
threat
in a similar manner I can work with
multiple buffers
so over here have multiple buffers I
loaded onto each one of them
and I schedule each one of them to play
in sequence
on the player as each bottle
is consumed by the playah I get
individual call backs
letting me know that buffers done I can
use that as a cue
and schedule more data
in a similar manner you can work with
the file
and a difference here is that you don't
have to actually deal with the audio
data yourself
all you need is a URL to a physical
audiophile
with which you can create an AV audio
file object
and then schedule that directly on the
player the player will do the work
of reading data from the file and
pushing and on that and interim
so let's now look according sample of
how we can achieve this
I first created an instance be engine
create an instance of a clear and attach
the player
the engine so the engines now where the
player
I'm not going to split my example out
and show how you can first work with the
file
so given are you are owed to an audio
file I can create an AV audio file
object
the next thing that I do is of the
engine for its main mixer
so the engine will create an instance of
a mixer node create an output node
and connect the two together I can now
go ahead
and connect the player to the mixer
with the files processing format so I
have a connection chain going all the
way from
clear that the source to the output node
that a destination
now I can schedule my file to play at
time new
which is as soon as possible and in this
case I pass a nose for the completion
handler
if I had some work that needed to be
done after the file has consumed by the
player
I can pass on a block here
so in a similar manner I can work with
the buffer as well
let's say that I create an AV audio PCM
buffer object
and lows some data into it the specifics
up that part a covered in Section 501 so
if you missed that police
I refer to that session want to have my
buffer object
I can go ahead not the engine for its
mixer and make the connection between
the player
to the mixer with the buffers format
now I can go ahead and schedule this
buffer
at time new soon as possible
but note that we have an additional
argument when we're working with buffers
the auctions argument we're gonna talk
about that right after this
but for now I'm gonna pass new and no
for the completion handler as well
so now that I've schedule my data on the
player I can go ahead and start the
engine
this creates an active vendetta red and
then called play on the play
and the player will do the work up
reading the data from the file in the
buffer
and pushing it on that and it said so
let's not talk
about the different buffer scheduling
options
in all of the examples and I'm going to
talk about now
I'm going to specify new for the at time
argument and that just means that in all
these examples
I'm going to schedule something to play
as soon as possible
so let's talk about the first option and
that's when you want to schedule a
buffer to play as soon as possible
in that case all you need to do is our
schedule a buffer
with the option set to net you call a
play on the player
and that buffer gets played a if you
have a buffer that's playing now
and you want to append a new buffer it's
the exact same call
you schedule the new buffer with the
option set to know
and so the new buffer get appended can
to the queue of currently playing
buffers
on the other hand if I want to in shop
my currently playing buffer with a new
buffer
I can schedule the new buffer with the
AV audio player node
buffer in trucks option so that well in
shop the country playing buffer
and start playing my new bottle right
away
let's now look at the different variants
with a looping buffer
so like I said earlier if I have a
buffer that to be played in the loop
fashion
like a sound effect for instance I can
load the data
in that buffer and schedule that buffer
with the AV audio player known
of the loops option when I call play on
the player
that buffer stops to play in a loop
fashion
if I wanna in shop a looping buffer
it's the same auction as what we've seen
before
I have to schedule a new buffer with the
AP audio player note
buffer in traps option so essentially
it's the same option
for when you want to interrupt a regular
buffer
or a looping Buffalo
the last case in an interesting one so
if you have a looping buffer
but you want to let the current loop
finish before you start playing
your new data you can schedule your new
buffer
with the AV audio player node but her in
shops at loop option
so this will let the current loop finish
and as soon as that loop is done the new
buffer starts playing
now that was a whole bunch of options
let's look and one practical example of
how we can use these options
so let's say that I have a sound that's
broken up into three parts
and example I'm gonna use your is a site
in
so you have the initial build up at the
sound which is the attack portion of the
site
you have the drawing portion of the site
and which can be modeled using just a
looping buffer
and this is the sustaining portion of
the sound and then you have the dying
down at the siren
which is the release portion up what's
up so let's say that I load up
each of these I sounds in two different
buffers
the way that I can implement this in
code
is to push schedule the attack before
with my options at No
and then schedule the sustained offer
with the AV audio player note
behold loops option so when I called
play on the player
what this'll do display the attack
portion of the sound
and then immediately start playing the
sustain portion of the sound
and continue to loop that sustain buffer
and that goes on
until I'm ready to inch up to after some
time has gone by
and I'm ready to inch up that I can
schedule my released by her
with the eighty audio player node buffer
in shops & Lube option
so this will let the Los Lupes up to
sustain buffer
finish up and then play the release
portion of my son
I remember that I said in the beginning
that all of my examples
involved scheduling events to play as
soon as possible
well I can also schedule events to play
in the future
so here's an example of that in this
case I'm just going to schedule
a buffer to play 10 seconds in the
future so I create
and AB on your time object that has a
Tampa a relative sample time
10 seconds in the future and I use the
buffer sample rate
as my reference point I can now schedule
the buffer
with this AV audio time object and
called play on the play
and my buffer gets played 10 seconds in
the future
all right so we've talked about player
notes
and how you can use a player to push you
on your data
on that ended today well if you want to
pull data from the end it right
how do you do that you use a note app
and here are some reasons for why you
may want to do that
let's say you want to capture the output
at the microphone
and save that data to disk or arm
if you have a music application and you
wanna record in life
of arms or if you have a game and you
want to capture the output makes
the game you can do all of that using a
note at
and what that is inthe essentially a tap
that you install
on the output bus of a node to the data
that's captured by the tap
his return back to application me a call
back lock
to going back to a familiar diagram I
have two players
that's connected to the engines main
mixer and I want to tap
the output up the mixer so I can install
a tap on the mixer
and the top will start pulling data from
the end at Red
I can then go ahead at that but Apple
then go ahead
and create a buffer object stuff that
data into the buffer
and return that back to the application
be a call back block
in code it's just one function call
you install attack on the mixers output
bus
0 with a buffer size of 4096 frames
and the mixers output format for that
bus
within the bloc have an AV audio PCM
buffer that contains
that much I'm on a data and I can do
whatever I need to do with that data
all right so the quick a summarized you
have an active vendetta red
you use clear notes to push you on your
data on that end the threat
and use no taps to pull on your data
from the end it right
let's not switch gears and talk about a
new node
call the input node the input node
receives data from the input hardware
and its battle to the output node
with the input node you cannot create a
stand-alone instance
you have to get the instance from the
engine
arm when you've connected the input node
in an active chain
and the engine is running data is pulled
from the input nope so let's go back to
a familiar diagram
I've connected the input node to the
mixer note
and that connect the output gap so when
I start the engine
this is an active chain and data is
pulled from the input node
so if I'm receiving data from the input
node and the engine is running
and I want to stop receiving data at a
certain point how do I do that
it's very simple all you have to do how
I'm so I I raced ahead
let's look at a code example of how you
can connect the input node
so I get the input notes from the engine
just make a connection to any other note
with the input no its hardware format
and then start the engine this creates
an active and it read
and the input notes posed for data like
I was saying earlier
if you have an input node that's being
pulled and you don't receive data
anymore from the input node
what you do just disconnect the input
node
so the input node will no longer be an
active chain
and in one report for data in order to
do that
is just one line of code using the
Indian
you disconnect note output up the input
node
now if you want to capture data from the
input node you can install a note to
and we've talked about that but what's
interesting about this particular
example
is if I wanted to work with chest be
input node
sagesse capture data from the microphone
and maybe examine it
analyze it and real-time on may be right
now to file
I can't directly install a top on the
input node
and attack will do the work of pulling
the input not for data
stuffing it in buffers and then turning
that back to the application
once you have that data you can do
whatever you need to do with it
and let's not talk about the last type
up notes in this section
effect notes effect known on notes that
process data
so depending on the type of affect the
take some amount of data in
the process it and push that date out
we have to main categories a perfect you
have AVR unit effects
and AV audio net time affects
so what's the difference between to AB
or do you need a fax
and acquired the same amount of data on
input
at the Amman update out there being us
to provide
so let's take the example of a
distortion
effect if a distortion no one has to
provide
24 milliseconds about but all it needs
is 24 milliseconds have been part
that it then processes and pushes out
as opposed to that time affects don't
have that constraint
so let's say that you have a time affect
that's doing some amount of time
stretching
if it is being asked to provide 24 min
the second
output it may require forty-eight
milliseconds have input
so that brings me to my second point it
is for that reason
why you cannot connect a time effect
directly
with the input node because when you
have the input node running and
real-time
it cannot provide data that it doesn't
happen
as opposed to that with a Dr unit
affects
you can connect them anyway and the
chain so you can use them with players
or you can use them with the input No
these are the list of the fact that we
currently have available
arm it's on the effects side we have the
delay distortion
EQ and reverb sure musician you're
probably already familiar with these
effects
so you can use them and real-time I use
them but the player arm
and on the time effects i'd we have the
baby speed and the time pitch
and these effects are useful in cases
where you want to manipulate the amount
of time stretching
maybe the pitch the source content so
let's say that you have
a speech file that you're playing and
you want to pitch the Y sup
to sound like a chipmunk well you could
do that
using wanna peacetime fix so let's now
look
an example how you can use one of these
affect in this example I'm gonna make
use
a BBQ but note that over here
I've connected the EQ directly to the
output node
in all of my prying samples I was
connecting
and notes to the mixers to be engines
mixer known
but I don't always have to do that if I
just have one
chain AppData in my application
and I can just directly connected to the
output known which is what I've done
here
so AR this is a multi-bank
EQ and I specified the number of banned
from going to use when I create an
instance a BBQ
so over here I'm going to use too bad so
I create an EQ two bands
I can then go ahead and get access to
each other bands
and set up the different filter
parameters connecting the EQ
is no different from what we've already
seen I can connect the player
to the EQ with the files processing
format and connect the EQ
the engine's output node with the same
format and that said
so with all this information
let's look at them all that makes use of
some other notes that brief talk about
okay
someone explain what I have here well
here I have to clear notes
and each of these players is going to be
fed by a separate
by separate looping buffers each other
players
are connected to separate effects and
each of these affects
a connected two separate inputs up the
engines main mixer
I have control over the output volume
up the main mixer and down here
I have a transport control which
essentially controls a note
tap that I've installed on the main
mixer so when I hit record
atop gets installed and I capture that
data and save it to a file
and then when I had play I'm just gonna
play that file black
so let's listen to what the sounds like
so the
sure I am playing the drums I can change
the volume
and the pan of each player
taken here that effect
now gonna go ahead and played the reverb
a little bit sounds a little too
someone keeping about here let me start
the other player
okay so what i thought i do now is used
the note app
to maybe capture a little life
performance
and any changes that I make to any of
the notes here
should be captured in that performance
so when we go back and listen to that
we should hear that let me do that
good
K
some gonna stop my recording stop
mightily
there and let's go back and listen to
the recording
good
and that's a preview
of AB Audioengine action go back
slides alright so to have the settings
that I was changing
on with the players well the volume
and the pan for each player but these
are actually settings
be of the input mixer bus at the players
connected to
so the wave weave exposed mixer input
bus settings
in the AM maybe Audioengine is through a
protocol
Cali if the audio mixing protocol source
nodes
conform to this protocol so the player
node and the input node
do that and settings like volume
you can change by just doing cleared of
volume equals .5
a player not ban equals -1 when a source
node is an active connection
with the mixer and you make change it
changes to the protocols different
properties
they take effect immediately however if
a source node
not connected to a mixer and you make
changes to the protocols properties
those changes I cashed in the source
node
and then applied when you make a
physical connection
to a mixer so these are the mixing
properties that we have available
under the common mixing properties we
just have all you right now
under the stadium mixing properties we
have pan
and we have a number of 3-d mixing
properties
that we're gonna look at in the next
section so
inform diagram let's say that I have
play 01 connected
to make someone and I go ahead and set
play 01 start pan
to -1 heart pendant the latter and clear
ones volume 2.5
so these mixing settings I'm now
Associated with play one and because
play once connected to mix 01
they also get applied on the mixer if I
were to disconnect
play one and connected to make sis to
these mixing settings
travel along with play 01 and get
applied
to make sure to so in this sense we've
been able to
catty settings that belong to input
possible mixer
along with the source node itself
alright
so let's now move on to the next section
on gaming and 3d audio
so in games typically you have
several types of songs that you play you
have short sons
and we've seen audio services which is
one of us capi skid use for that
for playing music we see if the audio
player
getting used a lot and for sounds that
need to be specialized
opening hours the API of choice now
while each of these APIs
worked really well for what they were
designed for if your application has to
make
use of all of them ban wanna biggest
trade-offs that you have to familiarize
yourself for the nomenclature
Associated with each API in addition
with on your services you don't have a
latency can t help when your sound will
play
with AV audio player you can play sounds
that you have and buffers
and with opening L you can play sounds
directly from a file
a play compressed data with our
knowledgeable AV audio engine
if we have to go back and cover cases
1&2 we can easily do so
for short sounds we can just load them
into a view audiobook hot checks
and schedule them on a player for music
you can just our create maybe audio file
object
and schedule that directly on a player
so how do you play sounds that need to
be specialized
will look at that now I like to
introduce
a new note call the environment node and
this is essentially
3d mixer so when you create an instance
of the environment note
com you have a 3d space
and you get an Elis know that implicit
to that treaty space
all the source notes that connect
to the environment node act as sources
in this 3d space so the environment has
some attributes
that you can set directly on the
environment node and then each of the
sources have some attributes
and you can set that using the AV audio
mixing protocols 3d properties
nine-term some data formats I just want
to point out
but when you're working with the
environment node all the sources
need to have Amano data format in order
for that
audio to be specialized if the sources
have a stereo data format
and that data as poss through and
currently the environment no doesn't
support
a data format greater than two channels
on input
so as a diagram as one looks like I've
created
an instance of an environment node which
means I now have a TD space
and I have an implicit listener I now
create to plan notes
we're gonna act as sources in my 3d
space
and using the AV audio mixing protocol I
can set it all up the source
attributes so what makes things sound
greedy
of virtual 3d well we have a number of
attributes
and some belong to the sources others
belong to the environment
let's walk through each to the source
attributes first
so every source has a position in this
3d space
and right now it specified using the
right-handed cartesian coordinate system
a positive access to the right positive
why is up
and positive the stewards the listener
now with respect to the listener the
listener uses
some spatial cues to localize the
position up the source
there's an intraoral time difference
just a slight
a slight time difference for the sound
made by the source
to get to each one of the listeners
years has also
and in Doral level difference in
addition
your head has the effect doing some
filtering
and you also have some filtering here
with the years the pin on the years
so we have several rendering algorithms
and each one of them are the spatial
cues differently
the thing is that we fix post this as a
source property
so you can pick rendering algorithm poor
source
and some other items may sound better
depending on the type of content
your source is playing and also they
differ in terms of CPU cost
summit you may wanna pick a more
expensive algorithm
for an important source and a cheap
bother them
for a regular source
the next two properties obstruct
obstruction and occlusion
deal with the filtering of sound into
obstacles between the source and listen
up
so in this case I have the source that's
the monster
and the listener that the handsome
prince and as a column
between the source and the listener for
the direct pop
of sound is muffled West that reflected
pots
across the walls are clear and this is
modeled by obstruction
on the other hand if the source
and the listener I and different spaces
to right now there's a wall
between the source and the listener both
the direct pappas on
and reflected parts of Sun I muffled
let's not move on to the listener a the
environment attributes
so every environment has an implicit
listener and the listener has
a position an orientation the position
is specified using the same coordinate
system
and for the orientation you can specify
using either to actors
up front and then up Victor or three
angles
your pitch and roll
you also have distance attenuation in
the environment
which is just the attenuation of sound
as a source
moves away from the listen up so in this
car after two points of interest
there's the reference distance which is
the distance about
which we start applying some amount of
attenuation
there's also the maximum distance which
is the point about which
the amount of attenuation being applied
is capped
so all the exciting stuff happens
between the reference distance
and the maximum distance and in that
region
we have three coats that you can pick
from
so the form of code this is what it
looks like all you need to do is get the
distance attenuation prime news object
from the environment and then you can go
ahead and tweak all the settings
now every environment also has
reverberation which is just a simulation
up the sound reflections within that
space
the environment note has a bit and
reverb and
you can pick from a selection of factory
presets
now once you picked the type of reverbed
you want to use
you can set a blend amount for each
source
and that just affects the amount of each
source that you're here in the refurb
mix
so for some sources you may want them to
sound completely dry
see set the blend margin:0 and other
sources you may want to sound more
ambient
so you can turn up the blend among we
also have a single filter
that applies to the output at the reverb
so let's say that you pick
one of the factory presets and you want
it to sound
maybe a little brighter you can do that
using the filter
in court this is what it looks like I
get the evil parameters object
from the environment in this case I'm
enabling it
and I'll order a factory preset the
large hole preset
and using the AV audio mixing protocol I
set the sources reveal blend
2.2 so now we've talked about two types
have mixers
you have the 2d mixer and you have the
treaty mixer
and source nodes but as the player the
input node
talk to these mixers using the AV audio
mixing protocol
so I just wanted to point out when a
source node is connected to a 2d mixer
than all of the common and the to be
mixing properties
take affect when a source node is
connected to a treaty mixer
then all of the common and a 3d mixing
properties take affect
let's look at what that looks like here
so let's say that I have clear one who's
connected
to the 2d mixer I set
up and to be -1 and volume 2.5
note that band is a 2d mixing property
but volume is a common mixing property
in this case both have them will take
affect
because the mixer known implements both
of these properties
if I disconnect play 01 from the mixer
and connected to the environment node
the pan property will now be cached it
doesn't take affect
because it's a 2d mixing property it
doesn't apply to the environment no
volume on the other hand will continue
to take affect
because it's a common mixing property
and it's implemented by the environment
out
so with all that information let's look
at a sample gaming setup
now this is just one of many ways that
you can do this
and this is just a suggestion it really
all depends on your application
but in this case I have to 3d sources
some going to use a player to play some
sounds they'll be specialized
and also live input so let's say that
the users chatting
and then you wanna specialized that in a
3d environment
I can connect the pair node and the
input node to the environment out
and that's connected out for the engines
main mixer
I can now have a second player I'm going
to dedicate
to playing music so this players going
to play music
and I'm gonna run it through an EQ and
connect that
to the main mixer let's say that I
present some UI
for the user so that he can tweak the EQ
settings
maybe to make music sound better
I have a third player now that I'm going
to dedicate
on the to you I sound effects so maybe
the sounds that are made
I think navigate through menus or if my
game avatars picked up a bonus item
except up so the the UI player is
connected
directly the engines main mixer
this is what the overall picture looks
like
so given all this information let's now
look at a demo
at the environment held
someone explain what's happening over
here in this demo
I am using scene kid for the graphics
and sink it also comes with the physics
engine
so this works nicely with AVI Kenjon
so I basically have two types us on Sat
I'm playing
that though son that place and that's
before
any ball is launched so to do that
I use a player node and I have
a the lawn sound effect in a buffer and
I schedule that buffer on the player
known
but I make use of the completion handler
to know when the player has consumed the
bottle
so when the player lets me know that
it's done with the buffer
I go ahead and now create a scene kid
node
that's a ball and i also create and AB
audio player note
attach it to the engine and connect that
to the environment note so I'm coming up
clear
a dedicated player to each ball
now the ball is launched into the world
and as it goes about
and collides with other surfaces for
every collision that happens
scene kids physics engine lets me know
that a collision as happened with some
other surface
and I get the point of collision and
also the
a imparts so
using back I can go all and dig up the
player note
that's tied to the scene kid note
I can't set the position on the player
based on where the collision happened
calculate a volume for my collision
sound based on the impulse
and then just play this out
but you can see now how in this setup I
for every ball that's born into this
world
a nuclear north is also created so the
number of players is growing and I'm
dynamically
attaching it to the engine and
connecting it to the environment known
so the setup is very flexible
I let's go back slides that brings us to
the end of our talk
so let's quickly summarize all the
things we've seen today
we started off talking about an engine
and how you can create different nodes
attach them to the engine and then use
the engine to make connections
between each of these notes we then look
at the different types of notes
on a destination node which is the
output node
and we talked about to source nodes the
player known
and input no the player is the
know do you use to push on your data on
that end the threat
we looked at two types of mixer notes
the 2d mixer
and a 3d mixer and
house source nodes talk to these mixers
using the AV audio mixing protocol
we then looked at effect notes and two
types a perfect notes the AVR you need
to fax in abit unit time
pics finally we
talked about no taps and that's how you
pull data from the end the threat
Sun I just want to point out that no
tops also useful debugging tool
let's say that you have a number of
connections in your application
and things don't sound the way you
expect them to sign
what you can do is install no taps at
different points in your chain
on different nodes and just examine the
output I V chip these notes
and using that you can drill down where
the problem is so in that sense no taps
a useful debugging tool
so that brings us the end of our session
I just wanna say that
this is the first version of AB
Audioengine and be a very excited about
it
so we'd love to hear what you think
please try it out
and give us your feedback if you have
any further questions at a later point
you can contact Philip whose I graphics
and game
technologies evangelist