by come to mastering multimedia playback
my name is stepping up nigga
amended
a team
if you're using a banged-up a BK to a
foundation
no ISOs and applications this the right
vision for you
the goal of the session to show you how
easy and powerful
me get their tickets when I was 8
endorsed in Yosemite
if more sessions focus on other major
operations later today
and this week you refer it to those at
the end of this talk
in the first part of this talk I'm going
to introduce you to a ticket by OS
and show you why and how we should use
it in your applications
but also give him everything overview of
the most important
API additions and changes and you I'm
behavior yet for the
bf for you this year in a week at
force10 in the second part of this talk
iconic shiny so who 32 best practices
for using a ticket in eighty foundation
you I S and with an application's before
that in
let's take a quick look dark on me to
stick in Iraq's on the lowest level if
the comedy a framework
to call home what and yes there a top of
a commute yes it's a V Foundation
a powerful objective-c framework they
provide to easy access to me yesterday
finally when you I kid leather
we have to meet up their framework
burden you I providing you
petechiae in the form of handling the
player controller
this year and I was 8
reading a new framework but AB kid
replacing parts of the media player
framework
AB kid
is on you high-level Media Framework
trying to access the rest of them
yesterday
not going to show you on this talk with
disabilities hopes up
for the IRS applications to be clear
not deprecating and people keep their
control I and II 8 but we're strongly
encouraging you to dock AB kit for me a
plate against that
so you have it
on what I mean yes they can I O S for
those of you
with north and background you might see
that is
spirits pretty similar tell me that the
gun was 10 you're correct
infect the same now on both I O S
endorsed 10 and will allow you to create
and maintain
cross-platform applications easier than
ever and now
I mean to do today to get 50 s sup to
now
be provided with two options for media
playback an IRS and people keep their
control a
and it's the Ivy control a companion mp3
player the controller
and any foundation society might be
using mp3 player controlling
applications
which means get that athletic you I
popular access to the media stack
which means you're limited to basically
a playback
all you might be using a foundation
and aspects as the mean yes that into
things beyond basic media playback
but you've done for many on play
together in the face finally
some up to you in the audience might be
the process of getting me a plane ticket
applications
maybe Tom in these two options you want
to make your life
as developers easier and that's why it's
something you follow a few
every kit provides the boss that's
played a controlled and behave yes
but in your full access to the modern
yes that
for any foundation last yet we entered
as a beacon rs.10
this year hearing every kid over to IRS
growth maybe can I O S
it's right here youll ever facilities
for media operations
on top of AB foundation and you like it
me a plague on IRS
is no easy a and more powerful than ever
any clear view controller
sorry every kid and I US just as any
player view controller up
state-of-the-art you're a subclass
rights to the same look and feel
as I'll be doubly cations and existing
and him we play our control API
he made it really easy for you
tied up any player view controller you I
was at the cations
let me show you the necessary steps in
the demo
sonics coat betrayed and you I was
application
we select the amplification template and
then press the next button
as the name we enter every kid player
press Next again
Sep the project on the desktop
now
we select the app delegate
implementation and the first you have to
do is to impart
AB foundation and at a big hit
then medication the finish launching
with options
the first written a replay of the
Comptroller by calling every play every
controller
up in it and then
betrayed maybe play object calling any
player with URL
and then years and this panel member
under you at for resource extension
and recessed name is going to be a long
boring and extension m.o.b
is that the playoff tix on a plan view
controller
let me set the if they have you control
at the retreat review controller
of our window finally
we have to move it move your project
and if we now build and run
you can see we have a fully functional
planning application miss was just be
lines of code basically
but example is probably not what your
application would look like
so let's switch to a different project
the first run this and show you what it
is
so this is very simple
me a planning application also media
library will have a reputation
and it's using the mustard interview
control a template
send the must have you here we have a
list of movies
and freed up the movie better company
over
the name of the file and Summit the
Federation anarchic one of the movies
you see that in the Detail View we have
some information about the movie
and describe oxy a and the rest of this
demo and not going to at
any player view controller and so you're
part of it up
three-start by modifying the main story
bought
as you can see here already have a
container view
29 object library
research for levy controller
checkin in San star star bart
office or you have it and then using a
controlled record
and she is embedded
and that began today play Wii U
controller up for going to interview
now we need to select the Segway
an inspector give it and identify a
in this case we just year's show movie
since we're using every player
controlling the storyboard
lots have too many link against the if
you could let
library from a so falling from UConn
libraries
we had a new framework sweet I pin
every kid selected in a press that
button
and now we have to modify didn't have
the control implementation
again the first thing we have to do is
to impart they had a fire
to import a foundation and impart any
kid
know when to implement the prepare for a
sec with send a
limitation the first
respect for the be taken into fire when
make sure that is so movie
then
get a BKB controller which is the this
mission control of the Segway
and finery be creating a play at the
same as we did before but using play
with you al
and as the to the control as a movie
property which itself Saur
and he said there's a tear up let's play
object
on the play Wii controller we know
burden run
conflict in moving can see that the
movie is not a Kia
and we can press player an impressive
was going button
goes into full screen and annotated to
landscape
they can see it's fully working right
sex I wanna show you highly-paid the
controller works and a foundation
city for those of you in the audience
that and you take the foundation a plan
view controller
but the strong reference in any playoff
checked this object provides the content
and every playoff segment is in a play
item which says the mutable data
structure
from in middle and yes at this means
knows what content on any play the
controller if through the following
steps:
first
Creighton ABS it from an issue for see I
can either be a look if I on this
or remote URL it may be s at
going to rate maybe play item 17 every
play item you can trade name play object
and finally such as a replay of sex with
the a player view controller
but if you don't
need to inspect any properties just
south of the content and just want to
play but every player the Contra
in two of us that's at once sex on you
in the demo
indirectly create and every play object
come in an issue rather
imparted to the replay view controller
and as a chance that the only reason why
inspected the ABS too far
was in order to implemented on public
use interface maybe kid
don't use anymore said he would take a
look at the replay the eventual API
my notice that set the player property
there isn't really much more
but there's so much stuff just get just
get automatically
the any further set up here's a list of
the most important every play every
battle a few just for your reference
might notice that is mostly identical to
mp3 player controller
never reason for that you want to make
your condition to educate
s easy as possible but doesn't you not
familiar with a movie player controller
let me show you what is he just makes
you look like a plate you control a
has a depth player controls is different
from
mp3 player controller and every player
be on August 10 instead of setting a
certain controlled style
anyplace you control automatically
adapts the cup and control set for you
justice on the demo when you show a
movie in bed at
unification and use a presence that
episode types they're pushing button
a player you control automatically
switches to put simply the controls
you don't want to show any controls at
all
select the option to hide them be taken
to assess the democratic control its
sofa converts chapters tapping the
Seebeck what was the comment button
fix the previous an acceptor for content
with this ruling it just subtitles
if they're going to let the media
selection button
along the user to select a different
audio a subtitle track
the name it also means
they play view controller met get
switched to defensive player controls
for live streaming content don't have to
do anything
finally
a play view controller has built-in
support about at play
and HDMI sony's enables airplay
pop acts an HDMI adapter application
automatic present the content on
external screen
keeping the player controls on the IRS
device sexy I replied you're going to
last
ends up again something we've never
trust a fun every major feature
as a better than any kid as well but if
you look closely
we notice one difference as I mentioned
before
a plate you control a america's elect to
close at four you
so this to less less for you to worry
about
but actually there's a lot more
let's take a look it up there Graham
from earlier for bed
if you want to replace the country play
item
did you use your place tonight Smith
play item on any player
but if you already know in advance for
the next item is going to be
you can have any foundation navel gazing
at you
to get smooth playback and switching to
the next play item is an energy player
if you play as a subclass of any player
the closet and
you a list a replay items each of which
is backed by
yes it
everything I'm showing it today and what
every player contra excess 582 pass
while
25 just talked about basically a play
that
with a foundation you can do a lot more
all
every composition the subclass ABS at
lawsuit a great mighty clip
and might attract media compositions
as a result the seventy years and our me
sum up your video editing applications
it doesn't matter if you provide
anyplace you control a maybe play item
that ban ABS said on a decomposition
either works fine
a composition sought to enter points to
you more advanced features
for instance it may be a composition
allows you to apply FN transforms
and simple chat to the transitions
popular content
you can even create your own custom
composite asked to create all kinds of
the effects
any arguments provides a similar
functionality for your tracks
any given position at the autorads
working combination any foundation sorry
any composition you want to analyze
25 with allies raw data during playback
you can use them to order processing tap
is it just a few classes today finish
provides you for many operations beyond
basic media playback
you want to learn more about this topic
take a appear as BBC sessions
like this one from last year and related
sent a card
let's take a look again at all this to
pay pay via Kentucky chess
says that shown in this talk in Pavia
pantalla
just the same he just sort of the same
features century player controller
but due to the full access to any
foundation
you get so much more
let me show you what can you do know a
foundation dedicated
your own I was at the cations
so there's an iPad version of the movie
Live evocation that his earlier to show
you how to use a player contra
and this demo I can now add the effect
the movies
as you can see edit that you could
affect to this movie
right now the effect is your impact I
want to stop dragging him goes up or
down
you can see how I can change certain you
that is in the movie
each and they represent you value on the
columbia and changing ahead and modify
set color
ship the cuts are different value
against up to any frame in the movie for
just the values
see a helmet for instance
let's go back to the beginning it's a
plane
says he can see the effects applied in
real time
and on the right edited with digital
media but also the
volume for the left and right on your
chin up during playback
not to do all of this applications is in
a fantastic position at the I
dimension 2400
a week it continues to menace the user
interface just as adults
for basic media playback cases
not have shown you how easy it is to
adopt any player view controller
many of the cation and what amazing
things you can do in commission a
foundation
I hope you can't wait to adopt any
player view controller the existing
applications
not too happy with the condition
I'm going to highlight the necessary
steps for the three common scenarios
in the first scenario
using any player layer and possibly
implemented on to use interface
thought of by replacing any player they
are back to you I've you
and user interface type: eric is
interface but every player you can trust
you
then that the player property on a plate
you control a and set up a play earlier
never chance that most of the remaining
coat with the unchanged
lessons and specially I needs if you're
using and can we play our view
controller
just her place and he will be clear view
controller lol in a bit continue for
by every player view contra ataque in it
and then create an associate the replay
object
attorney before however
if you are also accessing the engine
repair contract property
that scenario supplies Tia city using
and can we play contra on your vacations
it in with a couple more properties and
methods but don't worry
the conditions exit quite
straightforward and can be played on
track I can be grouped into two classes
uses a pic API across the pacific API
in the former case you use a plan you
can't relate the I
analytic a CD player and then play item
API
things like and the movie era la can
improve the excess lock
actually very thin wrapper object around
every play item X is looking to play at
a maryland for instance
yet to thank you much just you should
watch out for them
as I mentioned before
a player you can trust controlled first
and then it so there's no set a property
also and the movie play contra ought to
place by default
a player does not do that this anything
you cannot do I do not know how to do
with AV Kidney Foundation and switching
over from
from anti-nuclear controller Stockton
elapse
ask us and developer forums Letterkenny
if I S in our state
being a ticket over from was 10 as on
you I'll ever need a framework for a
foundation
a player the Contra provides just enough
to control its
and behavior give you full access to a
powerful multimedia stack
to please consider adopting any player
controller
and you I of the cations finally
want to give you a brief update on a
because 10
as he said yesterday in a keynote
what's in your seventy receive the I
refreshed that there is out
with a brand new UI for a week as well
if you're using a replay review
applications were received in you I
automatically going to change a single
line of code
up to ten in the fight you're not using
any baby yet
despite a good time to adopt the
introduction of a ticket buyers
what's out there in some user interfaces
and behaviors a player view
to make a pledge a controller you want
to learn more about how to use a clear
view
to check out last yes moving to a ticket
in eighty foundation
session and finally
for brand new class for you this year
and it was 10
he kept on you provide to you never
capture facilities
into a foundation napkins not being
intended it as an aficionado is coming
to the chemical to talk tomorrow morning
process in the lab said it is
interesting to you and now
then head over to fill a foundation
engineer to show you how to get the most
out of
a ticket and a foundation the IRS and
authentications
thank you Thank You chiffon
good morning I'm shyly foul an engineer
on the V Foundation team
and I'm here to talk to you today about
best practices before we get into the
details of these practices
for a show of hands how many of you have
used a B foundation before
lots love you
for you I would hope this section 3rd as
an update
or refresher on best practices as
technology
a balance with time so do best practices
for those of you want you to leave the
foundation
I hope this serves as a guideline on how
to approach
abit let's get started by talking about
why you would be interested in adopting
such practices
what's the motivation these practices
are designed to make your application
as efficient and perform and that's
possible making it responsive
doin users not only help with the
application
efficiency but also help make your
program
yeah help improve your program
correctness making it robust
and preventing any thoughts of Hank up
precious
media obligations some banks make use of
expensively sources like netbooks
these best practices our Design so that
you can make efficient use of such
resources
and lastly users will be thankful for
the improvement they see in their
battery life
as your application uses very little
about
here's a modern media fact we looked at
only in this top
eighty foundation sits on top of coal
media and its family a framework
and on top it AB kid which provides you
with standard playback controls with
just few lines of code
the focus for this section today is best
practices
specifically in the areas of inspection
and playback
if you would like to gain more
information about eighty foundation in
general
you can look at this stock from the BBC
call exploring AB foundation
based on the two major categories for
any
AB foundation object I'm ordered
separately
for the first category we didn't spec
Shin ABS and is an example
with any BS it as a client on this API
you want in charge
of eroding values whenever you need it
in your application
you can initiate I O and men AB
foundation request
the thieves a request for I O we go and
do all the looting work
so you can get a value the best practice
here
is to request values a synchronously why
a thing is loading
rely on to that in just few slides
for the other category would display
back AB player and playwright them
other controller object all you have to
do here
it's free and easy items and then he
should be back
eighty foundation and its underlying
machinery drive
in the playback Clark so that the user
fee
media freedoms on bank so when you hit
play
we drive the necessary machinery select
you use again experience a small
playback
as time progresses properties change and
if you would like to keep your
application
state up to date with the feed on the
Playback Engine
you can use and SQL you observing to be
notified
of such changes and if you are you
observing is also called at gave you
here's a look at are object diagram from
earlier
Stefan show you in a demo how to use
these objects and create a simple media
application
now let's use this as a roadmap for
talking about best practices
class by class starting with ABS said
as I mentioned earlier with AB asset you
can use
any if you can if you value loading
while poverty by method
which lets you load property a
synchronously before accessing them
for example if you're interested in the
precise duration opacity
you cannot be punishing for the duration
and redownload just about dried them on
to bigger
to be able to tell you what the duration
it but I'm file format it
straightforward
and that somebody information right up
ahead so we can download just that the
sub ita
but that's not always the case
sometimes many of us what you're a shin
any foundation would have to download
the entire fund into the media file
bar said be coated before we can give
you the value for a precise duration:
you might our why should I do anything
gonna keep a B foundation has to do all
this work
the Lord values or it big time to load
values
well you really should I'll I don't
spend
if you tried to access a property think
honestly by
accessing a ghetto before loading the
property
you would be blocking a main thread
leading to a spin and making your
application
unresponsive doin user
on a stand however you can dispatch this
work to a background
cue to access the get a and you 1 p.s
penny
met on I with loading think lesly from
any thread would block your application
and could lead to a hand a crash
this is because as you may already know
on i OS
we have a shared demand by media so they
be
with services media requests on behalf
of your application
if you tried to access a property
synchronously you would be bang media
seventy
or forcing me to 72 Lord aware you and
this might be
time this leads to a timeout
and media services domination
this not only affects your application
but every other application on the
system
which relies on media services so please
don't do that
now that we know that a good reason to
use ABA's even if the value loading
there don't want things to remember for
key
only load those properties you and this
baby using your application
every extra property means more work if
you intend to not use a particular
property
do not in Goa the wasted work
and the second thing is if you and it's
been the use of a particular property
you doing your application
you can still request all of them
together using
note values a synchronous people key and
completion handler
you can Boston and i do. he's eighty
foundation would
will go together and your conclusion
handler is called
once we are done loading these
properties
you no longer have to learn tracks
before playback begin
this has changed since the last time we
talked about best practices
in fact this has changed since I was 5
you really only need to load those
property you would directly use in your
application
now let's look at how ABA think a nifty
value loading
conflates into court in this particular
example
I'm interested in loading the property
the open
I boson an atty the displayable in it
and I provide a completion handler
in my completion handler I first check
to make sure the properties loaded
sometimes things go wrong like if you're
relying on the netbook resource
and usable the light goes out of range
after blowing can feel
so this is a good place to check with
such adonis
once you get the status you can see if
it's already loaded
and then you're gonna be a quoi or up
for the asset
are if there's a failure you can abort
and appropriate EDA
to you end-user one more thing to
remember with completion handler
is if another module has already loaded
the keys you're interested in your
completion handler is called back
immediately stay in this example
if a beep leo has already landed the
playable property
your completion handler is called
synchronously on the same
thread if you have poured which relies
on load values a thing that people can
use to get done
immediately that might not happen though
the completion handler has executed
so that's something to keep in mind to
prevent a deadlock
lift the best practices for Absa
not only does he's you're interested in
using in your application
you can use a BA thinking if you value
noting the list all the fuse together
in an atty and you can provide a
completion handler but despite want your
downloading this property
and your completion handler check to
make sure the properties are loaded:
before you access them
and lastly be prepared for synchronous
call back
if someone else has already loaded the
property on your behalf
yet read if I'd your completion handler
is buyback
immediately those were best practices
for Absa
now let's look at every player and
playwright and
as I mentioned earlier but they be
clearer and clearer I do
the playback engine under the underlying
playback engine drives the machinery
necessary so that your user fees we your
dreams on bank
so you have to do is use and if the
value observing RKB 0
to be notified of the change it so that
you can update your application state
here's an example if you have a
progressive download item
on an HTTP fella as a bee foundation
download some data
you get the ball back with the loaded
range as a buffer more data
you get get on the ball back with the
updated value for the Lagrange
a take an example of bacterial might
come in handy
its playback interruption if you use and
divide the deceived
8 phone call or FaceTime call when
you're application is being a paedophile
your playback is interrupted so that you
use again on for the call
in this case if you do you think AB or
on the player 38
you would see it transitioned is eel
this is a good
there is a good way for you doing be
notified of such interruption
so that your dont and upgrading and
lately probably back to end
and the last example here is media
services to be fit
as I mentioned earlier if your
application of some other application
wasn't paying attention to ABA thinking
it's p-value loading
and try to access a property think
honestly you have forced media server
need to dominate
this FX your application do your media
services %uh defect
amend this happened your plate icon
status transition to feed
and this is the place for you did throw
away all your lead object and rebuild
your player and playwright them
defending a playback
let's look at an example in court make a
view might come in handy
in this example I would like to decide
when to show or do you only you I in my
application
your I first created playwright amid an
acid
then I tried to access the tracks
property of an acid particularly
up by video and then I checked to make
sure
that the media Trac then only your
tracks before I obeyed my UI dual audio
only
this is not compete he got a firstly
we're trying to access the tracks
property on acid
without prior loading it this good
blocking a main thread and make your
application and responsive
and the second thing here is an
assumption that lack of media Trac
means audio only you can have
non-renewal Richard Wright
like subtitle in your movies
now let's look at how I can do this
using k Beale
I add myself as an observer for the
presentation size
on a playwright and and months AB
foundation is downloading the
presentation face
your observational buyback first check
to make sure that your presentation
thighs and feet away
you know this way you know not have the
tracks have a non-zero presentation safe
cannot do that make sure you have
accused
1 %uh audio track to do that
you can look at the underlying a be at
the track and make sure that
there's ok he's one of them which has a
AB media characteristic audible
this is necessary because sometimes you
can have movie filed
which have non over $10,000 by you know
for the presentation sized
but no audio track like bangor tracks
the PBRs be we just used before us
create a playwright amid an asset
then be there just about the value
observing the property of interest
after that me associate the bleary-eyed
amid the player
and in your observation by back you can
look at the change dictionary
to know what the new value is this is
the day to be when you work with these
objects
but if you want things to remember when
you're interacting with these objects in
general
but not assume the order in which events
up up
as soon as you associate a playwright
amid the player
85 nations dot its underlying machinery
so that
you're using an expedient this mod
playback
on Iowa 7 be made an optimization
beating this
the status to ready to play much more
quickly
so if you want to add yourself as an
observer after you create a plea over
the playwright him
you could miss this white notification
the pink this you can add yourself as an
observer before associating you play
item in the play okay
that way you won Miss any notifications
are sometimes in your application you
might have a particular fan i do.
where you would like to add yourself as
an observer
only of good any bank see if a user
presses a button
in touch basis you been used and if the
value observing
option initiated this flag lets you
access the initial value as well as in
you and you
the second thing to remember is that AB
foundation theory licensed the access to
every player and playwright him
on the main cue it safe to access
and register and unregister for
observers
for these objects on the mean cue this
was done to prevent any possible
refinishing
as might have been more used to
interacting with these objects
and make you was a natural choice as
most of these observations buyback
lead to your applications in traction
but you like it objects
which also happened on me cue
however this does not mean that we are
doing our work on a min Q
we are not effecting the end-user
responsiveness
all loading and playback related what
happens on the background cue
the only feel like the access to these
objects on the mean cue
if in your application you have a
particular sin i do. for
makes you think this requirement is a
hindrance please come talk to us in our
labs
of I'll enhancement request they are
really interested in listening to your
feedback on this
and the last thing to remember is
wherever possible
set up your playwright him before
associating it with the player
as I mentioned earlier as soon as you
create a player
AB foundation starts driving its
machinery so that we can get ready for
playback
for example if you have a streaming item
as soon as you create a player
we go over the network and start
downloading data from the fourth time
and after that if you are def issue a
thick dude I'm
we would have to throw away all the data
we downloaded and start reloading up
fascists to begin playback
in order to bring in that whenever
possible you can always fun video player
item
before associating it with the play here
here's a few examples up the banged-up
on for the nation's you can do
this is definitely not the exhaustive
list but just a few
you can add outputs you can select media
options like audible and legible
you can fact followed and robust
playback and times I seek the time
and after doing all those changes I can
associate my clear I don't the player
in somebody for any player and a ride em
use an FTP are you observing to be
notified of changes
at the Playback Engine is driving the
clock
did got so that you use again experience
this mode play back
do not rely on the order in which event
up to if you really need a budget lol
you can always use and if the value
observing option any Shin
auto add yourself as observers before
you create a player
the fear life your access to play and
play item on the main cue to avoid any
boys big race conditions
lucky menopausal set up your plan died
in bed autoconfiguration
before creating a player those were the
best practices for
AB player and fan item most of the
things we don't know about
AB player also applied to a BBQ player
as you've seen earlier in this top a V
QPR take a list of playwright and
if in your application you have an
Inspector window
for which you would like to access a set
of keys on each of the brand items
you can use AB playwright them spend
mean an initializer
which lets you buy a set of keys which
AB cube lia aur abbo would yield
on your behalf you have a BBQ player
the list of items and if you initialize
each of these items into the set of keys
as a BQ player is getting ready to
initiate any should be back with a
particular item
reload the 15th in combination with the
keys require
for playback and as playback from
dresses and we teach the next item
we load the second set of keys you
requested for that particular item
this is valid for every player has been
if you're using replaced got and item
but derided
you can miss you can use this as an
alternate to ABA think a nifty value
noting
answer abusing a v8 thing if you are you
looking for each of the asset
you can initialize each of the brand
items and we'll take care of you reading
the property
and if you're using this in 30 periods
even if the value noting
the best place to access your property
would be to cameo the playwright and
status
many receive an observation by back for
the status
and if you up to me lol and if the
sentence is ready to play
you acted keys would either be loaded of
real so then you can use status of value
for key
to access this property
and the last thing to remember but
eighty cuba is if AB foundation en donde
as andado
with a body blow playwright him miss
give that item and move on
so that your user experiences
uninterrupted playback
however if you would like to be notified
of such I don't
you can NS email you observe a week you
play with God and item status
those were some tips for using a BQ
player lastly
let's talk about ATP a view controller
but the repair your gun drawn on highway
audio replay review on all with 10
it's a good idea to animate your view
India view hierarchy
only when there's some why the funding
to present
only if there's some video frames you
can chill and to do that
you can t value observed ready for
display on i OS
you would observe on the plan view
controller that as a nice tan you
observe on the blame you
got himself as an observer put any for
display
and in your observation buyback you can
check to make sure ready for displays
yes
before animating your view or before
like showing you
new NIOS 8 and North 10th and not then
its content to live you
but going to leave you you can do your
custom drying
and rendering or would the playable the
condo LabVIEW is guaranteed to have
similar dimensions as the plan view
and if you would like to place the order
drying tube relative to the radio for
him
you can access the media bronze property
on the play view controller
here's a screenshot above the demo Meath
audio the did you do what you need on
the bottom right
was rendered using going to leave you
and lastly what chapter navigation: as
you may have seen in QuickTime Player
when you see two chapters using the
appropriate keyboard shortcut to menu
items
big-time player briefly flashes the
Japanese were indicted
and if you would like to get similar
behavior in your applications
which we highly recommend you can use
this API I've
a deeply love you this is only on with
Dan the flash at the number and ID
ideally you would do this often seek has
completed
so you can place this code in your
completion handler for think the time
for the best practices for play Wii U
controller is to observe ready for
display to know when to present your
view on screen
so that you use it doesn't have to look
at black screen
thank you then we saw how do you respond
in to leave you want to do custom
rendering
over the play a few in the auto the baby
is below
and about that despondent over live you
and the control said on top
and lucky we saw how to flash up to numb
Japanese number and title
during chapter navigation: using every
period
that brings us to the end of I roadmap
for best practices
let's wrap up
below that why it's important the Lord
values a synchronously and how to do
that using a BA think a nifty value
looking for a bf it
but every player and playwright im all
you have to do is use and its key value
observing
to be notified of changes and made a bet
some tips for using
a BQ player we don't know about how to
observe
ready for display know when to present
your view India view hierarchy
and then we looked at how to customize
your plan view my custom drawings in
going to leave you
and displaying chapter numbers during
navigation
that was best practices for a be
foundational a ticket I lost topic but
to me
in somebody a big it is now available on
i OS
along with the West End AB can provide
you with standard playback controls with
just few lines of code
if you've been using it to get on ice 10
you get DUI refresh for free
you wouldn't have to change anything
we looked at the demo which shows how
powerful eighty foundation can be in
combination with AB kid
to provide you with an application with
standard pay back under oath
and to add FX and visualizations
we highly recommend you to adopt most
modern
up modern media very much and audit your
current applications
to see if they can stand to benefit by
adopting these best practices
for more information you can contact us
evangelism team
or visit art check out %uh programming
died on a double up a website
which guy was born baby foundation and
maybe get you can also contact us
on a developer forums
we have some related sessions lined up
for you for the rest of this week
starting midline this of known by
harnessing meta-data
in audiovisual media tomorrow morning
we show your camera capture with all its
new features
and AB capture view we mentioned earlier
in the stock
and on Thursday we show you how you can
directly access
a media encoders and decoders that's it
thank you for coming and I disagree