welcome to advance media for the web my
name's journal will and I
Safari land rendering team today we're
going to talk about what's new with
audio and video in Safari
and how media integrates with today's
modern web
so this is the video element it's the
heart and soul
web-based media on one hand its
container for some truly advanced
technology
but video elements are also just another
brick in the dop
they can participate layout rendering
they can be styled with CSS with the
video element media now be integrated
into the same
response obtained Emma designs being
written for the modern web
did you know helps tell stories rather
than being the story itself
modern examples such as New York Times
snowfall article show how you can
really video into a rich storytelling
experience
video can add emotion and energy to a
page
even the something already as exciting
as the new Mac Pro and I can still take
center stage
but these weren't always this easy let's
take a look back
back at how the video and became a part
love this exciting modern web
so in 1999 this was how you added
video to your website the QuickTime
plugin another time the QuickTime plugin
with amazing
you could decode high bit-rate video and
exposed to reach
API the JavaScript for a while plugins
with the only way
at the with video to your website now
fast forward seven years in a 2006
this was how you edit video to your
website the QuickTime plugin
again by now the QuickTime plugin
supported the H 264 codec
and it delivered even higher quality
video but it was still a plugin
one which users had a fine download and
install
well not you Mac users of course but
wasn't something which website
authors could depend upon being
available across all their entire
audience
in 2007 though this all changed the
video tag was introduced
this was an amazing breakthrough no
longer did web developers have to depend
upon a proprietary plug in to deliver
video in their pages
video with house now integrated directly
into the web where
and as an html5 specification video
element
provided a constant thinker consistent
experience
an API across all browsers and platforms
brothers could build on
improving add video features without
waiting for plugin developers
and this triggered a virtuous cycle
innovation 2009
the video tag came to mobile browsers in
iPhone OS three
support for the video and it was added
to Safari previously the primary where
users party within iraq with video
was by clicking on YouTube dot com link
which would open up the YouTube app
but now video with a first class member
mobile browsers as well
and today's I West devices
are almost as powerful if not more
powerful than
desktop computers sold in 2009 we talk a
lot about
the video on it have to view deputies
that are all the videos are at
developer datacom or on the WTTC at you
have in your phone
2010 recovered the basics
adding a video mature web page 2011 we
talked about how to take that video
element and add CSS and Javascript to
make your own custom
media controllers in 2012 we showed you
how to play back multiple media owner
synchronized with one another how did it
do advance slowly
see affects with the Web Audio API and
how to take your JavaScript based
controls full screen with a four-speed
yeah so what we learned at WWDC 2014
you learn how we've there I would the
differences between
arianna Wes Safari on a West End what
that means for your web pages
you learn the best way to stream adapted
media
on your website how to use
less power when playing back video
how to coordinate your media time line
with elements your page with the time to
meditate
yeah I but before we get started the
talk a little bit about like
now how good is the video element on I O
S
it is so good at that whenever I
encounter a page
on Safari on OS 10 that insists that I
need to use the flash plugin to view its
contents
the first thing I try is to turn
user-agent: iPad
most the time it works what's that all
about
well I know that no one here would
deliberately write a page that insisted
on using a plugin
when html5 video was available I miss
can assume you've updated your right
hand side
recently but please up take your desktop
site as well
I can't have a time and a place but as
web standards evolve in browsers improve
those times are getting fewer and the
places further between
at a good that speaking a browser's
approving let's talk about how we've
narrowed the differences between Safari
on I less
and a West we've removed from the
distinctions between the platform
a giving you more control over media
loading with the preload actually
my last and by allowing the video a
moment to fully participate
CSS Larry but first appeal it actually
the video on its preload attributes let
page authors
control when and how the media is data
is loaded a preload value
9 instructs the browser do preload no
meta data
value meta-data ask the browser only
downer that enough
media data to determine that divider
that media's with height
duration: center and a valuable
auto means begin loading media
sufficient to begin playback
now in the early days a bio s
there was a lot to be on the internet
which could be played by OS devices
so in order to be able to tell users
whether the
median the page was playable or not
safari with download
enough maybe data to check playability
but in order to keep users data costs
down
it would ignore the P look at you behave
as if it was set to preload none
in 2014 unplayable web media
much less of a problem so new and I'll
with aid
Safari will honor to preload values
meditator
which is the new default and not wise is
the right thing to do
a most sites will see no change in
behavior
either in a browser or on their server
but even loading just made it a dick
load up for sites with a lot of video
elements so
now the preload value non will be
honored now it's still true that on I'll
West loading
beyond that it will still require user
interaction we still believe
this restriction is in the user's best
interest
but it does get rid of one frustrating
distinction between Safari on
West and I'll so why is this important
for video elements which don't
explicitly specified
preload 9 they will begin meeting new
events specifically the loaded meditated
now during development week came across
a certain site
which had the following on their mobile
page had a video element
with people controls enable that when it
receives the loaded meditative event
with heightens
controls it did so to enforce users
watching their pre-roll ads
so I O S seven
the video on shown nothing would happen
when they had play loaded with progress
loaded meditative it would fire
withdrawals would hide I with 8
as soon as the video was added to the
page looting would begin
alluded meditative with fire and
withdrawals with high leaving the user's
no way it actually
playing the video how can they fix this
but they shouldn't do is revert to the
old behavior by adding
preload not that just leaves in place
the implicit assumption that loaded
creeper loaded meditative the video will
be in play that they should listen for
the enclave
and hide the controls when that occurs
let users play
so that's
thats Newman loading let's talk about
leary
in previous versions a bio s video over
was implemented as a you live you
which was placed on topic web content
new in Iowa eight we have integrated
into the Roman directly as a need a part
of the industry
just as it is on a Westin Safari as a
result
the video element will now fully respect
the SS layer rules
however
caveat web sites which did not
explicitly place their video
top CSS z-index property may see some
weird behavior
they could have their video appear below
other layers that it didn't appear below
before
or other layers appearing transparently
on top at the video where could
intercept hutchins even users know we
have actually playing the video mackie's
either
so please be on the lookout for these
breaking changes: your website that was
platform differences now let's talk
about how the best way to add
adaptive streaming your website so
today's web devices run the gamut from
small battery-powered mobile devices
desktop computers to big-screen TVs
and it led to improvement called
responsive web design
whose goals to provided optimal viewing
experience across a wide variety of
devices
I he learning a page to respond to
different characteristics
other device on which it's running now
most responsive web design concerns
itself with the
size at the viewport which the page
shown but for video
other properties the divisor as
important
so yes what
screen sizes available on your device
but also
what video resolution the device the
code what codecs a profile to the
delight
device support and how much bandwidth
devices internet connection provide at
its most basic
a video a moment points to a single file
webster with only a single file
0 page authors left with the on enviable
task of picking a single version metal
pipe olive their viewers
so perhaps a desktop device with a fat
internet connection
should get a lower high bitrate Street
while a mobile device
on Wireless Ron a cellular might need a
small
lower bitrate version but that same
device plugged in and on wifi should get
the large bitrate version
to the this is easy with a single file
sitting on your server
instead this is a job for HTTP Live
Streaming
or HLS so each EP live streaming as a
mechanism for delivering multiple
streams
in a single manifest file the matter
playlist
or manifest describes the
characteristics of each substrate
and the URL where that's a stream can be
accessed the browser
pick the appropriate stream based on the
characteristics of the current device
a safari on West End NIOS
use the ED foundation play work
framework to play
HLS streets you get the same high
quality streaming experiences
a diff s and eighty foundation will
seamlessly switch streams
when conditions the network in the
device change to show you how easy it is
degree each left playlist with multiple
streams have different characteristics
my colleague brent for Jim will walk you
through the process rent thank each year
my name's friend full German I'm also
in his ear and WebKit layout and
rendering team and today I wanted to
a show you a few examples a
HLS and how might make you like better
now I'm sure that
getting up here the first thing you
thought was this guy is a skater
right I mean I love it I film it
and I had some great video that I wanted
to show off
that we filmed in Utah high fidelity
video
beautiful cinematography if I do say so
myself
wonderful wonderful a content and I
wanted to share this with
my friends and family who couldn't be
there that day so
what I wanted to do was put together a
website that would
a that would show this content when he
returned
this alright so now I have a the
single-source a element playing a video
this is the
the content I showed you in QuickTime
Player just a second ago
and let's take a look at what that would
look like for art
viewers great look exactly the same as
what I did in QuickTime Player
a so I'm done right all my friends can
look at this
and tell me how great I am well
know it turns out that a number people
were trying to view this with
lower resolution devices iPhone's and
iPad's and things that
that don't have the full a.m. pixel
content love
a giant display per projection system
like this
and it turns out they didn't even watch
it because it just took to long
to play going back to the original video
we can kinda see why that is
its about 250 megabytes for eight
seconds a
a video and that's not going to make
make many people
wanna stick around and wait for that so
what do I do
well the first thing I I would want to
do is
take this original video in Crete
multiple in coatings that are targeted
or optimize for different devices so if
I have
iPhone's and iPad's I want to support i
want video streams are more
a.m. a suitable or optimize for that
and so you could do this using a variety
of tools we have iMovie
we have the Final Cut Pro if you doing a
lot of these you might want to look into
compressor which is a great application
for doing this
we all have QuickTime Player installed
on our computers
and so let me just show you what we do
here in QuickTime Player
we can export the video in a variety of
formats who have
1080 P E 720 P and we have a set
love presets they're already laid out
for different types of devices
and so in QuickTime Player I would have
to go to each of these presets
individually in
and Alberta 1080 P version now put a
a iPhone 3GS version
and so forth now I'm not gonna make You
wait around way
why export these since a that's boring
but what I will show you is a
what I will show you is the Sat Nav
video encodings
that i won up with and since I was
running through this briefly before we
thus I have stuff here that you don't
need to see a alright so I have these
video encoding secreted
a bunch of different versions that
support the different types of devices
that I
I'm that I want to support so I've got
a high resolution for broadband users
ago at lower resolutions for people on
cellular I've got out a broadband
wifi version and
saddam of that once I've uploaded these
to the web server
that I'm pretty much ready to go except
I need to make some changes to my
webpage
so if I go back to my a my webpage
example
instead of just having this one a
this one video element or this one video
source:
element that is giving me my a
high quality video or are my parece
video
I need to add a version what's and you
to add a version
that supports say my iPad air
so I have a retina iPad I have a source
that is
a slightly different a location
a a different filing coding so in this
case I'm I'm grabbing the broadband
media
and I'm using a sess media selector
that a limits the a
clients that are going to see this video
two items that have a 1024 by 768
resolution like you have an iPad in a
device pixel ratio to so I say okay this
is my iPad
a here and while I'm at it I probably
want to have something for
iPhones five in 5 S's and maybe
something for a bunch of all their stuff
and pretty soon we have a a pretty large
set
for sources the
for for us to the surfing this web
server
I
okay so if we look at at this now you
refresh the page
was a look like
a look exactly the same I'm getting the
same stream that I had before because
I'm still connecting to this with
a a high-quality a while loop active
network and I'm showing it on a giant
screen with lotsa pixels
up I'm still getting what I expected so
I should be done now right i mean i
I'm able to deliver the right content
all these different people on different
devices
time to go home and and put my feet up
and and get the congratulatory e-mails
remember when I I seem right well
it turns out my brother-in-law was
camping we can I posted this
and had really spotty Internet
connectivity was
attack on the edge network or something
so I asked him what he thought about me
he said why didn't bother watching it
because it took too long to
to download and and never made any
progress
and I realize well we dealt with the the
resolution here
but we haven't talked at all about
network band with
and that plays a role as well now
as a web developer what we do in this
case I could write some kinda
a networks sniffing
algorithm to try to figure out how much
band with his being used in the download
rates in this
as he'd like to be really hard the to do
properly would be really easy to get
wrong and would have to be maintained
but what about this HLS technology that
chair just finished telling us about
the reduction should take everything
seems like a good solution already have
all my encoded
video here so there's there's really I
I've already done the hard work creating
the different coatings for the different
device types
so now I need to do is generate the
HLS master manifest and
and information that H a little use to
display this content
not to do this we need to use the
dynamic duo a
media file segment ur and variant
playlist creator
and these are fantastic tools that you
can download from our for our website
on but as you might imagine from these
names
they have a dizzying array love flags
and
in and entry points that you have to
provide and so
it's very difficult to remember we did
up just creating a a
shell script to do this for us and so
let me just put this
up here and
okay in them let me giving minutes a
right write that down
and then 0 well thats that's probably
not a great idea
how about to become by our lab later
this week and we'll be happy to give you
copy this
I'm alright so what does this look like
when we run it well
what I do is a horrendous make it HLS
script
I'll provide us with I'm
our feet at the input at the various
files that we want to
use reprocessed into the files and what
that ends up looking like
is I have this magic in XM 308 which is
the master manifest
file and I have a series love transport
streams that have been generated for
each by
encodings so in this case I have a
broadband a high
I'm high band with rate
version at this and I've done the same
in the script is done the same thing for
all the different options so
what I need to do is upload all the
stuff to my website
so I'd upload the the different
transport streams in my
and 308 file and at that point basically
done except for one change the need to
make
to might video I mean to my website
what do you do is get rid all of the
stuff
all and replace it
with one-line blinded a give you a sneak
peek at the end
this is a the index index in 308 this is
what we're calling
this is our manifest our master manifest
have
file for for it's a last and
missus me say past
alright let's see what that looks like
but you can guess
look exactly the same a but now we're
streaming
a this content in an adaptive fashion
where we'll a change to adapt to the
typeof devices that are being used
and it'll change adapt to the network
conditions so if i weirded
start playing this eight-second video
and and leave the room
in theory it would the speed would drop
it would it would degrade 28 lower band
with
version and if I were to return to an
area where at high band what they could
and pick it back up in return to
this beautiful high resolution imagery
I am so I think the
so I hope that this brief demo and in
this example how simple it is on your
website
we'll show you why we're so excited
about this technology and why we hope
that you'll try it for your
next project thank you
thank sprint that was great so
a for more information about how to use
HTTP Live Streaming
how specifically to encode your videos
for all the wide variety of I left
devices
take a look at Techno 2224 which
specifies
a all the settings you need presser to
generate multiple
encoding your video for Reidy a Apple
devices
and also you get down to the very in
playlist creator and media file segment
or tools as part of the each
be live streaming toolset from fell for
about.com
we have a live streaming developer page
we can learn all about rachel s
web pages and in a defense
but new in Safari on a left-handed
support for a media streaming technology
called media source exchange
or MSP this is an extension to the html5
specification
where a video elements source is
replaced by
immediate source object which requires
the page to completely control
looting at media day now MSC is prepared
primarily intended for
only the largest video providers who
have large and complicated CDN
need to micromanage every aspect of
their network
stack we build support a
for MSc in the Safari but for most web
sites we don't actually recommend to use
it
let's talk a little bit about why that
is
with great power comes great
responsibility except
and remember it being someone else 0
that
the MS Tati will accept raw data D-mark
that person the samples
decode those samples cue the samples for
display but that it that's all you get
for everything else your website has to
do it man
the browser will not fetch data for you
must be fetched explicitly by your page
through
XHR the browser will
not preload metadata for you you have to
do that yourself to major playback
buffers don't
dry once you've done these two steps you
will have reproduced
basic video playback but then again the
video on the could do that already
for all the benefits streaming media
your page month implemented man so
your page must monitor network
conditions to make sure that your
user's device can keep up with the
bitrate the sir
you also have to monitor whether you're
a
users are dropping frames their hard
work and keep up
with the the DVD sir
and when do I wind conditions change you
after
manually switch streams by prefetching
and starting over from
for a more appropriate Street
you have to do all this without detailed
information about the current state of
the device
whereas with HLS he commuted detailed
view over
that devices current state to make
better adaptation decisions
so for example h11 knows what other
processes might be running on the device
knows whether the devices on a your
cellular connection or on wifi
a choice is aware of the current battery
condition for the device
and it knows about the current memory
pressure systems under
so writing an MSc player involved re
implementing an entire streaming media
stack
JavaScript whereas each less has all
this data available
and yet writing a player for rachel s
requires a single line in HTML
what's more empathy is only available on
a West End so to reach I OS users are
likely to have to set up in Asia last
remaining
for almost every conceivable situation
HLS is going to be a better choice for
streaming media
okay what about cross-browser support
HLS a supported across
all versions as Safari on I O S 80 S 10
ever see is only supported in Safari on
West
the Android Browser Android crumble
support HLS but not Missy
I E 11 sports ms even at HLS
Google Chrome supports media source
extensions
but apparently it's developers are
investigating
implementing HLF on top in a messy as
JavaScript
and Firefox only supports MSc in its
nightly builds
but they're also looking at adding
support for HLS through em
the MSC implementation
so
as you can see the web has really
settled on a single streaming media
technology yet
CB take nothing else away for your
Safari users
using chalice okay that was streaming
now let's talk about power efficiency
Apple we care deeply about power
we make devices with and simply amazing
battery life
but it's not just about batteries
we care about the impactor devices have
on a
have on the environment as a whole not
evident
on how much performance we can squeeze
out a single lot power
use we've done this through a
combination of hardware and software
engineering but the last mile it's up to
you
its easy to do this wrong
and renew users batteries and user with
a dead battery is one that's not use
your website
so today we're gonna show you how said
minimize the amount of power you use
when playing back video
in Safari so first
we're gonna talk about using full screen
and we're gonna talk about how
sleep cycles fact battery but first full
screen
it may sound counterintuitive going into
force cream okay dramatically reduce the
amount of power your system uses as a
whole
at switcher hidden behind a full-screen
browser window
going to a low power mode called ap you
can learn more about
apk app specifically ad I believe
session on Thursday
something about programming low
low-power programming anyway look it up
its Thursday at 10:30
but in addition
when the system determines the Deacon
composite video without well doesn't
have to capacity to get video on screen
go through a low power mode but to
explain how that works
we first have to talk about pixel format
so
every web developer should be familiar
with RGB the web platform is written in
RGB values
where every pixels broke into a red
green and blue components
each component is given eat death but
video is different
videos to cut it into a pixel format
called why you
the where why is the luminance plane
you NVR to color play the Y plane
actually encodes the green
and brightness values and the UN the
plane's
include the blue enter the red and blue
respectively typically the Y plane is
given twice as much
DEP as the you envy planes
is why we call yupp 42 or other formats
like why you the 411
all those described the ratio the big
steps between
by: you the plane's and we give the Y
plane more Dept because the human
visual system is much better distinction
between values
green and values have lighten dark and
it is between
values red blue so if you're a mantis
shrimp this makes total sense to you
if you're mentorship longboards that is
but so why you be 42 only requires about
16 bits per pixel
to encode where is it RGB with alpha
channel requires
32 and sisters typically less variance
in the UN to be playing
they can be compressed much easier than
a RGB values
this is why video prefers to use my UV
over RGB
their side effect though
evolve this these decisions is that
since the web platform is written in RGB
video with NYU the we have to convert
from one to the other
when we needed rock/pop the video so
that's how this works
called composite where layers are drawn
together top to bottom in order present
the actual web page
your views are gonna see the typically
works like this: you start with coded
video frames you decode those frames
into yupp
and then convert them into RGB
draw your web content on top
and send them out to the video card to
be displayed
alright now if the system determines
that it can display a video frame
without having to draw anything on top
of it
you can skip all these format conversion
steps
industry from why you ve directly to the
video card
dramatically reduces the amount of power
required to display video
it does have a few prerequisites though
for one you must support the full screen
API if you have JavaScript custom
controls
should have at least one that uses the
request for screen method to bring
your controls and your video in 243
black is the new black
should only have a black background as
well behind your video
and no DOM element should be visible on
popular video as well
this is tricky because elements which
have an opacity
0 are still technically visible so don't
hide your controls were passing or at
least
only heightened with opacity use display
known as well
and
everything the not currently being
displayed in full screen mode
whatever be visible you might as well
hide it as well
will show you a quick little a snippet
of CSS have a higher dollar
your non post reno when you're videos in
full screen
so first the full screen ATI
and we talked about this in a previous
session so for more information about
how the full screen ATI works
check out I think it's the 2011 video
session but really quickly
if you just call this method from a like
a full screen but handler
it will toggle back and forth between
fullscreen hide everything the not in
full screen
give you a little snippet of CSST news
so first
for fullscreen element all a bit
ancestors are given a pseudo class
called
fullscreen ancestor so this will select
every child the purple screen ancestor
the
not an ancestor itself and it's not the
full screen element itself
and hide so did add this
line of CFS your website and non love
the objects that her
not in full screen mode when the rest
your content is will be visible
or won't be visible they won't be in the
winter tree and we still CPU cycles in
okay now as compositing
now let's talk about how video playback
X-ers sleep
something you should be aware of is the
way that media playback
affects your users systems think sleep
cycles
with Safari plays a video it will
conditionally block
the display sleeping using a sleep
researcher and it does this
to avoid the annoying behavior for
display going to sleep halfway through
an app soda
you know orange is the new black Corp so
far below only
block this sleep from happening under
certain conditions though
so the video must have
an audio track and the video track has
to be playing
it must not be looping if these
conditions are not met we won't keep
sleeping however this has kinda a
a dramatic failure mode so there was a
website we came across
up they were trying to do something very
cool with video
they used a full page video Minister
backdrop up their land
page and in order to do a fancy CFS
transition at the end of the video
they didn't use moving had to video
meant that they faded between
and even other video was entirely silent
with valid because it had it finally
audio track
so if you look at this page in you walk
to a few your computer
you came back in a few hours it will be
completely dead
because the Safari this looks like the
user is just watching a playlist a
different videos
so how can they fix this offer one they
could strip the audio track
silent audio track out of their media
they can also burn the fade effect into
the video a itself the video media
itself
and use the loop property did loop the
video over and over again
either one of those with let this play
sleep again
but we have also updated our
requirements Safari
addition to the video meant having an
audio and video track
not moving playing it must also be
visible
that means must be in the foreground
have
in the visible window on the current
space
if the video minutes in a background
have or the window with him
will let the system sleep again so with
these changes even if you do the wrong
thing
your page will still keep the system
sleeping but only when your page is
actually visible
okay that was power person see now let's
talk about how to use time
meditated coordinate events your page so
what is time to meditate
i'm eddie data is data delivered
alongside your video on your audio data
were each piece of data have a start
time and end time
in the media time but chair
I can hear you asking that sounds a lot
like tech tracks
that's true extractor one kind
have time to meditate but meditate isn't
limited to text another text like
things you can include arbitrary binary
information you can include geolocation
information you can control
spirit had images you can include text
you can include anything you'd like an
ability to track and have that be
available
through the time to meditate yeah I now
time to meditate has been available
need a bass nati form I O S 80 S 10 for
some time
but new in Safari on i OS and OS 10
its easy to use from JavaScript as well
it appears in a video of it as a text
track
just like the caption tracks we talked
about a previous study BBC's
these tracks we have kind meditate a
meeting that will be displayed by the
browser
instead will be available to your script
running in the page
you can use the same text track API's to
watch for incoming
meditated events as extract use
now text reckon sister contains a list
accuse each one
at the start time and you can add an
event handlers to these objects
that will get fired as the media
time-line goes into the queue
and leaves
now a WebKit de tu Q subclass attacks
track you
because interfaces experimental has a
website prefix
so this is not in the html5 spec yet
so pretty be prepared for this interface
to change that said we're pushing to get
these proposed changes at the specs
so each you will happy type property
which allows you to
interpret the Value property correctly
with the type look like
well the meditate acute type indicates
the source
edited it came from summarily can be
found in QuickTime user data Adams
they can be found quick on meditate it
could have been inserted by iTunes
it could be fine found in the mp4
meditate a box
or finally made it could be inserted at
I D three free strictly
your media stream
so these values allow you interpret the
Value property which looks like this
each value has a key between the key at
the tight
you can uniquely identify the meeting
the data value
the data property which could be a
string arraya number
an array buffer any JavaScript type and
the value may optionally have work how
you can choose between a a variety of
available cues for the current time
based on the user's current system
so would use this for extremely simple
example would be displaying the title
first
up a song long playing audio stream
another example would be to had entry
and exit points
the various places in your media streams
you can track whether users
say watch through an entire add or
skipped over it
but because you can package any type a
binary day do you like getting
any each less stream or a media file the
possibilities for this API are
functionally endless
it's a brad has an amazing demo showing
what kind of awesome things you can do
with time
added print thank you
so let's get back to let's get back to
longboarding
septa more smart footage here I am
a a really nice day in Utah and
with Adobe really need to take advantage
to summon the meta-data they can be
encoded in these
in these videos now RI devices can
already collect a lot of things such as
geolocation data and and add with
new devices we can now collect motion
data and there are a variety about
locations that you can use that will
in code other types of data that that
are
related to other devices and things that
that you may work with
this can all be encoded together and and
brought along as part of the media
and so I thought to be really
interesting to see what we could do with
that
now in this video we had some ok
some content that was in embedded in the
media stream
as id3 tag so it they contain a text
entry
thats a chase on object baird & Co to
Jason object
and I wanted to get a a feel for what
that look like
so I put together a page that showed I
the same long boarding video
with the meta-data displayed on the side
and so you can see the some other types
of content that would be in here now
this content was from a specific use
case so it's gonna vary depending on
where your media comes from what kinda
tools are being used to put it together
but in this case we have a speed we have
an ordered list
skaters we've got it notes field so that
be inching to see
what we could do with that let me just
briefly show you
I me just briefly show you
what I did to to get this data to
display
okay so just like before we have a us
a video source that in this case is
another
and 308 encoded video a
but when the videos starts I didn't
onload start handlers so that when the
stream starts playing
we can we can do something and look what
we do is
we need to register an event listener
for the ad track events that we can know
when tracks are being added to the
stream so the medals were
the deal star play in the meta data will
will be a
recognized by the system in als it afire
the sedate
when the track has been added
I want to add another event listener for
Q change this is the part
where WebKit will be firing the skew
change events
as this method it is encountered in the
playback
very important is this where we set the
mode to hidden
now the tracks in in the system
come through and in a default state
disabled which means that you will not
get
events we set to hidden because we don't
really wanna see this
this content we don't want work at the
nest surly do anything with it
but we do want to receive events when
these Q's are
encountered so that we can do something
with that as well finally the media this
is in the the Q changed
event handler where because I know that
this data is chase on I was able to just
take the data queue which is a WebKit
data
I track object that like you're just
told us about
and the retrieve the data portion that
and parse it as a Jason object what they
did that
obviously the first lady was to take
that
reconstituted Jason object and
immediately restring a fire
just why because I just wanted a
pre-printed for the screen and wanna
like write anything to do that so Jason
string if I will do that for you and
then you end up with
with something that looks a lot like
this
and that's great we're getting meta data
that's fire near a few times a second
and weak you know we have this
information we can do something with but
its
it's not really that compelling example
wasn't that interesting so I thought
well what else can we do this
we have a speed what if we
modified it so that I could show a hud
with
with the speed indicator on it that
would be kinda cool we can kinda see how
fast people were going
so to do that you make a few changes
for some gonna go and get rid this a
ripple style sheet I put in here just
the kinda get things on the screen
and replace it with a more
full-featured style sheet and I'm gonna
modified the Q change event I don't need
to restring up by the Jason object now
that I
I have it all I need to do is grab the
what's on you do to do is grab the
the speed added the Jason payload
and stick it in a did that I just named
speed
and that i'm gonna go ahead and add a a
a div to hold the hunt for that
will call this
awesome her right
so this look like now every will hurt in
the top of the screen
an FA began video playback
now we have a will speedometer reading
so now we have
live overlaying this video playback
we've got
content it's being being written by ass
and added by us
live on the web page and
and this is kinda example what you can
do with with this kind of information
I thought well this was kinda fun but
but would probably be more you know
there there was other continent there
there was a
notes feel that had information that
that called out things that they might
be doing on screen
and we had information about the ordered
listed the skater so i thought well why
don't we
when we make a a a a leaderboard show
kinda who's in
what position and maybe call out any
tracks and other information like that
so we need to do is in addition Mike you
changed event handler in addition to the
speed indicator
I wanna have a method that all show the
skaters in order
and I want to have a method that will
display the tricks that are being done
on screen
and I'm gonna go into into much detail
about
how this works except to say that
right the show the skaters in order I I
basically have
for 2nd 3rd 4th CSS class that I set up
and in the in the style sheet and I just
iterate through that list aboard skaters
and as the skater names come in
I style the did that has the name that
skater in for second third or fourth
position
I'm likewise I'm gonna have some code to
showed the tricks as they come in here
I'm just gonna add
did to the page that styled with the
trick style and with a little bit over
CSS animation
I we should we should
we should be done and then let me go
ahead and add centers the hold all the
skaters
a given the gives the names to the
skaters and that makes it
easy for for setting this all up
and let's take a look at what that looks
like not gonna hurt a
I've got the skaters in the top by
restrained a few things and grab some
snapshots the show them off
and let's go ahead and get started
ever go and so now we're getting the lie
playback on top at the video
with the skaters and I just point out
that you know these guys look
really good but imagine the skill it
takes to be skating backwards
filming this and I think you'll agree
that a lot of the magic is happening of
screen so but
here time edited did answer firing we're
seeing speed changes
we're seeing a tricks being called out
as their as they're moving along
and this is all happening live not
baking listen to the video
I could have done that but then we
wouldn't be able to modify this change
colors and whatever else
and this is a good part here a this guy
allan
he saw something he just slid away
carrier his he's gonna notice something
danger spot it is gonna bail out
poor Fred he hit the pothole had to get
off
he's now out other races got an axe he
falls away
and our last eight er and so we get the
position
the skaters and so the I
that's just a brief example what you can
do with this kind this kind the
meditative events
a and a little bit a CSS and JavaScript
on top at the live video I I hope you
guys
understand why we think this is such an
exciting technology and I can't wait to
see
would have all what I love you will do
with this in the future
thank you very much and back your thank
sprint that was
that was amazing backward 7 talk to be
there
so let's sum up where you guys have
heard today video in Safari on
I O S and a left n are now
closer behavior by supporting them
field attributes on I West and allowing
the video meant to fully participate
CSS mayor you've also seen how to use
HLS data: data streaming support your
pages
you've learned how to improve your users
power efficiency
by playing back video your pages we've
also seen how to use
time meditate coordinate events here
page with you media's time
so for more informa- information please
contact our evangelism T
and see the Safari for developers
documentation developer to topple dot
com
and don't forget about the Apple
developer for so
other sessions you might be interested
in harnessing meta data in auto
audio-visual media later today
writing energy efficient code parts
wanted to happen on Wednesday
and stop by the designing responsive web
experiences
for more information on responsive web
design that's it have agreed to be BBC