hello good afternoon
welcome to session 5:
5 harnessing meta data in audiovisual
media
I've heard we're competing with the
injured swift talk so
get intimate with your neighbors here I
my name is Adam Sonnanstine
I move engineer on the V Foundation team
and today we are going to talk about of
course
meta-data so what do I mean by meta data
well
for the purpose of this talk we're going
to find meditated to mean any data that
is stored in movie files
streaming presentations any other sort
of audio-visual presentation
that def describes the primary data like
the audio and video that we think about
when we think of this or two
presentations
some examples are always helpful when
you should be familiar with is iTunes
meta-data
when you have the third the song names
and the the artists in the album artwork
in your iTunes library all these things
are stored as the third have meditated
I'm talking about today
in the files in your iTunes library
besides iTunes meditated we also have
things like location information if you
have a movie that you took with your
your iPhone or some other location
enabled device and you played in
QuickTime Player
that will show up in the info window to
tell you where you were when you took
that
the movie that's also stored as the kind
of meta-data that we're talking about
today
and for new features we know that you
not always standing still when you're
taking your videos
so new NIOS Aiden OS 10 yosemite
we have features that support things
like dynamic location
at a location that changes over time so
these are some new features were gonna
be talking about later on
that we're pretty excited about and in
addition to
location this really applies to any
third meta data that you might want to
add
that changes over time in your movie
this is a screenshot of a demo app will
show you later
but the circle in the the annotation
text that off toward as the same sort of
time meditative for the as the time
location
hopefully that would wrap it a little
bit I
talk about what we're gonna cover today
we're gonna start I'm gonna give you an
intro to meditate in a V Foundation
some other classes that have been around
for a while for
describing all sorts meta-data how to
inspect that and how to author
going to talk more about these new times
meta data features
and then we give you some best practices
including some
privacy things to keep in mind and some
other best practices
surfers topic meditate in a V Foundation
well kinda classes are we going to be
using to describe a meta-data
well our primary model object that we
used to describe
both movie files or re-arm
you know it's a live streams is a BF
that in a bf it can contain
any number love if the meta data item
object
and each AB meditative item instance
represent a single peace dove meta-data
either your track name or your album art
even your
location stuff that's going to be
separate pieces have meta-data
in our Runtime Environment a closer look
at TV meta data item
at its core it has two properties the
first as identify which is actually a
new property
and that is going to describe the kinda
meta-data the you have
in this example we have the song name I
ended
represented by this long symbol name AB
meta-data identifiers iTunes metadata
song name
and then you have the value which is the
actual payload of the metadata item
for for song name it the name a song as
a string as an example for cover art
a you can see the value doesn't have to
be a string it can be
image or any other object that
supports both the NFL object in Ennis
copying protocol of
now if you've used a beam edited item in
the past you might be familiar with
the key in key space properties well the
identifiers
mention that was new its new because
that the combination
love the old properties key and key
space I'm not gonna be talking much
about kinky space today
mostly gonna be talking about identify
re going forward as the way to describe
your meta data to take a look at some of
the built-in identifiers we have
this is just a tiny sampling there's a
lot of them you can find them in a beam
edited identifiers
I've arrange them here according roughly
two the old notion of Keith Spaeth
am so that's to serve a sampling of the
kinda meta data that we already know
that you might want to represent
going back to the mid 80 I am itself
we have a property that's also new
called datatype which describes the
native data type
that your meta data is representing for
the case have our song name
it stored as the strength that we see
the datatype is a utf8 string
in these string constants that represent
the different datatypes
are all defined in CM meta-data dot H
and besides the datatype a property we
also have
several type coercion properties that
you can use if you know you wanna get
your payload
in the form above a certain type
objective the object
to have string value number value date
value in data value
and those are going to give you exactly
what you'd expect
for the case love where native paler the
string
only string values gonna give you an
interesting answer the rest will give
you know
for artwork example will appeal to the
Jay pag image
the the top three are gonna give you
know and the data value is gonna give
you the end a stated that you're looking
for
to grabbed a bite up the Jaipur image
there are examples where you can have
more than one non mil
type coercion method and one its
creation date: if you have
the date represented as a standard
string format for dade
you can either get the actual string
that was
a stored that way or you can ask the
meta data item to give you an instant
Savannah State that describes the same
thing
in a more convenient representation so
that's your brief intro to EV meta data
item
we'll be talking a lot about it
throughout the talk let's go back to EBS
its so we can see how we actually get
these metadata
item to the easiest way is just to get
asked for all of the meta-data that
applies to the entire asset
there are types the meta-data that apply
to just part of the effort
but this is how you get the meta-data
like the location in the song title it
applies to the entire after
there's also a way to get justice up to
the meta-data
we have this notion a meta data format
but I'm not to be talking about too much
today
but you can use it to get just that
subset love the meta-data
the for our example when we're getting
iTunes meta-data we're going to use that
AB metadata format iTunes metadata in
grab all about using
the meta data for format method
and then from there we can use the
filtering method meta data items from a
rate filtered by identifiers
to get just the items that correspond to
the song name identify your
they might be wondering why you can have
more than one song name
in a single asset will get back to that
in just a little bit
first i wanna talk about how you load
the payload
up committed item wave emitted item
conforms to the ABA thinkers key-value
loading protocol the protocol that we
define ourselves in a B foundation
in a lot of our core model object confer
conform to it
because a lot of times when you getting
a BF that or navy medic item we have an
actually load the data behind it yet
you can use this method mood values a
thinker slifer keys
to load the specific values you want and
I'll do that a synchronously few not
blocking your main thread
with some sort of thinking is I or
something like that
to for this case we have omitted item
we're looking for the value
so we just slowed the key value and when
we get our completion handler
we're gonna check the status to make
sure that that loading succeeded
in assuming that we did week and then
just go ahead and grab the value in you
that
have we see fit so back to that whole
multiple titles in one meta one asset
thing one reason we might have that is
if we have
the asset localized in multiple
languages
to an African have the same meta data
items in multiple languages
the example that we're going to talk
about is QuickTime user data for name
that identify your if you use this
identify ring your files
in QuickTime Player for example can pick
up the title
in display in the title bar so this is
just yet another example of how many
that is used
in our applications and this particular
example other movie
actually has a look the title available
in both English and Spanish
so here we have the English as the
system language so quick time player
picks that up
that picks up the English title but if
we set our system language to Spanish
it'll pick up the Spanish localization
that title instead
in these are represented as two distinct
pieces UHV meta data within the file
in the way that you distinguish between
them is that they'll have different
values for these final two properties
have a beam edited item
locale an extended language tag extended
language tag is new
in this release I to BCP 47 language tag
and it's particularly useful when you
want to distinguish written languages
so that a that's how one reason why you
might have more than one
merited item with the same identify your
I mentioned before that not all
meta-data applies to the entire after
well one example love that is meta data
only applies to particular track
for this example we have a a special
label attached to a subtitle track
called sth the stands for subtitles for
the Deaf for hearing
a hard of hearing and that's basically
just a moron rich former subtitles
that includes things like labeling who's
talking and
mentioning sound effects that are vital
to the the understanding
and we talked a little bit more about
sth
and accessibility in general last year
and are preparing and presenting media
for accessibility talk
for checking up for more details for the
purposes of this talk
just know that to get this as the age
label here it involves setting track
specific metadata
so let's talk about how you actually
find out after track has this Medina
well you can use a BF that track and it
has pretty much the exact same API as a
BF that
for reading meta-data you have committed
a property
you have term editor for format method
into if we wanna find all the tag
characteristic
that are in a medida her in a in a nasa
track
when asked the track for its metadata
for the format QuickTime user data
and once we have that we use that same
filtering method we saw before
in order to get all love the items that
have
the identifiers QuickTime user data tag
characteristic
so this is a one example of tech
characteristics is the sth that I just
talked about
and it's the payload love that metadata
item that tells you what kind
ab tak characteristic you're dealing
with we'll talk a little bit more detail
about
sth in how you operate in just a little
bit
so going back to our list %uh
identifiers
you might have noticed some patterns if
you're looking closely
each of these groups has their own
version of a title or a song name or
something like that
we noticed that and come up with our own
special kind identify recalled the
common identify your
which can be used when you want to look
up safer this example a title without
carrying exactly
how it stored in your file them for
copyright here we also have
a comedy in a fire that represent
copyright these are not the only come
identify risk
there's a whole list oven but these are
just two examples
so if we go back to our example were
looking for iTunes song name
if we don't actually care that the the
title love our asset is stored as iTunes
meta-data
we just won a title we can display it
somewhere you can ask the asset for
its array of common metadata and this is
all the meta data items
that can be represented using a common
identifiers
and any use that same filtering method
we've been using to filter down to just
the ones that have the common identify
your title
in you can go from there with your title
and also worth noting is that
a bf the track has the same property
come in today to
you can do the same thing over there as
well
so that is your brief introduction to
inspecting meta data with the V
Foundation
talk a little bit about authoring if you
wanna make your own files that have
the location or iTunes metadata in them
well we have several
different classes that can write movie
files
a VFX work session ABS writer in the
capture movie an audiophile upwards
in these all have the exact same
read/write property called simply
meta-data
you given a rave meta data items and
then that will be written out to the
file
similarly four track specific meta data
like this tag characteristics
you can use in ABS the writer input
which also has the exact same
property now you're not limited
to just writing out meta data that you
got from somewhere else like another
file through the API if you've been
looking at
you can also create your own editor
items with the mutable subclass
love meta data item and as you might
expect this just has read/write
properties for all
the up properties in a beam edited item
so for use an example %uh writing
subtitle track that is marked as sth
well its actually two different tack
characteristics that you have to use
is that will create two different
metadata item was at both the
identifiers
to the that identify we just saw the
QuickTime user data tagged
characteristic
but one of them will set the value to
transcribe spoken dialogue for
accessibility
and the other will be described music
and sound for accessibility
then we get the subtitle a after writer
input that's gonna writer subtitle track
and set that array of the two items on
our asset writer input
that tell you the author a subtitle
track that is a marked as sth
justina just one example love you think
tag characteristic
and evening beautiful Medina item
special note about
ABS at export session by default
the export session is actually gonna
take any of the meta-data that
in the the source asset that your
exporting
its gonna copy that over to the output
file
now that's not the case if you set meta
data on its metadata property
that'll be the signal to tell the export
session to ignore the meta-data in the
source file
and instead right just which you put on
the property
so if you want to do augmentation above
the meta-data or some other
sort of modification you wanna grab that
a rave meta-data
make a mutable copy do any adjustments
the you want and then set that
on the meta-data property that's just a
quick note about expert session
last note about offering meta-data is
HTTP Live Streaming this is actually a
new feature
in I was 8 OS 10 yosemite
and you can use the new tag called the
session data tag
in your playlist which has to required
fields the data I D which is a lot like
are identifiers that we're talking about
you are I which can point to the payload
or a value which directly specifies the
payload
and optionally some language information
here's an example that shows a very
similar to what we saw before with the
titles and two different languages
but this is the mark up the you'd use
for HTTP Live Streaming
the for more information on reading and
writing matter they don't we do have
some sample code
it's called AB meta-data editor and for
more information about
the details have writing HTTP Live
Streaming meta-data
see the the document that this URL
I so that is a crash course in meta data
in a V Foundation
our next topic is time to meta data
the time to meditate although I mention
we have new features it is not a new
concept
we supported the notion of chapters for
quite some time in conceptually chapters
are just an example of time
meta-data each of these chapter markers
it's just a piece a better day to
that is describing a particular a
range the time line up the movie
in that all that time to meditate is
just meta data associated with
range have time and for filler Lee
with are looking are dynamic location
example
we have the path that's drawn here
that's really just composed
love a number love pieces have met a
data indicating the current location
each one of them associated with a
particular time in the movies time-line
30 demonstrate I QuickTime Player
features with dynamic location
in Yosemite I wanna bring my colleague
felony up to the stage for a demo
tag I'm here to demonstrate how to read
and playback meta-data
using QuickTime Player yet I have a
movie fine
which has both audio and video and time
location data stored in a different
track
so now if I bring this up and QuickTime
Player
this is the usual you I for audio and
video
new analyst daniel Smith D in the movie
inspector
you can see a map for you if your movie
file has location data
you map you is presented along with the
Lord
there you've recorded this radio so here
the blue line indicates the pot maybe
Dakota do we do.
and the Red been is an indication of the
current location
or the location on the time line of the
movie
so if I do in a little bit and start
playing
you can be as the movie progresses the
bend location is being updated
to be in sync with the video
I can drag the scrubber around and you
see the been
moving back and forth I can also go
and click at any point in the map
and you see the media seek to that
location to present
bed your media wats menu it at that
location
this is map view in QuickTime Player on
with Dan yes maybe
thanks Johnny so let's talk about what
we just saw their
so that location information was stored
as time too many data in the file
in order to have Quicktime Player draw
that information on the map
we use in a bf reader to read all of the
location information from
that after and because times when data
is stored in its own track
we use in a BF 3 to track up wit to read
that data
im you to new class called a bf reader
output meta-data adapter
that knows how to give us that data in
the form have a class called
EV time to meditate a group and then we
from there we can grab each location in
dry that path
on the map to a tee time benedita group
is a very simple class it's really just
a few properties in array of meta-data
items
combined with a time range to describe
where in the movie
that date applies
to see a little bit a code for using ask
the reader for this purpose
the first thing you want to do is find
the track that contains your location
information
we'll talk more about how to do that in
just a second and any use that track to
create
a track %uh f3 to track output any use
no output settings
and then you create your merited adapter
with that track output
and then in the loop you just take your
med after in called the
next time to meditate a group method
over and over again
doing something with each piece of data
like drawing on the map
in till that method returns nil and then
you know there's no more data to draw
so in terms of finding the right track
to read
the way to do that is by examining the
tracks in your asset in looking through
the format description
each track to find the identifiers
you're looking for to you first start
by getting the tracks with the media
type metadata in and for each other's
track
you can loop through all of its format
description usually there's only one
and for each format description you're
gonna grab with the identifiers using
this function
and check whether that I don't identify
rate contains identify you're looking
for
in this case were looking for the
location I said 6709 identifiers 2013
found it
we're good to go and we can resume with
the code on the previous slide
so that's how QuickTime Player is
drawing the maps were joined the path
on the map before you start playback the
other thing that quick time player does
as he saw as they can update the current
location
while you're doing playback or even
scrubbing around in the way it does that
work already playing
the asset using AV player item and we're
gonna use a new class called
AB player item meta-data output you
attach to your player item
which often knows how to vendors data in
the form of time
benedita group but unlike the author
reader instead of getting all the data
up front
you gonna be getting a piece by piece as
the movie plays
a little bit a code you first create
your metadata output using the it with
identifiers method
and in this case were only interested in
a meditated it has that
location identifiers so that's all we're
gonna get by
opting into this way and you create a
delegate that you
you define and that's what's going to
receive the meta-data during playback
any set that delegate on your output and
tell us what do you want to send
the date on
and then you create or grab your AV
player item
and call at output to attach your output
to the player item
in finally make your player
an associate your item with the player
as the current item in star playback
it's important to get the smooth
playback experience possible
we highly recommend that you do all of
this third setup work
before you start playback or even attach
the item to you the player
so a little bit a look at what your
delegate method might look like
is only one delegate method if the
metadata output did output time to
meditate a group from playwright Amtrak
method
and the first thing you want to do is
grab an item that you can get your
payload data from
in this case to keep things simple I'm
describing the first item from the first
group
but keep in mind that there could be
multiple items there could be multiple
groups
one reason that there could be multiple
groups given to this method
is that the medida output
will keep track love whether the meta
data is coming in faster than your
processing it and if it is it'll start a
batch that up
in give you the metadata in batches when
you're done with the previous batch a
metadata
the moving on with your item you gonna
do this load values you think Chris Lee
for keys dance that we talked about
before
in this case were interested in the
value and data type properties threw in
a load both have those
I've omitted the air checking for
brevity here
but you'll probably want to do that
they're checking like we had the other
flood
and once we have the the completion
handler we can ask the item for its data
type
and make sure that the data type are
prepared to handle in this case my code
only knows how to handle
location information in I so 6709 format
for you to make sure that's the right
data type
and from there we go and dispatch are
coded the main thread that'll
update are you why for that O
QuickTime Player is updating the
location
meta-data during playback of course this
is not the first API
that we've offered for reading time
meta-data during playback
there is an existing property called
time meta-data and every player item
by mir's say that the AV player item
edited output replaces
that property for this for all these use
cases
now we're not deprecating the property
yet but we do recommend if you're new to
time to meta data
to just adopt the meta-data output and
not worry about the property
if you're already using the property
virgin we do recommend that you move
over
but just do you know that you should
make sure that
your code is working properly after that
transition in particular I'll point out
that the
medida output will give you for certain
kinda HLF content will give you
a more specific identifiers then
the old property did for just make sure
your code is prepared to handle that
and the last topic on reading time
meta-data is chapters
chapters like I said I've been supported
for some time even have their own API
chapter meta-data group best matching
preferred languages this is on
EV after and this will give you an array
of time to meditate a group
that contain items with the identifiers
QuickTime user data chapter
in with the border this for some time
for QuickTime movie files
in .m4v and new in Iowa
8 is the and Western your seventy is
support for chapters in
HTTP Live Streams as well as mp3 files
now tell you more about how to author
there is HLS chapters in just a little
bit
for more information we have some sample
code that does
approximately what QuickTime Player is
doing
where it can show your your location
during playback
we also have a a previous session about
after reader that goes into much more
detail than I did hear called working
with media in a V Foundation from 2011
to tell you read in playback time
metadata our next
time to read it in the topic is how you
can create your own movies that contain
times meta-data
we saw the screenshot before and I
mentioned that these annotations are
stored as times meta-data
and to show you this demo app I'd like
to invite Shoni back up on stage
to demo it this time let's look at an
apt
on how to auto your own custom meta data
in your movie files
killer I have a video and if I would
like to share some notes
but my friend who's good at mixing
colors in a movie
I can now do that within the app
to add annotations I use 8 to finger
gesture
I can use a pen gestured to the size and
then
add a comment
which is enough for my a whoever looks
at the media later
to fix the colors there and then I begin
playback
and as playback progresses I tracked the
SoCal did where
I want this to be fixed and now that I
have this annotation
and I I can write it out along with the
audio and video to do that I hit export
and now we see if a deeply love you
control over it shows the exported movie
along with the meta data which was
written to hit so if i start playback
you see the annotations morning along
the time line
in the pot image I up changed
so if I scrub back in time you can see
the
annotation mowing you might wonder that
the annotations babe into the video
frame it's not
it is being rendered real-time using any
player item edited out but
and you can change the color or the font
of the annotation
so if I begin playback you see the
rendering is happening in real time
that a beat and annotation writer we
have this available as a sample code as
well
thank you there was a great
demonstration have not only
the playback part of it but also how to
write that data into the file
first take a look at how that was
accomplished so we're going to use in
ABS at writer
to write the file and we can use ABS
writer input in order to write
that metadata track to the file in just
like the reader side
the writer has a new class that the
meta-data adapter
in that class knows how to interpret
inferences
a AB time militant group in right that
into the file
see a little bit code first thing we're
gonna do is create
are after writer input we're going to
use the media type
EV media type meta-data once again no
output settings
and we're going to have to provide a
clue to the source format
the format of the data that we're going
to be a pending we'll talk more about
this and why it's required on the next
flight
anything plea create your meta data
adapter with the reference to that input
and as you generate or receive your time
to meditate a group you'd simply use the
append time to edit a group method
to continue to offenders in write them
to the file
with the deal with that force format
thing well
it turns out that in order for EV of the
writer to
be able to write your meta data in the
most efficient way possible
in need to know up front exactly what
kinda meta data is going to be writing
and this will result in you know the
most the lowest
storage overhead in terms of the number
bites your file takes up
and it also has affect on how efficient
it is to play back
this kind of content you don't want to
be using too much power when you're
playing with
but kinda content back you do have some
options in terms of how you actually
construct one of these form and hence
if you're reading from a bf the reader
you can actually ask the track the
reading from to give you it with the
format descriptions
and use one of those if you're creating
the medida group yourself for getting it
from some other source
then you can use a new method called
copy format description
that will give you back an instant up cm
format description that will do
this job for you it's important to know
that if you go this route
need to make sure that the content
submitted a group our comprehensive
in terms love it containing every
combination identifiers
datatype and language tag that you are
going to be a pending
that is it contains an item with each
other's combinations
and of course in the theme for many
scripts in is a thief type you need to
see if relief that when you're done
course there's one more way you can do
this you can create the format
description directly
you think or media API's in here use
this
long name CML data format description
create with meta data specification
function
you gonna pass in the midday to type box
that the third admitted it we've been
talking about this whole time with time
to enter data
and these metadata specifications it's
just an array of dictionaries
each dictionary contains those
combinations I was talking about before
the identifiers datatype and optionally
extended language tag
for you wanna make one of these meta
data specification dictionaries for each
combination you plan to append
for the one thing that was not obvious
about that demo is that
we're actually writing meta-data time
today to
that describes one particular other
track so
for the example if these annotations
we're really just talking about
the video track up the movie and not the
sound or anything else like that
in tho just like we had a way of making
tracks Pacific meditated that applied to
the entire track with this tag
characteristics with %uh before
you also have the ability to formally
mark your meta-data track
as describing one particular other track
and you do that with the ad tracker
association with track I've input method
using at the printer the after better
input to using to write your video track
in your receiver is the input to using
to write your meta data track
and use the Association tight meta-data
referent so
that's how you create meta-data that
time too but also specific to particular
track
the next thing we did that was
interesting in that demo is that we
actually use our own custom identifiers
we had that big with the built-in
identifiers we don't have to use those
you can actually build your own
in as I mentioned before and identifiers
just a combination of Keith Basinski
and has a particular format is just a
string but it's in a particular format
to help you make your own custom
identifiers we have this method
identifiers for key in key states that
the class method a navy medic
item and there are some some rules to
follow
your key space needs to be four
characters long if you want to use it
for time to meditate a
we actually recommend you to use our
built-in Keith Spaeth the QuickTime
meta-data Keith and we also highly
recommend you use reverse DNS notation
for your custom keys to avoid collisions
with other kinds the meta-data to brief
code snippet you can see you can
simply use this method to make your
custom identify your
in and set that on the identify property
I love your beautiful medidata
in addition to custom identifiers you
can also create your own custom data
types
through all familiar by now through this
presentation with some of these built-in
data types that we define
is a lot more than the is but we've been
using these quite heavily already
is a really useful but sometimes you
want your data type information to
express more
maybe about the demesne you're working
in if you doing a serial number or
barcode kind of thing
you might want to define a data type
that's the sort of your number as string
datatype
or barcode image as Jay pag datatype so
you have more specific information about
what your meta data actually contains
anyway that this works is you have to
tell us
exactly how did he realize that
a custom data type and the way you do
that if you tell us that your custom
data type conforms to one of our
built-in data types
so in this case the fuel number conforms
to the utf8 datatype third
under the hood with utf8 string but we
know that it really represents
a barker a serial number in same with
the barcode image
in a way that you do this is you
register your data type using the CM
meta-data
datatype registry register datatype
functioned as defined in core media
you can create your own custom base
types but you can
create a your own custom type that
conforms to our raw data
built-in type if you're datatype really
is just a custom sequence
a bite so there are some rules to using
a bf
writer for reading time meta-data
most importantly every minute they die
dem that you up and
has to have 90 values for identifiers
datatype
and value in your identifiers have to
conform to the the format that we
specifies that we highly recommend using
that utility methods talked about
in the value has to be compatible the
datatype you can tell us
that year and a string value is a utf8
string
but don't try telling us for your custom
class is a utf8 string because we won't
know how to serialize that
properly and the other player will fail
and as I mentioned before
you have to create your ass writer input
with the form at hand and that must be
comprehensive
and we describe that for for the last
topic
about after writer in time to meditate a
is a recipe for
creating your own movies that have the
same sort of dynamic location that we've
seen a couple times already
in to do this you can use EV captures
audio and video data output
in target that data at two instances a
after writer input
in the same time grab looking
information from core location that
represents the location information
in right that to its own ass the writer
input in for more
detail about you that we've actually
implemented out and made it available a
sample code
to see if you capture location if you
want to make your own movies that
contain dynamic location
we also have sample code is shown a
mention for the demo we just showed you
that's called a be timed annotation
writer and of course for more
information about asset writer in
general
see that same talk I referenced earlier
working with media in the V Foundation
left a quick topics about times
meta-data export session
just like we said the acid export
session will by default
passed through any of your meta data
that applies to the entire asset
or entire track it'll pass that through
copy it to the output file
will do the same thing with time to
enter data that exists in the source
file
provided that your destination file type
is quick time movie
we'll talk more about file types in just
a little bit
but basically export session behaves
exactly as you'd expect
in our last time to enter data offering
topic
is HTTP Live Streaming chapters so if
you wanna author chapters in your hols
stream you can use the session data
tagged we talked about earlier
and the special data ID com dot Apple
that HLF
dot chapters and your you are I should
point to Jason file
that describes the chapter information
for that stream
if course for more detail on this see
that same link that I
referenced earlier for HTTP live
streaming
art for that is timed meta-data our next
topic is privacy
wise privacy important in this context
well
anytime that you're writing your users
data to a file
you need to be Elise consider it about
their privacy
and be aware that the meditator the you
right out to these movie files can
contain
user identifiable information the most
obvious example that is location
in so because movie files can be
distributed
and we want to protect the privacy of
our users for our
built insurance services we do our best
to strip out
any potentially user identifiable
information such as this location
we recommend that you do the same we've
given you a utility for that up
called AV meta data item filter right
now there is only one filter that we
make available but it is geared towards
privacy if the Mediterranean filter for
sharing
and metal strip out any of this 30 views
are identifying information that we're
talking about location is only one
example
but it also is true about anything it
doesn't recognize because it doesn't
know whether that might contain
user identifiable information so that
includes any meta data that uses
identifiers that you define yourself
it'll even some things
like many data that a important to the
structure of the movie in chapters are
the best example of that
and also any commercial related data
like your Apple ID
30 use the matter did I don't filter
you're gonna just
crew for civil create your filter and
beaded your original array of meta-data
items using this many data items from a
rate filtered by
meta-data I don't filter method this is
a companion to that other filtering
method
based on identifiers have been using all
day and then once you have your filtered
array
love metadata item just set that on your
out that writer or export session as you
normally would
well actually I mention expert session
but things can be simple if you're using
the export session in only one
to copy the time are the meta-data from
the source outside and not add your own
you just set the filter
on the export session in it'll actually
do the filtering for you
the filter both static and time to enter
data and
but it will only filter the meta-data
from the source after
if you set your own meta-data on the
metadata property it won't feel too that
for you
you need to do the process that i just
described above doing the filtering
yourself
in the only other thing to keep in mind
is that the export may take more time
when the filter is being used because it
has to go through and examine all the
meta data items
so that privacy our last section other
talk today
is some assorted best practices when
you're writing your own files that
contain
meta-data first up
what if you're reading time today to in
you have multiple streams
love meta-data that use different
identifiers
how do you get those in the same file we
actually have the situation in the
the demo app we have that circle is
comprised of two different pieces of
information
the position and the radius so where
we're representing the is in the demo
app has two distinct
streams have meta-data into the most
obvious way I can think of to get this
into a file
is to use two different AB
after writer input which was all in
having to meditate attraction the upper
file
pretty simple but there's nothing we
could do it
you could instead combine those two
different types of meta-data into one
time to meditate a group and write that
to a single asset writer input and that
was all thin only one
meta data tracking the output file that
contains multiple different kinds of
identifiers
there are some advantages to this
approach not the least of which is it
can result
in lower storage overhead and therefore
as we always see more efficient playback
but there are of course pros and cons to
everything
so you'll differ want to consider
combining into one track
your different meta-data if they are
used together during playback
and they have identical timing in this
is definitely the case with the example
we just saw
with the circle center in the circle
radius
if these are not true then you might not
want to combine in effect one instance
where you definitely do not want to
combine
is if you have one typeof meta data that
the thirty did
with another track in the file that like
our are annotations are fitted with the
the video track but then you have
another typeof meta-data
like location that 32 with the entire
asset you don't want to combine those
into one track otherwise your
location in that example will be come
mistakenly associated with just the
video track and that's not what you want
so that how to deal with multiple
streams time meta-data
next topic is duration of your time to
meditate a group
when you get a time to edit a group from
maybe foundation it's always going to
have
a fully formed time time range
so that means it'll have a start time
and duration
we actually recommend when you make your
own time to an idiot a group for
appending
with a TV out the writer that you don't
bother giving us a duration
in to see how that works here's an
example of a group that starts at time 0
but doesn't have a duration so how do we
know when and
of course we'll wait till you append the
next one and then we'll say that
well K the end time I've the first group
is same as the start time love the next
one
for this ensures that your metadata
track is gonna have
a continuous stream up contiguous
meta-data and we think that for most
cases this is the best way to store your
metadata
in the way you come up with this is when
you're making your time range you just
use KCM time invalid
for your duration: and we'll take care
the rest
we do recognize that there are cases
where you might not want to have
contiguous meta-data you might wanna
author an explicit gap
into your meta data stream answer for
that our recommendation is you give us
in the middle there a group that
contains 0% item
this is the best way to author a gap in
the meta-data
and you can see we just do that by
presenting a
empty array when we're creating our time
together data group
and notice that we're still using KCM
time invalid for a duration here
just tell us when the beginning above
the the meta-data silent so to speak
is and we'll figure out how long a laugh
based on
when you append your next non-empty
group
so that's how you rate gap in your
metadata
a last best practice I mention output
file type before
and here's the XB longer explanation
well after writer and an after-tax per
session support
writing to a wide variety file types
you've got QuickTime movie impact for
an offer to buy their kind of file types
and those file types
can carry different kinds a meta-data
some have more restrictions and others
about what kinda metadata can go into
that file type
for the easiest situations if you have
an export session and you're going from
one from the from the same file type as
your source to the output
so for this example they're both
QuickTime movie file
this is the easiest way to ensure that
all of that data is actually gonna make
it into the output file
if instead you using a different output
file type like impact for in this
example
then them up different things are going
to have to happen
you noticed as last year item didn't
quite make it into the output file
it because they have no equivalent
representation that works with an impact
for file
if you're looking closely of a notice
that those top two items have changed
although they sound very similar they
are slightly different
identifiers because that's the kind of
it in a fire that works for them pick 4
for both after-tax per session after
writer will do the thirty three step
process
first they'll try to past that data
through directly
if possible and if not to try to convert
the identifiers
into an equivalent representation in the
output file type:
and if needed those work we have no
choice but to just drop that
be submitted data on the floor centers
have guidance on how to choose an output
file type:
well my key recommendations are if you
are
using say an expert session to copy all
of the time
or all of the meta-data times or
otherwise from the store sales at your
destination file
the best ways to try and use the same
file type: that you started with
and if you don't know what that file
type is you can use the end of URL type
identify key to find out
you can also always use the QuickTime
movie file because that is going to
have the the greatest chance up
supporting your meta data no matter
where it came from
if the Foundation supports it there's a
good chance that I'll be supported by
the QuickTime movie file
and of course this is the only way if
you're writing time to enter data
to get your time too many data into file
is to use QuickTime movie file it's the
only
file for that supports that right now
and of course
good advice is always to check the
results no matter what
check that your output files contain the
kinda better data that you expect
all the midday to the expect and you can
choose to use them in the API's
that we've already talked about if you
wanna do that at runtime
some guidance if that doesn't end up
being the case
if you don't get all the midday the you
expect we can try to do the conversion
yourself
especially if you have a custom
identifiers in or going to a file type
doesn't support your custom identifiers
take a look at that along with the
built-in identifiers we have
and see if there's something that's
roughly equivalent to what you're trying
to store
and you can do that conversion yourself
one particular example I wanna call out
that involve
only built-in identifiers is when you're
right when you're trying to go from
I D 32 iTunes wavy foundation currently
isn't gonna do that conversion for you
but there's no reason that you couldn't
do that yourself
so once again just take a look at our
long with the identifiers
in match them up in do the conversion in
your own code
that is the end the talk do we covered
we talked
obviously a lot about meta data in AB
foundation talked about all the
different classes you can use for
inspection talked about TV after 10 EV
meta-data
item and how those work together and
also offering we talked about
the after writer acid export session
even briefly on the capture audio and
movie file output
we dove into time to mentor data
including all the new features that
enable things like
the dynamic location in your own time
for the data like the
annotation demo we offer talked about
privacy considerations in some best
practices like how to choose the right
file type:
for more information contactor vandalism
team
or see our programming guide there are
some other related sessions you might be
interested in
if you miss this morning's presentation
on modern media playback you can catch
that
and the video recording tomorrow there's
also a
capture camera capture talk focusing on
manual controls
and on Thursday will have a talk about
direct access to
video encoding and decoding which I'm
sure a lot if you will be interested in