well confession 506
your app your website and Safari
my name's working mondello and I'm an
engineer on a safari and WebKit team
some four get started gonna ask one
obvious question
show of hands and then a second question
the first of
how many do you have caps in the App
Store nearly all of you
great book in a WBC you're in the right
place I'm how many of those APs
have an associated web site now the show
of hands that's
excellent you are all in the right place
awesome
so yesterday you saw Craig demo
a bunch of cool new features with the
name continuity the ability to
pick up writing an email where you left
off from one device to another
picking up a phone call from one device
to another I've been thinking about
continuity
continuity is more than just a suite of
features that we've included in the last
ten your sanity
and I'll SAT just regular old bird
looked it up in the dictionary it's the
unbroken and consistent experience
or operation have something over a
period of time
I take comfort in this definition
because unbroken this
and consistency are exactly what all of
us as users are looking for today
many of us on more than one device
we move between those devices throughout
our day something that's not uncommon s
starting a task with an app on your
iPhone and finishing up later on the
haps website on your Mac
for instance and this year we've got a
call technologies that you can
participate in continuity
hand-off at exactly what Craig use to
move from sending email on one device
to typing up on the other we're gonna
fall session on hand of this year
it's tomorrow at 2 p.m. so if you're
here you're gonna be interested in that
as well
but even before hand of users are making
these kinds of transitions between taps
web sites
and various devices every single day and
in this session
I'm gonna go over some of the best
opportunities that we've identified
to make these kinds of transition
smoother for our users
ensuring continuity for all of our users
is going to require
a holistic approach to software
development bringing together
three different kinds of disciplines the
first discipline
is that the app developer whoever's
writing Coco Cocoa Touch
objective-c and now swept probably must
have you in this audience
but it's also to take the back end
website administrator
off again take the back end website
administrator
whoever's running user accounts state
databases
all that sort of stuff but finally
its also gonna take the front end web
developer
whoever's writing JavaScript HTML CSS or
whatever cornu fancy languages
preprocessing down to those these days
so if you're here you probably
specialize in one of these areas
you may know about to have them you
might just be getting started
work to work in a one-person shop you
may be responsible for all three of
these aspects if your application or
service
regardless no matter which bucket you
fall into
you're gonna leave this session today
with actionable techniques you can put
into place
to make your users experience is better
specifically
we're gonna go into today is giving your
native Iowa sap
access to credentials that Safari has
stored
for your website to make your users
login experiences
easier than ever then gonna learn about
autofill how that works on the web
and ways to make that better as well
democrat a look at ways that Safari
promotes your website
and your website's content learn how to
make that
even better and finally we're gonna look
at your website
and how we can make your website
consistent across devices
whether the user is viewing on iphone or
on a Mac with a 27 inch Cinema Display
that sounds good to you let's get
started
first thing i wanna talk about his
credentials
if you're after service has accounts
your
defining a credentials these days for
users to prove to be
are who they say they are today
most credentials and former user names
passports
as matter fact my colleague injuries
been working on a corner application on
the side
it's called shiny and its application
has accounts
what it does is every single day that
you log into shiny
its gonna show you a picture a shiny
object
but only if you're logged in it's very
important to him don't understand it but
it's going okay
something that I realized why was beta
testing injuries ap
is that my first run experience with ap
wasn't as good as I wanted it to be
I started my relationship with shiny by
creating an account on the shiny website
and then later I went to the app for the
first time and I got this login screen
I could do anything until I got past the
login screen
when I'm run into a situation like this
I might go ahead and look up my password
in settings on I laugh or if I'm feeling
a little lazy at the moment
I just might switch back to using the
Website or leave ap altogether
we don't want people to leave your app's
we want gauged happy users
said today I'm very happy to say that
we're gonna solve this problem
by giving your application access to
some of the data
the Safari have stored for your website
the usernames and passwords are saved
for your website safaris technology for
saving user names and passwords
is called autofill and i'd give you a
little background on that right now
first thing that article does Isabel's
are forms for you
kinda like the forms that you see when
checking out an online shopping site
with information from your Contact Card
of a also saves and fills user names and
passwords
to make locking in your website's a
brief
and finally autofill generates passwords
for users
given the state of web site security
these days with major Web sites being
compromised with seems like
every other week it's a really good idea
to use a random password that doesn't
overlap with password to using
on other web sites and finally
I cloud keychain of else thinks your
passwords across all of your devices
said it a breeze to login no matter
which device you're on
I really love it when my credentials
thinking across my devices
when those credentials a randomly
generated I am in a sweet spot
both security and convenience but I've
already mentioned
one place that the system breaks down
and that's when your application enters
the picture when the user hits an app's
login screen
anything can happen they might look up
the password
they might already know it they might
decide to leave your apt
so we want to do today is taking this
failure point
and turn it into something awesome
letting your applications leverage the
security
and convenience i cud keychain and
Safari autofill
for users it's going in going from
seeing application login screen
the looks like this to seeing a simple
picker
where they can securely and easily hand
credentials back to your application
that you could use to attempt the login
no typing acquired
to get into the details how this works
I'm excited
invite my colleagues enter Bali to the
stage Andrew
be thank you rikki
guess I'm Andrew Morley from coral West
security engineering
and maybe predictably for security
engineer I'm going to start off by
talking about password security
passwords some of the most sensitive and
important data
do we have on any of our devices
passwords to banking website
have access to all our money and
passwords to
even something like social media well
thats really our entire
online reputation so we've really gotta
protect them as we
visit website in Safari and let Safari
stayed user names and passwords for us
it's keeping track love which web sites
they came from to make sure
they are only ever filled back to the
exact same website
this security and actually privacy as
well guarantee
is provided by Safari itself since
it has all the necessary information
about which credentials
went with which website and I'm using
credentials here
to mean a username and password pair
I'm sure like me you have hundreds of
native I less applications installed
and these are all run and managed by
Iowa
so what we need to do is provided way to
let
I A with no that a particular ap is
associated
with a particular website and to do so
in a secure way so
I'm going to be talking about a way to
associate ap
and your website and its really quite
easy
it involves adding one file your website
and one new entitlement to your ap
once you've done that then you get
access to a few simple API is
which allows you to see if you use a
have anything saved in Safari
and it's so get the username and
password
and to let Safari no if the user has
created an account
or change the password with in your
application
so really what we doing is trying to
make sure your
that the website developer and
the owner of the website a really okay
with
that two entities sharing information
Buckley we can use crypto graffiti for
the subject much favorite favorite
subject
every I'll with developer has a key
and a certificate issued through the
developer portal
or now automatically by Xcode every
website has all
really should have a key and certificate
issued by CA which they use to secure
HTTPS TLS website
first we going to look at the app side
things
so in the same way that Safari is
maintaining internally
a mapping between a credential and which
website it came from
you could imagine I left having a
similar table
linking aP's and web sites and whether
they've been approved
to share information between them you
can see here
that to have been marked as approved and
one is pending
so let's look and see what it takes to
go from from pending
to approved whenever you have it
installed
it gives iowa's a little all the domains
it which is to share with
I with then a pens Apple ap
site Association to the end to former
URL
and requested from server
the server then responds with the signed
file
listing all the applications but it want
to share with
I West End verifies that signature and
check
the two ap names match
once that occurred we know the apt name
and the website name and we can go
complete our table a market is approved
such the flow let's go into a little
more detail
I mention that aP's include allister
remains
there included in the apt entitlements
an entitlement is a find
key-value that included with every
application
it signed so Iowa snows the developer
really intended
to include that information anything
that added
or removed breaks the signature and code
signing on let it run
with you know it or not your application
already includes
the entitlement application identify
it and it automatically by Xcode and
its value is in the form of team ID
dot on blood & fire and it look
something like this:
the two parts the team I T is
a unique 10 character string issued
to every developer and you can look it
up on the developer portal
the bump identify part you actually
specified yourself from with an Xcode
in the general identity section
together the key mighty and bump like 10
to fire
create an application identify it unique
for every single
I wesat out there so we can specify we
really want that one
today in I with 8 where announcing the
new
Associated remains entitlement
its value has the former service coal on
forty-four fully qualified domain name
optionally
a port it'll look something like this
because for best feature want the
service web credentials
its easy to add value to this
entitlement there's a new section
under the capabilities a tab Xcode
Associated remains
country dance all you need Association
on the upside of things let's look at
what's needed service i'd
as I mentioned I less is going to be
requesting the Apple
ap site Association file but if we just
get that far what's in it
well it's just a bit binary blob but
inside is a very simple but a chase on
there's dictionary which contains least
application identifies in
the same way you could list multiple
domains in your entitlement
you can list multiple application
identifiers
in this file which allows a really
flexible
many to many relationship
the content-type returned by the web
server needs to be application
PKcs 7 mine which means it's been signed
the signature is provided by CMS that's
the cryptographic message syntax
which is the same format used by s/mime
but to a quick look what it takes to
sign file
so here's the Jason he saw a moment ago
but with all the white space removed
and I'm saving it off into Jason doc txt
next and providing it to open SSL s/mime
command
and feeding in the certificate and key
provided by the CIA for our site
this is almost certainly going to be the
same that is used by a web server
but it doesn't have to be as long as
it's valid
for the site being associated in this
case example dot com
the output then is be Apple ap psych
Association file
you can copy straight to Web server
hosting
and when that's their that everything
you need to do
except I O S is going to be making
requests of
the file from the web server and Web
servers can
return different codes let's have a look
at
some other statuses
if the file exists only get 200 OK
I wes is gonna take the file and check
the service name and application
identify match
and the signatures valid and is it mark
lot ap two main path has approved
if it gets 200 OK but there's a problem
with any of those checks
we go in market is denied
likewise any in the 300 or 400 range
like 301 302 redirect or
404 file not found we gonna go straight
ahead
a market has denied
anything and 500 range like a $500
internal server error
we're going to just assume is temporary
glitch with the web server
and retry its worth noting
that this association and approval state
is removed
anytime the application is uninstalled
by the user
which is really useful if you're
developing and testing and neater
go to this of you a few times to get it
right
so now we've set up the trust
relationship between
ap on a Web site let's see how we can
integrate prompting for safaris saved
passwords
into application flight
here we are all home screen the shiny ap
just installed and waiting to be
launched
once launched its gonna go to this flow
because we need the username and
password to log onto a backend server
right away
the first thing it does is check to see
if we already have any saved
they could be saved in the keychain as a
username and password
could be no wolf token or cookie that we
can use to login
because I just installed it there's
nothing there so we just gonna have to
prompt the user
one season has and to their credentials
then we can save them
practicing the next time and then we can
login and
see the wonderful shiny teapot T also
another one of my favorite things
so next time come back and launch the
application on check
for safe credentials is going to be
successful and we can log
strated
now let's go back to see what the first
user experience flows like
when we can check the safe credentials
in Safari
we just inserting another step again
the app is gonna check it's a demanding
itself but if that isn't any
we going to be prompted to see if they
have saved anything
in Safari
if they sweater credential reflect an
account the username and password is
going to be returned to application
which can exchange it for North spoken
save it in the keychain
whatever is required by a back-end
server to authenticate
and then you can log straight in
it might be worth noting that you still
need the using the password view
as a fallback in case the user haven't
saved anything
with Safari or declined to select one
plus the flow now let's look at the APR
you can use to implement this
we introducing three today
sec request shared web credential sec
and shared web credential and sec create
shared web credential password
the first is what causes the count
picketed to be displayed
it has three arguments and the
completion block
the first allows you to specify domain
name
the second username if you already know
it somehow
and then a completion block which will
be run
after you use a has selected item
all it has not been displayed for some
reason
now already listed all those to maintain
your entitlement
and you have usually no idea what user
names your
uses half so what you can do is pop no
for both the post first two fields
passing null for the main just uses the
entitlement values
and popping all for the user name will
get
anything that can be found any of the
domain to the entitlement
so whenever the code is executed we get
the pic /a
you just like the credential and
the completion block runs into it
is passed a data structure credentials
which contains the username and password
and maybe era if anything's gone wrong
let's look at some the code you might
want to include in such a completion
block
and its again pretty straightforward we
just checking
that there was no era and a credential
was returned
we extract username and password from
the data structure
a part of to the method that application
already had
to log into the server because it is
running in a block
I'm gonna run that on the main cue just
in case you need to deal with you on
are Eric condition down here will run
if you didn't like the password or
they're just down there
I'm gonna show the locking you why which
is awful back
and again dispatch that to the monkey
and that's really all there is however
your application
might allow a user to create an account
from within
the native application and in this case
we need sick add
shed with credentials
this time you must specify domain name
and username
and password as a completion block
but an error in this case usually means
there's something amiss
with your app site linking and the
approval process so it more useful
during development if there are no
existing accounts in Safari
when you call this this complete with no
you like just go straight in
which makes it really easy to include in
your flow
and make sure those credentials adjust
their the next time to use a go-to
website
in Safari i wish i cud keychain on any
of their devices
if the user can change that password
from within an application
make exactly the same call but just
apply the new password
in this case with an existing item began
to prompt to make sure thats
what the user wants to delete an account
he just popped no as the password
argument
again use is going to be prompted
note should only beat this if they
really on deleting their account to the
just looking out
then taken any their credentials next
time they look back in again
or maybe already determined that those
credentials style
and they wouldn't work anyway to finally
PRI
simply returns a random password each
time it called
its in the same format used by Safari
returning for a moment to the completion
block
there'll a number there is that can be
returned
and have a look at them now
the first is a sec parampara
and a description no demean provided
what tends to be happening here
is your parting no as your domain so we
can look at the entitlement
but the entitlement isn't there to get
the node two main provider
could also get a missing entitlement era
and this mean
you all specify a domain name but there
is no entitlement
next you could get a sec item not found
error
and this means that there is no approved
two main
which is the same you get if just aren't
any
but you are approved we were turning
the same error condition for both of
these at the privacy feature
which means that rogue applications and
never going to get
any more information than they they
really does work
so now let's have a quick demo putting
it all into practice
the first ball let's go to the shiny
website but
I have actually gotten account yet so
I'm gonna sign up
Safari is suggesting to fell apart what
on going to accept that
and ok today shiny thing is macaroons
that's gonna very well with the T
so let's go over to ISL s and have a
look
I with native shiny ap well here it is
going to launch it and he will
username and password so it was Andrew
and I have no idea what it what came up
too quickly
so let's go back and see if we can
change the application
to fix that
here we are in P Logan view controller
and it is cool down a bit we got the
method login
we'll catch credentials it possible
it in turn is calling model with a local
keychain credentials as possible
that takes to block the first will be
passed
the username and password if there's one
in the keychain and the second
is what's wrong on failure this no
credentials
site so I'm going to create a new method
two parallel this one
log on with Safari credentials the
possible again taking
success block and a failure block
so this code is very similar to the one
I walked two in the slides
lot into the calling the method directly
recording the success block
and the failure block if those era 42
declined to select anything
so now I'm back in the era block the
failure block
a previous method and
instead of the back and fullback
being show log on you wind title mints
I'm gonna put a cold one method that
and them in this way we have a cascade
all blocks so if there's nothing found
in the keychain
because of a lip-lock if there's no
Safari say credentials
it calls its failure block which falls
back to locking you why
so what's a give this a bill didn't see
what happens
to launch it and yes we gotta pick up
Morgan and never to date my current
the app did provide a way for us to
change a password
and it already pre filled one out from
the sec create
shed web credential password so I can
accept that that looks
reasonably secure change password and
because I already had something the
keychain
its from to be gonna go head update
that we are look straight in and
now
come back to the Mac
all being well yes there we go i cud
keychain it on its magic
and the username and password
yes I thought he did has done its magic
the update a password
is over there
so though there are quite a few steps
none at the mall particularly difficult
and it allows
of maintaining a very very high level of
security
this lost broken point in the
convenience and security ecosystem
to be may complete
thank you all
thank center I am really excited to see
what you guys are gonna do with these
API's
it's really a personal pet peeve of mine
to get stopped in my tracks in a login
screen
and I'm really excited that if I've gone
the Safari create an account there
to never see that again sec
at shared web credential the API the
danger told you about the girl you step
add a password to the user's keychain
update a password in the user's keychain
or two weeks
something it's really neat it's not me
just because what it's going to mean for
all of us in this room as users
because it perfectly captures your
applications intent
your app tells I'll ask exactly what I
want to happen to use his credentials
and they're automatically synced across
all of a user's devices with i cud
teaching
it's not as clear-cut on the web.
however
your website doesn't have a way of
saying hey Safari
I just updated entries password from foo
to bar
instead what Safari does is it uses a
series of jurisdiction in order to
figure out what your website's doing
and update your users passwords
accordingly
and make this all work Safari needs to
understand
your website's forms secure the flow
diagram
how conceptually a password manager
could be looking at your web sites
users move between states like not
having an account
registering for an account having the
account and logging in and out of it
Safari does all of this automatically
there's nothing that you have to do
there's no opting for re-analyzing your
website and offering password features
to its users
because this is automatic and it's using
heuristics
things can go wrong heuristics aren't
perfect
and when things do go wrong continuity
breaks down for your users
for instance if Safari didn't have a
password saved for your website
when you cough sec request shared web
credential from thing I less ap
gonna get back an empty array and if so
far did notice that user change their
password on your site
it so far I didn't understand that
happened when you cough sec request
chaired by credential
gonna go back a scale credential in your
users are going to be logged in
effortlessly
because it there it's an everyone's best
interest
test their web sites with Safari
autofill
fortunately it's really straightforward
to do this
all you have to do is pretend to be one
of your users for a few minutes
let's go back to the state diagram
the first thing going on do is get
yourself cleaned by circling user
account
because you don't interfere with
whatever credentials you personally have
stored for the website for your building
and then the first thing your gonna do
is create an account
just like your users would got your
accounts Creek go to your website
account creation forms
and sign up the two things that you're
looking for here
are Safari offer to generate a random
credential for the user
a random password and that after you've
created the account
Safari saved the username and password
and the way your gonna check this
is by an OS 10 opening up safaris
preferences going to the passwords pain
and I'll ass you open settings and go to
the Safari section and you have finalist
passwords and usernames that have been
saved
alright now you have an account
snatch em accounting a lot in the first
thing you're going to do
is locked up and try to log back in
again
when you go to your website login page
the thing you're looking for
is that Safari pre-filled the
credentials City users have to take them
in
right we've done that next up users
gonna gonna change their passwords at
some point
during their relationship with your
website you're going to want to do that
when you're logged in go to your change
password form
and while you're there make sure the
Safari offer to generate a credential
for users
and its save the updated credential
appropriately go back to that list
make sure that the new credential saved
and finally if your website offers a way
for users to change their passwords when
they forgot them
go ahead and check back to you make sure
the Safari save
a good credentials
and finally to simulate a user having
started their relationship with your
website
outside safaris watch delete the
credentials
that you've created for this website
going to settings going so far as
preferences
delete them then go back your login page
manually enter them and make sure the
Safari save them at that point
so that your users have a great
experience
all right testings over hopefully
everything works perfectly
but if it didn't i'm happy to say that
we have to new strategies to tell you
about today
you could put into place on your
website's forms help Safari understand
your website better
the first one is about declaring your
forms intentions
new and Safari 8 on your sanity and
Safari and I'll SAT
Safari supports three new values for the
autocomplete attribute
username current password and new
password
these are relatively recent addition to
the HTML specification
and it really easy to use just label
your username field as username
any field but asking for the user's
current password is current password
and you guessed it a new password is
your password fitzwater few samples at
this
here's a standard login form you're
probably asking for the users username
and password
go ahead label them in for type text
username
are complete with his name and label the
password field current password
I whatever form users create account
pretty similar
just label the field as username and new
password and safaris can understand your
forms a little bit better
and be sure to offer password generation
for users
if you want your users to confirm their
passwords to make sure they entered them
the right way
of times it's fine just go ahead and
labeled of
your password field and Confirm Password
field as new password
and safaris can understand that better
as well
and now changing passwords that's fine
you can wanna know the user's current
password to prove that they are who they
say they are
and you're gonna want a new password has
that's the point just use current
password
a new password something you might
notice about the slide
is that I'm specifically outputting the
current users username
within the form this is a really good
idea
because what this does is it tell Safari
which user is having a password updated
this is really important if users have
more than one account on your site
but it's just a good idea in general now
if your design doesn't accommodate the
sort of thing putting the user name out
in plain text read only like this
don't worry about it just change the
input from type text
type hidden your users are going to see
a
but safari is and safaris can understand
your forms better
and do a better job ensuring continuity
with respect to your use his credentials
and finally the Forgot Password case in
this case
you might want to know the username same
things forcing caveat you can hide it
and this time all you want a new
password so label it that way
these three new values add to an already
long list of values that you could use
with the autocomplete attribute
to help Safari understand your forms and
your intentions better
so for instance given input element and
you label it autocomplete
phone when the user uses
autofilter fill out the form you're
gonna be saying hey sorry
when you're on a feeling this please put
the phone number here please don't put
anything else
and safaris gonna do it right okeydoke
that was the first technique I wanna
tell you about make Safari understand
your forms better
and it's pretty universally applicable i
mean you could use it on any website
that has forms
the second technique I want to tell you
about is a little more specialized
specialized because it has to do with a
certain type of web application
and that's the kind of web application
that loads content dynamically
the exit charging using javascript you
know these pages
they don't of all page refresh when you
click on a link everything to snaps and
instantly
these pages are great for users this
dynamism is awesome
but it's that same kind of dynamism no
four-page transition
makes it a little bit harder for Safari
to understand that one of these
transitions in the password state
diagram
happened fortunately using some of the
same API's
you're probably already using to build
this web applications
those API to get off our to something
interesting happened with the user's
credentials
we're talking about is history and
histories pushed a
and replace statements what you do with
these
is you contribute to the browser's back
forward left
so funny user on your site and I click
three links when I hit the back button
if you're not using this you go back
three-page it's not a single page
if you're using pushed a your adding
state to the back far left
the only go back one-page
specifically push state and replaced a
take a data object
which represents the current state if
your web application this is what you're
gonna get back
when you listen for the pop state event
when the user hits the back button
that event a fire you go ahead every set
up the state as if the user has just
hit back in motor home page
as a user it's really easy to think
about the back forward left as a left to
right
or right to left syriza pages I want to
encourage you to change your thinking on
this
really what the back forward list is is
to first active user state
and with pushed a and replaced a your
dynamic
html5 JavaScript driven XHR never reload
awesome web application
can go ahead and add to it cell
the next time that the user is under
dynamic website and I gotta change their
password
just call push state once the password
change has succeeded
this way safaris gonna know that's a
really good time to propped about
saving it updated password saying it
looks like you just change your password
are you sure you want to do this and
remember
history API and everything I showed you
really only comes into play after
building one of these dynamic
JavaScript driven applications if when
you click on a link or do something else
a full page reload happens
I don't worry about this
cell by testing your website with Safari
autofill
finding any problems and trying to fix
them with the two new techniques I told
you about
you're gonna do a better job ensuring
continuity with respect to user's
credentials
their passwords automatically fill in
all be logged in all their devices and
Safari
and your I les applications will have
access to great passwords
in Sec request shared web credential
but if these two techniques not solve
all of your problems one gonna do was
encourage you to please
file a bug if you file a bug
we might be able to give you a
workaround for your problem
and regardless of whether we can give
you a workaround
your real-world test case your problem
is exactly what we need to make Safari
heuristics better
real-world test cases make everything
better for everyone
so please file box I promise that we'll
use them
so I was awful ensuring continuity with
respect your user's credentials
next thing I want to tell you about his
ways the Safari promote your website
as Violet 7 afar user start page
is a nice friendly easily capitalist
abusers hand-picked favorite
and I'll SAT we augmented that view to
contain a few sites that the users
visited frequently
and Safari analyst 10 yosemite shares
that same start page design
the quality of the icon for your website
that shows up here
can make a huge difference its a first
impression and can make
all the difference between a user
promoting
a frequently visited site to a favorite
or removing it outright
and I bet that you in your team's sweat
over your application's icon for hire
less from the senate to the App Store
and it's time to do the same exact thing
for your website
let's get into the details have
specified icons
first up Afcon website probably have a
favicon
shows up in the address bar next to a
website address on August 10
on website about specifying Kabir Khan's
for a long time
it's really easy little bit markup in
your pages head section
or a standard half an hour on your file
server
and spars can affect that but for the
start page %uh
I'll ass and OS 10 what you're really
gonna wanna specify
is what's called Apple touch icon you
might already be specifying this
because this is the icon it's used when
a user ads your website
to their home screen I less three Li
easy to do this
simple link tag inside the head section
and you can even specify multiple love
these
with different sizes so there an
application like Safari
only downloads the one that it needs
down that's the lowest resolution one
possible
conserving band with for users for
information on the sizing
and encourage you to check out
configuring web applications on Safari
web content guide
to the reason for using Apple touch
icons for the start page
is because there are you a ton of them
out there and there are ready you
the right resolution to be shown on a
Mac and i OS device
don't let the park with us Touch and
Apple to check on weird you out with the
last 10
just think of this as your web site icon
and about the icon itself use every
single pixel in the square canvas
available to you
safaris gonna show all of those pixels
and if a user does
head and adds your website to the home
screen I less
or you know that icons around of I'll
wes is gonna handle that for you
so there's no need for you to mask the
image we don't wanna have mismatched
corner radii
and finally now that Safari on OS 10 is
using Apple touch icons
you gonna put Apple touch icon mark-up
on all of your pages
not just the ones that you're serving to
mobile devices
miss really no cost to doing this a
little bit of markup
and only devices that care about the
icon are gonna go ahead and download
them
alright that icons the first impression
how your web site is seen by users in
Safari
let's talk about other ways that Safari
permits or content
Safari today is more than just the way
the people browse the web
safar users ad pages to read later using
reading list
the after party cleanup articles for
them to read later or right now
using Safari reader
and on August 10 maverick's in Iowa 7 a
feature called shared links
lets the user find articles to read find
other stuff that's interesting
ever shared on social networks well new
to Safari 8 analyst 10 yosemite and I'll
SAT
your website can participate in shared
thanks
this works as you might expect using
your web site's RSS feed
so as soon as a user chooses subscribing
shared links
I'll SROs 10 safaris gonna periodically
picture feed and show that content to
users
the content that shown in the sidebar is
directly taken from your rss feeds
something the note here is that you
wanna serve your rss feeds
and the markup Insider Pages head
sections to let browsers detect them
all devices even mobile once
Safari on iphone is just as capable of
participating in shared links
as Safari on Mac
turn our attention back to reading list
even if your site doesn't have an RSS
feed
users can add your content to their
reading list
and as you might know many view in the
audience as a I left seven
your application can add to users
reading list
piece a cake all you have to do is
important Safari services framework
and call a single method the text URL a
title
and some preview text because you're
specifying the title in the preview text
you're in complete control the holdup
the situation shirt and a little bit
familiar to you
yet again it's not always clear-cut and
how to express the sort of concepts
on the web a page on your website
doesn't have a way of saying
when I'm added to reading list use this
as my title and this is my description
it can't say exactly that but they're
are things that your web pages can say
that help them out so let's look at an
example of this
hear some markup taken from the WebKit
blog recent blog post about
fourth here lol VM jet that makes
JavaScript in Safari
superfast encourage you to read it's an
awesome blog post
that title doesn't really work as a
title of the user's page
because has bread crumbs surfin Safari
archive
but here using Open Graph meta data
standard I've put markup on the page
clearly expresses a good title and a
good description
same really simple to use
and when your website speaks with
intention the strong
safari is going to listen because you
express the exact information insofar as
looking for
Safari can rely on you rather than using
heuristics to get the job done
there are other ways of specifying the
same sorta data here some markup you may
be familiar with your web developer
med name description this is one way
that you might be specifying a
description to let's say
search engines for your pages on your
site
Safari can listen to this too because
the concepts are closely aligned
your site scription and reading this
disruption
open graph is just one meta-data
standard
you should be checking out today there
are a bunch of them on the web
and this example with reading listening
getting better titles and descriptions
is just one example of how many data
could help you out today
browsers search engines other web sites
they're all gonna find uses for this
meta data in the future as they display
your content
to try to make it more attractive to
users so I encourage you to check this
format out
I think about adopting a medida strategy
okeydoke checkpoint by now
you've added this simple file to your
web server if adopted entitlements
in your eyelash application and your
ensuring continuity with respect your
user's credentials
making easy for them to log in your app
you tested for part of it
you made it work great on your website
your icons are awesome
just as good as rap icons and you've
adopted some meta data
so that website browsers and search
engines understand your web content
better
for the rest of our time together I
wanna go over a few examples of how we
can make
your website have a great experience
when transitioning between devices
users viewing your web site on mobile
devices and desktop devices
the first example if I wanna talk about
is called be sticky mobile website
sometime in a problem I just ran into
the other day hate this all the time
but actually just happened last week my
friend was reading an article
on her iPhone look good to her she
thought that I might like it
so she sent me a link to it I'm sitting
at my Mac
and I opened it up and this is what I
saw
I saw the website Mobile layout stretch
up
super wide with my for texts that are
completely unreadable
another website when I run into this
problem i've seen this version of it
where the content is constraint is say
320 points
this is unreadable either cell
what I was able to do with this problem
was look at the website address
the page that I was on and notice that I
was on a mobile specific subduing at the
site
and that by removing m dot from the URL
I could get a version of the website the
look great on a desktop
with a nice constraint with so
some of our users going to be able to
figure some other stuff out
but they shouldn't have to and most of
them what
let's get to the bottom of this problem
figure out how to fix it
here's what I think what happened the
concept diagram
might not be exactly the same from site
to site but the big picture
and what happened here is it the user my
friend
went to a link on her iPhone when she
went to example that common this case
the website said hate I can tell you're
on an iPhone from your user agent string
I'm gonna send you to a mobile version
of the site because I think that's
better for you
and then she sent me a link to that
mobile version of the site
and I went straight to the mobile site
it didn't have the kind of thing
courtesy to write me back up
to the desktop version site and now
with hand of on OS 10 yosemite and Iowa
City
it only takes one person to reproduce
this problem you don't need friends
sending links to each other
so there's even more reason than ever
before to get
your URL strategy together
the solution this case I alluded to it
earlier it's pretty simple
let the mobile website route users back
to the desktop web site
giving me the version of the website
that's appropriate
iMac 27 inch Cinema Display
for this would've solved by immediate
problem but there is a much better
solution to be had
and that comes by admitting at the time
of the mobile website
is over using technologies like
responsive design
and layout html5 CSS you can make one
version of your website
the looks awesome for all of your users
whether they're on an iPhone
an iPad or a neck
i'm happy to say we have a full session
on responsive design this year
and you should check it out it's Friday
morning and if you're interested in this
and you have a mobile website you're
gonna wanna go to that
okay one more topic to talk about
and that's video since the dawn of
iPhone
users have been grading getting amazing
video on the I left devices
and that amazing video has been coming
to them without the use a
any browser plug-ins using
standards-based video
and because if this users have been
getting excellent battery life
and smell video playback even on
relatively low power devices
for a consistent unbroken experience for
how users get video on your site
you should use the same video strategy
analyst Ken it works just as well there
gives users better battery life and
smooth playback
and if the reason it maybe you might be
avoiding losing the plugins on
the desktop is because a maybe pre-roll
advertising or some other
interactive component you can do that
today with Javascript HTML
and video it's really simple
for more information on advanced media
for the web you should check out
actually you should have checked out the
session this morning at 11:30
go back and watch the video if you
weren't there
okay so in the last 50 minutes
we've covered quite a bit and all of it
has been about ensuring
continuity unbroken consistent
experiences
for all of our users but that they're
using our products and services
with a nap with the website and no
matter which device there on
salary cap here's what I want you all to
go out and do today
first things first but the sign Jason
file on your server
at the entitlement your application and
call the API's to make sure that nobody
in this room
ever see the login screen and I a less
after when they created their account
on the website and Safari and Safari has
credentials
next thing to make sure that those
credentials that you're getting back
from sac request shared web credential
are always up to date
test your website with Safari autofill
everything might work rate
but you should run into the problems
before users do if there are any
and if there are look at the two
techniques that I told you about today
no matter what kind of website you have
you should adopt autocomplete attributes
and use username current password a new
password
to make easier for Safari to do the
right thing with your forms
in my only take five minutes and it'll
make a huge difference for users
then sweat the details on your
application's icon
make your website's icon look as great
as that after APs
and then look at midday to find ways to
make web browsers
search engines and other web sites
understand your content better
for when they're showing it to users and
then
think about your desktop and mobile
website if you have two different
versions of your website
try to have fun you want more
information on any of this
I encourage you to get in touch with
evangelism
ETF won support forums
I got some really correlated sessions
this year some of which I pointed out
earlier
advance media for the web touch it.
with and keychain adopting handoff to
make the smooth transitions
just like use of crack in mail and
designing responsive web sites
thank you so much everybody hope you
have an awesome WABC