hi everyone I'm team in a few minutes my
colleague Brady will come up
we both engineers on apples would
contain how often have you heard a
presentation start with
today I'm really excited to talk to you
about blah blah blah
and I told myself I didn't really wanna
introduced this session that way and
then I realized I actually am really
passionate about this topic
because over the past two years have
worked on a lot of graphics technology
on the web like a CG
canvas CSS transforms animations
filters and I really think like web-dl
is the next significant leap in the talk
graphics you can do in webbrowser
repeal takes the the power
the open gles standard which is popular
on my ball chips
and combines it with Nick speed and
convenience have JavaScript
the web programming language this means
well
because you got this proliferation
really powerful keep you hardware
um combined with this incredible
performance improvement in JavaScript
we've had this sort of sweet spot we can
do these amazing graphics
this gonna give you before power for
configurable and programmable pipeline
as well as performance but because you
talking directly to the GP you
and because JavaScript is
a super fast nowadays this get allow you
to write
web content such is showing an
interactive 3d model
while still maintaining their
flexibility and he's abusive having your
text in the attractive controls in HTML
maybe wanna take that 3d model little
bit further
and do something like a an architectural
walk work a
flow-through a a building site you can
see here we've got
more advanced lighting shadows is also
data visualization
and mapping unit 3d mapping is becoming
more popular
but such as 3d let's say you want to do
a 2d
you wouldn't provide something like an
image editor that's doing to day
operations on your
your content and he get to do something
the previously wasn't available
always difficult to do in regular
JavaScript awesome is very popular on
on the web is just doing image
transitions so you got something
bit more be more exciting than a normal
image slide we can do a 3d ripple effect
and of course those games this is a
a demo angry bought by unity where you
got this console level
game engine which has things like a
realistic lighting particles
and shadows and also the ability to
destroy
evil robot or maybe you want to do
something
make you to do something like casual
gaming
and this is a sweep by play campus and
it's a really great innovative take on
that
infinite to tear on a incentive like
sliding along in 2d
you're actually flying this summer nice
stylized I
plane around this radio Island it's
quite fun so what did you learn today
I'm will stop by how to setup
had to get access to a video and send it
up in your web page
and they were gonna show had to do basic
drawing with you on this is going to be
sort of like a crash course in how to
draw something with web DL
and you get an idea of how powerful the
rendering system is
went to get that were actually gonna
move on to advanced roaring
and had to do simple animation and
nothing because its web technology
we want to tell you how would your feet
into other part to the web platform
important topic is whereas web-dl
available
and we're happy to side with deal is
available in Safari on almost any
seventy
and I was announced on Monday and what
wasn't announced
but I'm happy to say that also available
in Safari on eyewear
I'm
be even better news is this with deals
available on every device that can
install these operating systems
I'm if your program on you want to use
web video content in your app
you gonna wanna know about the modern
web kid API and its wk we view
class now one of the many benefits of
using this new modern API
is that you get full benefit love the
the jumps with nitro engine which means
you're
your contents gonna be running super
fast which we all know is
Craigs mom's favorite feature and she's
updated elapse
do the modern API I'm something else is
that the a the API service
area between I O S in with 10 is
identical this means that your
your content should run this time on
both devices with a course
the understanding that some devices
don't run don't have as powerful GP use
but otherwise it's identical and simply
because it's a web standard
that same content should run on other
browsers that support web DL
now creating great 3d content is
made a lot easier if you have a good
tool system and
even though a deals a relatively young
technology it does have a sort of
thriving ecosystem
tools the couple I wanna call out in
particular and he's a big vendors
Epic Games the makers have Unreal Engine
and Unity Technologies makers have unity
but both have announced web-dl export
from their systems
um this means not only to get the
state-of-the-art 3d
engines and editing environments US get
access to the marketplace where you can
purchase 3d models
or materials or other assets to help you
make your content
another example is the company could
play campus who also have a 3d engine
and editing tool
but they do it all within the web
browser and this means that you can have
distributed teams
working inside a browser editing the
same content it's pretty cool
if you're a developer there's a bunch of
open source liar is not just listed a
few here
much to these dues wrapped the lower
level with DAPI in something
from the higher which allows you to
program in terms of fees in q2 materials
rather than buffers and triangles
but today we gotta talk about buses and
triangles because we think it's
important
that you understand that level love have
programming such as if you are using
from these high-level tools
you have some hints as to what might be
going wrong what you can do to improve
the content
before getting to that I just wanna talk
about one thing which is
a motivation why we doing this so Apple
is always
considered rich powerful graphics to be
super important to
web developers into this fiery engine
effect this is why
about a decade ago we invented the
campus element which is what the bases
away geo is
I'm as soon as where deal was announced
we joined the working group
and to this day we volunteer ourselves
as the editor the specification
the next question is why do we choose
Open GL
and I'm jail is the most important
standard a graphics API that around
I'm it's already been demonstrated it
can run on a billion mobile devices
and the content you create there is
still just amazing on on other devices
more powerful devices as well so again
it's sorta made
a no brainer that we choose the best
standard and that way all browsers can
implement we end up with web-dl
okay so let's get coding I like all
program examples we want to start with
hello world and
went to the hello world GL so image in
your opening your text editor
and with starting with a blank slate
which is good type a few commands and
create something
that this summer the 3d interactive
environment
where actually start with something very
simple which is a triangle but
well that might and disappointing if we
go back to the 3d environment
we look at it and think actually let's
take a look at actually made up
millions a little triangles makes those
triangles have hair color
or texture applied to some lighting and
then we're entering it again with
another part where we might be doing
blurs
a close eye shadows or whatever when you
combine all together
you actually do get the advanced
rendering so you
you learn a lot of detail from how to
draw one triangle
and the power that you learn goes on to
create better things
so it start creating configuring and
roaring and for that we need four things
first we gonna meet somewhere to draw to
something to drawn to
them again in the coming to draw with me
to configure that
being tuzla paint we wanted wanna paint
with and lastly we going to do the
drawing will go through to the steps one
by one
let's start with something to draw on to
and
artists like myself call this a canvas
which is a super
convenient because HTML already has an
element called can def
so use that and this is like a regular
image element except
instead of getting the the graphics to
draw from say a fall on the web
you provide the command in javascript
that drawing to the image in the brown
surrendered that
you might already have one in your pages
the camps element we can create 13
JavaScript by create a lament
in my example under pretend I'm already
got one in the page I'm gonna selected
using the
Dom a PRI and restoring the local
variable campus cuz I wanna reference to
it lighter
now before I can draw into it I need to
tell the system
how big an image it is or how many
pixels it needs to allocate
so that when I draw the the rendering
happens into that into that image
I do that by setting the width and
height variables on the campus
here I want to set it to 600 by four
hundred but also want to take into
account
if I'm on a Retina Display I wanna high
resolution image from clearing
window device pixel ratio
that's all I need for me to draw the
next thing is I need something to draw
with
and in with GL that is the web your
rendering context this is the object
that exposes the entire web geo API
I'm income for me do that you get one
quite easily disco get context
passing the cracked the screen printed a
web DL I'm
if you're familiar with to decamp it's
raining would have seen someone call
this with the 2d eight
to the string and you get the two DAPI
so he we've
we could with witty oh and we have a
very cool GL which is
the thing we gonna draw with if you're
familiar with
native open geo programming you might be
wondering where did I set my pixel
format
and create my rent a buffer zone from
about 6-8 ra you don't have to do that
in web DL
the previous step allocated the image to
get a drawing to and this step is giving
you the context that you get a draw with
that all you have to do
next we're gonna need something to we
need to configure the system
and this is where it gets a little bit
tricky so if with very few lines with
we've got time to draw with now we're
getting into the made in the system
we're going to give this is where we
will start the crash course in in with
your rendering
before we able to render something we
need to do a few things we need to
create buffer and buffers are just a set
of data that we gotta upload to the Jeep
you
and that data can be any types of things
but they're almost certainly go to
contain the geometry that we won a
random
next thing we need is a program which is
going to be the actual way that we have
your renders it
now you baby milk be confused here
because I we're already making a program
what's
is another program and the answer is it
is we could get into the details of what
it is later
but just imagine that you gonna be
running from specialized code to get
uploaded also to the Jeep you an
executed their
let's start with the buffers I wanna
draw this triangle
and the triangle just made up of three
points
in with GL the coordinate system goes
from -1 -1 on the bottom left
to 11 in the top right and I wanna
create a buffer out of the 3-point
so I'm going to do is allocate six
values arrive six values
am at those points to those six values
so you're good x1 y1 x2 y2
x3 y3
and this is all I need to apply to the
Jeep use on a show you had to do that in
with GL
in javascript we'll start with the rave
six values
this is JavaScript awry and I'm gonna
sign it into a flight 32 Ryan this is a
special type to rain JavaScript
telling the system that I want it to
imagine
or allocate the stators affixed length
awry
where each value is a is a 4-byte
floating point number
this comes in handy because when we
uploaded to the Jeep you we've already
told the system
what the typeof data is in that way it
doesn't have to do another conversion
from JavaScript
to actually create a buffer chemical
create the
create buffer command and younger
provide the data that is going to be
uploaded
the Jeep you so I just tell it type of
the you just created send that verdict
vertices
variable up there and that's all we had
to do to create a buffer
they will talk about the program now
conceptually what we doing
is we've got some jobs could command
Rick executing
and then we gonna end up with pixels on
the screen who are really happens
is that we present some javascript
it gets into the rent with your
rendering pipeline and it's something
that draws we've really gotta understand
what's happening in the wave your
rendering pipeline
now you can look up Open GL text books
and I'll explain the same thing
but it made up and basically I steps and
each of these eight steps you have
different configuration options you can
pass to them
but this to the you have almost complete
control over near the two most important
ones are the ones we gonna talk about to
die
and that the vertex a two-step and the
fragments a two-step
we take them in isolation we can really
consider that for the sake of this
presentation
I'm executing JavaScript I'm gonna send
the command into the vertex ada
the FedEx site is going to do something
with it sent the commands in the output
on to the fragment China which is going
to do something to it
and eventually with the pixels on the
screen and this combination at the
vertex I turn the fragment China is what
we were referring to is the program
before
shoulders at this these little programs
that you gotta
right in another language which we get
to lie to and the things that execute on
the Jeep you
and the reason is to have them if
they're two different operations the
picture is mostly about geometry so
you're passing in
a points to it and it's gonna output
converted point
the fragment writers really about what
color pixels you gonna do
based on the input have point we're I
type this
diagram clockwise 90 degrees we'll look
at another way
here got the buffer the al Qaeda before
upload the Jeep you
I'm ascended into the vertex ada he said
it doesn't quite work this way
and this is where the parity pews comes
into play I'm actually get a separate
each of those it the buffering to set up
three vertices
and it gets 10 to a different instanceof
the vertex shader and these are all
I executed in parallel on the Jeep
usually get this great performance
so given a vertex which is just the XY
point in this case
the FedEx site is going to do something
and create another point
and send it back to the system month
system is is
collected all the points it's going to
do what's called restaurants Asian
so now knows where the geometry on the
screen is going to be displayed
and which pixels going to be touched but
still doesn't know what color to draw
the pixels
and its this is the next step where it's
very similar to the vet excited step
it's gonna take all those pixels
and then send them out to bunch a
parallel instances the fragment Childers
and fragment shaders just have the one
task
given a pixel what color should it be
let's look at the code for this I miss
up by creating
at vertex shader object which I do like
red china
passing in the promoter tell you that
it's gonna be a type that excite a
annex I'm gonna tell it provide some
source code for the shade I'm not
showing you the source code at the
moment
you can just imagine I'm getting it from
somewhere it might be I created by
JavaScript
Armada preloaded at all got it from the
internet and we'll get to that later
I'm gonna compiler which is turning it
in command we can use
later on the Jeep you I did the same
thing with the fragment China
its pretty much identical course I'm
gonna use different source code which
will see
once we have those two objects the
vertex shade on the fragments ada
I want to create a program and you tell
a program that it's two objects that
needs to talk to the two shyts we
created
and Italy kit and then lastly I'm gonna
tell where GLD this is the program I
wanted to use when you do you draw ring
little we have to do for configuration
so we now have
a setup where we have something to draw
or we have something to draw with
and with configured to draw or and the
last thing we need to do is render a
masterpiece
now the next rikki step
I haven't shown you any source code but
what week but the general idea is here
we have a bunch a wedgie
we had have a bunch of JavaScript we
have some buffers on the on the Jeep you
that what I want to render
and about these programs that go to
render it and I need to
at two you through JavaScript tell the
system
helm binding the data in those buffers
two variables in my program
you see the variables in the program
later the first thing I'm going to do
here is say
when you come to execute the program is
going to be a variable called a position
and I want you to associate every vertex
in the print that you've uploaded as a
buffer
to that variable
next when you actually go to use the
buffer have to tell the system
well I uploaded X why XY XY
so what you do is to it a shame that
when you're processing this buffer
take it to a time and that they're
floating point values
then I just have to draw or a send-up of
a I'm gonna draw or the vertices number
of a starting position 0 and about three
of them which makes the three points in
the Triangle
and eventually we end up with that with
the trying on screen
now that a if you have a look at the
source code all at once you might be a
little bit worried that it was actually
a favor the source code I skip someone
the slides because I wanted at ameritech
you whatever
but the important thing is actually
while you any true red triangle is an
insane amount of
hell behind that red triangle the power
comes from the shyts and that's what
we're gonna look at next
so I didn't show the source code shyts
getting would get into that
shade is a written in a language could
jheel shutting my major GLSL
it is he like languages designed for
parallel graphics
what this means is that it's got its
looks like say but it's got some
extra premiums for the I'm vectors and
matrices
and also some operations on those
premiums so that you can multiply
matrices and whatever you don't have to
do the math itself
it also has a bunch a built-in functions
such as trigonometry functions or other
up operations on the mattress is like
dot product than normal
and some other other so helper functions
to make
the common in in graphics operations
let's go back to the the view the
rendering pipe
so I had the Buffalo sending off to
multiple burdick shade is that was
standing on
franchise will simplify it again and
come back now
the data I was sending in the buffer at
the top that you familiar with
I at the moment only have XY positions
but really you can send any data into it
so here I just added some other book
other data and again
this is the this your input to the
vertex I'd each pot chunk of the
buffer is going to be associated with
the vertex
turned into a particular instance
but you might wanna send their data into
the vet excited that shared across
all the instances the running and you do
that by using uniforms
and the global constants 0 good example
that this might be the current frame of
the animation
you wanna Ronald mouse position or the
time the the
rendering time the a all maybe the
camera position
on matrix that you want to do is a
viewing position
so the bit excited cop right on most
dubstep to the inputs ones coming per
vertex
and the other one that's coming as
global variables not only has one
Toscana to produce a point
the producer that point by writing to
the global very vocal goin to skool
position
the franchise quite similar its ghetto
use the position that was passed by the
vertex Ada and any other data
and the global constants and its gonna
write to one thing which is the color
the pixel
which does by writing to the global
variable geo fragment position
let's look at the finally look at the
source code
so by Vidic shade of I've picked the
basically the most simple vertex shader
I can I can do
now remember we saw that we were binding
in in javascript
the value a position that the sorry
variable a position to the buffers we
passed in
he's right actually get to do it so here
I am in the ship that excite a saying
the data comes in from the vertex the I
want you to
associated with the very well I position
and
I'm doing the one thing I have to do
which is running 2g opposition and I'm
just riding the same value that I got in
its just sending the input straight
through
I'm this step normally you would do
something like I
map from your world cornett system into
the camera cornett system which then the
camera maps it into the screen
coordinate system
because I the dangerous and is actually
really an already in spring court system
I can just pass through for convenience
the fragment traders equally simple all
the French example equally simple
I thought was a boilerplate the boiler
plate is telling the system
what level of precision I want to use
for floating-point operations
and then going right the color the pixel
and in this case
I'm running to G of RAM color and right
every every instance the fragment
shaders writing the same value
which in this case is for a
Victor for values which is the red green
blue and alpha values
so here I am writing a hundred percent
red 0 green 0 blue one hundred percent
alpha and this is why every pixel came
out as read
that it was pretty simple and to take it
show you a little bit more power
the shade as I'm gonna show a a live
demo
okay so he's a triangle now this is
running into far into web page
and what you've got is a the top of the
screen is a web video campus throwing
the triangle we did before
the bottom of the screen showing the the
source code to the shyts
so in this case it's showing the the
vertex ada
and he's the fragment Jayda and this
whole environment is life so if I make
an edit in the page here
it's got to grab the source code at the
page recompile the program
applied to the Jeep you and render again
it's actually rendering constantly hear
you just don't see it because nothing's
changing so he's an example let's say
his his the the me running the color the
the pixel an upset at 2100 one if a
change is to just one
I get full red green 0 blue and I get
yellow let's reset that go back to the
frack the vertex ada
again he see here is the the is the
attribute imparting in I'm also passing
in some uniform values which is the time
isn't
every time i render I update that values
that I can read it in the shade up
so I could do something tricky here like
will maybe I wanna do some kinda corny
transform
on it make
the triangle twice as high so I just
multiply the walk position
or I can do something like if I take the
attribute Ian and I say I want the
Excel you to be the one billion why
Valley TX value we've got this
flipped triangle and that preloaded one
which is doing it here
so in this case what I'm doing is I've
got the input variable in a post in Cle
time into mapping that between 0&1 in
calling it
it's on it to the very will progress and
then when I come to write the position
I'm just telling the position that I
want to a
interplay between the X&Y positions
using that program
value that's where you get this nice
reflection across the diagonal axis
it's reset again to go back to the
fragments ada I'm
now we can do some cool things in the
fragment rada
for example I've I've got this
communication between the the vertex a
donde
and the fragments thereof Alec have
telling it the che to
with a position in X and why is that the
fragment so if I say instead of the
green value
I said to be safe right position
X then we get a gradient because the
value moves from zero to one across the
across the triangle I'm again after a
preset one thought on it type it out
I'm doing something similar here with
the the red value is the exposition the
the Green Valley with what position and
Anna Bligh value is of lighting over
time to get this nice
triangle it's moving I'm kinda getting
sicker the triangle
so let's have a look at it in why Prime
I'd
now he said really GL's bedroom with two
triangles I wanna draw
I A a a rectangle which is really just
two triangles
join together and if we go back to the
solemn I do see that the same animation
is still running
know what's really impressive is def
program is running
and calculating the value every pixel
every time we draw or
and this really blew my mind when I
first sort but even this is a pretty
simple example we can do
way more cool things three's a little
bit more code
but what it's really doing is just
taking some sign wives
and with slightly different offset and
adding them up to get this
this a this interactive thing no images
here it's all been calculated life
and a cool thing is you can play around
with stuff so here is where I basically
choose the frequency of the
plasma make it a little bit a higher
by dividing by leff and that's a
I don't really like the colors this is
the his the point I'm sign in color
value
at saint -4 do plus for like those
colors will be better
and I can go up here and say well he's
the number generations and I'm adding up
so it's a go down
in 2007 do something like three
come like that looks pretty cool
now as programs you know that you can do
cool things like
here let's say I want to change the
value of pi something it's quite hard to
do in the real world as far as i'm
concerned. who say something like five
six
we can go it's the kind not affect you
even do something crazy happens when
I'm now come across something earlier in
the week which
I which I really liked which was a eyes
are on the web knows a guy in his name's
Israel
and he saw the WWC branding and said hey
I could write a shaded the does this
and I asked him if I could use it and
he's the code this is really cool so
this is again
a program that's running for every pixel
every time we draw or
and it's a love that this interactive a
WWC logo
Sea scroll down to the fabled code
amazing that all running every step
so uncommon out the final one get black
here to see what he was doing in each
step so there's a gradient
there was the balls that he was on a and
many many some of them out to
that and then eventually gets the
squaring
I think this is really cool so I'm I
wrote this whole system in a couple of
hours
what's up important to you is that this
actually couple communities out there
that have something very similar shade a
toy to calm and the GLSL
a a workspace overcoming what school
playground maybe
if you look these up you'll see a whole
example %uh amazing shade as the rule
really blow your mind
sewn up up shade is I see like programs
that you write
in GLSL and upload to the Jeep you you
get complete control over the
vertex positions the party in and the
color the pixels
you a rent this grain and they're
extremely powerful
so with that I'm gonna pass it on to my
colleague Brady
who's going to talk to you about how to
do advance rendering
think it in
so far we've seen the hello world
program web GL
the basic triangle in ya there was a
little bit an effort to get that basic
trying on the screen
but once we'd gone through that effort
with just a few lines a share code
we started XIV some pretty fancy things
pretty quickly
there's a lot more to be said about
cheaters and we'll get into that
more very soon but i wanna start out
focusing back in that red triangle
so what is that triangle the triangle is
three points in space
I can rearrange those three points and
move this triangle on reshape it however
I'd like to
make you really skinny and tall knife
two triangles
to slightly different colors this is
Arnold very familiar to me for some
reason
hello that's why okay so that's part of
the needle
love the compass and thus far logo
so let's build up on this a little bit
we're gonna take this for a logo
and we're going to bring into the third
dimension
using my geo so this is the most basic
example other 3d
compass you could say but except for
that picture on top
it's basically just a great desk
so the greatest is actually very similar
to that red triangle that we started out
with
and by that I mean it's nothing but a
whole bunch of triangles itself
as the is already mentioned even the
most complex scenes in with GL
are just hundreds thousands maybe even
million two triangles
so free to those triangles we have three
points of course
was collected the code the deans already
showed us where we
take three points to make a basic flat
triangle and uploaded to the GPO
in for are desk our basic little gray
desk
we're just gon do more the same a lot
moreover the same so how do they get all
these
these coordinates here I tell you what I
didn't do
I didn't calculate them by hand I didn't
Titan out by hand
I use the tool as Dean is already
touched on
your toolbox is very important when
programming with wedge heel
unless you doing the most basic examples
a handful triangles
you're probably going to want to rely on
3d modeling tools
pre-existing 3d models to shape your
geometry
and the parents and get them into your
web DL program
the street native tools is great web
tools out there Dean touched on a few
but what they all have in common is that
they'll export vertex data
and that is any data you want that's
whatever Texas
its any data you want for any point you
want
we've already touched on the most
obvious believe this data which is the
cornet XY and z. cornet at that point in
space
we can also directly include the color
over the point
but then as we get into more advanced
graphics programming want to include the
normal doctors have the point
this tells web GL which direction the
point is facing
which is important for things such as
lighting later on
and then we can also include texture
court minutes
so watered pictures pictures are just
lacked bitmap images an array of pixels
each pixel has a color to it you know
this as an image
right so here's the Safari icon it's
just an image
but what X accordance do is they mapped
those pixels from the image
on two or three dimensional shape so we
can have a basic uncolored
3d shape and use a flat image
to define what colors that will show
so how does this look in code better
example uploading the geometry for shape
onto the GP you
for use in our shooters program are
sheeter programs
here's the first 10 pixels from the disk
so for each have these 10 vertices
we have an XY and z. cornet
and then our tool can also output the
texture coordinates
these are just X&Y coordinates
into a texture image to map the pixels
on to our geometry
instead of working from the native pixel
count the image
it works from zero 21
so once we have that data from our tool
we need to get it onto the GPO
so you've already seen the codeine
showed us but how to get the position
vertices
up onto the GPO we're going to do a
little bit more
the same to get the texture coordinates
to the GPO we're gonna satisfy
a new attribute remembered attribute is
away
to specify to the GP you the input into
the shitter programs
and we're gonna say that the input to
the picture corner attribute is
or texture cornet buffer
and then we'll go hand upload the data
from a javascript array onto the GPO
now back to our vertex shader source
code this is the most basic vertex
shader
example Idina showed us where we have
that position attribute as an input
will just go ahead and add the texture
corner attribute as an input as well
and now it's available to the vertex
shader
one of the examples Dean shown the demo
had what's called
varying variable in the share program
get in touch and what that is
so I'll tell you now varying variable is
a quick and easy way
for the two share programs to share data
so I declaring
the view text record in variable we can
pass data from the vertex shader
to the fragment share and then since
we've already pre calculated
what the texture coordinates are we
don't need to transform them anyway in
any way
we're just gonna pass from one directly
to our fragment share
so over in the fragment shader source
code will
make a similar change will declare that
texture cornet attributes
and now it's available in the fragment
shader so this is the texture
coordinates
we've gotten from our tool we've gotten
a javascript array for them
we've uploaded into the Jeep you now the
cordon survey able and a fragment shader
program
no need to worry about the texture
itself
so the way web-dl gets the textual data
from
an image that is your texture and uses
it initiator programs
is why using a sampler
so back in our JavaScript were
configuring our shooters will just
declare sampler variable
this is uniform variable as Dean already
mentioned it's a global variable the
JavaScript can assign to
to pass in data into the shooter
programs
someone has been declared in javascript
we can go back to a fragment shader and
declare their in GLSL
the type your sample to the that's one
of the few types
in the G language that operate on
pictures and once we have that sampler
will change that straight red color we
were saying every pixel was read
and I will use the sampler with this
quick function call what this motion
call does
is a says for the texture source
represented in the sampler I want the
color of the pixel
at the structure cornet and then we
assign a 2g of red color
and that's what's gonna show up in the
same
so toucher source what is a texture
source
in open GL it means one thing: Karen
Webb GL working with web technologies
there's a few different options for your
texture source
the most obvious is the image on if you
have an image
in your HTML page in the markup in your
pages finish loading
you can use that image on it as a
texture source
you can also create an image on a
dynamically and as long as he waited for
it to load
those pixels are ready to be uploaded to
the GPO
you can also grab data from a server
directly using XML HTTP request
you can and actually she to your quest
has the ability to
grab the Rob bites at the response and
that is used in web DL to get those
protects points into the shitter
and as a video on the video min is a
great way to display video
in your web page without using any
plugins in a native
web technology manner that interacts
with all the other web technology is
great
but what a video really is just sequence
images
safe use a video element as your texture
source when you're drawing a frame
if you're seen ill grab the freeze frame
love whatever's being shown in the video
meant at that point in time
and that freeze-frame will be used as
the image for the texture
last but definitely not least some
pretty cool
possibilities with the canvas element
being used as a texture source
you can draw whatever you like into a
canvas Alma and image
taxed you can use the canvas 2d drawing
API's to try to be seen
you can also use the wedgie lepi to draw
three-dimensional scene into a campus
and then use that campus as a texture
source for different web GLC
this way you can render 13 be seen
to use in another three seen for a movie
screen or a billboard
television or much more creative ideas
but how the solution code words can
stick to the basic image on it
here's an image on and I have in my
issue mark-up
and is pointing to an image that
represents the Safari logo
now in javascript first we asked the GO
Contacts
to create a texture and then similar to
what we've done a few times
we bind and do some binding doo-doo
to specify which structure we're working
on
picture 0 this constant might seem a
little weird
the story behind textures euro is a each
program you said a shaker programs
can access up to 32 textures and there's
a constant for textures 0
one to all the way up to 31 what is
using one in this example so we'll stick
with the first
then we get our texture source using
this basic da maybe I we grabbed a
reference to the image on
now this line of code is where the magic
happens in this line of code
for updating the rock pixel data RGBA
bites
eight bytes for component and we're
uploading it to the GP YouTube use
initiator programs in the key in this
line
is the texture source and that's the
image on the eve grabbed
and this is where you might put X
Malaysia to your request the video or
the canvas element has a texture source
if that's what you're doing
and then we're gonna go head and
interact with that uniform variable that
we created earlier the sampler
and now we actually need to set its
value and the value were sitting here 0
because we're working on texture 0
behind-the-scenes web-dl translator
into an object that says I'm gonna be
sampling
pixel data from texture image 0
now we're ready to go and that vertex
share
can put those pixels onto the screen
from a texture
so using textures we can map a flat
2d-image onto our 3d geometry
in this example I've been talking about
so far
it's a very basic disk and a very flat
image that's just mapping 121
by using our tools we can have a much
more complicated texture
we're different regions are the texture
represent different parts
the geometry and then we can have much
more geometry as well
side like to show you a live demo I love
what we've talked about so far
some not gonna show you any coding this
demo I just think it helps
to visualize would have been talking
about with the structure cornets
by building up an example so here's our
very basic
three-dimensional deaths
you can see it's kinda wireframe which
is nothing but a whole buncha triangles
the build-up this round shape
but as I alluded to in the slide right
before sir the demo we can have a much
more complex version of this
we can build up the geometry to
represent the futures have the compass
in three dimensions
and then we can go ahead and apply that
complicated structure onto that geometry
and now we have a live 3d representation
the compass
now to really came into its life let's
start animating
sirs this is a really quick little
routine that just in a meeting a camera
around the campus
following some sine waves and the time
just kinda given who all have you ever
to further convince you that this is a
live 3d model I can show you the parts
that are independent from another
so let's go and start that needle
spinning
saw that data are generated using a tool
its outputted
the corner and information the texture
I'm the position card information the
tax record information
it's also in outputted whole bunch of
other vertex information
we've uploaded to our share programs and
can be using
to show this compass know the same code
was being
executed both in javascript and on the
shoulders
no matter which geometry and vertices
I'm passing into it
but vertex information does not need to
come from a tool
we can also procedurally generated for
tax information
so here we have a train underneath the
compass that we're generating in
javascript
it's just a few dozen lines of code to
generate this
stripper train and Ernie so we can move
the compass over to train
the needle still spending and some more
advanced things we can do to
right now haven't talked about yet but
we'll get into in a little bit more
detail later
to add some lighting so now we have some
lights and a meeting over the train
you can see how they affect the entire
scene and the compass itself
so in a demo re showed alive
representation
few the concepts you've been talking
about so far output in complex geometry
from into out putting tax information
from it all
but the code there in a demo really was
only
a few dozen lines a javascript and
vertex shader
programming that we've already gone over
there's some additional javascript to
enemy things
but it barely scrape the surface of what
web DL can do
even with that procedural terrain
generation and the lighting affects
which I've been told you any details
about that still barely scratched the
surface what we goin to
it is immensely powerful it is a tool
box unto itself
and trying to describe everything would
take a lot more the sessions
psalm I'm not going to go into much more
detail on any of that
but im gonna talk about a different tool
box now like to shift gears
and touch up on the web platform a
little bit
the web platform is premature at this
point it's been around
for dozens of years and web GL is just
one of the newest star children tools in
the web platform
but there's also some very basic tools
that are still there
issue miles what started it all issue
male specifies the content and structure
but the document your web page
and then a little bit later we introduce
CSS which specifies how that content is
presented
CSS can do simple things like change the
font have some taxed
but it can also animate the transitions
oven imager any ailment
from different points on the page
including 3d transforms
that's already been available in CSS
native a
a native web technology that resisted
web-dl
and then of course there's JavaScript we
talked a lot about JavaScript today
because
use JavaScript to drive a wedge EL
JavaScript
also has native Don bindings to the HTML
content
and can transition styles on the page
so using just his bottom tier the
technology is the smell the CSS and
JavaScript
we've already been able to do some
pretty cool things
for example if I wanted to go into and
create a 3d image gallery
I would need to jump in the web jail
just to do that the HTML Kansas fi
series of images
and their relation to each other the
order in which they appear
the CSS can define a 3d
presentation at those images and
JavaScript contrive some CSS animations
between them
something else has already been possible
is really advanced
tax operations using HTML and CSS and
things like the font face rules
you can add your own fonts the content
you can really finally tweak
how the fun is rendered and
its pretty simple to do versus if you
tried to do for rendering in red GL you
might find it
much more difficult also in this little
video I just showed
you can see that HTML and Javascript
have built-in
event handling for the mouse pointer and
a whole bunch is
built-in controls and built-in hit
testing for different elements on the
page
these are all built in an easy to use
already
and then added even more basic level
woody shemale does
is layout content it lays out taxed and
other elements on a page
you can see in this I book example the
text flows beautifully around elements
on the page
and that was basically all free for
whoever wrote that content
and put that image into that document
and then very importantly sticking with
the native web technologies whenever you
can
get to accessibility for free
so today we're talking a lot about tools
and
the point I'd just like to drive home
here is to use
the appropriate tool whenever you can
it's an old programming at age
in its really true when we take a
platform is mature is the web platform
and introduces something as powerful as
well Geo
finally have one more thing we need to
talk about that's when to drop
so far deny have described a lot about
how you render
and individual frame in your scene you
set up
the geometry objects and the colors and
you set up your shoulders
and then you make a call to draw
triangles and boom
you've rendered still friends you should
the demoss we showed you
had animation evolved how that animation
happen
well as you know by now JavaScript
drives drying
in web GL but Javascript is not always
running
take this beautiful web page here its
clean and
looks nice but it's also very static
and as long as I'm the user and I'm not
touching the mouse or keyboard
Anna interacting with the page it all in
the pages very static it does now timers
or any other things going on
no javascript is executing so how can we
render web-dl
no javascript is executing well
but then if I start moving the mouse
over the page and selecting things and
dragging in
bringing at menus now JavaScript is
executing a whole bunch
except it's responding to all these
events that are happening its executing
a synchronously
hundreds of times a second
so in one of those little JavaScript
executions you could do some drawing
but you probably shouldn't draw in every
single
event handler that's called takers dad
just be crazy
you be drying trying to draw hundreds of
times a second
that can possibly work because drying
takes a long time compared to how
quickly these events would normally be
handled
you can only get bits to the screen
sixty times a second
so basically you just slow down
responsiveness you start chewing through
CPU and better luck battery life
and you wouldn't even get anything out
of it
but there are times when you might want
to draw in direct response
to one of these events imagine if you're
entering a 3d button
using web DL in the user clicks on it
you might immediately want to
redraw your scene to update the state
there that's great
that make sense if you have a complex
scene that is animating a lot of
geometry though
you probably want a smooth animation you
probably are going for that 60 frames
per second
animation now to get that I can tell you
one step house rule
please don't use timers JavaScript
timers
our way to execute a channel code at
some point in the future
that's based on the time delay dis
it turns out is not appropriate for
rendering animations
on one example words inappropriate is
that the system might be under load
and you might not be able to keep up
with 60 frames per second so if you set
a timer
to run 60 frames per second not knowing
the systems under load
you're going to be trying to draw more
often
then your drying can be presented on the
screen
this is just wasteful its gonna waste
CPU heat up
user's mobile device burn through
battery
so what can we use instead
there's an API specifically for drying
that you should use incentive timers and
it's called request animation frame
much like a timer you pass a call back
to request an emission-free
such the first thing you do to use it
know when is your call that called
your call back is invoked when WebKit
Safari
or that your application that runs
WebKit
knows that it's time to draw
so if the system load as lights and your
drying is simple enough
you can keep up that 60 frames a second
circus animation frame will be called
sixty times a second
if the systems under a little bit a
heavier load and you can't keep up with
that
it'll call requests it'll call your call
back less often
if your web content is in a background
tab in Safari for example
or the canvas your web GL is painting
into is
off-screen request an emission-free
might be called
much less often or not at all because
what it knows
that trying a scene that can't be seen
is not important
so here we have a drying called a
culture in and we set it up to be called
by calling request and mission frame
with the triangle that
insider call back we do some drying
this can be updating physics based on
the amount of time that's passed
responding to cue that user events that
we've logged as the user was moving the
mouse around in
pressing keys in search and then we can
drive the individual moments were seen
the compass other entities the train in
the background
and then when we're done drying we
request the next compaq
were telling WebKit hey we finish trying
one frame
now it's time for me to be told when to
draw the next room
and that's it
so that's all we have to talk about
about these nitty-gritty topics
the code and how things fit together if
the web platform
but i wanna show you one final demo or
call it the request animation frame demo
because this demo certainly does use
request animation frame
but it also uses a whole lot more so our
friends at Epic Games
we're happy to let us use this demo from
the Unreal Engine
and this is just a really cool little
temple thing we have
money go and take a full screen so this
is rendering in Safari
this is executing JavaScript this is
executing
fragment shooters and vertex shares
and what we're seeing is just
amazing so there's a lot going on here
we have light reflection allottees
surfaces
really interesting marble and glass we
have fire casting
reflections in light as we move around
you can see the background scene being
reflected
of the shiny walls finest tears over
here
says enter this hallway
me go back and forth to three times I
love this you can see this
orange reflection on the wall some
wondering where that weren't as coming
from
something also interesting as you see
this room overhears a lot brighter
the engine is doing HDR for dynamic
lighting effects
to great effect so we can see that these
fires on these podiums here
they're casting shatters into the
hallway here's a more example the HDR
contrast
I mean it's a bright room so it's dark
off in the distance this in millions are
triangles millions vertices
it was generated with some pretty
advanced tools
but then the actual code the drives it
isn't nearly as advances the data that's
coming in
it's just relying on the power G on the
power the web platform
to do previously impossible things
using the tools to the web platform and
to rapper sup I like to invite my
colleague dean back on stage
thanks very that
pretty awesome and like I said the start
with jill is insanely fun technology to
play with
so while you might not get quite to the
Unreal Engine straight away you can
certainly play with stuff
right away and get some amazing input
let's wrap up
so with jail provides rich fast powerful
graphics inside the web browser
it's available in Safari on both I was
you seventy and I oocyte and it's also
available in the modern market I PIKK we
have you if you're a developer
with that I wanna tell you drink eat
more information is an
email address you can get for contacted
Apple as a few web-sites
because with kate is an open source
project so you can follow along with the
development
on wiki total the some related sessions
the one yesterday on the bond market
APRI
which is definitely worth checking out
and we've got one
tomorrow on the web inspector and modern
JavaScript which causes important to NGO
and we're looking forward to seeing what
we do have a great rest the conference