good morning
and welcome to WWDC session on Ironwood
branch
I'm prescod you up and I'm here with my
colleague
ready to party to share with you how
beautiful ring
the Ironwood branch platform we have
some
awesome stuff you're bringing to you
this fall and I can't wait to share it
with you
but before we go there knowing some of
you are probably knew to advertising
and perhaps you know what I hadn't been
for the first time
that stock with two foundational
questions
why advertise and why
I had left after the fourth question
why advertise see you develop this app
you put a lot of time and energy in that
and put it on the App Store
not do things can happen
first users can find your app
our second you can find users for your
app
users will find your app if they know
about you
audio app is featured in one other
categories in the App Store
but with thousands of ups
coming on App Store everyday natural
discovery of a rap
becomes increasingly difficult and you
don't have much control on
so what can you do to take more control
on the success of your app you
can advertise when you advertise you can
find the right users
that make the difference and when it
comes to advertising
your ops audio products to millions
of Apple customers around the world I
had
is your best choice why
because I had is part of Apple
and vino Apple users all
$800 million of them me know what
acts and other iTunes content they
downloaded
and we know how and when the user last
june
be introduced i'd workbench a
self-service
mobile advertising platform that
provides you
the simplest way to promote your product
to millions of Apple users around the
world since we introduce I'd workbench
you've successfully help developers many
of them
advertising for the very first time
drive millions of visits
to the iTunes product fetus I'd
workbench
is open to everyone and you can promote
anything using I'd workbench you can
promote your aP's
you can promote your products your
brand's
your service including your iTunes
content
but its music books I movies
last June that mean to you sidewalk
bench
we started in the US as the fourth Mike
and a few months after that
be expanded internationally I will brent
is now available
in 14 countries and expanding rapidly
now creating a campaign using I'd
workbench
is very easy you can create one
in just a few minutes to demonstrate but
a
I have official you how easy it is to
advertise using I'd want bench
thank you punish good morning everyone
I'm ready to carry from my and
engineering team I'm hitter demo
I had workbench in the family will see
how easy it is to promote
an app during give them all
you thief lol options but I'm going to
focus on a few
and the car more later let's get started
I had workbench
effective herbal doin work bench for
Apple dot com all you need
is an Apple ID to log in may login
the five page you go to if the National
dashboard is a summary of on the
campaign and I think gives basic metrics
to get into the campaign creation flow
left click on Create campaign
the first try you have is what do you
want to promote
ap our product
netconnect ap be auditory apt
that are published in the App Store from
my time in america
I add workbench automatically gets all
absentia published to the App Store
and makes it available here so you can
promote to campaign let me Santa Clara
for big back my goal is to drive down
looks
I'm going to CPC cost-per-click
looking at my campaign
picking on Mac will take me to step 2
targeting
targeting is all about finding that
night Rd in for a campaign
we have two options auto and manual
in Quetta auto I at feinstein guardian
for you
in Getafe manual you get to said
departing for france
never set out a next country where you
are at it going to run
not affect United States next act added
the combination of creating
and destination when effect banner for
creative and definition i cant
I guess definition efforts to any
after product page menu that can
review the abbeydale and download the
app right from there
next Friday defended if you're in with
your campaign is going to run
the default started today and ended a
month from now
limit and if next budget
how much money you're willing to spend
on this camping man for two thousand
dollar
daily spangler is automatically
calculated
CPC bit how much you are willing to pay
park-like the maximum you are willing to
pay per click
made their 50 cent at Lady
CBA by an optional picking up calculate
will give us the estimated number of
impressions
and perhaps if you want to see more
impressions untapped
you can change the combination of
targeting budget in bed and your team up
next
name online I'm use the term line
several times in this page
moneyline a line in a combination of
them
targeting budget and bit you can have
several lines in a campaign London and
if line
my simple art online
clicking on next will take me to the
targeting summary page
met on the line for lifting for this
campaign
we have diff 19 you can always add more
lines by clicking on create Lamberton
looking on next de castille
neck that's kept me which is creating an
act the first right we have
selecting a great man united going to
run cried the universal app
so Testament detected back and game
iPhone iPad and you know what's up that
said if you are so
for languish in a pic with English mean
what right up there as well
then thats defined the creative it to
try to
using a template and from my desktop
from my desktop
Eve uploading your own banner
but for now let's select company dumping
the a bestseller template for you to
make it easy
and you can see that different for max a
for this template the prophetic Mariko
for title
that give the name of the app and for
message
if you are somebody had a and for Carter
action
you have therapy to find one are you can
always send a custom text
not detect download now and he did the
preview
how your banner is going to look on a
new life
you can click on view of IVF to see how
we are prepared to create do for
iPhone iPad portrait and landscape not
have the ability
better definition iTunes I just got
another fed up to the destination
its binding to the car I i cant product
page
funded act to go live
we need also see a diff fluid the line
that we have created
I found it on the line
thank you that name Matic orelon
picking on next will take us to the ax
Armani page
where you'll see all the acts that are
created for this campaign
on you can always create more act from
here by clicking on create AAC
looking on next mistake after the
campaign summary page %um you can give
you all the details
in one place when you're promoting
what you're targeting when you attack
Inc if you have not fed up the payment
yet
which is a credit card you can always
click here
but let summit
the creators are summit fr I aggregation
review
after month an approach your camp end of
life that's how simple it is
back to punish so next
let's take a deeper dive at the tools
options
controls flexibility you have in making
advertising work
using my workbench relook at the
chip look at the choices you have into
the audience
the controls you have in setting a price
the tools and options you have to create
an add
make an impact and finally the the data
and insights you have
to understand your campaign performance
and optimize
let's talk to choosing audience
selecting the right audience for your
Apple product
is key but I'd workbench you make it
very easy for you
to define your audience at the highest
level
you have two options auto
and manual are targeting
which is signed the demo is the simplest
and probably the most powerful option we
have 1 I'd workbench
this is where I had does
all the heavy lifting for you if you
want control
you can choose manual when you choose
manual
you'll have several options to define
your audience
on the left side uses simple targeting
options
like gender age geo
and device you can choose for aid you
can choose specific
age group that you want to target for
geo
you can choose I specify states and EM
is
that you want to target for users on the
right side
that some very powerful options starting
to the top
iTunes preferences is an option
that is exclusive to I had this is where
the power of the App Store
and iTunes Store comes together to help
you find the right audience
when you make a selection here you're
basically selecting users
called actually downloaded content in
that category
so if you were to promote a health and
fitness
ap wouldn't it be great if you could
choose the audience
who like to download health and fitness
aP's are who you who like to download
fitness and workout music retired
workbench
you can do that very powerful the next
the options
lets you define value at once very wanna
show you add
which is actual notes when you wanna
that scheduling and how often
do you wanna show and had to a
particular user which is frequency
capping
you can mix and match any of these
options
to define the right audience for your
campaign
next let's look at the flexibility you
have
and setting your price: with I'd
workbench
you can choose how you wanna pay for
your campaign if you want to pay for
every click
you can to CPC if you wanna pay for
every thousand impressions
you can to see p.m. the bid you enter
is the maximum you're willing to pay
when you win the auction
I'd workbench is a bit odd marketplace
and on this platform you have the peace
of mind to know
that you only pay up anymore
than the next highest bidder now let's
look at the options you have been
creating your ad
there are a range of options you have
when it comes to selecting your act you
can have banner ads
video ads which are also known as people
are rich media ads if you want higher
engagement of the user's guides
banner ads provide aid direct path to
action
up on top of a banner you can take a
user directly to an iTunes product page
are to a mobile website up on top of a
banner
you can also take a user and show them a
video
and then take them to iTunes product
page are to a mobile website
let's take a look as an example how a
banner ad looks like
here's a nap you see the add will render
at the bottom
after a few seconds to ad will refresh
the use and engage us with the ad
and when the user clicks on it the user
is taken to the App Store
the user can download the app at this
point
now once the user downloads the app
we don't chill the same download add
again to this user
which means you don't waste your money
showing ads to users who already have
your app
Nexus video ads video ads the
automatically
before a video content they play
directly in a full screen mode
between you ads you can also have an
optional call to action
which will take the user can I do this
product page
on a mobile website here's an example
above you can chase lie or let the light
chase you
introduce a nitrate and I O S
bookmarking tool for natural light
light right for iPhone now available in
the app's
as you noticed there was a lot more link
at the bottom of that BDO
the user clicks on that lamar link and
the user is taken tonight is perfect
beach
you can also have the user go to a
mobile website
if you want to create rich media ads
for more hiring agement you can do that
using I don't think as well
up on top of a banner you can in March
your users
into a very custom product or brand
experience
you can choose any combination of
features and any combination of cargo
actions
to create a rich media I show you an
example
but the couple I and had actually used
really good features
to create a great experience let's take
a look
here's the app you see the had been
rendered
the user taps on the ad and it's taken
is a must into a brand experience
the user can browse through the pictures
gallery
the user has been it is still within the
app
you can take the user to Facebook so you
can have a Facebook integration
you can have the user like your page on
Facebook
you can have the reservations Mar module
within the app
finally you can integrate the app
download right from this plea
so as you see I'm in the you can do a
lot of things when it comes to reach me
gots
now that awesome add was created
using a free tool that is available to
everyone
which is gone as I producer
without producer you can create
highly interactive rich media ads they
made it so easy for you
that you can just drag and drop your
assets in a visual layout
are you can customize the visual mail
you provide you with an extensive
library a $4,500 blueprints
which I like templates and when you use
one of these blueprints
the combat built in performance and Alex
so you can see how you use it is
engaging and interacting
with the rich media ad and finally with
I pretty the 4.2
that was introduced just two weeks ago
yet integrated I producer with workbench
which means if you create an ad using I
producer
you can now applauded directly onto
workbench
and then you go to work bench
you have it available to use
so want to create a campaign
your campaign is running and you want to
see how the companies performing
when it comes to camp in performance
people I do rich
and Alex that helps you understand how
your campaign is doing
so you can take the right actions
to give you data performance metrics as
well as conversion metrics
which includes you know what you spend
is your top two readers
number of impressions you've got as well
as the downloads that you received
so you can tune your campaign you
provide you this data at every level
at the aggregate campaign level as well
as
at Lord line and adults
you can also download is data as a CSV
file
from any of the mouth extreme
so at this point I'll ask lobby to walk
us through some of these tools and
options that we talked about
to make advertising work thank you very
in this demo I'm not to walk you through
some of the core concepts that pressure
mention
touching targeting some of the new Act
for Mac on our tix
let's get started have been working on a
campaign
haha picnic that finished his campaign
together
exceeded
campaign and pick just one line with a
man you're targeting
and I want to finish show you what
targeting I'm fed up
by editing the line and literally act
after this one
the car running option
manipulative man you know and DEF
and for the country if you get in a good
state defend a different targeting
options
that we have available you can see on
the options on the left hand side
on the right you see the options have
been selected by default
it's all let my partner
fee of the after a printer when affect
lifestyle
fought on video and travel
never act out I wanted a similar thing
wanted to live style
and wanted a foot on radio
and travel economic Senate Mar
messed up on in a holics performing for
Act I
my family did to create a banner
defend their gonna do video ethically do
a website on the destination my goal
here is to drive traffic to the website
and for Friday
lividity fart not given them spend
budget and big here let's go to the next
day
their weekend
create an act here we have to try since
a banner our video
attack video and very wet act you want
to attack Iran
are divided for Mac long-range that pic
you are so
for language let's keep it at English
and he had that effect there they need
to upload a video file
I am your friend
supports to format from the media file
and furry
animal the nephew my specs here right
here
the inkatha you to follow defect so you
don't rip on any validation errors
let up
the fight is being uploaded from my
laptop do the work myself much right now
watched the fiery just the fireworks the
file will be transcoded
to multiple farm act disorder divider
Andalucian like iPhone hired Laura
iPad hi to them north it's uploading
right now
many think
takes time I get them
defusing the network bandwidth I guess
right now if you'd like to file a brief
Federer and you thought the status
change the formatting did random video
transcoding is happening
did actually transforming the video
disorder other devices
let's take a quick preview
you can chase like
or let the light Shishir introducing
nitrate
and I always put marking time for
natural light like right for iPhone now
available ironically video
100 one thing here
for you have an advertiser preparing one
file
21 technical specification be assured I
your add video act is going to run
on all Apple devices in the best way
possible
to back how simple it is still up
creativity actor you the flood effect
for Mac the inca you to take advantage
of it accepted definition and the fed
and I do have at
website you can you the URL right here
and then even after for the destination
the name I like the name like pregnant
thank your
and likely would have if artifact to go
live
in a defined in the line not defended
the video online that they create an
earlier
name tag and I
name again my awesome video taking on
extra day after the Act summary page
to tax that mr. of them
powerful act for Magglio at so far in my
two demos the mainly focused on
creating a campaign on editing a
campaign focused on the baton parting
a knack for Mac once a campaign is
created
the next thing to fogarty monitoring the
performance of the campaign
to ensure that it is going toward the
goal
your head out for in order to monitor
the performance of the campaign
the aftermarket the next I want you to
take
I want to take you to the Alltech FEI if
have this to campaign
there have been running for a fifth
month I want bill
show the performance of this campaign
you see that actual just the basic meant
to expand
impression DDR and conversion
you can click on any of this metric and
going to the death
may be far did you since campaign stock
and you have different custom dating if
you can fact that they're prepared for
you
misconduct of 30 days back to spend for
the last edited for this campaign
seems like we are spending more in the
weekend gonna spend is coming down into
the death
you have different metric that you can
view
have listed here and
you can overlay any metric on top of it
are if you want to compare how ya been
spending
compared to the previous media you
cannot affect
empirically with me that gives you
how the last edited is performing and a
button up in a 30-day
only the pretty
need feature made you can overlay any
metric here
and compared to the fan
I wanted average CPA madrick
impregnating less than two dollars for
download here
that's going to the likes
buddy finally gives you the committed a
number you can always
fact I'm thank you to staff to see how
the line for performing
in fact we are spending more on this
line on this one
and you can do similar analysis on that
site at La
buddy far did you hear that the fan
fucking video you can always change tab
the metric and change to the bank he did
graph
pretty close on this to act your
may go back to the summary and find a
couple of things here
you can easily toggle between a graph on
the table you
features to do so
Rd you can scar down and you can click
on Download via free
to get a file and your dad desktop
and offer announces and don't see if
he's available
across the board on dashboard on every
and XP
that we have
to toxic Greek or we offer you know how
to measure it
the performance of your campaign
all the data that i've been showing last
five minutes
back data is available to the API
connect them not to talk you through the
complete overview of I add 120 API
that we have released this year say you
are
you an advertiser you created multiple
campaigns
on managing on earth campaign
and you want to scale be on the web
interface
ABA Pheri for your aggravate her
want to get the metric unincorporated
your own dashboard
ABA for you let's get into the
more details you can also use it for
bulk operations
UPA's have two broad categories
reporting then you can get the metric
and perform their of Ryan and real-time
analysis
what I mean by real-time analysis
you can write a program for example the
grounds at the top of every hour
get the metrics a night at the data
and modify your campaign data you can't
rape the bed
start and stop a campaign add that's
what a popular B&M analysis
for of an analysis you can do you don't
act
campaign management in the campaign to
do
a bit but a campaign data and start and
stop campaign find track
let's get into some very basic the
talking about EPA here
for communication
APA you have Jason orange GPS
we want to keep the data protocol pretty
simple 30 the Ghana dan
and unity that kept used a fun for data
got and its owner GDP at for security
the next authentication
the US plans to take the K private key
an access token and a combination
for a vindication making it a very
strong authentication
I'm for key management you want to make
it as easy as possible
so you can we having them interface for
that on workbench
ap
so how do you manage your def a PIA
get the basics tab download Keith verify
keefe
on in today
go to work bench got an API page
click on the download link to download
the key
menu Donald the Keith did you read the
file to have peace
and sample programs and family programs
up already embedded with your keys
run the sample program and verify the
key
fine and then don't know the API
programming guide
read your own program deprive them on
your farmers
and integrate that's how simple it is
new cookie walk in from the car matter
we have any session but session
initialization which is key
because you need to pop aficionado for
every method that you are going to Cali
a program
fun API campaign matter magnetometer
to get the campaign tito
reporting API to get the metrics
and campaign management API to update
the details
as I left out on top
now I'm going to walk you decide on the
fam program that every damn
using the highlighted made it here
indexation
get campaign did out and a bit like
for here just summer program sample
matter
man I'm trying to pass access token
prepared the press tab
posted to the Federer
and get the response back and read
defection from back
session ID from their funds once I get
the fish in it.
iPad affection I D cue get the campaign
to identify that
get the campaign a def and forget about
running state
possible the summer get that fought back
next for the campaign you don't I got
and passing
the line 95 which I want to increase the
bid thank give the line at session ID
line I T and Phoebe Mb
pasta Federer and get their funds back
that's how simple it is to write the
programs to communicate with API
powerful secular and easy to use
got paid out the death
I'm going to pass on to punish to walk
us through
what's coming next take a fresh
think you're on the it's fascinating
what you can do with the PI's
and how you can make by changes to your
campaigns from your own user interface
so what's coming to spot
so far we've talked about how I had
workbench can help you acquire new
customers
but that's just half the battle for you
to grow your business
you also need to reengage picture
existing customers
and have them do more of what you want
whether it's spending more time in your
app
buy more of your products are even
trying a new app
I came across a study recently on the
web
by mobile analytics firm local ex which
said
22 percent of the maps that were
downloaded
were used only once and over sixty
percent of them
will use less than 10 less than 10 times
now you want users to frequently engage
with you up
on your website let's take a few
examples how
engaged to be engaged in with your
customers can help you grow your
business
first example is about a game app
see you came up with a new iPad washin
after iPhone game
now who would be the best customers for
this new app
of course the user's who use that game
on the iPhone
what if you had a way to connect
with these customers and informed them
about your new game and what if you
could inform them
about this new game when they're on the
iPad
arthur you enhance your app and United
more levels
Morgan levels are you are more things
that you wanna sell in Europe
what if you had a way to reengage with
the user's
and Scholl are promote these levels
only to users were beached seven levels
in a game
a show this much in NYS only to you to
to users who actually buy merchandise
like this
and what about all those users who
downloaded your %ah
but haven't used it in the last two
weeks
what if you had a way to reconnect with
them
and motivate them to try come back and
try your
app again and what if you could connect
with them
when they're not in your app let's take
another example
a retailer see you have a regular
now you have users who browse through
your product catalog
and acting to the shopping basket many
of these users
exit the app before they actually make a
purchase
what if you had a way to find these
users
and bring them back to finish the
purchase
and what if you could bring them back
exactly at the point where dad left
in the shopping basket so they can
finish the transaction
in next step
and if you want to send offers to a
loyal customers
what if you could show these offers deal
I'll customers irrespective of
what I was devised their own
and for users and your customers were
items in the wish list
what if you could reconnect with these
and inform them
when the items and the Restless are on
sale
now in each of these examples that we
talked about
you talked about reconnecting with a
specific group of audience
whether it's all the customers who have
downloaded iraq
are the Dharma users who haven't used to
ap
are the loyal users who purchases for
you
other users who have an abandoned car on
your shopping
on your app be call
these group of audiences
segments now they're probably a million
ways you could segment audience
you know your business and your app and
users best
so you will segment two users the way
you want it
and for you too easily create segments
you're introducing a new functionality
this fall with I was 8
which we call audience segmentation
billing segments using audience
segmentation is very easy
you could do it in just two steps
the first one is you get segment ID's
from Ironwood branch not every segment
is unique so it has a unique segment ID
you can download the segment ID's from
I'd want bans
want to get the segment ID's you can
integrate the segment ID's
in Iraq
you map the user behavior are the
functionality you have in the app
BD segment ID and when a user
demonstrates a particular user behavior
reaches the functionality city just a
particular level
you in through my dad in a weight that
you automatically make API call
using the new I O S it as decay
and past that segment ID onto one page
now when you do that your segments but
automatically start getting populated
on i'd one-page here's an example
segmentation was done
based on time spent in an app
various segments users who have spent
less than one hour in the app
1 to 10 hours 10 to 20 and 20-plus
hours India now if you were to reconnect
re-engage with these users
you would probably have a very different
strategy when it comes to be engaging
you
with users who have spent less than out
in your app
compared to have spent more than 20
hours
here's another another example
segmentation is based
on level the views
whenever you are you thirty just a
particular level
the goal from level 1 to level 2 API
call that I talked about his
automatically made from the client site
from your apt
and the night segment ID's past and the
user gets added
to this new segment so once you do
segmentation this way
using Iowa City we can unlock
some amazing thanks which being brings
us to the second thing that the
increasing this fall
because I like audience insights
then you're segments Beach a particular
potential abusers
even show you unique audience insights
into your segments
all for free at no charge
these insights are based on iTunes data
surveys show you how the distribution as
up the users in your segment
the demographic distribution how age
gender Houseal income distribution is
for these users
show you the top regions the top
countries top States
the Emmys these users come from
the top languages these users have on
the devices
as well as the top iTunes preferences of
these users so you know
what are the things that really like to
download
now once you have these unique insights
you can take some
very tangible actions
if you know the demographics of the
audience and in the segment
you can find junior ap pursuit
more of the demographics
if you know the top regions and the
languages
of the audience you might want to
consider localizing Europe
if you haven't English up and you know
that the top region
is asia-pacific and the top language is
Japanese
you might want to make a Japanese up
if you created a segment of all your
lawyer users
now you understand the characteristics
of those audience
and then using workbench targeting you
can find
more of the same and you can't build
your audience pool
and finally with audience segmentation
an audience targeting together we can
bring you
another big thing which you're also
introducing this fall
and recall it i dnt targeting
i dnt targeting lets you re engage with
every segment that you have
in a customized me you can give a
customer experience
each of your segments so now you when
you had those garment users wouldn't use
your app
you can we engage with those users with
that segment
show them a custom message motivate them
to come back and try out again
and then you have users who have reached
a certain level and you want to push
them to the next level
you can create a segment of the users
who have reached a level two
show them a custom message about love
pretty
and engage with that take them to level
not open the app deep link them
directly to level three
and those users who had an abandoned
card in your retail ap
you can re-engage are retarded those
users
irrespective of what device they are on
and bring them back to your app
not only bring them back deep link them
directly to the shopping basket so the
next step
they can finish the purchase
so really anything is possible for each
of your segments
you can create that awesome message
and take the user to verify you want in
the app are given to any website
now that's not it with the audience
retargeting
actually find those users for you
on any I was device
so now when you have an example that he
went to use your iPad
ap a new app now you can find
your iPhone app users
when they're on the iPad
so what you're introducing here is a
crossed ap
cross a device retarding
docked is huge
what is unique about this the first
thing is
automation that comes with it
when you both segments using I was 8
your segments are automatically updated
in real time
no more of manually harvesting idea
phase
sharing them with your network partners
your data is most secure when it's in
one place
and there's no better place an Apple
iPad but you create segments
this me same addition is automated
audience insights run based on
segmentation
that the Obama updated as well as the
audience retarding
is updated in real time
the next thing as privacy
audience to be targeting and the Sendai
solution be talked about
is deeply integrated with the IRS
you get all the benefits of the built-in
privacy controls
that comp the solutions complies with
the limit at tracking
so now if you have a user who has limit
at tracking
on but use that is removed automatically
from the segments so the user is not
retarded
everything is automated you have nothing
to worry about
so with the audience segmentation
audience insights
an audience to targeting I had becomes
I'd workbench
becomes a complete solution you cannot
only for acquire new users a new
customers
you can now understand your existing
users
and he engaged with them to grow your
business
what is coming will be introducing to
new ad formats
this phone interstitial ads
we can also call is full screen banners
and medium rectangle
article as and Rec bodies ad formats
will be available on iPad as well as on
iPhone
soviet-backed you'll have for at formats
to choose
banner ads video ads
and officials an Amtrak
the next is gonna continue enhancing the
I had were bent API's
willing to use I don't want API 2.0
which will give you a full
read/write campaign creation capability
so if you work with a demand-side
partner article as DSP
you can now have your DSP plug into I'd
workbench
and create and manage campaigns on your
behalf
from the own you I an interface that's a
move to words programed buying
automated way of booking campaigns and
managing them
from your own UI blood supply to APIs
for segmentation that we talked about
Justin
a little bit ago and finally be
continued that you expansion
be going more countries and then as but
would think that we have in plans for
you
suitors to summarize you use at the sign
the demos in Troy the talk
i'd workbenches the simplest way for you
to reach Apple users
it's very powerful and it's open to
everyone
so if you haven't tried workbench yet
go to i'd workbench for Apple dot com
and login
but just your Apple ID make sure you
take advantage of the API's that be
review today
the new art form at the probable down
and coming in phone
and finally the key thing make sure you
enable you up
for segmentation you can get those free
insights that we just talked about
and you cannot sorry engage with your
current customers
if you have more questions please reach
out to our evangelistic
Mike Malone have
lot of documentation
on I had online want but help
and you can also find us in the Apple
Developer Forum
there was a session but is very related
to what some other things that we talk
about
today it was yesterday in case if you
mess that make sure you watch it later
on
in that session we talked about how to
use the API for segmentation
so if you're interested in that make
sure you you take a look at that
that said thank you and have a great WTC