alright good morning everyone
come to session 5 11 this is the
introduction to the photos frameworks
collectively known as photo kit and my
name is Adam swift no jokes please
I'm a software engineer on the IRS
frameworks photos very much dean
alright so
we're really excited about introducing
you to fuck it today
the fuck it up for kate is comprised of
two frameworks the first framework is
the photos framework
which gives you access to the photos and
videos
from the user's photo library and you
can use it to build
a full-featured ap like the built-in
photos application the second framework
is the photos UI framework
and this is a framework that will allow
you to build a photo
editing extension ap extension that can
be used right within the built-in Photos
app
so
in the session we're going to focus
first on
how you can use the photos framework to
faction manipulate photo library model
data
handle external changes and both
retrieve an edit
photo and video content in the Iowa
State photo library
now we're gonna turn our attention to
the photos UI framework and walk you
through the steps and the concepts in
you need to understand in order to build
your own affects engine for editing
photo and video content alright so let's
get started
with the photos framework the photos
framework is a new
objective-c framework in IOSA and
it allows you to make your application
a first-class citizen other system photo
library for everything from something
simple like a custom image picture in
your application
to going a in building a full-featured
custom
application for or browsing the photo
library and editing
and we really believe in this because
we're using
the photos framework in our own photos
and camera applications that are built
in
in IOSA for those have you have worked
with photos in the past
this photos framework is designed to
supersede the a
AL assets library which doesn't provide
which doesn't provide much of the
functionality and features that you get
with the photos framework
so what do you get with the photos from
work
yet access the photo and video assets
albums and moments
something you couldn't get with the
assets library and then
in you can also add/remove
modify assets in albums right in the
system white photo library
you can then also edit photo and video
content
and meta-data that is written directly
into
the system photo library now works at
about a2
its okay on so
we're gonna walk through this API and a
couple steps the first section is going
to focus on the model data
and this is going to walk you through
how to fetch the model object
how to change model data how to handle
external changes
and then we'll turn our attention to
working with the image and video content
%uh there's ass how to retrieve it
efficiently
and tips for working with a different
types of image and video content
and then how to go ahead and make
changes and apply those back to the
photo library
so I can start of looking at
model data so model data in the photos
framework is represented with
what we called model objects and knees I
represent the structure
%uh the photo library these are the
records that represent photo and video
assets
moments albums and folders and
the key concept I want you to take away
from this section
what are the key concept is that model
objects that are presented in the photo
framework
are read-only and that is I
a nice benefit because it means you can
work with those objects
in a thread safe manner you can pass
them between threads without worrying
about their data changing out from
underneath you
there's no worries about locking and I
am
handling I can't rent changes
so I'd like to walkthrough their
different model objects that we provide
with an illustration using the built-in
I S eight
photos application so we'll start with
the assets
these are the photos and videos that you
see here and the Photos app
and then containing assets we have at
the next level up
asset collections what we call asa
collections in the photos framework
and in the case we're looking at a view
that shows I
moments and a moment is comprised of a
collection of assets
at the next level above that we have
what we call
collection lists and these are lists
amass a collections
and in the case you're looking at here
we're seeing the year moment for you
which is comprised of a series of
moments which then in turn
are comprised assets
now let's walk through these model
objects in terms of the API's that are
exposed to you through the photos
framework
the first one look at is the assets
photos and videos
and photos and videos assets are
represented by the pH
asset class and as you look through this
UI
in the phone as application you can see
it's a photo that's the media type
but then at the top of the screen you
can see we're displaying the creation
date:
and the location which are both
properties of the asset
down at the bottom of the screen you can
see an icon representing
a heart that is whether that asset has
been marked as a favorite
and these are all properties available
to you in the model object
pH asset
at the next level up we're talking about
the ass a collection and again we're a
little
illustrating that with the moment an ass
a collection is a general
ordered collection assets so they're
couple different types we've got
moments like you can see here we also
have albums
and Smart Albums
the essay collection unsurprisingly
represented by the pH
as a collection class and it has the
properties of the type
title and start and end date and you can
see these properties reflected in the UI
going one level higher we have the
collection list
and a collection last is an ordered
collection
up collections and the case we're
looking at here we've got a moment year
but you can also have a collection list
that represents a folder
and something that's unique about a
folder verses a
a a moment year typeof collection list
is that a folder
can actually contains subfolders as well
as albums
so that's why we say a and ordered
collection of collections where those
collections might be
and has a collection or a collection
left
the collection list classes the pH
collection last and similar to the essay
collection has a type
title and a start and end date
so when you wanna work with these model
objects you need to get them out in the
photo library
so in ordered I to get these model
objects out of the photo library the key
concept here that I want you do
to focus on in this section for fetching
is that
you use the class methods on the model
object that you want to fetch out
so when you wanna fetch up assets say
you wanted to fetch all the video assets
you look for the class method on the pH
asset class fetch assets
with media type specifying the media
type video
similarly as I said before a moment is a
type of asset collection
so to fetch moments we use a class
method on the ass a collection class
to fetch moments with options now in
both these
examples I'm admitted the options but
they give you an opportunity to do
things like filter or
sort the results that you get back
so the next key concept I wanna I cover
as far as collections
are concerned is that collections in the
photos framework runtime don't actually
cash their contents
excused so what that means is that in
order to find the assets them
live in an album you need to perform a
fetch similar to the ones that we just
saw
for general-purpose fetching so here's
an illustration of that
defects the assets in an asset
collection represented by an album
we're getting back assets 0 is 0 class
method on the pH asset
class and fat assets in the ass a
collection
my album
now the next construct that I want to
cover here is
something we call a transient collection
and this is a really
useful on concert that we've made a lot
of you serve
in the phone is application where we
wanted to represent
a collection that isn't represented in
the actual photo library
an example that is a search result or
user selection as they're picking up
items
in the UI and
by taking that selection I've other
items are our model objects and putting
it into a transient collection
the benefit is the transient collection
is interchangeable
with the regular collections that you
might fetch at the photo library
so you can do things like reuse your
existing view controllers
or fetch the contents of a changing
collection without worrying about
whether it's represented by something
that really exists on
on the fund a library or if it's just
something that you users working within
the runtime
to create a transient collection there's
a class method on the ass a collection
class to create a
transit as a collection you can also
create a transient collection list
but to create a trendy nasa collection
we call transit as a collection
with assets and simply pass n an array
of assets
as well as an optional title
so what are you getting back when you
perform these fetches most the time when
you're writing an application to work
with photos you're going to be
reading those objects looking through
them working with them
so we wanted to make it as simple as
possible to get those objects out and to
work with them directly
so you wanted to get synchronous results
and you want to quickly
but especially when you think about i
cud photo library
the result so that affects a result in
effect could be potentially very large
in the tens of thousands of assets are
even more
so it's really important that you don't
fit all those objects into memory at
once
and you really want to work with them in
batches as your
working with them are displaying them on
screen
but we didn't want to put that
complexity on you so what we did
is we've introduced a class to represent
the objects that you get back from a
fetch
holiday pH fetch result and the peach
FET result takes care
up tracking the full a results at
by keeping track at the lightweight ID
is representing each other contents
that fetch but when you access the
content so that fed result to
to pull one of the objects out will then
you a fully realized object
that you can work with it's got an API
that
familiar and similar to the end of the
race so it should be easy to
to to work with and I'd like to show you
an example of what
I it looks like as your working with a
fete result
so II on the slide here at shown
a federal tax representing say offensive
10,000 assets
and as we're iterating through that
result set pulling out assets
has we access an act a 10 the indexes
will behind the scenes pulling a full
batch to represent that object
as well as many of the others in it as
you iterate through
over that match to the next batch will
pull in the next
Batcave objects but released the
previous ones so you don't wanna
mind a pulling out all that memory
so now that you've got the thanks
now that you've got a model objects that
you're working within your
application your user may will
oftentimes wanna make changes to those
objects so
I wanna take a look at how you can make
model changes
with those model objects to support
things like
the user wanting to favor the photo or
added
our photo to an album because as ice
I said earlier the model objects
themselves a read-only see can't mutate
them directly
so the way we express changes is there a
change request API
thats based on change request classes
that you create in a change request
block
and then hand to the photo library so
that he can
apply those changes a synchronously how
to process
and the reason those changes are applied
out a process and a synchronously
is twofold the first reason is
for some operations it may be very a
expensive or processor intensive or just
take a long time
but even more importantly than that
because you're working with the user's
actual photo library
some others actions may require user
authentication
for example if you wanted to delete 10
photos
the photo library is going to prompt the
user to say is this application
allowed to for a delete these 10 photos
to allow the user to have a chance to
confirm that
so let's take a look at the change
request classes it's actually pretty
simple
for each a model object class there's a
change request class we got the
asset change request ass a collection
change request and
the collection was change request and
each of these changes has classes
provide
model object specific API's to allow you
to perform the types of changes that
they allow
so the example I'm showing here is for
the acid change request where you can
set
the creation date for an asset or two
said it has a favorite
about some other things to to understand
about the change request classes
that they are not subclasses up the
model classes
and there's a good reason for that we
wanted to provide a really clear
separation between
the thread safe immutable model objects
and the objects that express mutations
that's the change request these change
occurs classes are also only valid to
work with
in a change quest block hi so I'd like
to illustrate that
I with an example now
so here's an example I where I've
provided a sample implementation
a method to toggle whether an asset
has been marked as a favorite
so the first thing will do in this
method is
asked the fish a shared photo library to
perform some changes
and will pass n a change request block
here
first step in that block is to create a
change request for the asset that we
were provided in the method
and we're using their pH asset change
request class here you can see
and then the last step is simply to set
on the change request the value our
favorite
to the inverse value up what the asset
currently haz
that's enough 24 the block to get past
to the photo library
and those changes to be performed on
your behalf
after those changes are performed will
call back to completion handler
and let you know if there is I if you
were successful
and performing those changes
so one other aspect working with change
request that you want to work with that
you wanna do
is to create new model object and you
can create new model objects
with the same change across classes but
creating a different kind of change
request
using a creation request so in this case
sectioning example where
you can create a new asset from an image
using the creation request
for asset from image class method
and if all you want to do is create a
new asset from an image
are you're done you just passed you just
make this call within a change request
block
and the low library will take care of
adding the ass
but if you want to work with that asset
within that change request blocked his
do some additional work
say to add it to an album
well remember that the asset won't
actually be created
until the work is performed out a
process so
within the same change request block we
a you can access a placeholder object
from the change request
representing that new unsaved object and
then you can use that place holder
to add a new asset to a collection or
even potentially in new place holder for
a collection
one other thing you can get from a
placeholder object is
you can access the local identify which
is a unique string that you can use
later on your application to fetch that
object back
even on another invocation
so what happens to these changes
well the changes are done when the
completion handler is invoked
but the model object to read only
and they aren't automatically refreshed
or modified out from underneath you
but more important in these two things
when we're talking about changes
as a really important thing to
understand the changes that you
requested me
incur side effects or
I may be influenced by external changes
coming in from elsewhere
in fact there are a lot of sources for
change into the photo library
there's your application there's the
built-in application as I club photo
library
cloud photo sharing and my photostream
and all of these things can have an
impact
on the data that you're working with so
what we recommend
is that instead of trying to take the
result of a change in your completion
handler
you work with the single change
notification system
to handle changes there and reflect them
to user that way
so what happens is anytime there's a
change to the photo library
will publish a pH change to registered
observers
and that changes delivered on a
background cue and it provides details
on
updated and deleted object but where
begins to get really powerful
is when you're working with fat results
where you can provide you details on
what indexes and objects were inserted
updated deleted or moved that apply to
that fetches
I wanna dig a little deeper into the
fetters I'll change details
when you create a federal assault by
performing a fetish for a collection or
any other general-purpose fetch
the factors that will implicitly
register itself with the photo library
for calculating changes and all those
change details
are calculated in the background so they
don't
they don't run while you're users
interacting with your application
if you're providing if you're fetching a
fete resulting you're not interested in
change details
you can opt out the their different
calculation
by one other special options
but if you do want the details if you
want those incremental
differences then it's important that you
get the
updated fetch result for the veterans
out that you started with
from the pH fetch result
change details object and I'm gonna walk
you through an example
to demonstrate why that's so important
when the photo library receives a change
if you've registered yourself
as an observer will call the photo
library did change method
and pass you the pH change instance
in this case in this example which by
the way this example is taken from the
sample code that's provided with the
session
so I'm omitted some other details to
make it will clear on stage
but although this is available in the
sample code that you can download from
the
dub dub DC website
arm any I getting back to the first
thing we're going to want to do in our
change handler here
is to I dispatched to the main cue
in the reason for that is because we're
going to work with our user interface
objects are view controllers
and you know it's only safe to access
those on the main cue
so once we've dispatched to the main cue
will ask the change instance whether any
change details for the fetters alt that
we're working with
in our view controller and in this case
we've got time
represent itself that assets that sir
affect result that we're presenting
in a in a collection view
so if there's a change that affects the
collection view the content
recollections you
we want to know what those details are
so well as the change in stance for
those change details
and if there were any change details
then we know we need to update
are FET result based on what those
changes were
and the way to get those details are to
get that update effect result as I was
saying
is to get it directly from the change
details object
the change details have already done
that work force and that we were sure
that the other details were going to ask
for about inserts updates and deletes
are going to exactly match up to the new
result that we're working with
so on the second slide here I'm gonna
show you how
nicely this works with an object like
the collection view
so now we can tell the collection view
to perform a Batcave updates
and walk through the change details to
see where they're removed indexes
if there were will translate them into
index past that the collections you can
understand
and tell it to delete the items at those
paths
similarly well as the change details
with the inserted indexes in that fit
result
if there were what other collection view
again to insert items at those paths
and same with changed index is dead
affect the fete results
well as the collection view to reload
those items
so now I'd like to take a moment to show
you a demonstration
above the sample code that we've
provided
with the session so the first thing I'm
going to do before actually run
the sample app is sad just give your
view
the photo library that we're working
with here
aunt so I'm running the IOSA built-in
Photos app
and you can see I've gotta series a
smart albums
in this album list here and in
particular
I've got 9 photos in my favorites
library
now I'm going to switch over to the
sample application
and we've got listing here with a
special entry on top
all the photos in the photo library we
can take a quick look you can see
got a pretty good size library here but
we've also got a smart elements
so I'm going to tap on the favorite
album
and you can see it's the same contents
but it's pretty obvious that one up
there photos in this group doesn't
belong
so I'm gonna tap on my moose and
you can see when you look at the sample
code we're gonna use
I'll bring up the menu with this added
button
but when I press on favorite the code is
going to create a change request
to set that asset as not being a
favorite anymore
K when I back out to the favorite Smart
Album
you'll notice the moose is gone nothing
in the code actually asked to remove
that moves from that smart album
this is one other side effects I was
talking about where change that I
requested
has triggered secondary change a that is
reflected in the user interface
now if we switch back to the built in
phone as application
you can see that changes immediately
reflected there as well
the photos been taken out that favored
Smart Album to
now there's one other thing I want to
quickly go through to show you
in a in terms of the sample code and
that is
if I go into the photo list
and I find a photo that I think the user
wants to delete why I as the user want
to delete
I'm gonna go ahead and create a if you
look at the sample code you see I create
a delete change request
but there's no code in the application
to provide this prompt
this is the photo library performing
some work out a process to let the user
know that an application
has requested a change that's
destructive to their library
and asking for confirmation so you can
see allow sample photos up to delete one
photo
and in this case I'm not going to delete
it but you can see
how some the work that per is performed
at a process can have such an impact on
your changes
alright well that covers the the work
with model objects that I wanted
introduce from the photos framework but
there's a lot more that you could see in
the sample application when you look at
all the
images an image data that was presented
so I'd like to invite Carl
up to talk about image and video data
thanks
good morning I my name is Karl school I
also were coming I was for us remarks
so we've just been a little while
talking about how you can discover and
work with the structure
up the users for a library and that's
great but we're missing
a key ingredient cuz it is the user's
photo library
how do we actually get a hold open
display image and video data
before we began it's useful to know
that the user's photo library actually
caches a variety of representations for
each
asset for images we might we might have
representations that vary from
all the way from the full science
original all the way down to small
thumbnails
videos might be cash it in writing a bit
rates and sizes
they might even be streaming K with I
clout photo library
we might not actually help all of those
representations cast on desk summerall a
bomb or in some cases even on a might be
available
that makes a campaign when you want to
display image data
so what we have is we provide you with
the class
the pH Image Manager the pH image
manager's job is to abstract way
the shortest your decision from having
to decide you know do I wanna thumbnail
by one
a medium size large what you want so
basically it's a usage-based
API for images you tell us how big do
you want the image what are you trying
to do with that are you trying to
displayed in a small great on-screen are
you trying to you want the full size you
want something that screen size
and will try to find the right the best
available representation we have for you
similarly videos you tell us what
quality you'd like and what you plan on
doing that that is a just for user
playback are you planning on exporting
it or you can work with that in some
other way
and we'll try to pick the right
representation
one key thing here is that on like the
model E
a fetching API which is largely
synchronous
the image request API's are largely
a synchronous and that's because even if
the data is available locally we may
have to do work
before we can handle the day-to-day pics
after the right of a disk they have to
be decoded
but the most important case is
in the case of something like I called
for a library we may not have the data
locally available at all
we may have to go out to the network get
and and
bring it back to you so let's take a
quick look
and what that looks like this is a very
straightforward such
crossed I'm sorry image request are
in this case we're trying to fill a
reserve a straightforward for across
created
on an iPhone turns out to be about 160
by 160 pixels
so we set the target site we tell it
that
the image should feel that target size
and then we issue the request and when
it comes back
if there's any image data available were
handed to you the info dictionary
is there and we'll tell you a little bit
more about what we handed you back
specifically is it substandard is it
the right size good
so let's take a look at it a little bit
more urban advanced image or crushed
so when you wanna make a more
advanced request you create an image
request option
in this case occur after I create the
option
I I really want this photo thank so I'm
gonna tell the option that gas it
allowed to go out to the network can go
out to the 2i cloud and fetch the data
down
because that might take a little bit I'm
I'd like a progress and worthwhile
you think this is a good idea you can
always show the user that we're in fact
doing work
K and then finally just said it as an
option when you actually make the
request
I want to spend a second and talk about
the call back that actually produces the
data
there's two things to keep in mind again
this block will take will be called back
on the main thread
and the reason is because the feeling is
the general you want to use it for even
a second call back you typically using
for display on the main threat
there's an option a way to make a
synchronous request if you're working in
back route
K the other thing is actually this blog
can be called multiple times for each
request
because it turns out that a really
common you
UI design is the user wants to see the
image data as soon as possible
so we have any image data available will
return that you
right away and then if that is
insufficient to fulfill your request
we go out possibly to to the desk
possibly I clout
will go get the data and when it arrives
then we'll call it a second time
thank you of course if the date is
already available
then you only get the first call
let's take a quick look requesting be oh
so in this case
the user has scroll to somebody on a
they just want playback
so we're requesting a player item for
the video
we get back a player and we can create
an AB player up it looks very much like
the image crossed it's pretty
straightforward
and again if we want a more advanced
request
let's say the user now wants to push
this
in this video up to their own sharing
service a different sharing service
so now we're going to create a video
request option
and of course because we're sharing it
we want to be high quality we
you know we maybe you're on an iPhone
and you want the full 1080 P
K so we wanted to be high quality and if
it's not available
because we were playing a before that
might have been streaming we are
you know we say okay it's all right you
can go out to the network and download
and it's particularly important for
videos of course to have progress
because
videos can be very large and then
finally we set the option
note here that we're actually using a
slightly different APR specifically
requesting X
this were specifically requesting an
export session rather than a playback
so this is good we can fetch individual
images and that works pretty well
by it's really common for
photo app to one ish old lotsa images
the user doesn't want to scroll through
the images one at a time
they wanna see a great images in either
a regular
square grid or a more interesting you
know Thailand brick mortar layout
that poses some performance problems
even if the individual images are
relatively cheap there's a lot of
so what do we do that the general thing
the people want to do is you create a
cash around what the users looking at
figure out which direction they're going
East are cashing ahead of demand you
stop cashing behind
so it's a pain Marie you can have to
track all this data
you have to know to retrieve stuff from
that cash we've already got an API for
doing a lot of this
and that API's the pH cashing Image
Manager
K the caching image manager's job is
exactly what it sounds like it's a job
is to cash
images on your behalf K as you make
requests against the caching Image
Manager
if it's in its cash it will read it will
return that directly if not it will
automatically fall back to the default
image request behavior
at the general suggestion is that you
create a caching Image Manager for each
sort of distinct view controller that
you have up
that's because each view controller
typically has it own display
I love image data I you know
a gridview controllers going to behave
its gonna need different cashing
behaviors then
like upon up you are you're scrolling
through
so let's take a quick look at what I'm
talking about here so we have the user's
phone
looking at some nice pictures and the
scrolling through now this is what the
user sees
but we know that underneath what they
actually have is the sort of
long ScrollView all photos above and
behind
and what they only see is the visible
range
so as the scrolling down we wanna start
cashing ahead of where they are
so that the data is available
immediately when they one
you need to display it to the user and
of course from Emma reasons we wanna
stop cashing behind
just sort of calculate this range
maintain it and as you scroll
just keep update K the API for the image
man
the caching Image Manager is actually
pretty straightforward
you calculate what going to be visible
soon
you tell us to start cashing it and out
stuff is
scrolled of you tell us to stop cashing
the only key thing here is when you
start and stopped cashing
used the same target size content mode
and options
that you will use for the actual request
image
otherwise we don't know how to look it
up now
we know how to get hold image data
weekend and we know how to get
hold it fast we know how to get ahold
video data
but of course just looking at data is
only half the story
users love to touch their photos they
want to adjust them
crop it so much just right apply filter
so their kids look
you know extra-special pretty so
much talk about editing
if the acid is editable the at its are
now in place
okay you no longer need to save your
edits as a new asset
you can at edit any asset edible
the edits are just like in the real
photos up there are non-destructive the
user can always revert
you can also programmatically revert
changes that you make a visible
everywhere the show up in your apt the
shop in the photos up the shop in
male messages other third party apps
an with I club for the library they're
actually visible cross
all your devices as well K
so how does editing work well
at a very simple basic level you ask us
for
input image we handed to you
and you do whatever transformations you
wanna do wanna you can crop it you can
edit it you can
going to you know pixel operations on it
and when you're done you generate a new
image
a new output image and you handed to us
and then we say that on top at the asset
but just take a look at how that works
K first you wanna ask us for the input
image
you ask the asset for its content input
editing input me and what that comes
with his the content editing input
carries a
bunch of information that you'll need in
order to actually
do your work it gives you a URL with
reference to the full site sasser
it gives you some orientation
information so in this case
I'm creating a core image image and I'm
sure I'm going to be using some other
need new filter stuff that we have
available for you now
and I'm gonna do some work so
I don't work uses cropped it maybe is
applied to filter looks great
how do we say that well you create
to da a content editing output you take
your data
the fully output with the fully rendered
output save it as a jeep eg right to the
URL
and then use that the adjustment data
I'll talk about the adjustment in just a
second
and then how do you save it it's the
same a saving any other model change
you create are ass a change request
you set the content editing output on it
but the whole thing and a change block
and that's it
so I was a little bit misleading
actually why I said it was that simple
so there's theirs alone another wrinkle
cheese
what if
someone has already edited that image
well
the key point here is that actually when
you
editing image you actually have the base
image and some adjustment it your output
image the thing that you give us that
the
and is actually the result of applying
this adjustment to the base
image so really what we haven't you
is the base image plus whatever
adjustment data is already on that image
and that way the user can continue
editing as if they were
they had never left their editing
session like you do a crop down
and what we can do is the original plus
the crop
information so that you can show you to
the crop but they can extend the crop in
an out they can remove it entirely they
can change it
and when you're done you hand ass
your your output image ended
the new adjustment date so that cycle
just continues to the next person that
asks
will get back the base image plus the
new adjustment data
so how do you save the adjustment it
well the adjustment data actually can be
use a peach adjustment data object but
really the data can be whatever you want
right for instance it could be the name
and parameters for current filter
it could be anything that you want that
describes your
at its om notice here that actually be
on just that data we also in ask you to
include a for manana fire format version
they basically are a way for you to
identify
what edit it actually is whose who did
this edit what's the format
a bit K and I'll talk a little bit more
about that in a second
so I misled you again
there is one additional case of course
what if
someone else had edit the image
it works this the scenario that I
describe a force great if you were the
one who previously added
but whatevs somebody went to ap a
and they apply to crop and then they go
to ap be
and they want to do more added well
you have to tell us what do you
understand the adjustment it what ask
you will give you the pH adjustment data
you tell us do you understand what this
is so looking at this is actually seems
relatively straightforward
but we're not putting any restrictions
on what the form and identifying format
version can be
several developers from different
companies could for instance get
together and define
a common identifiers version and yet
adjustment data format and that way the
user could move seamlessly between those
those aP's K let's see what happens
depending on what you return when we ask
you this question can you
understand us do you understand it
yes you say yes that's great we're
headed the base
image and the adjustment data and you
can behave as if the user had just
sort of turned around we did a second
come back and started editing again
that sort of the ideal case what if you
tell us
no you don't on this case unfortunately
we don't have any choice we have to hand
you the fully rendered
output from the previous at the user can
continue editing
but the cam back out like in this case
the previous
ap applied in water filter it
effectively blocking my filter we've
thrown away the color information we
don't have it
if the user wants to go back they
basically have to revert back to
original
so let's take a quick demo so here we
are
is what we had before and gonna take a
look
see let's look at our favorites again
and here we go she looks very nice
but I i wanna play with a little bit I
think that this photo could be better
so actually I'm gonna what's trying
assuras
what a you know what I didn't I don't
know
that doesn't require it to me K so at
this point we started with the original
image in there are no adjustments so we
didn't even ask do you understand is it
doesn't matter
we had to do the Basij this time when I
go into edit
what's gonna happen is we're gonna say
do you understand the Edit
and this app have to be the same ap
sources: gas and erstand
so this time I hand the other hand you
the base image
which is effectively original plus the
adjustment that a lot that did the post
rice
which allows us to switch a completely
and now it's in sepia night but it's not
see be applied on top of the post rice
it CPR
applied instead at the pasta rice
actually kinda like this I think I'm
gonna leave it I like that old-time look
and just to prove it look
the Photos app sees it as well all right
so we've talked about doing this in the
context of your own application but of
course
as we showed in the keynote we can do
this from inside
the Photos app as well and to tell you
about how to do that
somebody
morning my name is Simon but they're and
in this last part of the session
let's talk about photo editing
extensions
so what up for anything extensions how
can they be useful to you developers
and what do they bring to our users
through the new feature in I was eights
that allows the users
to accept to access to your image
or video editing tool right from within
the built-in camera or photo
applications
no need for the user to switch between
applications no need for the user
to grant specific access rights to your
application it's a very simple way
for your tour to reach its audience
we think it's a great way to put your
creativity
inside the hands of our users
so this feature has been showing in a
keynote on Monday but let me refresh our
memories with the two sides
so here we are on iphone editing and
image
using the eye with eights built-in
photos application
the user can tap on the top left button
an axis any available editing extension
can pick one and this could be your
editing tool extending the editing
capabilities of the built-in aP's
for now the user can interact with
whatever interface want to provide
and when they use is done the changes
are saved right
in place inside the uses for the library
no need to create the duplicated
assets and if the user has turned on I
cut for the library
those changes will be applied to all
other devices
to the user could go on his iPad and
then draw your beautiful effects
on a larger screen saw what you need to
create your own
for reading photo editing extension
and it turns out it's it's really simple
it's basically three steps
the first one is to create not extension
targets
the second one is to provide view
controller which will manage to you I of
your extension
and then these you control a needs to
adopt a specific protocol
which is a set of methods that photos
will call
in order to communicate with your
extension
the good news is the first two steps are
really easy thanks to the new Xcode
basically all what you need to do is
from your applications Xcode project
add a new target and select the photo
editing extension templates
exclude we create whatever is necessary
for you to get started
and have something working it we create
a view controller
which you can start using or which you
can replace with your own
if you happen to have you are existing
tool or you can try that you want to
reuse
note about the user interface
you've seen for extensions are shown
full stream
now the top bar with the council and
unbuttons as well as
the title of your application is shown
automatically for you by the Photos app
so you see you liked to design your
extension not to have its own navigation
bar
now onto with the protocol at options
for the protocol which is specific to
for two extensions
and this protocol is the finding the
footage you a framework
and is the pH content editing controller
it consists of four method
and the first one quite obviously is
called
when the user celexa extension and this
is where you get
the input data before you extension is
presented on screen
a simple implementation could look like
this
and the first thing you might notice is
that the input object which is given to
you
the kids content editing input is
exactly the same object
as the one car described as a few
minutes ago
so basically we have the exact same
class is the exact same concepts
as when editing a photo using the photos
from work
just here rap slightly differently for
the specific needs of an extension
so you would typically read out
the input image in this particular case
we're going to work with a Display Size
representation
we don't need the full-size image right
away here then we need to decode any
input adjustment data
or fall back to some default settings
does non
then you set up your yours interface to
want the way you need its
and you to be find it useful to hold on
to the input object
that was given to you now the user will
interact with your extension
and when the user is done the second
method will be called
and this is when your extension we need
to provide the final
outputs data and headed back
7 implementation can look like this
for images issued raids a pic
representation on the full-size image
with your effects a fight with used to
create this adjustment stayed objects
which describe what ever you
applied to the input image and then you
create an output object that wraps
all this information and when you're
done you call the completion handler
you notice in this example that the flow
is synchronous
but it doesn't have to be a if you
prefer to have any sickness work fo
it's totally fine this have to call the
completion handler
when you're output is ready
now you remember this story about
resuming editing
so imagine that the user six-year
extension
using an image or video that already has
been edited
that has some adjustments data you
remember the first question
that we ask you is do you understand the
given the existing adjustment data or
not
and that way we can provide you with the
appropriate inputs
and this is when this method can handle
adjustments data is going to get called
on your extension
and a typically implementation could be
a simple as
sticking with their you support the
format identify your and version of the
such as India
and finally the last method previously
is when the user cancels your extension
one thing to note is which is not just
is that this method can be called at any
time
so for example if your extension require
some time to produce the output
for example you're editing a video the
user could use
could decide to interrupt you and cancer
right away at any time
so just keep that in mind
and this is basically all what you need
them
to create your own photo editing
extension so we're really excited to see
a
all the tools that you going to create
and all the great ideas that you went to
provide to our users
using this API and let me conclude
with a short demo of that in action
so let's switch to our demo device
and I'm going to go to the full
implications
and here is the image the that has been
just applied
just has been edited by call with the
city of inter
now it turns out that the simple at is
actually vending a photo editing
extension
so what I can do is right from within
the Photos app
top it it's select the top left
extension button
and here you see our sample extension so
let me select its
and what I can do is not only a plier
outfielders but i can assume
resume what was previously did so for
example I could decide here to bring
back the covers
and even and hands them something to
replace the seeker figure that was
previously applied
and I'm going to choose a chrome feature
and that's it
you see how easy it is for the user in
just a few taps
to use Europe photo editing extension
so our time to wrap up this session what
have we learned
we've introduced the new photos from
work which allows you to access
the whole photos the users for delivery
in
and which allows you application to
gain all the features like the one that
has which we provide with the photos
application
so you app can be a first-class citizen
of the I was photos
eco-system and then we've seen how easy
it is for you
to provide you editing 20 using the
photos editing extensions
if you want more information you can
contact our eventually something for
you can read out the condition and if
you want to ask questions of an answer
as you can
on check out our developer forums
we have a couple related sessions some
of them have really taken place to check
out the videos
like the one about what expenses you can
create on I worse and worse than
or how we can capture contents from the
camera
using even more control Nile on I was
eights
and we have two sessions taking place
this afternoon
if you're interested in knowing more
about how to edit images
and apply your custom filters using Core
Image
and with that I thank you very much for
your attention
and so there is official