however when I'm temperature
good morning thanks for coming
so I'm going to talk to you about
web inspector and modern JavaScript but
first
amid just talk about modern JavaScript
so
what exactly is modern JavaScript well
let's go through some other history have
JavaScript which
is also known as ECMAScript as something
you may know
but it had a long history it's been
around
since the 90's and it had a lawyer a
momentum
back in the 90's when it was first part
in the browser wars
but it kinda ive sputtered and stalled
but Javascript is alive and well
nowadays
everyone's using it for webapps to
server applications
and some other standards bodies have
been
battling over some what should be
included in the next version of Java
Script
and I'm happy to say that
they finally started coming together
and started releasing what is known as
ECMAScript 6 and this
sixth addition brings a lot of cool
things
an it's really just JavaScript and
that's how I'm gonna refer to it
in in this modern JavaScript world
there's a lot of great things in this is
a summer them
there's some tea structuring maps
promises
and let's go over some of these new
features that are also
now available and I was a an OS 10 use a
MIDI
so
when they're available I mean you can
use them in Safari
a war your I with applications are Mac
applications
and not just in web views but also
JavaScript or contact
so let's talk over somebody's
let's first talk about some math
additions
JavaScript has had a mass objects
pretty much since day one but
JavaScript nowadays is super fast with
the modern lol VM jet that we have
and I would say an OS 10 you seventy you
need these super fast math functions to
do complex things like
web GL or complex scientific
calculations
and mostly you will recognize a lot of
things
in in this list that you used in the
past for
your your own applications and they're
now available
in modern JavaScript so that's the map
additions
now let's talk about maps and sets
so what do I mean by maps and sets
well in JavaScript you might think
this as a map this is something that you
create as a generic object and it's
really just a property bag you can throw
whatever you want on the subject
you can set simple strings and
any object can be the value and you can
remove things from that map
well these maps have some limitations
their string coercion
when you're when it comes to the key
everything
that is the key needs to be coerced into
a string so it's not going to give you
exactly what you want if you want to use
it for
a property back that's tracking some
node
it won't work well
in modern JavaScript there's now a map
object
and it does pretty much the same thing
that you would do
with an object has a little bit
different syntax an API
but it's pretty much all the same the
most powerful thing you can do
with the map object is you can use any
value
as the key and a lot of people will use
this
to track DOM nodes that they have in the
page
adding some additional data on the side
instead have tacking it onto the DOM
node itself
so it really allows you to convict
compartmentalize data that you're
tracking on the page
but there's some issues with that if you
add it to the map
that map is gonna hold a hard reference
to it and that's why modern JavaScript
has a week
map and that means whenever the
the the key disappears or gets garbage
collected
it's also removed from the map so in
this case
I have a node in my week map and win
that node is removed by doing every move
collar or
remove child in that page
it will no longer be on the map in the
data that's associated with it will also
get garbage collected
so that's maps and sets and there's also
a set object
that I didn't cover but it's pretty
straightforward it only allows
the key to be added to them the set
so now let's talk about the structuring
if you got excited about some other new
features in swift
this'll be right up your alley as far as
jobs here goes it allows you to return
like multiple objects
in an array in this case I have an array
of 20 two numbers here
and traditionally I would have to
collect that in a result object
and I would have to break each piece of
from
from not afraid to use it in a separate
variable that made more sense
in the scope I was using it
but with the structuring weaken
break that down to one line now my
function that's returning to
to results that maybe didn't make sense
is there a but it was what I could use
to return
multiple things at once I can now
save those into the alpha and beta
variables
rate there and one line in
this might look like in Arabi when it's
on
when it's on the the left side we're
dealing with
the destruction syntax
and it's not just for a race you can the
structure objects
and this is when it becomes more of a
pad pattern matching
so he in my example here say I have a
point object
and normally I would have to save it off
into a result
and break each piece out if I wanted to
use some more concise intact
for those those variables
but now I have object is structuring in
this case
in if I'd why a different variable name
then the property
I can separate them by Colin so X is the
value that's coming out of the object
pattern matching and at my axe
is the variable name in the local scope
in this case
but if I want to use the same name I can
omit the second piece
and just use why and why is now a local
variable
in the scope
and you can do some really fancy things
that I don't have examples for but you
can
deeply nest these pattern matches and
objects with the raisin vice versa
so you can really break apart your
object if that if that's what works for
your application
so that's the structuring
now let's talk about what we call the
spread operator
and this is something that is barred
from many languages
but it comes in I'll very
very handy and I love using it and its
it really is takes away some other
common idioms that you would do
before if you're building up arguments
that you want to call on a function
as an array before you would have to
resort to
dot collar don't apply and
pass in those arguments but now with the
spread operator
which is represented by three dots
prefixing
an object and in this case it's have
it's an array
but secretly the spread operator works
on anything
it even works on maps in a burqa and key
value
sequences so
anything that's has support for
iteration which I'll talk about a bit
can be spread and this will spread it
out and call my function
to with the three arguments that are in
the array
one thing that you could never do in
javascript and you can
only do now with the spread operator is
called the constructor
with an array and put or a a map input
you can now take your part amid a
and spread them across the day
constructor instead of having to
manually do
is zero wind too and break it out like
that
the spread operator is also useful in
construction I love
array literals say you have something
that's pretty repetitious
you wanna have a separate form and a
combined form
normally you'd have to either repeat the
data or push and pop
and an ad at everything concatenate
everything together
but with the spread operator you can
just spread those other races
right out into the new array that you're
constructing so this is a handy way to
do
pretty complex concatenation and you can
understand what it's doing
without having to parse different calls
to different
array functions
so that's the spread operator now let's
talk about something new a new
for loop that's available in javascript
JavaScript has
traditional loops which you can iterate
over an array
by doing and an index in a length
and you still might need to use this if
you care about the index for the length
and you're doing some complex operation
based on those
some people have avoided the syntax
because
its it's ugly and they you something for
called for each on an array that let you
integrate
over individual items in you hand the
lead
get the item right there that you can
work with
but this creates a closure it does a lot
of complex things that
you did might not want to deal with
overhead wise
well with the the new for Lopez in
modern JavaScript
this is all you have to write to iterate
over an array
in this will iterate over every item in
the array
if you break early it'll stop but it
starts at the the first item
but it's not just for a raise say you
have a set you can head to rate over
that set
and if you have a map you can iterate
over the key in value
very similar to what you can do in swift
so now you have the key in value right
there
to process both at the same time instead
of doing
actual lines of code using the four and
loop
which is available jobs good now you can
do it right here with four of
and forearm is the only way to iterate
over the keys and values
in maps for and will not do what you
expect
and for reasons I'm not going to go into
but maybe you want to iterate over we
clap
that's not supported for
reasons that involve the garbage
collection
you cannot iterate over the keys and
values over we clap
in this is part in the spec
so that's four of loops
now one other new things and modern
JavaScript that I'm really excited about
its promises it solves a long-standing
problem
love JavaScript now the job description
moving more and more
a synchronous everything's a synchronous
you you don't wanna be blocking your
application
and say you have a function that you've
written
that load the URL maybe a dozen XHR
behind the scenes for you
to wrap up all the different browser
incompatibilities they're out there
so this will load URL
and that's a little do you can't get the
data
to get the data you might be inclined to
do return result
that gives you the data that that was
loaded but this
this is synchronous you can get away
with this in a
in a shipping product without blocking
your user interface
so you have to resort to a call back
function
and JavaScript make this real easy I do
this every day
when JavaScript pass in a call back
function
and it worked and it's very usable and
it's very handy
but when it gets deeply nested and
you're passing in multiple information
in
it just gets confusing and hard to
follow you have all these load calls in
this case
were which one is handling which
information
well this is what promises of with
promises
you can write something like this where
the first load returns a promise
and immediately on returning I promise I
can call the then function
and that's pretty much the only API you
need to be concerned about with promises
and you can pass a call back to that
then function
which will get called win that promise
is for filled
and that call back
can return another promise and this is
where its magical
you can chain keep chaining all on that
soon these call backs are in line here
just for clarity for you
but they might be they might be named
functions that you have somewhere else
and it makes it very clear that this is
the order operations
so that's promises and taking it to the
next level
you can then use and another API a
global API
promised at all and what this does is
you can pass in an array
above promises and it will return a new
promise
in that new promise that it returns
is dependent on all those promises
finishing
if any of them a row your then object
can get past the call back that gets
called for errors
but in this case done will get called
when only all those promises succeed
or or for filled
but maybe you only care about the first
one your loading Ubuntu images and once
you got one image you ready to go
that's where promised that race comes in
it will call
your call back win the first one of
those promises fulfilled
so that's a quick glance the promises
that pretty much wraps it up with modern
JavaScript at least the parts that we've
already implemented and decided we're
ready for consumption
there's a lot that's being done in
ECMAScript 6
that is not ready and it's going to be
coming down the pipeline
but these pieces we feel you're ready to
use in your application
in browsers that support them
so now let's talk about the web
inspector
so if you're not familiar with the web
this is what it looks like and we've had
this year I for a while
but we've done a lot we've fixed a lot
of bugs with
added a lot of features but the main
thing we've done this year
is made the web inspector available in
more places
we've listened to your feedback n you
want to be able to inspect your map
Mac application you want to be able to
inspect your javascript or context
and that's exactly what you can do with
IOSA
and I was ten years seventy
so with Safari you've been able to
inspect
your I O S aP's and Iowa Safari by
tethering up to
your computer but now
you can inspect your Mac application
and right there
from Safari see a list if your Mac
applications
so what's that look like but first
like I said you want to inspect your
javascript for contacts
but web inspectors all about the web
and it's only been able to work with
WebKit up until this point
but now web inspector can connect to
your job corps based applications
so even if you're not using a WebView
but you're using javascript core for
some logic in your game
you can now add about that JavaScript
right now weapons factor
and it's really great so let's let's
show you what it looks like
so Mac app app at inspection
like I said we'll show up right next
year i OS devices in the development you
in this case I have to Mac App and
the second one here JS pawn is a
javascript crap
the first one is a WebView but the right
there side by side
the first class citizens
and like I said you can also stock a
next year i OS applications
in Iowa Safari from the same development
you
but for Mac App inspection we require
you to add an entitlement
to your apt we you don't want anyone
else
debugging your job your contacts or
stealing your JavaScript code from your
Mac application that you've worked so
hard on
so we require you to have this
entitlement on your applications that
your
developing locally and it's very simple
to do
and I'll give you a demo love it here in
a little bit
bill what about jobs get core inspection
what's that look like well it looks just
like the web inspector
this is the same web inspector that he
saw a little bit ago
the other one was for the webview this
one's for JavaScript
or contact there's a couple buttons that
are missing
that don't applied to jobs Cooper
context like styles
in the DOM and things like that but for
the most part
its everything you need to debug your
job corps application
and you have the full council you can do
a rebel
evaluate JavaScript or see consul
dialogues consul dialogue is now
available
in your javascript per application so if
you have your own log function you can
now a bandana and start using confidante
log
in get all the great benefits the weapon
sectors log functions
but if you don't do anything the consuls
pretty much all you have available
and I'll tell you why we don't know what
youre valuating in your javascript for
contact
if you're evaluating large scripts those
are something you probably wanted about
but you could be evaluating something
every 200 milliseconds
and that would quickly pollute the
sidebar here see you
any script that you want to debug in the
weapon sector
will we will lead you to Supplier a URL
or just a plain name for that script
and we've given you a couple new API's
for this
there's always been the evaluate script
functions
we now have a new Objective C one that
takes a source URL
in this URL can be a file URL it can be
any URL the
the weather sector really doesn't take
it
take it other than to get the name at
this point
but if it's a far you're a little have a
little bit extra benefits and I'll talk
to you about that a little bit
but JS a value it's kept has always
supported the source URL
but a lot of people just passing all to
it so if you're using the old capi
make sure to start passing a source URL
for things that you want to bug
that way they will show up in the web
inspector
and that's for scripts but what about
your contacts identifying a Contax is
pretty difficult with does give we don't
know what it is
the by default it'll just say JS context
in the development you
but if you have multiple contacts you
don't wanna see a list that says Jess
contact as context as context
you want 10 identify those and
as the developer you should know what
you're using that context or and we
pride
these new API's that lie you to name
your contacts
in the name is only use for debugging
it'll on the show up in surprise
development you
so let's just give a demo this so I have
a
I'd at a sample application that we
released a while ago
a at at a previous WBC jet spong
and it's a simple pong game but I I have
some things I need to do to it to make
it work with Jess contacts in Section
the first thing I need to do is make
sure the entitlement as their
in if you're in the App Store you
probably already have an entitlements
file
in this case already have an app sandbox
and that will give me an entitlement
and I have it right here in the sidebar
JS on entitlements
so let's go in and at the entitlement
that we need
and I said it was calm diet
Apple security
get task I'll and it's a boolean
and we'll go ahead see yes
so that's all I need to do to allow JS
contacts inspection in my application
and I'll go ahead and say that and I'll
go ahead and build and run it
and it's a very simple pong game the AIA
is controlled by
JavaScript that you can modify here in
the amp I'm not gonna talk about that
but now I can go to Safari and in the
development you
I will see Mac Pro and I will see
JS pong and my JS contact and I didn't
name the context yet so it's
getting the default name and I'll go
ahead and inspect that
and you'll see the resources are empty
I'm not seeing that
are that AI script that I've loaded but
I'm
if I wanted to bug that on need to give
that a name
but at this point I have access to the
Consul if you don't do anything
you can do evaluations here in the
console
you King get access to any Global's that
you might have available in your
contacts
and you will see exceptions and logs in
errors
and in this case we have an example
exception
in this will give you a Bactrian not
just your javascript
but have your native code so you can see
exactly where
that function or script was evaluated
all the way to your native codes you can
trace it back to the exist the origin
so let's go back into Xcode and
name some of these so it's pretty simple
others comment this out
this is this on a my contacts Hong Kong
tax I only have one context but if I had
multiple ones that would be
imperative for me to name them
and when ima valuating the AI scripts
all I have to do
is constructor URL in this case I'm just
making a URL with the string
and it really doesn't have a fun and
location
and I'll just use the new with source
URL
method and
pass in that URL now let's build in Iran
and see what happens in the weapon
sector
will go ahead and reconnect to the pawn
game in
in the resource sidebar we now have that
AI scripts and in the in the app
we didn't syntax highlight it but the
web inspector knows exactly how the
syntax highlight JavaScript
so we can set breakpoints right here
and since the script is called every
iteration
the movement it should break right away
and now I'm in the debugger I have
access to the call stack there's nothing
other than this
function being called but if there is a
deeply nested cost like you would see it
right there in the sidebar
and I can also im bring open the scope
chain
in weekend just like you would any
JavaScript context
you can now inspect the objects that
you're getting passed around
or your global scope in this case
and we can do with any degree does and
step through
and do anything you would do in a normal
the biker
in addition to hovering over variables
to see the current value
or evaluate things in this current scope
in the council so in this case
let's try modifying the ball here
maybe we wanna to modify the rules upon
here
and make something really easy to hit so
I've gone ahead and modified that and I
have
a update function here
that will redraw my my scene and you can
see the ball
increased in size as I met after I made
that change
in this is working with I objective-c
bridge subjects the ball object here
is a bridge objective-c object that you
can use as you would a normal JavaScript
object
so that's JS context inspection and
we'll go ahead and plan
love all stays the same size and keeps
on going
so again anywhere view any JavaScript
context that you have in your
application
can be the bag now as long as you have
the right to limit
in this also applies for I O S so only
builds that you build and run
onto your device or into the Iowa
simulator
will be inspected bull any app from the
App Store will not be allowed to be
inspected by anyone else
so that's all you need and again
name your contacts and name your scripts
so you can easily identify them we heard
about it
so now let's talk about something that
we've had the weather sector for wild
the time line and something new this
year is the source code time
so what do I mean by that what sorts of
problems does it solve
so source code timelines
help you answer this question what
happened when
I clicked on something on the page
maybe it's a new project that you're
working on maybe it's something you
wrote years ago and you don't remember
how it works
and you wanna find that line the code
that handles this click so you can fix a
bug
or so you can just modify it
first a new behavior that your your
client is asking you to add
so when this quick happens there's a lot
of stuff that's probably going on
but you really only care about code that
you wrote maybe you have some analysts
code
or a lot of other code that it might be
hard to decipher
or see the airline inner interleaved
functions in a vet calls and all these
things that happen in a
big modern web application
so when I click on that
you start wondering were okay what
script is handling this
this button and it turns out it's this
one
but with the new web inspector we can
dig deeper
in this script I can now see a time line
representation
what the Scriptures doing
so I can see over time where the mouse
events are coming in
where the clicks events where the timer
was added where the timers are firing
where I might be doing forced layout
which is
a pretty evil thing to do in a modern
weapon web app
so what's it look like in the web
inspector
well here's the new web inspector time
line
and you can see in the sidebar here
we have all OVR scripts and resources
from the page birkenau in their
hierarchy of how they're included
by you the developer in the page
and you can expand each script to see
what that script is doing
and where the line of code was and in
this case
you'll see a whole time line where
things are happening repeatedly you'll
start seeing patterns
and allow you to identify problem areas
if something's firing too much
too little not at all if you don't see
it in the list
and if you want to dig deeper into the
code all you have to do is click right
there in the sidebar
in it'll take you right to that location
you can mouse up and down through the
sidebar
and have your code on one side in your
time line data in the sidebar
see you can gathered good overview of
what the script is doing
really quick
so that source code timelines and I'll
give you a demo here in a little minute
so something else that's new in the
weather sector is a breakpoint probes
so you might have some information that
you want to know
win you when that mouse is clicked or
what when your mouse is moving
and those things are kinda hard to debug
in the debugger you often have to resort
to print after bagging
because you don't want to constantly be
switching contacts between your app
in the page and the web inspector
so you often resort to print after
bagging
in your clutter go after consul with
thousands of lines
in its hard to decipher specially if
you're debugging multiple areas
better not related and you don't care if
their inner
the about the interleaved data so that's
this is where break point probe covers
it and let you see these properties
that you might care about without having
to break out to the web sector
so let's just go ahead and give a demo
this
so let's go to Safari here and I have a
simple
stacked the block game
that I want to to it's been a while
since this was written so I wanna see
what's going on
let's let's go ahead and use the time
line panel for this
I'll go ahead and bring up the web
inspector in the developing you
show web inspector and we'll go to the
Timeline panel
by default the timelines empty it it's
not recording all the time
and it only automatically records when
you reload the page
or when you press the record button
appear in the quarter
and this can record any length of time
that you would like to
to record but when you when I reload the
page
it'll only record a little bit so I'm
just gonna go ahead and start recording
here
and see what this page is doing as I
interact with this game
and you'll see the events and although
the work that the engine is doing
in response these events start filling
up on the time line
and I'll go ahead and stop this
in my application has three scripts but
the logic is all unblock such as: all
the other stuff
stuff I didn't even write I don't even
know what's going on there
so I can ignore those but they're doing
some work in normally that would
that would clutter up my UI but their
collapse here so they're not taking up
in space
I'll go ahead and expand the script that
I care about here
and I can see that timers are firing
pretty pretty at a pretty good clip
as I'm interacting with the page and
there's he key events that are firing
everytime i press a key
summer the other feet new features have
the time line here we can now zoom in
scale the
the overview panel so if you wanna dig
in to see
where things are happening across
domains
in this case we have three timelines the
network requests
layout rendering and JavaScript and all
3 play a key role
in the performance of your page so if
you see anything
interesting happening in a specific time
range you can zoom in on it
make its make a selection and that
informational show up below
in the time line
and you can also drag the surrounds the
scroll and scrub through your time
as things are happening on the on the
page
so in this case let me reword and I'll
I'll show you the networks
and in this case it's a local file but
we now have
network load information and you see
those on the network time line
and you'll notice that the time line
just automatically stopped recording
their
it records up to a certain amount of
time unless you manually hit the record
button again
to to record more information so let's
look into the network time line here
and we can see although the network
details that you might be familiar with
in the previous never time-line they're
all there
and you can sort for these columns by
whatever information you
find most interesting if you're looking
for a large script
you can sort by transfer size and see
the biggest script
show up right there was corrected
start time you can also do
click on the other time lines and get
detailed tablet
linear data love what was happening in
that time range
and again this is all time in space so
you can see as
these they are rendering events filter
out they
they disappear from the this play below
JavaScript and events is a special view
and if you're looking for the old
profile data
this is where its move to so as a
recording time line
we will now capture profiles all those
entry point since your javascript
so whenever script is evaluated you can
expand the
see all of the functions that were
called
in your script and how much time each
individual functions took
to make up that piece that entry point
so that's a brief glance at the time
line but there is one cool thing that
people always forget about
when they're talking about the time line
and that's the filter
the filter bars vastly under-appreciated
in the weather sector and even Xcode
where it comes from where you can filter
down this list
to find what exactly you want
so in this case I look I did a filter
for event
and it found at event listener right
there and then brought it to the front
expanded those profiles and showed me
that exact function I was looking for
so that's the filter bar and I encourage
you to start using filtering more often
in the weapon sector and even Xcode
will go back to my block application and
bring up the weapon sector
and let's go ahead and
go to the resource sidebar here and
I really want it improve this key
function listener
this keel cue the slur its use in key
code which is pretty
arcane and there's some new API key
identifiers that's been out for
for years that I could use that would
give string representations
at these for my cases instead of the
numbers
so what all do like I said that when a
when we set a breakpoint anytime that
key is pressed its gonna interrupt
my process so now to do another key I
have to hit continue
and log what I wanted and press another
key figure out what I'm doing here
but with this breakpoint we can add
a break point action
and I'll go ahead edit this break point
which will bring up the breakpoint
action pop over
and let's go ahead and add a probe
so we have a few actions available I'm
not going to cover the them
but they're pretty self-explanatory
probe expression in this case is
is brand new and we'll go ahead and
evaluate an expression that were
interested in
and we have an event object here and
I want to know what that key identifiers
and that's all I need to type and I want
to automatically continue after
evaluating so it doesn't pause in the
divider
so we'll go ahead and break out here and
when I added that probe
it added a new sidebar Adam called
probes and this is where that day they
will show up
in a table so I'm gonna go back
to my game interact with it and now it's
logging that key identifiers everytime i
press the key
and showing me the values that I can now
take in input into my code
improve my code and I didn't this would
have been a
a back-and-forth process or a lot of
assumption of what these identifiers
were
now I can see the mall in a table and go
back to my case
and modify them
so that's probes
so that's a little bit about Brad Pitt
pros answers good time lines
and I encourage you to play around them
and see how they can fit into your
debugging workflow
so now let's talk about accessibility
new in there
women sector we have and accessibility
details for you
and this is pretty
pretty important if you're working on a
major website
you want to be accessible to everyone
Apple cares a lot about accessibility
and we do a lot of work to make
accessibility matter
but it only goes so far as to how much
you put into it
when you're developing your own
applications and that goes for IRS
applications and web applications
and on the web we have something called
Aria
and its recently hit a milestone in our
area one
or is about to and
that allows you to a fine for a DOM node
what that download does as a role
in those roles are translated into
things that the per
that the person using the computer with
voice-over
can hear or see
with with your with your web application
and in this case i have a web page
there has an alert in a similar alert
and those are notoriously hard to debug
or hard for cited a non side the person
to see
when they pop up in a web page because
they're not gonna be able to see that
contents
unless you annotated with re-air roles
in in this case the the voiceover
machinery
and accessibility machinery in webview
exposes a lot of details like child
relationships
and these relationships are not
necessarily the same
as a normal DOM node relationship where
where your parent could be someone
that's deeply
I'd a deep ancestor view
and we show those in the sidebar here
as a parent-child relationship and
they're all linkable so I can click on
them
and go directly to these other child
nodes that are part of my alert and see
that this button has the right role for
a button
and it will allow people it won't allow
people to focus that by the last people
to click it
and that's a brief summary have what you
can do with the weather sector
and accessibility there's a session
tomorrow morning
that covers accessibility and the web
and I encourage you to go check it out
if you add if you have a website
or whether you in your IRS or Mac
application please do make it accessible
so that's accessibility details now
let's talk about something that's
that's really fun which is color
colors one of those things we as people
can understand numbers but colors
there's millions of them and its very
visual
in a very personal process picking the
right color
and if you're like me in the
you're working on a web page you might
have a client come in and say
I want discover salmon or
this color toe it it's hard to
for them to take those words and you can
translate that into the right color
wouldn't it be great if you could just
bring up color picker right there in the
web page
and modify right there in front of them
so that's what we've added in the web
inspector and I'll give you a demo
so I haven't icon that I've been mocking
up and often
I do these things in the web as that's
something I understand I can
I can play around with it a lot easier
than maybe I could do in Photoshop
and this icon's little small so I'll
just go ahead and bring up the web
inspector here
and I have a
class that I can I had to make a little
bigger for you
so now I have my icon has a couple
colors it's got this color for the cliff
in its got a gradient in the background
I can bring up the style sidebar
and see those colors and
in this case I'm using some named color
CSS has hundreds have named colors
but maybe it's not the right to: that's
a little bit more green than I expected
or the light blue is is
not enough see farmer whatever your
clients telling you to
to make this color so I can
click on these color swatches and get
a color editor or
I can switch over to the CSS resource
and get the exact same experience but in
this case
we want your source code to be front
center so we don't even add those color
swatches
but we have a new feature that lets you
get a data detector like experience
when we detected that the color we will
show
a color we'll next to as you have for it
and when you click on that we'll we
bring up the color pop over
in in this case we can just click around
you can see the color updating live
right there on the web page
and I can find the right color that i'm
looking for. for the school
and if it's a name color it will default
back to the name color syntax
but if it's not something that's named
it will just give you the
RGB syntax or RGBA if you picked it now
for
but we didn't stop there we now let you
do
gradients ingredients are even more hard
to visualize thing color
because you have that interplay the
colors transitioning from one to another
and it's hard to see those in your mind
but we can go ahead and edit this
gradient
and it gives you a simple slider they
might be familiar with
in from other you eyes and I can drag
these around
and you'll see it's updating the source
code as a drag this the percentage is
changing
and when I let go it updates the page
live so I can see exactly
what is applying to this page
but you can't just edit the color stops
you can edit the type a gradient
or you can pic let me radio so it's
coming out from the center
and I can click on these colors and get
the color wheel
and start editing each of these color
sups directly
so I can find the the exact look i'm
looking for
drag the surrounds
maybe we want it to be more starburst
look
little bit more yellow
or the client might say oh I i won a
linear gradient in this case
so let's go back to that traditional I O
S look
for for gradients as start picking some
pretty wild colors here so that's
the gradient editor in the at the new
web inspector
and what I didn't show you here
let's go back in reload here
if I make any of these changes say I
want to go back and save it
let's make this a red and that works
that looks like a sunset in the weapon
sector
I can just go ahead and hit command s
that will bring up the traditional save
dialog
go ahead and replace it and now if I
close the weapon sector reload the page
I have that grading color right there
the icon the different size because I
was modifying the DOM and
that doesn't save but if you're editing
a CSS resource
or any other local file resource you can
save those right back to desk
from the web inspector so that's color
and great in editing
and I hope you play around with it and
try it out it it's really fun
to just get down and dirty with those
those colors
and the gradient syntax is something
that
I still have trouble remembering but the
weather sector will just help you right
there
get the right syntax and and let you go
on to do more important things in your
code
so that's a summary of all the new
features and just the
a brief introduction have all the new
features in the weather sector
so I encourage you to take advantage of
the new jobs for playing which features
as you're able to you release and use
the new Braun and browsers
or use I was a exclusively or Mac OS
you seventy exclusively you can start
using some of these new language in
syntax users
the weapon sector is now available again
for
your Mac applications if you have a
WebView that you've always wanted to see
what it's doing in your application
there's been a few ways to do it but you
can now officially use the weapons
factor in your Mac application
and I want you to enjoy debugging your
javascript contacts this is something
that
may seem simple oh yeah there's now a
debugger
but yeah and now there's a dub auger
you can now do about this javascript
that's been plaguing you
or giving you these weird errors or its
always been hard to debug these contacts
because
there's been no departure that's been
able to give you that information
and again it's really important to make
your web applications accessible
and here I was applications accessible
and be a colorful person enjoy color
editing and the weapon sector and great
in editing
and again for more information you can
contact evangelism at this e-mail
address
or the developer technical support and
even Apple forms
I'm on the Apple forms if you have a
question about the weather specter
or anything web related or one of our
team will be able to answer it or I
would
there again there's a couple more
sessions that my interest you as web
developers or IRS
developers that have web or JavaScript
contact
you can go to the session tomorrow
morning and learn all you need to know
about accessibility in your web
application
in then stay in that same room and learn
about responsible have designed for you
making your web
aP's scale from desktop size I
iPhones and that's it thanks a lot