everyone thanks for coming today my name
is David altered the secession 513
we're going to talk about video encoders
and decoders today RA
we want to make sure that no matter what
you're doing video on your application
you have access to to hardware encoders
and decoders
this this will help users this work
improve user experience in a number of
ways obviously they'll get better
performance and they'll
in OP will be far more efficient but
most importantly
this will extend battery life users will
really appreciate it if they're
if they released him their portables as
well as their I OS devices have improved
battery life
and as an added bonus people with
portables will love it if their fans
don't
don't kick in every time they doing
video processing self today we're gonna
break the for stricken break this down
to a few case studies
we're gonna look at some common user
scenarios the first scenario we're going
to talk about
is the case where you have a stream of
h264 data coming in over the network
and you want to display that inflatable
air in your application
the next one word in top that is the
case where you have a stream
h264 data coming in over the network you
don't just want to display that your
application but you wanna
actually get access to those decoded CB
pixel buffers
next we'll be talking about
when the case where you have the
sequence of images coming in from the
camera or someplace else
and you'd like to compress those
directly into a movie file and
accompanying that there's the case where
you have a stream
images coming in from the camera or
someplace else and you'd like to
compress those but get direct access to
those compressed sample buffers
so that you can send them out of the
network or do whatever you like with
them
and then finally we're gonna give you an
intro to
our new multipass AP I thought we're
introducing in Iowa State and
and yosemite RA
let's do a quick overview of our media
interface stack
you've seen stuff like this earlier this
week that will do will do it once more
and there's a little focus on video on
my in my
view of this as we're talking a video so
at the top we have eighty kit
AV kit provides very easy to use high
level in
view level interfaces for dealing with
media below that we have eighty
foundation
AB Foundation provides an easy to use
objective-c interface for
a wide range of media tasks below that
we have video toolbox
video toolbox has been there on I was 10
for a while but now it's
family populated with headers on I A
West this provides direct access to
encoders and decoders and
below that we have corn medium for video
these frameworks provide many have the
necessary types that you'll see
throughout the
in a interfaces in the rest the stack so
today we're going to focus on AB
Foundation and the video toolbox
need the foundation will be looking at
some interfaces that allow you to decode
video directly into a
into a layering application or compress
compressed
frames directly into a file and the
video toolbox will be looking at these
interfaces to
give you more direct access tempers and
decoders so you can be compressed
directly to see pixel buffers
or compressed directly to CM sample
buffers them
a quick note on these on using these
remarks a lot of people think they have
to die down to the lowest level in use
the video toolbox in order to get
hardware
acceleration but thats really not true I
O S
ATK AB foundation and video toolbox will
use hardware
kodak's analyst am AV Kidney Foundation
will use hardware kodak's when they're
available on the system
and when you when it's appropriate and
video toolbox will use hardware kodak's
when it's available on system and when
you request it re:
so before we dive into more staff
foregoing
I'm gonna do a quick look at this cast
of characters these are some of the
common types the on counter in RM
in these interfaces first of their CD
pick some buffer
see the pics a buffer contains unblock
update have
image data and wrapping that
that buffer data is the CD pick some up
for mapping
and the see the pics above for wrapping
tells you how to access that data
it's got the to mention with the high
it's got the pixel format
everything you need in order to
correctly interpret the the pixel data
next week at the CP pics a buffer pool
see the pics a buffer pool as you to
efficiently recycle CB pixel buffer
backings those those data buffers can be
very expensive to cook constantly
allocate and deallocate
so pixel by purple allows you to to
recycle them
the way picks up a purple works is you
allocate to see the pics a buffer from
the pool
and the see the pics a buffer is a wreck
an object
when everyone releases that CP pics a
buffer the data backing goes back into
the pool
and it's available for reuse next time
you allocate a pixel
pixel buffer from that pool
next thing is that is pixel buffer
attributes
this isn't actually a type like the rest
of the things in this list but it's a
common
com common object you'll see listed nor
interfaces you'll see
requests per pixel paper attributes
dictionaries picks up a fresh beats RCF
dictionary containing said requirements
for
either CB pixel buffer or affix a buffer
pool
this includes the you can list include
several things thus conclude dimensions
that you're requesting
the with them hi this can include a
specific pixel format or a list a pixel
format for you'd like to
to receive and you can include specific
compatibility
flags requesting compatibility with
specific tech display technologies
such as Open GL OpenGL ES or core
animation
are it next week at cm time cm time is
the basic description
description of time that you'll see in
our interfaces this is a
rational representation overtime valium
contains a 64-bit
time value that's the numerator and a
32-bit time scale which is the
denominator
we is the sort of rational
representation so that these time values
can be passed throughout your
media pipeline and you don't have to do
any sort rounding on them
alright next see in video format
description
you'll see this in a bunch for
interfaces and ASEAN video format
description is basically a description
of video data
is contains the dimensions this includes
the pixel format
and there's a set of extensions go along
with the
with the have seen video format
description
these extensions can include information
I hadn't
to in information used for displaying
that
video data such as pixel aspect ratio
and it can
include color space information
and in case a page 264 data the
parameter sets
are included in in these extensions and
we'll talk about that more a little bit
later
all right next to see a black pepper fam
block buffer is
be the basic way that we wrap arbitrary
blocks Data Inc or media
in in general when you encounter video
data compressed video data
in our pipeline it will be wrapped in
cm1 for
RA now if cm sample buffer
you'll see seem simple but for sure a
lot show up a lot more interfaces
these rap samples data at in that case a
video cm
sample buffers can wrap either
compressed video frames or uncompressed
video frames
and seem simple buffers build on several
the type that we talked about here
they contain a CM time the is the
presentation time for the sample
they contain a seem to be a format
description this describes the data
inside the same sample buffer
and family in the case of compressed
video they contain the same block buffer
in ASEAN bloc buffer has the compressed
video data
and if it's an uncompressed image in the
CM sample buffer
uncompressed image may be in a scene
depicts a buffer or it may be an ASEAN
bloc
for are right next week at cm clock
see in clockers is the core media
wrapper around us or subprime
and like the clock on a wall there's no
clocks on welfare
like a clock on the wall times always
moving and it's always increasing
on ASEAN clock me one of the common
clocks that with that you'll see used as
the host time clock
so if you can cm clock get host time
clock
will return o'clock which is based or on
Mak Mak
absolute time so
cm clocks are hard to control I'm you
can't really control them
as a mention they're always moving at
always at a constant rate
so cm time days provides a more
controlled view on to ASEAN clock
so if we go ahead and create a CM clock
based
as CM time days based on host time clock
week and then set the time to time zero
on our time pace now
time zero on our time base maps to the
current time
on the CM clock and you can control the
break
have your time pace so if you wear them
to go infect your time base rate 21
time will begin advancing on the time
days at the same rate at which the clock
is advancing
and same time basis can be created based
on cm clocks where they can be created
based on others the impact this is
iraq let's hop into our first use case
this is the case where you have a stream
of data coming in over the network
and center to video data coming up the
network we can safely assume that the
cat video
and so we've got AB sample buffer
display Blair Witch 2
which takes a street which can take a
sequence have compressed frames
and display in a layer inside your
application
AB sample buffer display where shipped
in maverick's
and its new in Iowa State
so let's take a look inside a be simple
but for display where
as I mentioned it takes a sequencer cm
sample takes a sequence of compressed
frames as input
and these need to be in CM sample papers
internally it's going to have a video
decoder
and will decode the frames and has in to
see the pics on buffers and will have
sequence at CB pixel buffers
cued up ready to display in your
application at the appropriate time
but I mention we were getting our date
of the network a lot of times when
you're getting
come getting a stream compress video of
the network it's going to be in the form
of an elementary stream
and I mention that CM sample AB sample
buffer this way where
1cm sample buffer input
well there's a little bit of work that
has to happen here to convert your
elementary stream data into cm sample
papers
so let's talk about this h264
defines a couple of ways of packaging a
the h264 spec
to find a couple ways of packaging h264
data
the first 1 I'm going to refer to as
elementary stream packaging
this is used in elementary streams
transport streams a lot of things with
streams and learning
next is impact for packaging this is
used in movie files
and MP mp4 files
and in our interface is the deal with CM
sample buffers
core media Navy foundation exclusively
one
the data package this in the impact for
packaging
so let's look closer at add an H 264
stream
and the and h264 stream consists of a
sequence blocks of data
packaged in now units these these now
units can
contained several diff that this is the
network abstraction layer
and these are network abstraction layer
units
these can contain a few different things
for stuff they can contain sample data
so you can have a a single frame a video
could be
packaged in one now you now or
a nap a frame a video could be spread
across several million its
the other thing that millions can can
can contain as parameter sets
the primer sets the sequence primer set
and picture frame percent
are chance updated which the decoder
holds onto and these apply to all
subsequent friends
well until a new printer said arrives
so let's look at elementary stream
packaging elementary stream packaging
in elementary through packaging the
primer sets are included in now units
right inside the street
this is great if you're doing sequential
playback you
reading your primer sets and they apply
to all this all subsequent frames until
new primer sets right
and pick for packaging has the now units
pulled out
and it's in a separate block data and
that's market data is stored in the sea
in video format description
so as I mentioned each cm sample buffer
references
this cm video format description that
means
each primer data have has access to do
to the primer sets the sort of this or
to packaging is
superior for random access enough I'll
it allows you
to jump anywhere and begin decoding at
it and at an iframe
so what do you have to do if you have an
elementary stream coming in
well we've got you've got a couple
you've got your primer sets in now units
and you're going to have to package
those in ASEAN video format description
well we provide a handy utility that
does this for you
see in video format description create
from x264 primer sets
had RA
Sep the next the next difference that we
can talk about between
an elementary stream and and pick for
packaging is
in now unit headers so each now unit
mystery
in an elementary stream I'll have three
or four bytes
start code is the header and an impact
for packaging
we have a wank code sell for each now
unit your stream they're going
you have to strip off thats that star
code and replace it with the linked CXO
that felt like that for now you know
it's not that hard
so let's talk about building a CM sample
buffer from
from your elementary stream first thing
you're going to have to do is take your
now you know
or now units and replace
the start code with the link code:
and Gill wrap that now unit Nancy M
block buffer
when no care for simplicity I'm showing
the single male unit but if you have
a framework consists of several million
ants you need to include all of the nal
units in your cm sample buffer
so you ever seen block buffer you have
your say in PDF format description that
you created from their initial
from your primer sets and throwing a CM
time value there for presentation time
with your frame
and you have everything you need in
order to create a CM sample buffer
using CM sample buffer create
are right let's talk about AB sample
buffer display layer in time
so as we saw all seem simple buffers
have an associated presentation
timestamp
and our video decoders going to be
spitting out CD pixel buffers
each with an associated presentation
timestamp
well how does it know when to display
these frames
by default it will be driven off the
host time clock
well that can be a little bit hard to
manage the first time clock isn't
really under your control so
we allow you to replace the host time
clock with your own path
your own time base to do this you set
the time
yeah in the example here we're creating
a
time days based on the post time clock
and we're setting that is the control
time base under AB sample buffer display
where
here we're setting the time this time 25
which would mean our frame
whose timestamp is five will be
displayed an earlier
and then we go ahead and set the time
base rate to 1%
an hour congress begins moving at the
same rate as their
post host time clock and subsequent
subsequent frames will be displayed at
the appropriate time
RA so providing
the same sample buffer sleepy simple but
for display where that there's really
two
major scenarios that can describe this
first off there's the periodic source
this is the case we getting frames and
basically the same rate
at which they're being displayed in this
in there AB sample buffer spyware
this would be the case for a live
streaming app or
like streaming up with low latency or
videoconferencing scenario
the next case is the unconstrained
source this is the case where you have a
large
at large that seem simple buffers at
your disposal ready to feed and
ABC people AB sample buffer display
layer at one time
this would be the case if you have a
large cache Baffert network data
or if you're reading the same sample
papers from a file
all right let's talk about the first
case this is really simple
friends are coming at them right knee
which they're being displayed you can go
ahead and Justin cue the sample
buffers any with your AB simple but the
display layer as they arrive
you use the enqueue sample buffer couple
are at the unconstrained sources a
little bit more complicated you don't
want to just show
although CF cm sample buffer simply be
simple but for display earlier once
no one will be happy with their what you
wanna do
at the example mister display where can
tell you when
if when it's buffers its internal
buffers are low and it needs more data
and you can ask it when it has enough
data
the way you do this is using their
request
media data when ready on cue
you in you provide a block in this
interface
and AB sample buffer display where will
call your block
every time the its internal cues are low
and needs more data
inside of that block you can go ahead
and loop
well you're asking whether it whether it
has enough data
you use the israeli from our media data
com if it returns true that means that
once more sample papers
so you keep on feat in sample buffer
zone assumes that returns false
means has enough and you can stop Sam
to pretty simple loop to rate
alright let's do a quick summary of what
we talked about with the B sample buffer
display where
at this point you should be able to
create an AB sample buffer display where
you flirt haddock how to convert your
elementary stream
elementary stream h264 data into cm
sample papers that are
that will happily be decompress by AB
sample
efforts play where we've talked about
couple of scenarios about how you would
provide the same sample buffers
to your layer a simple spyware and
finally be talked about using a custom
same time base with the eighty simple
efforts play later
re: let's dive in for second case
this is the case where you have a stream
h264 data coming in over the network
but you don't wanna just displayed an
application you one actually decoders
frames and kept the
get the decompressed pixel buffers
so what we had an AB sample buffer
display where
contains a lot of the pieces we need but
instead of accessing the video decoder
through the AB sample paper display
where
will access it through the BT
decompression session
like the 80 simple but for display where
PT decompression session 1c
cm sample papers as a template
and it will decode the same sample
papers to see me but some papers
and receive those in it and help call
back the %um
so in order to create a PTT
decompression session me a few things
first you need to provide a description
of the source buffers that you'll be
decompressing
this is a CM video format description if
your crew
if you're decompressing from elementary
stream you've created this from the
primer sets
if you just have a CM sample buffer that
you want to decompress you can pull it
straight off the same sample buffer
next you need to describe your
requirements for your help pics buffers
use a pixel buffer attributes dictionary
for this
and finally you need to implement a VT
decompression help call back
alright let's talk about describing your
requirements for that for the output
pixel buffers
here you need to create a pic summer
fresh its dictionary
slip let's look at a scenario where we
want use their output see pics /a
buffers in an open gles render pipeline
really the only requirement here that we
have for output pixel buffers is that
they be open gles compatible
cell we can go ahead and just created
CF dictionary rawness dictionary
specifying the KCB pick some up for
OpenGL ES compatibility key
and said set it to true
so it can be very tempting to when
creating these pics about prejudice
dictionaries to being very specific
that way there's no surprises about what
you get out of the BT decompression
session
but there's some pitfalls here so let's
look at this case where we had
KCB pick some up for OpenGL ES
compatibility key set to true
here a decompression session the decoder
inside for decompression session is
going to be Deacon frames and helping
wavy
see the pics above urs in that BT
decompression session with them
ask is this well it'll ask itself if
this
pick some up for compatible with the
those requested attributes
and the answer is yes that wavy friend
is open gles compatible so it can return
that directly to your call back
but let's say you were possessed to add
be gr8
request here pics about brach abuse
so just like before that decoder inside
for BT decompression session will decode
two-way TV format
and we'll ask whether this this see the
pics a buffer is compatible with the
requested out but requirements
and it is open TLEs compatible but it's
certainly not be gr8
so it will need to do an extra buffer
copy to convert that way the data
complete ERA data
so extra buffer copies are bad they
decrease
efficiency and they can lead to to
decrease battery life so the world story
here is
the don't over specified
all right let's talk about your output
call back
so alpha comeback is where you'll
receive the decoded CB pixel buffers
and think see the pics /a buffers don't
have a built-in timestamp so you'll
receive the presentation timestamp for
that
for that pic sober for here and
if they're errors or the frames drop for
any reason you receive that information
the app called back
and it's important to note that the
output car back will be called for every
single frame
be pushed into the BP decompression
session even if there's an air
even if it's dropped
alright let's talk about providing
frames here BT decompression session
to do that you call Vicki decompression
session decode frame
just like AB sample buffer display layer
you need to provide these
as CM sample buffers
and he need to provide these frames and
decode order
and by default DT campers decompression
session he could frame
operate synchronously this means that
your help call back
will be called before BT decompression
session decode frame returns
if you want a synchronous operation you
can pass em the flag requesting
enable a synchronous decompression
i right let's talk many seconds
decompression them
with a synchronous decompression the
call to be key decompression session
decode frame
returns as soon as that hands the frame
of to the
decoder but decoders often have limited
pipelines for decoding frames
so when the decoders internal pipeline
is full
the call to VT decompression session he
could frame will block
until space opens up in the decoders by
climb
we call this decoder back pressure so
what this means is that even though
you're calling BP decompression
session D could frame and requesting a
synchronous decompression
we will be doing the decompression a
synchronously but the call can still
block
in some cases so be aware its you're
doing it against the compression but the
call can block so don't perform you I
tasks on that
thread re:
if you find yourself in a situation
where you want to ensure that all a
sequence frames have been cleared have
the decoder
you can call DT decompression session
wait for a sinking springs this call
will not return until
all frames have been omitted from the
decompression session
so sometimes will decoding a the coding
sequence a video frames
there will be a change in the same video
format description so let's look at the
case where we had
had a sequencer an elementary stream and
we
created the first format description
that if the first primer sets that we
encountered
now we r format description 1 with our
first spf MPPs
we can go ahead and create RVP
decompression session with that format
description
and decode all the subsequent frames
with that format description attach the
same sample buffer
until we encounter in New a new
SPS MPPs industry then we need to create
a new format description with that new
with the new SBS MPPs
and we have to make sure that the
decompression session can switch between
these former
descriptions so to do that you
call BT decompression session can accept
format description
this will insure asked the decoder
whether it's able to transition from
format description want to format
description to
if the if deter answer is true
yes can't switch can handle the new for
accept the new format description
that means you can pass subsequent
samples with that new format description
attached to them
into the decompression session and
everything will work fine
if it returns false that means the
decompressor the decompressor cannot
transition
from that first format description to
the second format description
and you need to create a new VT
decompression session
and be sure to and pass the new friends
and into that one
and be sure to release that all DT
decompression session when you
when you're no longer using
RA quick summary of what we talked about
with BT decompression session
we talked about creating the BTD
decompression session
and how to make optimal decisions when
creating a pic summer for
your your picks up a fragile its
dictionary for
for specifying your help requirements
we talked about running your
decompression session both synchronously
and a some
synchronously and we talked about
handling changes unseen video format
description
so with that what's happened in Turkey
three
this is the case for you have a stream
of you have a stream of
see the pics /a buffers are frames
coming in from camera
or another source anyone compress those
directly into a movie file
well for this in you may be familiar
with us already
we have a VSS Writer ABS at writer
has an encoder internally and it's going
to be in coding this brings into cm
sample buffers
and it's got some file rating smarts so
it can
write these optimally into a movie file
we're not actually going to talk about
talk more at this point about
a BFF writer but it some
it's an important concept important
thing to bring up in the context of the
stock
so if you want more information on ABS
at writer
you can go back to WWDC 2013
and the top moving to a peak it may be
foundation or 2011
working with media maybe foundation
re: let's just substrate and case for
this is the case for you
have that stream data coming in from
your camera
needn't and you wanna compressor you
don't wanna rating to a movie file
you want direct access to those
compressed sample buffers
so we want to approach our video encoder
through
BT compression session rather than
through the Absa writer
so just like ABS operator BT compression
session pixie pixel buffers has a temper
and it's going to compress those in
return them sample buffers
and we can go ahead and send that
compress data out over the network
so to create a BT come DT compression
session meet a few things
and this is really simple you just need
to specify the dimensions you want for
your compressed out per
you need to tell us what format you
wanna compressed him such as KCM video
codec tape
h264 and
you can actually provide a setup pics by
fracture be it's describing your source
see pics /a buffers that he'll be
sending to the ET compression session
and finally you need to implement a PT
compression out but call back
so you've created a BT compression
session
now you want to configure you configure
VT compression session using PT sessions
set property
in fact you can have a whole sequence
that PT sessions at properties
property of so I'm gonna go through a
few common
properties here and but this is not an
exhaustive list
the first 1 I'm gonna mention is allow
for a mi Orden by default h264
encoder will allow frames to be
pre-ordered that that means the
presentation time simply pass them and
will not necessarily
equal the deco decode order
which they're amid if you
want to disable this behavior you could
pass false to allow free me ordering
next one average bitrate:
this is how you set a target bitrate for
the compressor
h264 entropy mode
using this you can specify CA VLC
compression or came back
compression for your h264 encoder
i right and then there's the real time
property the real fun property allows
you to tell the
encoder that this is a real time
encoding operation
such as Anna its live streaming case
conference in case as opposed to
more of a backgrounder activity like a
trench coat operation
and fine the final when I'm gonna
mention here's the profile level key
this allows you to specify specific
profiles and levels
or specific profiles and allow us to
choose the correct level
and this is definitely not an exhaustive
list there's a lot of a lot of
these options available so go ahead and
look in VT compression property study
each
and see see what we have for you
alright let's talk about providing see
the pics above urs TV decompression
session
use BT compression session and cold
frame to do this
and you need to provide CB pixel buffers
and see the pics ever as i've mentioned
see the pics /a buffers don't have it
presentation timestamp built into them
so as a separate premature
your provide the presentation timestamp
you need to have feed the frames and in
in presentation order
and its were one more note about the
presentation order
day the presentation timestamps must be
increasing
no duplicate presentation timestamps no
timestamp
go backwards and so
compression sessions you become
compression operations usually require a
window frames that they'll operate on
so your output may be delayed so you may
not receive
you compress frame en route to call back
until a certain number frames have been
pushed into the encoder
RA and finally if you reach the end of
the frame for your pass into the
compression session
and you wanna have it admit our the
frames that 3c so far
you can use BT compression session
complete friends are pending frames will
be omitted
re: let's talk about your help call back
so you're up call back as well where
you'll receive your output cm sample
buffers
these contain the compressed frames
if there were any errors a truck frames
you receive that information here
and final thing frames will be omitted
in pea coat order
so you provided frames to the VT
compression session presentation order
and they'll be omitted and decode order
RA well saying if compressed a buncha
friends
there now compressed it in CM sample
papers which means that they're
using impact for packaging and you wanna
send as
that out of the network which means imy
you may need to switch these over to
elementary stream packaging
well once again you're going to have to
do a little bit of work
so we talked about the primer sets
before
the so the primer sets will
in your and pick for package which h264
will be in the sea in video format
description
so the first thing you're going to have
to do is extract those parameter sets
and package them as now units to send
out over the network
well we provide a handy utility for that
too
cm video format description get h264
parameter set index
RA and the next thing that you need to
do is
upset at what we did with the B sample
buffer display where
are now units are are all going to have
my
headers and you're going to need to
convert dazzling
headers into Star codes
so as you extract each now unit from the
compressed data
inside the same sample buffer convert
those headers on the now units
alright quick summary a that what we
talked about with the PT compression
session
we talked about creating the BT
compression session
we talked about how to configure it
using the PT sessions that property call
and we talked about how you would
provide see the pics /a buffers to the
compression session
and finally we talked about converting
those seem simple buffers into an h264
elementary stream
packaging re: and with that
I'd like to him things after Eric so you
can talk a monthly pass
good morning everyone my name is there
turnquest on the core media engineer
and today I want to talk about
multitasking coding so as a media
engineer
we often do it two opposing forces
quality verses
bitrate: so quality is how pristine the
images
we all know we've seen great quality
video and we really don't like seeing
bad quality video bit rate is how much
data
per time is in the upper media file so
let's say we're preparing some content
if you're like me you go for
high-quality first so great we have high
quality
now in this case what happens with the
bitrate unfortunately
if you have high quality you also tend
to have a high bitrate
that's okay but not what we wanted for
streaming this content or storing it on
a server
black case you wanna low bit-rate but
the quality isn't gonna stay
this high unfortunately that's also
going to go down as well
so we've got we've all seen this as
balking cutter artifacts or an output
image that doesn't really even look like
the source
we don't want this either ideally want
to me like this
high-quality and low bit-rate in order
to achieve that goal we've got a
multi-pass according to a B foundation
and video toolbox
so first off what is more the passing
coating
what's your overview what single passing
cutting his first so this is what David
covered in his portion of the talk
was single passing coating your friends
coming in going into the encoder and
being admitted
in this case we're going to movie file
then once you're done a pending all the
samples
were finished hour left with a row to a
movie file
simple enough let's see how multipass
differs
to uncompress friends coming in going
into the compression session
being omitted as compressed samples are
gonna change things up a little bit
we're gonna have our frame database this
will store the compressed samples and
lowers random access and replacement
which is important for multipass
ever going to have our anchor database
missile store
frame analysis
so we're done a pending for one pass in
the a.m being cuddled aside
I think I can actually do better in
another pass I can tweak the primers a
little bit to get better quality
it will require some samples and you go
through and send those samples against
the encoder
and then it may decide I'm done or on
actually are I want more passes in this
case let's assume that we're finished
so we no longer need the encoder
database or the compression session
but we're left with this frame database
we want a movie file
so we need one more step there's a final
copy from the frame database
to the up a movie file and that's it
we have in multi-path encoded video
track on a movie file
call let's go over some encoder features
my first point is I wanna make no dove
is that Davis said that single passes
hardware-accelerated
and multi-path is also
hardware-accelerated you're not losing
any hardware acceleration there
second point is a multi-pass has
knowledge at the future
now it's not some crazy time traveling
video encoder bonus points were filed
that enhancement request
arm it allows our is able to see your
entire contact
sign single-pass as friends come in
thinker have to make assumptions about
what might come next
and multi-path it already seen all your
content so I can make much better
decisions there
third it can change decisions that it's
made so in single pass
soon as a friend amid is omitted that's
it can take no longer change
jerry can no longer change its mind
about what it omitted
multipass because the frame database
supports replacement
each passing Gautrain change its mind
about how to achieve of more quality
and as a result of this you really get
optimal quality per Bette so sorta like
having a
very awesome custom encoder for your
contact
so thats how multipass works and some
and features
let's talk about new API's so first off
it's like about the V Foundation
in a V Foundation we have a new AV after
tax for session property
we have new path descriptions for ABS a
writer and poet and we never use IEDs
reader output so first was governor
overview
ABS an extra session and ABS an extra
session going from a source file
decoding them then per for performing
some operation on those uncompressed
offers something like scaling or color
conversion
enter and cutting them in writing into a
movie file on this case what is a BS in
extra session provide
what does all this for you its easiest
way to transcode media on I was an
hour's 10
so let's see what we've added here Sony
yesterday for a session model passes are
taken care of
for you automatically there's no work
the have to do to send the samples
between passes
and also it falls back to single pass a
multi-faceted and supported
so if you choose a preset these the
codec for multi battered and supported
don't worry are you single pass
and we have one new property set this TS
and you're on a Mac opted in a
multi-pass
and that's it so for large majority view
this is all you need
neck for talk about ABS writer save your
ass writer you're coming from I
compressed samples you want to compress
them to write them to a movie file
you might be coming from Open GL Open GL
yes context
in this case was a BS writer provide
wraps this portion going from the
encoder to the open the file
another use case it simmers ABS extra
session
re going from a source movie file to a
destination up a movie file
and modifying the buffers in some way on
this case you're gonna use an ABS a
reader output an ABS a writer and poet
you're responsible for sending samples
from one to the other
let's go over new ABS a writer input
API's
so like a view of the extra session you
need to enable multipass
so said the CS and you're automatically
often
then after done a pending samples you
need a marked the current passes
finished
so what is this deal well this triggers
the encoder analysis
internees to decide if I need to perform
multiple passes
and if so what time ranges so the anchor
might say I wanna see the entire
sequence again
I wanna see subsets the sequence
so housing her talk about what time
ranges wants the next pass
work through ABS writer input path
description so in this case
we have time from zero 23 but not the
sample a time three
and samples from five to seven but not
the sample at times
so passes corruption is the encoder
encoders request for media and the next
pass
and may contain the entire sequence or
subset of the sequence
on a path description you can create the
time range is that the cutters requested
by calling source time ranges
all right let's talk about how a bf
writer input uses path descriptions
so when you trigger the encoder analysis
think attorneys reply with what is
what decisions it's made you provide a
block on this method
to allow the encoder to to give you an
answer so this book is called blinker
makes a decision about the next pass
in that block you can get the new path
description encourage decision about
what content and wants for the next pass
with the %uh that works on a sample
so here's our sample we have our block
all back to you provide
inside a call back you call current path
description this async odor what time
ranges once for the next pass
if the past is non mil meaning the
encoder wants data for another pass
you reconfigure your source so this is
where the source will send samples
to the ABS writer input and then use you
prepare the
ABS a writer input for the next pass
already familiar with
request media data when ready on cue
if the passes mill I'm using color is
finished passes
when you're done you can mark your input
is finished
all right let's say you're going from a
source media file I was our second
example
so in new APIs for ABS a reader output
you can prepare your source for
multi-path
by saying supports random access equals
yes
then when the coder what's neat I'm
Rangers you need to reconfigure your ABS
your output to deliver those time ranges
so that's reset for reading time ranges
within an iterative time ranges
finally when all passes have completed
become our configuration is final
this allows the ABS rerouted to
transition to its completed States
organs are tearing itself down
right now there's a couple shortcuts you
can use if you're using ABS return ABS
writer in combination together
so you can enable ABS a reader output if
the if the asset writer input supports
multi pass
so if the encoder supports multi pass we
need a sport random access on the source
then you can reconfigure your source to
deliver samples for the ABS a writer and
poet
so with the reader output call re
separating time ranges with the path
descriptions time ranges
let's go over that in the sample sunset
delivering for an arbitrary source we
now want to deliver for ABS rear output
we call re separating time ranges with
the past scription source time ranges
grant so that's the new API a foundation
for multipass let's talk next about
video toolbox
so video toolbox are in Kotor frame
analysis database
we like to call this are RBT multipass
storage
we also have additions to BT compression
session which David introducing his
portion the talk
and decompress frame database or as we
call it BT frames I'll
so let's go over the architecture but
this time are placing your
the frame database and incur data base
with the objects
but we actually use so in this case we r
BT frame silo an RBT multipass storage
we're done with this past week owner
wants to see samples again
were sending in those samples that have
requests
they were finished and we can tear down
DVD multi bass storage in the
compression session
and look for their frames I'll so this
is where we need to perform the copy
from the frame silo to the up a movie
file
right we have a problem with the file
so first off let's cover what DVD
multipass tortures
so this is the encoder analysis is a
pretty simple API
first you create the storage and then
you close the file once your
finished so that the on that's all the
API that you need to use
the data stored in this is private to
the encoder and you don't have to worry
about it
national talk about additions to be
decompression session
so first you need to tell the BT
compression session any colour about
your BT multipass storage you can do
that by setting a property
this will tell the encoder to use
multipass and use this
BT multipass orange for its frame
analysis
actually got a couple functions for
multipass
to call begin past before you attended
any frames
after donna pending frames for that pass
a call impasse
and pass also asked the encoder if
another path can be performed
so if another if the encoder want
another path to be performed you need to
ask you what I ranges
have samples wash wax pass that's called
the
BT compression session get time ranges
for next pass and give an account in
Assyria time ranges
now talk about the BT France our
services the compressed frame store
so like the other objects you created
and then you you wanna add samples to
this BT frames I'll
so frames automatically be replaced if
they have the same
presentation time stamp and how this
data is stored is abstracted away from
you
and you don't need to worry about it
it's a convenient database for you to
use
then you can prepare the BT frame seller
for the next pass is optimized the
storage
for the next pass
finally let's talk about the copy from
the VT frame silo
to the app a movie file so you can
retrieve samples
forgiven time range this allows you to
get a sample
in a book called back that you provide
in added to route that movie file
right that's the new video toolbox API's
so want to close with a couple
considerations
so we talked about how multipass works
and what API's you can use in
AB foundation a video two walks we need
to talk about your use cases in your
priority in your app
so if you're performing a real-time
encoding
you should be using single pass real
time in cody has very specific deadlines
have how much
compression can take and multi-pass will
perform warn
passes over the time range so you single
pass in these cases
you're concerned about using the minimum
not a power during coating
you single pass water passes will take
more
power and as will the encoder in-house
you're concerned with using the minimum
amount of temporary storage during the
encoder transcode operation
you single pass the encoder analysis
storage and the frame database will use
more storage than the output media file
however if you're concerned about having
the best quality for your content
what he passes a great option
if you want to be as close to the target
bitrate you said on the BT compression
session or ass writers possible
use multipass multipass can see all
the portions are your source media and
so can allocate bits
only where it needs to very smart in a
sense
if it's okay to take longer in your app
so if it's OK for the encoder transfer
operation to take longer for better
quality
multipass is a good option but that the
biggest takeaways in your app
you need experiments you needed think
about your use cases and your users and
if they're willing to wait longer for
better quality
that's the thing about contact
so if you want your app has low quality
are low-complexity content
the abyss like a title sequence or a
static image sequence
all single pass a multi-pass are gonna
both give you great quality here
but multipass will give you much better
call you in single pass these are both
pretty easy to encode
that was talk about high complexity
contact think this is classic
Inc under stress tests water fire
explosions
we all love to do this but single-pass
and multi-pass Argos both gonna do well
but more to Bass Pro I won't do much
better than single past user
this kind of content is hard for
encoders to income
words more got a better decision well
that's in varying complexity
so think of this as a feature length
movie or documentary in Final Cut Pro
or anime movie trailer might have low
complexity
regions a title sequence high complexity
transitions
because there's a lot of different kinds
of content will be passing able to
analyze the sections and really give you
the best quality for bed
again the messages with your content you
need experiment
so you know your content and you should
know if multipass
will give you a good benefit and and use
cases
so let's go over what we talked about
today AB Foundation provides powerful
APIs operate on media
and for most viewed these are the API's
you will be using
now when you need the extra power video
toolbox API's provided direct media
media access if you fall into one did
use cases the david talked about
this is a good I way to is that it's a
box
finally multipath can provide
substantial call you improvements
but you need to think about your app
your use cases and your users
before you enable
so for more information here's our
evangelism email we have the foundation
documentation and a programming guide
we can answer your questions on the
developer forums
for those %uh view they're watching
online /a a lot of the socks already
happened if you're here live
so these are talks might be interested
in thanks everyone have a good rest your
day