my name is David Hayward and welcomed
first up to discussions today
or image in we'll be talking today about
what's new in core image on both
iowa's and West End so what is
core image core image is a fast easy
flexible framework for doing image
processing
and it supports oliver supported devices
on both
ISL s and OS 10 it's also used by
several of our key applications such as
photos
and on both platforms and allows you to
get very
good performance results and very
flexible output for those of you who may
be
new to core image I just wanna take a
few slides to talk about some of the key
concepts could also be relevant for that
press the discussion today the first of
filters core image filters ally to
perform per
pixel operations on an image no simple
example
you have an original image and you want
to apply it sepia tone filter to it
and you get a resulting image policy
that's fun but where things start to get
interesting is where you
combine multiple filters neither chains
or complex graphs
and here an example you can see a very
interesting result you can get by just
training three filters together sepia
tone prosecutor rotation to turn it into
a plutonium age
plus contrast to make it more dramatic
one thing to keep in mind is these
intermediate images
are actually like we'd object so there
need not necessarily even be memory
associated with these have any
significant paramount
another thing that's important to keep
in mind is
each filter may have one or more
colonels Associated
so these kernels are the actual
algorithm that implements
filters affect and one of the great
things about core image
is we can take these colonels and
concatenate them into programs
and this allows us runtime: to minimize
the amount of intermediate results
and with some great a compiler
technology on
both at the image processing and at a
lower level compiler level
were able to get the best possible
performance have a complex crash
so that's the basics in terms of how it
works
these are the four key object types that
you need to be familiar with if you want
to use core image
the first which will be talking about a
lot today SCI colonel
and this represents a program that's
written in sea ice
work or images colonel language second
object type is a
CI filter and this is an object that has
on mutable input parameters and those
parameters can be
images are numbers are vectors are other
types and it also
arm allows you to use one or more
colonels to create a new image based on
the current state at the output
at the input parameters third
key type is a CIA image and this is an
immutable object that represents the rep
receipt recipe
to produce an image just the active
creating an image does not necessarily
and do any real work the actual work
occurs when you render a CIA mission to
a CI context
and that's the object through which you
render results so those are the basics
when I wanna talk about today's what's
new in core images here we have a lot to
talk about
we have a bunch of new things that are
on iowa's for example
we have are most requested feature which
is custom CI colonels
we also are like talk about how you can
do photo editing extensions using Core
Image
and also how we can now support large
images on West
we also offer made some improvements to
have a GP render is used
we also has an API monetization
we have some new built-in filters we
have some UCI detectors
and then last time we talk about some
new things that we have on me
on Mac OS 10 side on
improve raw support and how to use a
second cheap you sup
first and most interesting i think is
custom CI kernels and I'll ass as I
mention this has been our
top requested feature encore image
already has 115 great built-in filters
on iowa's
but now you can easily create your own
so this is a
terrific feature for developers when
you're
writing CI are kernels on IRS you can
use the same CI colonel language that he
you stay on OS 10 there are few
extensions
on which allow making typical of are
colonels even easier
and we'll talk about that and much more
detail in our next presentation
work in your RCI colonels live
well they can live in your application
the kernel code can either
be a text resource or it can just be in
a string if you'd like
are the kernel is are wrapped up in a CI
filter subclass that you provide
that applies a colonel's to produce an
output image
another great place for your custom CI
colonels to go is
inside a nap extension for example photo
editing extensions
can you see I kernels and CI filters
across as very effectively
and you can use them to modify our your
photos or videos
so again we'll be talking our next
presentation
in much more detail about how to use CI
colonels I less but let me just give you
a little teaser now
were how simple it is here we haven't
just basically two lines of code
how do you say a custom CI colonel we
created in a string
which has some CI encore image our
source code in it
this is a very simple are colonel that
takes a pixel value an inverter
and you'll notice it's actually
subtracting it not from one but from the
alpha value
that's the correct way to invert if
you've got preoccupied data
which is what coronet receives once you
have the program written
then all you need to do is create a RCI
colonel object from not
string and then apply it you can specify
two things one is the
are the resulting extent of the produced
image
and also the arguments that will be
passed
to that colonel in this particular
example there's only a single argument
which is the input image
and so as a result our arguments part
down below
arm is just an array with a single image
in
so to give you a little bit of idea what
that looks like in practice I have a
quick demo
this is a fine example that we wrote
and it's kind of an example of something
that you wouldn't we would necessarily
has a built-in filter
see but it would be funny for
presentation like this so we have an
application called cock or image from
house
and this allows you to explore all the
built-in filters
and also allows you to seek some sample
code for how to write
our custom CI colonels so the image
starts out as gray
the first thing we need to do is provide
a an image to start with and we're gonna
say that we want the video feed to come
in and
on-demand out a filter and you can see
we're seeing a list of all the filters
that are
park or image and we created one down
here called WC 2014
and hope you can see this I can kinda
waiting for the camera
arm what we're doing here is actually on
algorithmically
taking the luminance from the video feed
and then using not to control the size
of a geometry geometrically
power generated rounded rectangle
on and we can change the size of that on
larger or smaller or we can change the
amount of the rounded
radius here sexual easier to see
that it's a video feed when it's smaller
but it looks
more called
so I'm and we're getting 30 frames per
second on that which is probably the
frame rate have
the have the camera so that's our
a short example and we'll have that code
available for talent at some point soon
so again that's custom CI colonels and
please come to our second session to see
all week learn about that are the next
thing about to talk about briefly is the
our photo editing extensions on iowa's
their hold talks on that
this year to be that easy I'd like to
talk a little bit
on about how that works in relationship
to core image
so here's just a little short video
run-through of what how this works in
practice
I we have image user went at they
product elicit extensions we picked the
core image 1
and this particular core image-based
extension has two sliders
one is the amount a sepia tone which we
can slide
and we're getting very good frame rates
to the screen as we do this
and then the second slider is a vignette
amount so it starts out with a large
radius and if you bring the radius mall
are you get more
have the vignette a fact as you can down
and all this is happening right now on
display sized image
later on when you hit save it's applied
on a full-size image
which is 12 megapixel image in this case
and it goes back into your library with
your at
so that's how it looks in practice I'm
not to go into too much detail on how to
occur despite me some good advice here
our first of
you can start to create a photo editing
extension by going into the templates
in Xcode I will also provide some sample
sample code as well so that a good
starting point
on but as I said I wanted to talk a bit
about how you can you score image
effectively
within photo editing extensions is
basically three steps
the first step is one year extension is
initialized
what you want to do is you wanna ass the
editing input object for display size
image initially that a UI image object
in from that you can create a CG image
and then from now to see i image on that
sounds like a couple steps but it's
actually those are just lightweight
rappers
once you've created that CIA image we're
gonna store that in a property for our
our delegate and everything it's good
time to do it at that time is to create
your view that you can be rendering into
we recommend using a Goku
and also create a CI context that is
associated with that
without you and it's good to store that
away in a property as well
step 2 is on what you do every time the
user
makes it added in your extensions every
time the slider moves
and this is very simple what you do is
you recall the display size CIA image
that we created in step 1
we apply the filters to correspond to
the slider adjustments
so in the previous example was are the
sepia tone filter and the
vignette effect filter and in with you
change together you get the output image
from that
and then you're gonna draw that using
the CI context that we also created in
Sep point and step three is what happens
when the user clicks the Done button
and it's a slightly different because in
this case you want to apply the effect
on the full-size image
so what we have here as we can have the
adding input object for its
full-sized image URL from that we create
a CIA image
can we apply the filters to this as well
now for most part this is the same as we
did in step 2
some parameters however such as radius
is may need to be scaled
arm in accordance the fact that you're
now working on a full-size image
once you on have chained together your
filters you ask the output image
and then you on the way this API works
as you return a CD image so you can do
that very easily work or image
you ask a CI context to create a sea
change
and this will work even on the full-size
image
so that brings me to the next subject i
wanna talk about today which is working
on
large images on iowa's so we made some
great improvements here in
addition to the supporting kernels as I
think our second key thing that we've
added this year on iowa's
so now you can we are full support for
images that are larger than the Jeep you
text her limits
and this means the input images can now
be larger than 4k
and output renders can be larger than 4k
we refer to this as large images but in
practice
4k images are not that large these days
many ever
devices cameras heard bigger than that
so this is actually really critical
feature to support this size image as
well
the way we achieve this automatically is
that we have on a Mac tiling support
cordage
and this among other things leverages
some great improvements that were made
an image I O
and their J pegged to improve how Dakota
encoder works
and also there's some great features and
core image
our language that allow supporting have
large image is well
let me talk about that last item in a
little bit detail so the CI colonel
language
allows your kernels to just work
automatically regardless of whether
tiling
happens or how at what size it happens
so this is a great feature that makes
reading see i've
colonels very flexible the way
this is achieved by toukie extensions if
have in our language and these are
available both on OS
can and on I lessnau the first is a
function called discordant
heard escort and that allow score image
to support tiled output automatically
basically allows your kernel to see the
desk corner
can in the native images space even
though we may only be rendering
a given Tyler time
similarly there's a a function called
samper transform
and that allow score image to support
tiling have large
input images automatically so this is
the two key things about the CI colonel
language that I'm
talk about much more detail in our
second presentation
so another great thing about our large
image support is how we work together
with RCG image rest and how we get some
great
improvements on Iowa State by being lazy
so one thing to keep in mind is if you
have a small input CD image that you
create a CIA image from
then the image is fully decoded at the
time you call CIA image
in it a CD image and that's actually
usually the right thing to do for small
images
on because you may be using at image
multiple times and you want to
take the performance impact
decoding the tape at once early however
for large images
that's not a good strategy because you
don't wanna require all that memory
to be up for that trip back to be
compressed unless you know you need
so if you have a large input CG image
that image not a pic image behind that
siege GNH
is decoded only as needed when you
costly I context render
so that's a very important detail
on similarly when you're producing a CG
image
out as a output a CIA image when you
call
RCI context great CD image if the output
CG images
small the image is fully rigged rendered
when CG images called
however if you're producing a large CG
image as an output
such as an example other for extensions
on image is only rendered as needed when
the CG image
is rendered this is also important
because
a very common situation as you pass a CG
image to CG image destination finalize
to encoded back into shape
so what all this means is that if you
have a very large a pic
you can take that large Jay pag decoder
apply filter to it
Henry encode it back into a Jay pag with
minimal memory
and great performance and this is a huge
win for core image on iowa's
so let's take a quick example you
applying a sepia tone
affect to a 4k by six KJ pack
200 mega by Syed image that on Iowa 7
took seventeen seconds
to decode apply the filter and
reincarnate as a jetpack
Iowa State that's one second and
and just as important I wes is the
memory high-water mark
because I can really force your
application into a unhappy place
and are high water mark on Iowa 7 was
200 megabytes which makes sense we have
a source
image was fully decompressed and we need
to produce a whole new image which is
the same size
however because we now have tiling are
high water mark is now 25 megabytes
and just to summarize when I was 7 be
worked on the full image at a time
and because it was largely of headies
SEP render
I'll ass 8 we have automatic tiling
and as a result we can use the GPO which
is a huge win
sup we've also made some other
improvements to how GP rendering works
for core image on high last
which are come important so
are your application sometimes the
surrender in the background often either
when the app is is transitioning to
background or when it's fully in a
background state
on I was seven that is supported however
all background renders used to slower
core image CP rendering power on Iowa
State we have an improvement in this
regard which is that renders that occur
within a short time a switching to
background
will now use the faster GP render now
into service with a lower GP priority
an advantage that is that any foreground
renders that happen at that time
will not be a have any performance
impact on because
core image will be using a lower
priority render so this is another great
advantage
there are some restrictions on this our
Jeep you usage
it is not allowed if you use CI context
raw image
in rec from wrecked because in that case
core mission is to render into the
client's
on legal context however any of the
other internet it's called
calling create CG image or render to see
the pics a buffer
are rendered a bitmap will all work in
this way
are another great improvement we have is
oftentimes he wondered
do rendering in the foreground when you
wrap it in the foreground
but do it are from a secondary Fred in a
plight manner
so if your application is showing one
thing and then doing something on a
secondary thread
using Core Image I was seven that
required
care in order to avoid nor for that
secondary thread to avoid causing
glitches for the foreground thread
and across the only sure-fire way to
avoid that was to use core images slower
CP render on Iowa State we have a new
feature which is secondary thread can
now render
arm into a context that has had this new
option specified
to see i context priority request low
any idea now is that context renders
using that now context
well not interrupt on any foreground
higher priority renders
this is also great for application so
this
much bring me some final thoughts on the
according to CP rendering
basically there is three key reasons why
we
an app would need to use CPU render on
Iowa 7
for example the CPU are render issues
when
are Jeep you text her limits were
exceeded
well starting on Iowa State that's no
longer limit
in Cornish so that's not a reason
anymore some early
are the application might needed to
render briefly on in the point in the
background
that's also been improved in iowa say
and lastly if your application wanted to
render from a secondary
thread one in the foreground you might
have used the CPU render and now that
it's no longer
a limitation so I met some great ways to
keep us on
core image is much faster Jeep you
rendering pap
the next subject to my talk about this
afternoon is about some
API modernization made both on arstan
and on high last is a small communities
but they are open
and total are first of our core image
doctor subclasses
on a West End can now use properties
survivors
are it said one thing to be aware of is
that
core image filter subclasses I do not
need to release
are the object associated with input
I've ours are properties
on so it's a little bit non-standard as
a class in that regard
by supporting properties that means a
code that used to look like this where
you have
output image equals filter are value for
key
Casey I output image key can now
be a little cleaner and just look like
out image because filter
dot output image
we also have our convenience method if
you I want to create a filter
and also said a buncha parameters all in
one fell swoop
this can be now done by saying filter
filter with name
and then specify some parameters at the
same time
and in those primaries are a dictionary
where you can specify all the inputs and
convenient manner
is it even slightly simpler case which
is are very are commonly is about where
one of your inputs as an input image in
you just want to
get the output of the filter so this
means you can
apply filter to an image with the setup
parameters without even creating a
filter object
lastly what are the common questions we
get from developers is how do I
correctly
orient my image so the orientation is
correctly upright
and the ass tentative specification has
a
setup a possible values that tell how
the image should be flipped a rotated
and me provided a code snippet in the
past for that but
much easier is that we provided an API
for that now
in Iowa State and I was 10 so on
simplest way of calling it is to say are
image by applying orientation
and that gives you back in new image and
again you're specifying an integer
orientation value
on as an alternative to doing the same
thing we also have an API that allows
you to get back to
a fine transform that is equivalent to
that
and the reason why that's useful is
usually or hitting your image
upright is only the first serve several
a finds that you may apply to your image
may also be scaling it to fit are
panning at
and so by getting this a fine matrix and
concatenating with any other refined
matrix you can get a little better
performance and accordingly
so we've also made some modernisation on
to west end with regard to color spaces
the default RGB color space is now a ser
GB which is great because it matches
with the default
om RGB color space that we haven't
iowa's it also matches what most
a modern applications expect for on
tagged
images similarly
our default working space has also
changed on a West End
it is now a linearized version at the
Rec
are 709 a chronic disease and again this
match is that the fall
we have for our working space on iowa's
and
has a great performance advantage which
means that in most typical scenarios
where your
have sRGB content going into a filter
and it's working space
and then going back to sRGB up but no
matrix math is needed at all
so this is a great created
next article like to talk about today is
some a new built-in
cordage doctors so we have
several I'd like to talk about are one
is new to
I was a is we've had in CI area
histogram
and see a histogram display filter on
the first
filter CI area histogram takes an input
image
and the rectangle that you wanna
generate a histogram affect
and it'll produce output image that's
typically 256 by one
pixels so that image is useful if you
want to render and get the pixel values
that occurs at a
check on give you your your histogram
get a very efficiently
however often times you also want to
display this histogram to the user
so we have a second filter which SCI
histogram display filter
and it takes as an input this 256 by one
pixel image
and produces a pretty crash with how red
green and blue grass in just like this
it's very easy to use in your
application just chained together these
two filters
this is another great doctors I'm really
pleased with this is
I'm with always had filters for doing
calcium players on an image
but we have a new filter called mask
variable blur and the ideas you want to
apply a blur to an image but you won't
apply
different amount up were at different
locations so the way this filter works
is you start with an input image
and you provide a mask image in this
example we have the
the mask is white in a lil lower left
hand corner
black in her center and then white again
in the upper
right hand corner and what this means
when we combine these two images with
the master very popular
is will get a resulting image that is
defocused at the corners
and then gradually transitions to a nice
sharp image in the center
on this is not just on with plans but
it's actually done with variable radius
players
which is quite track so their couple
different ways you can use this you can
use this to achieve a certain effect up
the field effect
where the topping bar if your image my
people are in the center may be sharp
or you can actually I'm Han create a
mask image
with a person in the foreground and then
nicely blur the background with a nice
Boca so hope to see what a fine examples
that how this another fun when we added
which is accordion fold transition in
this is something we did for
are the male team that we've also
provided as a public filter
you provide to images a before and after
and a couple parameters like how many
folds in
how many pixels at the bottom are shared
and what this filter looks like in
practice
has this and if you actually look
carefully
that's the actual entire kernel for this
filter so
home its international trickery
another filter retarded on in prior
releases we've had
of filters for generating QR codes
aren't we
added on a new one for generating code
128 barcode
and it works in a similar fashion you
specified input message as an estate a
and in this case is an additional
parameter which says how many pixels a
quiet space you want
and it'll produce an image like this
we've also added another one for Aztec
codes again same kind of idea for the
API you just
specify the input message and for this
particular generator it
has a input correction level reached
tells how many air crash in a bit
half
another new filter which is also fun is
CI perspective correction
any idea behind this is you have an
input image and you specify four points
and it will create a new image that is
cropped
and undistorted preserving the original
and intended aspect ratio
so this is again very nice for are
capturing parts have
an image and under storing them
me at a handful of new plan filters
lanier dodge and burn penlight subtract
divide
on also just to be aware we've are made
affects to use of light plane mode so
that better matches
back on and then there's a few other new
ones we've added that are
on you on iowa's passages our class
distortion
ha stretch crop remorse a correction on
trustee which was a great demo from our
conference show two years ago
and then who knows if we have some more
time we'll get a few more in
but what that brings us to the day is
over 115 built-in filters on iowa's
and of course that really is an infinite
number now that you guys can
create your own custom filters so
excited to see all sorts of new things
another area we made some improvements
in Inc or image is CI detectors
so what is a CO detector Russia
detectors and abstract class at allows
you to help find things within an image
and our prior to iowa say we had just
one type which was typeface
but without a tumour so we now have CO
detector type rectangle
NCR Tector type QR code
so how does this work well creating
attackers largely the same regardless of
what I protect your creating
here we have an example of creating a
detector typeface
where we say detector detector typeface
and we can also specify some options
their couple options that are very
useful for all the sectors one is
you can say whether you wanna have arm
high accuracy or lower accuracy
which depending on your needs might
allow are you trade of performance
versus
precision are also you can stellar
detector with the smallest feature
detectors
to detectives are not also can greatly
improve performance
and of course now that we've got these
new detectors you can just use detector
type rectangle
or detector take your coat as well
so are just as a reminder so when you're
using the face detector
on there's a couple options that you
wanna passion when you're asking for the
actual features an image
well as you can specify what the
orientation at the images
that's important because the face
detector look for upright faces
ha so you can specify options to say I
want to look for are
I blinks or smiles and that's specified
in the same options dictionary
and let me show you a little bit
occurred about how we can now use
detector
to create a sort of augmented reality
example here
the idea we wanted for the slow the
sample code if you want
start with the input image find the
faces in it and then put ask where is
over
the image where we find them and so this
is a little closer but as sample code
first off for each face that we detect
on in the features are a
we're gonna check to see if the eyes
were closed for a
then we're gonna create a CIA image with
color and
we're gonna have different colorways
based on whether the eyes are closed
or not or whether faces smiling or not
now
that API actually returns an infinite
image
so what we need to do is to crop that
image to the bounds for the feature that
was detected
we then take that cropped image color
and the composite over the previous
resulting image
and this is also a new API that we
provided it's basically convenience API
thats
on equivalent to using core image
source: over compositing filter
and this is what it looks like in
practice here's a little sample video we
shot where
on we've I'm are detecting the faces a
real time
and coloring I'm based on weather the
faces smiling or blinking or
combinations
we're going about 25 frame purse frames
per second
are beginning something similar also for
rectangle features the
idea behind are rectangle features is
you understand that
in a lot of cases the first step in
looking
in an image for something interesting is
to look for something like a rectangle
are for example if you're looking for a
sign or you're looking for a business
card
or if you're looking for a piece a paper
oftentimes looking for the rectangle
first is a great place to start
so we've created a generic rectangle
detector object
and it takes one of church with one one
option parameter
which is the aspect ratio me on a search
for and again
are you can acid attack your to return
me features a wreck
now right now it just returns one
rectangle but that may change in the
future
so here again we wanted do a little
sample here little bit fancier because
we wanna
arm it said I just doing the bounding
box overlay
we wanted make a lot prettier so again
where looping over all the
features in the image for creating a
on ICI image with color which is
infinite
but we're gonna take that infinite color
image and run it through the
CI perspective transform with extent
filter
and that filter does two things first of
all you specify an extent
which in this case for specifying 0011
so now effectively we have a unit square
image
and then the other parameters take that
unit square and stretch it
to the top left top right bottom left
bottom right corner it's
and then we over laid out on the
previous result
and here's what that looks like in
practice this is the name plate from my
office
and we are taking running through the
detector
are getting the detected rectangle and
then producing this
overlay tinted red image
are lastly we can do the same thing with
QR codes the
coheres factly the same are the only
difference is that we're using
the QR code future instead this example
you could have also gotten the message
from a QR code but in this case
I'm just gonna to an overlay so all I
needed to do was
use with accordance and again as you see
an example we can
detect this QR code and do an overlay in
real time
sup thats the the Boca my conversation
with the last thing I wanna talk about
is improvements that we've made on to
raw support on how its 10
so let me talk a little bit about are
raw support
so I'll talk about history fundamentals
have raw image processing
com some architectural overview and how
you can use this great filter we have
called the CI raw filter
so history first so on apples for
supporting ross
since back in April 2005 on
over those years we have been
continuously adding support for cameras
in improving the quality
we have about 350 camera supported today
and that's not including
on all the DNG possibilities and what
are the improvements we made
in hours 10 this year's that we support
the latest version at the DNG
specification
so that greatly improves number images
that we can support
and the other thing it's wonderful about
our support is provided the entire
operating system
which means everything from NS images to
CG images will automatically support raw
files
on system services like spotlight and
quick look support
these on key applications like
preview finder even mail support bra on
our photo applications have a church
iPhone photos
on also of third-party out can also get
this for
very little effort
so what is involved in processing your I
mention this is why you know I
the subject is actually very are dear to
my heart
because it involves a lot of very
advanced image processing to produce a
RAW file
so you start off with the fact that raw
files contain only a minimally processed
data
from the camera sensor image and in fact
the images actually missing typically
sixty-six percent of the actual data
because at each pixel location you only
have a red or green or blue value
and that means to produce a final image
we actually have to
makeup good values for those missing
sixty percent
have your data and that requires a lot
of advanced image processing to produce
a very beautiful image at the end
there are several steps in this process
they involve extracting critical
metadata from the file
decoding the raw sensor the mosaic
reconstruction which is
hugely complex task our lens correction
noise reduction and then there's a set
of operations that are in the color to
main
such as mapping seen referred color
values up it referred
and adjusting exposure and temperature
intent
and then adding contrast and saturation
to taste
so it's a lot of steps and we've made
some significant improvements to several
of these
an on OS 10 your sanity so we've
at Paris for for lens correction great
new noise reduction which will show in a
minute
and also some improvements the colors
well
so as I said before API's like NS image
in CG image
world get raw support for free and
that's because our support
provides a default rendering which is
process according to all OVR
parameters and or whatever our latest
algorithm is
on however we have this API which is
called the CI raw filter
which gives your application much more
control and
allows on you did get CIA image
with extended-range floating-point
precision
and also on that object are easy to use
controls
control how are raw imaging results are
processed
and it gives you fast interactive
performance on a GP
some great stuff that you can use in
your application
so this is sort of how it works is a
flow diagram you start out with a file
and I can on the pass either as a file
URL or an estate a
and not past as an input to create CI
raw filter
also can be specified on that raw filter
are several of our
processing parameters once you've set
this correctly
you can get in cinn Chaput which you can
then
on display on the screen and by default
it a look just like our default
rendering
however the great thing about the CI raw
filter is that once the user si nos
and your application has controls you
can alter those values
send them back into the into the RCI raw
filter
where can be read displayed all in real
time
another great feature we have on this is
we actually are
have a place for you can insert a custom
CI filter in the middle of our raw
filter processing before we've done
anything to change the data from
a linear space so this is very useful if
you want to do certain types image
processing
how Chris you can also apply filters are
after the
CI raw filter but this is a great center
functionality for certain use cases
and lastly doesn't have to go to the
display you can also take the CIA image
create a CD image from that and
producing new CG
a file on disk from that
and this is an example of how loco it
takes to use this filter
basically we start out with the URL we
create a
CI filter filter which image URL and
I'll return to see ire of filter
on in this particular example we want to
get from that filter what are two fault
value for the luminance noise reduction
was that returns as an object
we can make some are slight change to
that like say for example you want
I love your images be slightly more
noise reduced you can take that value
added it to it and then set a new value
and then once you're done setting values
you can get an output image
so just a few lines of code you can on
leverage I love our rock pipeline
so to show this in much more detail in
the past the state over to share on who
will be giving a live demo this
thanks in this part of our talk I would
like to show you some of the great
things that you can also doing your own
applications
using the CI role filters and always
stands built-in support for roll camera
files
to do that we created a very basic
simple application
that simply puts up our NS opens
GL view and which is tied up to see I
roll filter
and another in SU which is tied up to
the controls of the CIO filter
so let me run that and point it
to a role image
now by default when you actually open up
a RAW file
we will talk into our own calibration
data base and make sure that we applied
the corec set of calibration
settings that are specific to make and
model for the straw file
and some of the settings are for you
when the last correction
white balance settings
a noise reduction said things that we
will go into more detailed
in just a second exposure and
balls contrails show there's not much
going on with this
a very good image in the first place so
let me pull up on more
challenging image to show you the great
benefits of using raw files
now on this image by default on you
loaded you see that
parts of the image is close to clipping
point specially the sky and the
mountainous region
so we're probably losing some color
fidelity in this region
what's more interesting is the part
of the trees which are on the expos and
we're probably not getting the right
amount of detail
so let's see if we can actually improve
this image
the first thing that I would like to try
is setting to exposure to see how it
actually looks like
wanna probably increase the exposure to
make sure that I get the detail in the
tree part
of the image but as you can quit the C
word losing all the detail and hide
and opposite is also true once you start
decreasing the exposure
you're getting back to color in the sky
but your
losing all the detail in the lowlights
show there is something that that can be
done better
and the answer to that is see i
highlights and shadows field
normally if you were shooting J pick you
what I dot but of the J picnic order to
this
highlights and shadows but what
interesting
when you're shooting RAW is that you can
actually insert this filter
into the middle of our role processing
pipeline
and take advantage of the linear input
space that we're operating in
that means that you will be able to
better keep the color fidelity
you'll operates on the linear sixth and
pipeline
and at the and get better results so
let's try that
the first thing that I want to do is
increase the shadows
and almost immediately I can see that
all the detail in the shuttle part
is kept is are brought back
same for the sky I want to bring it down
to make sure that I can see more of the
sky
college and i cant easily do that
without
or loving any part of that image
show docked is a good example of how you
can actually use the CI role filter to
make sure that you can develop your own
images are in the best way that shooting
is appropriate
next nice filter
now noise reduction is a very
challenging problem
and are traditionally it is very
confidentially
compassionately expected expansive
algorithm
we're very happy to offer you a new
Moyes reduction algorithm starting in
all estan yosemite
that doesn't compromise on the quality
and you can still use it
at an interactive 60 frames per second
to show you that we have this
very noisy image of the mosque on a
Santa and I want to
focus on this part of the image just for
fun
I'm going to turn off all the noise
reduction to see what we are dealing
with initially
so this is the origin this is how the
original image looks like
and using the CI role a Ellen R and
Santosh I most filter settings I can get
it to a state where I feel
that this most comfortable for Mike
image so probably first thing that I
want to do is get rid of all the color
nice
and I'm using the CNR slider to do that
and look how interactive this process is
same for telling our you have a wide
variety of settings that you can play
with you can go with something that is
very smart
or something which keeps all the
luminance nice
so I wanna probably hit somewhere in the
middle right get
I got rid of most of the noise but still
capsule
mother good thing that you can do is
brought back some of the fine
high detail back to the image after you
clean up all the bad news
so the detail fly there is the one that
she would be using for that
and quickly you can get back to this him
grain
type of look
same is true for high-frequency contrast
and if you choose to do that
you can also play with that again 60
frames per second
so that is the noise filters starting
the tallest annual summit EU also be
able to use this filter for your G a pic
images
and this is going to be a really nice
advancement
on top of our offerings
the last thing that I want to show you
today is Lance correction
so a lot of the point and shoot cameras
a in the market today
are actually relying on digital signal
processing techniques
to I fix some of the compromises that
are made and
in the Lancers what I mean by that the
input image
as you can see by default is looking
Korek
to us but actual the role image that is
coming in
is booking like this so whenever docs
data is available
in the file roll camera will try to do
the right thing and actually correct for
this
arm aberration but for your own
application you may choose to skip this
step and actually do your own set of
filters or your own last collection
and it's an easy way to actually
go back to actual Ralph sample
of the file itself I'm going to now
quickly turn it back to Davis who's
going to talk about I
users of the second ship you
thank you sir so on as you saw we had
this great new noise reduction
and its have very complex hardcore image
filter that we developed and
I'm it makes great use to the GP you on
this which brings us up to talking about
the second G'pa so year ago we
on out to WC our new Mac Pro which has
this great feature having a second cheap
you are just waiting for your
application to take advantage of it
so let's talk a little about how that
can be used
sup arm so we have some thoughts about
for Corey mention for ross when is a
good time where you might want to use
the second GP
and couple scenarios come to mine one is
if your application
I'm has ability to do speculative
renders for example
you may have a large listed images the
user might be looking at one
but he may switch to the previous or the
following image in any time you cure
application could be speculatively
rendering
the next or previous image on a second
thread
similarly your application may have the
ability to do a large batch
export and you want to do that in the
background and you want to use the Jeep
you
but are you don't want that
background-repeat: you to affect your
foreground GP
usage so these are both great reasons to
use the second Jeep you
on because it allow it. get the best
performance
without are causing year user interface
to stutter
art for its usage some
how does one do that well you could do
this are today on maverick's
at pics around eighty lines open GL code
hard to tell are too chrissy eye contact
that refers to the second offline GPS
on however we've added ace simpler API
in core image on your sanity which is CI
context offline GP wouldn't action
typically to specify 0 so with one API
call you get a CI context and
when using at all renders will use the
second GPS
is very easy and a show that an action
on a
bring us around back up to do a quick
demo
well in our first demo we show that even
the most computationally expensive most
for the Rockets can be down at 60 frames
per sec
I'm going to bring that up the kitchen
back and open up a very noisy
image
so are Ellen R controls can be done at
60 frames per second to show you
that we actually wrote a little bit of
court
to you display the frames per second
when I'm actually sweeping through all
the noise filter settings
and as you can see I'm getting 60 frames
per second
a all the time now let's say that you
have a background for it
where you are cost company exporting
images and for some reason you want to
do
a cheap you pipe on your first
cheap you to simulate that written a
little bit
of text application which is using the
first GP
and when I go back to my own application
which is now also using my first you I
can see that
the frame Nate is actually suffering a
little
I'm going to run my tests it one more
time to see what type of frame rate I'm
getting out of this
and you can quickly see that it has
dropped down to 50 percent
I'm getting 24 frames per second show
can lead to something better than that
and the answer is yes if we are
if we can offload this work to our
second GPA using
the the CI GL offline contact
I will get back to my or regional
performance
in my active ap and to show you that
call one more time I can see that the
user
controls are once again very smart and
the frame rate that I'm going to get
is close to 60 so once again this is a
great way to take advantage of the
second you
if you are cost simply doing
computationally heavy algorithms in the
back row going to handed back
once-over today so to summarize what we
talked about today
on we've talked about some key concepts
understand about core image
we've talked about what's new in core
image on iowa say
most notably custom CI kernels and large
image support
we talked about some new things in core
image
on yosemite on notably some
API modernization and some on great new
noise reduction can draw support
on the faucet talked about how to use
the latest
CI detectors and on how to
work with RAW images in my sleep and not
imagine before so
on this unusual commissioner who to
contact alan's great person to talk to
if you have a request for more
information
are related sessions there's when I
really hope you guys can come to is ours
a second session this afternoon where
we're going to be talking about
how to write custom CI kernels and I'll
ass are
and also we have a lot session that
follows that so if you have
are coding questions please come in we
would love to hear your
here questions or suggestions so that's
all thank you so much for coming