good afternoon everyone my name is
Alexander Ehmann and
talk to you about developing custom car
image kernels and filters
on I O S let's start with a little bit
history
I'm we've been able to write custom
kernels on
Mac OS 10 sense 2005 with the advent of
core image
and now but I was a we're gonna show you
how you can do that
I'm are embedded devices
so the main motivation why would you
wanna write custom kernels
well you can there are we although we
provide many many
built in card for kernels and filters
there are situations where
you can use an existing setup filters or
some combination of to create the effect
your trainer
achieve so if you're trying to do
something such as a hot pixels affect
everything yet a fact which is
example we're gonna go into complete
details a bit later on that something
you would have been able to do without
writing a custom kernel
or if you want to create some sorta
interesting distortions such as the
trustee deformation that we showed how
to do in our talk two years ago
that also would have been possible but
now Iowa State with custom kernels it is
so let's talk a little bit about our
agenda first offer gonna start about
we can talk about the some some core
concepts involved in image processing
how to use court image
more than gonna go through a whole
series of examples
on how to write custom kernels your own
net organs been a majority of our time
today and then at the very end we're
gonna talk about some pot from
differences in between
OS 10 anti-western what you need to keep
in mind when you're writing
kernels for I your target so
key concept and its get some from eighty
if you're here for the earlier talking
to go this really quickly
I'm and explain how koreans works
so if you had for example a input image
the original image on the left and you
want to play
sepia tone filter you could easily do
that according to issue
apply much more complicated effects and
create arbitrary photographs are not
just necessarily daisy chaining
images up in this manner but also
creating more complicated graphs
and these are all lightweight objects
that eventually get combined together
and
each one of these filters can be
represented by
some number of kernels and internally
work or image does
is it will combine is all too in into
one program such that we minimize the
number the media buffers that you might
have and maximize performance which is
our goal
so
let's talk about the classes they're
gonna be dealing with today and again if
you were here earlier you gotta the
brief comes to this already
first class were gonna deal with the CI
colonel which is what we're gonna spend
most of our time working on today
and it represents the
I'm the object that encapsulates the
kernel that you'll be writing to drive
dude to interact with your image
and is written in our core image colonel
language which is based on your cell
next object is a CI filter which you
used to
drive the prime matters the I
colonel and it has any number of inputs
making the images and its numbers are
co-directors
and one output which is a new output
image we don't have a CIA image
which is different from other images you
may have seen moderate other API's
because it's an immutable object in only
represents the recipe for the image that
doesn't actually contain any
real data it's just a recipe for how to
produce the final result and its also
the cart based on Cartesian coordinates
nor lower left corner
and may have infinite bound so it's not
necessarily a bounded wrecked it can be
infinite as well
the final object ever gonna be dealing
with is a CI contact
Missy I context is the object that you
use to
render all your images your CIA images
whether that be to a CD image rav4
to an eagle context or whatever other
destination you desire
so let's take a look at how you might do
this if you're dealing with
standard C++ code in dealing with I
just you know trying to produce some new
output image given some some bucket have
bites
so you would typically write some for
loop over on the roseanne imagine then
iterate over all the columns and then
for each
input pixel input buffer I J produce
some
you run your honor them here indicated
by process pixel and create some new
output value and put that into your
result
what we like to do with a requirement is
abstract all that for loop away for you
and have it such that
all you need to do is concentrate on
your core algorithm when this case
process pixel and we will take care
are running that in a parallel fashion
for you on the Jeep you in running it as
often as possible
now in order to UCI colonel you need to
rate you need to subclass
from CI filter and CI filters gonna tell
us
given some number of let Satan is there
is your more
input images and some parameters how to
apply that
colonel onto your input image
and produce one new output image
sup let's take a look at the workflow
and I West
and if you've you've written colonels
sorry the written filters on a
I O S around a stop in the past this is
gonna sound very similar you
but we've got a new think so first
things first create a CA input image
with RCA input image then we supply CI
filter
we're going to get our output image
eventually once we're done running CI
filter
and then we have our open image we can
display it as I said earlier using
either
a CG image or rendering a CJ major Eagle
context
what's new and we're going to talk about
today is how you create those kernels
and how you apply the parameters that
you have from your filter to the kernel
to get your your final output
so talk about what exists currently Inc
or image
right now when I was eight we have 115
built-in
filters take a little closer detail
closer look at this we can see that
they're actually from this 102 said 115
there are 78
which are actually just purely modifying
the color
above the images there are another 27
which are pure geometry distortions
and then their final 7 that arc
convolutions
which brings us to our next point what
is the enemy ICI colonel
and I Wes so when I O S and on the west
end we now have a CI colonel class
but I O S we now have two new classes
that allow for greater performance and
specializations of
CI colonel and allow us to do higher
performance
optimizations then week when we do
currently elsewhere
I'm so we have a CI color colonel and
see I work colonel
I wanna talk about all three those today
in order of difficulty
so let's look at little deeper into the
interface for what is the icon looks
like NBC there are really only two
methods
that we care about the first one is to
create a colonel you call colonel with
string
and then to create a new CIA image after
having run your kernel
you call apply with extent and a few
other parameters and again it's
it's important to remember that calling
apply
doesn't actually render anything it's
just a recipe so you can daisy-chain
ease up
create whatever graph you want no work
is performed until the last moment when
you actually need those pixels
so what is CI colonels language well
it's based on GLSL
and it has extensions for imaging so to
deal with piling in
um all kinds of other optimizations we
put in
it also all the inputs and outputs are
floats so
frilly easy is let's now take a look at
what is involved in writing it's the eye
color colonel
so as I was saying all the inputs for
see eye color colonel are going to be
flow data and that doesn't it does
regardless of what your input data is
whether it's
RGB eight or 16 bit and sore flow data
it will
come into the kernel as flow data as
affect for
and the output from every CI filter is
also gonna be effect for
so let's take a look at the simplest
possible example we could come up with
which actually does nothing to this is a
no up it just takes an input
in this case is going to be an
underscore underscore sample and you can
see we just returned which is
effectively just affect for
and we just returned estar RGBA so if we
were to apply this filter to the input
image on the left
we get the exact same image on the upper
I can make things a little more
interesting and just swap the reading
greenhouse is a very simple process
we just take are red channel think
but in the location of the where the
Greenwise and take the green channel
and put in location with a red was and
if we were to apply this kernel
to our input image we get a new output
image and you can clearly see that the
Makrana Feb
for round has changed colors and same
thing for the
green we can make things a little more
interesting and was so what it looks
like when you actually wanna
have an input parameter that controls
how much of this affect it supplied
so here we have a new variable called
amount that supplied its
using our kernel damages use a mix
function to do linear interpolation
between
the original unmodified pixel value
are final destination value as if it was
at value 1.0
in any input value amount it was going
to be something that goes between 0&1
and if we were to apply this colonel in
very the value between 0&1 interactively
we get very quickly a
you know I'm animated blending between
these two
extreme images and that's pretty much
all you need to do to write a color
colonel on
I O S
the next thing we need to do months
we've done we've done our working
colonel and running a sec colonel is we
need to subclass EI filter in order to
drive that colonel
so in this case we derive from CI filter
we've created a new filter called swype
red green filter
with it has two properties first
property being the input image that
we're going to be working on
and second property is the input amount
so how much of that
I'm 101 we want to go
so we'll take a look at the methods that
were gonna be implementing today
first things first we're going to be
using us throughout our our presentation
today we're gonna have a convenience
function for creating a colonel such
that we don't recreate these kernels
at every frame because we don't want to
do that we're gonna have a custom
attributes method which
is oftentimes used to drive you elements
such as what we signed
carnage fun house earlier the previous
talk
and the method that you absolutely must
implement which is output image and
that's
we take all your input parameters and
you drive your kernel to producing up
with image
so let's take a look at the actual
implementation
as you can see creating cycle a colonel
is just some guy calling cycle a colonel
colonel with string and passing along
are
kernel code next thing we need to do is
call self
my kernel and then we apply that
and we pass into arguments the input
image which maps to the first parameter
var colonel
an ample amount which maps to our second
parameter or chrome
and that is literally all we need to do
to create a custom color colonel
and I West so now let's look at a
slightly more complicated example
where we in addition to modifying colors
I'm we in we also use position to
determine
how much of an effect should be applied
to let's pretend we wanted to do having
an effect take the image on the left
buy produce a new image on the right
that look like it had been
I am being added try his case
you can see that the we want the pixels
at the Center the image to remain on
modified
and as we go further out towards the
corners at the image we want those to be
as dark as possible forget to get those
as being like value between
10 and we're gonna be linearly
interpolating
along along that vector
so if we were to look at what an image
look like if we were to create
that zero to one mapping for the entire
image
we get this great image in the middle
here and if we take our image on the
left and we multiply the red green blue
values by that
new computed value we would get our
vignette effect and it's really that
simple
for now let's take a look at how we use
position information inside a colonel
her to the signature for a colonel we're
gonna go over through each step but how
we would create a simple
color kernel that depends on position so
as I mentioned earlier CIA images may or
may not be
have a 0-0 origin in this case you can
see that
the image is not your thing and what we
need to do is find out where the center
the images because every pixel that's
gonna get dark and
is with respect to the center so we need
to know how far away we r
annexing we can do is we can take the
size the image and just
divide that into you and we have
affected it takes us from the lower left
corner the image
to the center and then if we add these
two factors together we have a new
vector called
I'm Center offset
which takes us from the origin the image
to the Center in our Image
we then gonna keep you warm or value
which may be passing into our
colonel which is the extend to the image
divided by two
and that's going to be the longest
length love any point in our Image
and we're gonna be dividing values by
that such we can determine how much the
effect needs to be applied
so as I was saying earlier we have many
extensions inside halfcourt much to do
with imaging
one of them is called escort and this is
gonna tell you
which current pixel you're trying to
render
in global space so
what we need to do is figure out how far
away from the center is
every single desk or that's gonna get
evaluated miss functional get called on
every single fragment you're trying to
render
in the image so you can see here
it's a simple matter of just subtracting
one factor from the other we just take
that court
mine a center of said we get a new
factor called back from center
so inside the kernel is what it looks
like
where they're going to get the link for
that Victor with call distance in this
case
we computed darkening amount by doing
distance divided by radius which is like
half a bar diagonal a direct original
rectangle
one minus that is going to give us are
darkening amount
and then finally week call we return
effect for
that takes our input sample s multiplies
the RGB value but I talking about
and maintains alpha as its and having
any effect
to now let's take a look at what we need
to do in objective-c lawn
first things first the DOD was tempered
demand definition we're gonna talk live
in more detail what that means in a bit
but this is how much what what is the
extent to the output image gonna be in
this case it's
are open image is the same size are
input image
thats constant where they're gonna
compute are radius
and then creative ektu which takes us to
the center of the image
and then all we need to do is call self
my kernel apply with extent
DOD and then pass in an array of
arguments which
again you can see the input image match
is the first parameter of our kernel
center of that matches the second
parameter
and radius matches that their brains
that's how we pass parameters from
objective-c land into are colonel
language like
so let's talk a little bit more about
may have definition
oftentimes the meaning definition is
equal to the input image size:
but there are situations when asked not
to be the case so if for example we have
to input images
and we were doing at source over you can
imagine that if
either one of these images didn't have a
0-0 origin
the output image he would want to create
would be larger
and he would want to take the Union over
those two and that we all we need to
think about what
are the non-zero pixels that your
kernels gonna be producing by taking a
given set of
input images and that is what the domain
of definition is
and as a primary you have to always
specify
and that's really I need to know about
how to write color colonels
hi Wes now the talk about work colonels
it's our second subclass RCI colonel
and let you do Juma tree modifications
to an image
so in addition to specifying arlyne
you as an indigent specifying DOD you
also need to specify an hour Weimer
explain what that is in a minute
let's take a look at the workflow
workflow is basically that you getting
input position
and you're asked to produce and you
output position and those are good both
gonna be victims
so let's once again look at the simplest
example which is
a kernel that does nothing just returns
dust court
if we were to apply that colonel to our
input image no change
so we were to look at a random pics on
our image will we need to think about is
in our output image where does that
pixel come from
in our input image not as the equation
we need to come up with
in this case you can see that is just
identity there's no change which is why
we can just returned escort
let's take us like the more interesting
example where
instead of just returning desk or two
we're gonna flip the image around
the center ovett in this case
should be fairly clear but if we look at
a pixel near the shoulder this woman
on the right and the output image the
where we need to read from any input
image is not the same location
instead we're gonna be reading for a
different location the y value won't be
changing
but the x value is different so desk or
dot why is fine desk or Dynex needs to
change
how do we do that well we have an Excel
you discord rx we know what the with the
images we can pass and as a parameter to
our kernel
and using that we can do image with
minus X
in that gives us the location in our
region input image from where we want to
read
and if we do that you can see that
colonel above
mirror axe that's all we need to apply
adjusted escort image with minus X for X
Gordon and return the same value in wine
we getting
in the mirror in effect
so let's take a look at what we need to
do in objective-c
so now instead of cream colour kernel we
create issue I work colonel
we pass along source code we had earlier
and then we call apply and now apply to
see has
one additional primary need to pass
which is an R Y call back
nominee were the next thing we're gonna
do is talk about what is in our I call
back and why do we need to do that for
kernels
and why it's important so
our life stands for regional interest
the basic idea is that
internally car images going to tile your
image and perform
smaller renders such that we can deal
with larger images and do things
optimally on the Jeep you now as I'm
sure you can imagine
what we need to do or producing a
rectangle it's a rectangle five-year
is determined where the data in the
original input image comes from
such that we can load that and we can
figure that out our own
and you need to help us provide provide
that information for us
and you do that by providing an hour why
call back which is the additional primer
that you need to specify
for a walk colonel so in this case
should be fairly obvious if we take our
merit colonel that if we look at the
rectangle on the output image
in the rectangle on the input image that
the weep over the arc our court system
already once again
we can see that the width of the
rectangle is unchanging the height of
the rectangle is unchanging
the origin while the rectangle in
changing but we do have a new origin
so we need to do given an output
rectangle five on the right
we need to figure out where the one on
the left in the input image comes from
is compute
a new rectangle a new origin and that
simply equal to the image with
plus sorry minus the origin
and the with the the rectangle that
we're going to try to render and that is
basically all we need to do for our why
function
so now let's take a look at a little
more detail
are mere colonel now it in this case
rest art of writing a check that I
mentioned earlier we
that CIA images may be a definite extent
and in order to keep the kernel little
sample
arm word we decided to just show you
what looks like a few
are dealing with flipping around the
center the image in this case
it doesn't deal with images that have
infinite extent so we're just gonna
return of
this wouldn't be a difficult market in
to make but 21 for doing a slight
so first things first sight or open
image writer for the american we're
gonna make sure we're not dealing with
an image in infinite extent
where then gonna get a few parameters
that were gonna be reusing
so first thing first we gonna created a
fine
transform that moves are image
to the origin and then
applies that translation
onto the image to create a new output
image within our apply our American on
and once we're done we create a new
translation the news it back to where it
was in our case
we're looking at places like there was
no actual translation but if the image
was 900
we would have had to do that it's
oftentimes easier to think of
a colonel in terms of how would this be
either when its image is centered or
it was 800 and then do the work about
moving the image
I in Objective C Robin is to do it in
the kernel
so let's take a look a slightly more
complicated
colonel so let's pretend you have any
input image or some input video
indecisiveness image was 1024 by 768
but what you really wanted was an image
that was
wider and was a I'm in the
with a 1280 so we can do that with an
anamorphic stretch
and we're gonna do that by maintaining
the center the image in just stretching
it out
further as you get away for the way from
the center
I should be fairly clear that
based on his vector field that
some the vet y values for this car can
change as well Roenicke modifying values
an axe
so we can think about this problem
purely in terms of X values
so let's take a look at libitum af
it helps oftentimes they have in verbal
functions and let's take a look at how
we're gonna
model this problem in our my head so
let's pretend we have an input value X
and some
output value after backs
if we weren't modify and we're gonna
users with respect to the center the
image
all the all these matters can be with
back to senator mitchell gonna go from
minus whatever to do with over two
if we were not to modify the scale this
image of we were taking an input image
size you know 1024 by 768 producing 1024
by 768
we just have identity so slope of one
some input value X I is gonna producing
new same
the same value on the y-axis FFXI
musical tax I but we want instead is
that as
as we get further away from the center
the image we want are points to be moved
more
and we can do that by creating a curve
like this which maintains a slow curve 1
through Center the image
an equation for this is just X over
one minus absolute value of x overcame
talk about
that K content in a moment and this is
the exact same
equation there were gonna used to
compute the DOD your domain a definition
that we spoke about earlier
so now if we take that equation we put a
source values X into it we get a new
destination the UX
which shows how far away we moved
in this case that the equation is really
handy because it's very easy to invert
so for isolate the value back to the
previous equation from source to death
we get a new equation called s to source
a fax which would just be
one over sorry X over one
plus absolute value of X over K
and this is the function that we're
gonna be using interm
internally in our colonel and our WiMAX
because I said earlier you always have
to think in terms of where does this
pixel come from in the
input cell
how we can to K it's relatively simple
matter we just do desired weight on his
case 1280 divided by Amber with 12
1024 we get some scale value became
value was just able to enter with
divided by one
minus one over scale and then if we were
to
plug these values into our equations is
he that source the desktop 1024
we give us $12.80 and s2 source of 1280
would give us
1024 so all the math works out
now what are the kernel look like
relatively simple to get to reuse our
equation we talked about earlier
first things first we're gonna
translated such that were working with
respect to the center
within our player equation and then
translated back and that's all we need
to do to create an amorphous stretch
but we do have to specify R Y function
let's talk about
what in our life function might look
like for this
colonel so if we have an input rectangle
are
we're gonna be asked to produce some new
input rectangle our prime
so for a given rectangle try to render
word as the rectangle in the input image
come from now if you didn't have an
invertible function you can always
return something larger
but that might hurt you if you were
trying to
deal with very large images so it's
helpful to try to get this to be as
often as possible
in this case we have easily readable
function so we're gonna be able to do
this exactly
so let's take a look at the left again
nothing changes in wind so we need to
worry about is
what's happening along the x-axis so we
have our left point which is what are
the original tax
from original input are I'm up a
rectangle we want to find out where r
Prime is we just needed put it to our
equation for destination to source only
get a new left point prime
min if we look at the point at the other
end of our
input rectangle are so which is able to
our dot
origin %ah tax plus the width of the
rectangle work early trying to render
we can put that through our same
equation in getting new
right point prime
should be fairly obvious we have all the
information we need now to produce
the rectangle for our why function
image is going to be computed by
calculating a new with which is equal to
right point prime minus the point prime
and then we just returning new rectangle
which has the left point prime as its
origin
the same origin why that we had for the
input a new with
and the same height not tell you would
provide your R Y
function for this colonel
so let's take a look at how we get to
reuse our
cold once again from our kernel we have
our equation
and if you look at the code here now
we're back in objective-c land
and we got to reuse the exact same math
just
written in C is that have CI's colonel
language
win create a function that just does the
equivalent to what we shown in the
previous slide into a code
and returns a new rectangle given three
input parameters
are input rectangle are a float
center and I'm f load all UK which is
our constant the equation
the may have definition similarly can
reuse the same after we talked about
earlier
and instead of using the odometer
one-plus
absolute value of x-over k we use one -6
over K but it's exactly the same
otherwise
and we can take that same to a coating
applied to
any given input rectangle are to figure
out what the output rectangle
our prime would be that we were
producing given a certain scale
center to now let's take a look at the
output image map it
which is what we used to drive our car
loan
we took a few three-factor 33 contest
ever gonna pass into a colonel in its
oftentimes
good to compute what whatever as much as
we can outside the kernel if it's a
constant and isn't changing on a per
fragment basis
so in this case we have our a value k
then we can compute
in objective-c landed get computer just
wants which is great
and we're gonna compete the center which
also can we can compute outside the
colonel
and then finally the DOD which is what
are the output pixels that we're gonna
backs rendering
and then all we need to do is call a
plywood extent on the kernel that we
created
given id the DOD and now we have in our
why call back
is a book called back that has three
permanent that we passin
Inc wrecked center and K wrecked is
given to us in the case of
8 work colonel index is always gonna be
able to Europe is only one image
we'll talk later about other examples
about how the business little more
complicated
and finally we pass are two parameters
Corps Colonel centering K
and that's all we need to do so
earlier a little more function it's
useful for dealing with you I lamented
that is the
custom attributes method
a custom after his matted let's return a
dictionary
for the whole budget key such as what is
this filter gonna diss what's his
display name
what kinda categories as it applied to
so for example this is a distortion
effect
would apply equally well on video or
still images eccentrics her up
and then for each input parameter you
can talk about
what are its limits in this will help us
automatically put up you I for your
element so if you're using it in the
context of something like
CI fun how's it would be very easy to
just interact with your kernel
sup thats all have to saying
so far about color kernels and more
colonels
let's do a brief over you so in case a
collar colonels
we have 0 or an input images
the input type is going to be an
underscore underscore sample
which is effectively just affect for
the output type: is going to be a vet
for
you do have to specify a domain and
definition audio de
and you do not have to specify a
regional interest function
in the case of a work colonel was only
ever one image the you'll be modifying
you can get to that location near cali
trying to render by calling the function
test corner
which is gonna give you affect you the
output image
is basically just gonna be a pic to
location once again
you have to specify DOD and
a region of interest function
the next thing we're going to talk about
is the more general purpose colonels
which are just see I colonels and they
have the properties listed below
and on that note I'm headed off to tony
has been explained that and a lot more
detail
thank you
thank you Alex good afternoon everyone
my name is Tony
and what I wanna talk what now is the
third and final typeof
colonels car general kernels
so here they're going to the three types
occur knows we supported OS
and what we've seen so far are the first
two color and work
which allow you to implement the
majority of voters with that little cold
as possible
and out a third type car general Carlos
basically complete the set by allowing
you to implement any kind of doctor
so when we did need to rate the general
kernel well it simply whenever you
cannot express Yorker know as either a
color
or a warp one thin air could be that
your car needs multiple samples I love
your input image
so for example any type of player a
convolution filter would be
that colonel and if I concur a second
scenario would be that you colonel
contains a defendant text you read and
by that what I mean is
you have to sample from in image a in
order to you
determine where to sample from image be
and in a moment we'll take a look at a
couple examples that illustrate the fair
use cases
the first let's just go over some basic
principles behind general colonels
if you recall this diagram earlier for
college her nose
this shows that you can have one or more
input image images
your kernel along with an open image but
the key difference here is that
incentive
each input you colonel being just
individual
color sample we actually getting fed is
a sampler object from which you can take
as many samples as you like
and order them however you need so let's
take a look at how you would have to go
about
reading a general kernel so here we have
a very simple kernel that effectively
does nothing
it takes an input image as a sampler
samples from it
and returns the color unaltered but in
order sample from this
input image you have to provide their
corn in it in them for space
and not invest nations face and there
are several reasons why the two faces
are different
want to be your input images pout but at
the very minimum
the sampler spaces in the corner space
that's between their own one
but instead of having a card escort and
sampler transform every single time
you kid also conveniently call another
CR language extension call center court
and d2 pieces over kernel functions are
actually affect me insane
in fact Impala the exact same colonel
program
the name I wonder why would you sell to
transform when you can just call center
court in rate less code
let's imagine have a kernel here that
she does something and
in this case it's just gonna apply a of
set up two pixels in a vertical
direction
and let's walk through what would happen
in this at this kinda weird to be
executed
so say we have an input image here
that's just 600 pixels wide by four
hundred
in your destination space and we're just
gonna render that out to you with the
exact same dimensions
anything to them it's input image not
pilot our sample faces just gonna be
normal in NOLA cornett between with the
range of 0 to 1 in both axes
and let imagine word asked to render out
the specs on the center
which has a value 300 index and 200 why
in the first call to Southlake Wardle
actually transform this tie you over to
South
space interview about 0.5 0.5
and then if you would apply that of that
in that space
you get a value of $0 play five and 2.5
and as you can tell you end up something
from outside the image
and the result you get will be incorrect
instead where you wanna write
is occur know that looks like this so
again let's walk through what would
happen
in this case for the colonel was
executed you gonna for Scott death board
which will give you a value of the 100
and 200
and then you can apply the of that in
that space
and you get a value of 302 002 then you
gonna
cost down to transform with that and
I'll give you a buyout 0.5
and 0.5 05 anything and how this will
give you the correct
location sample from so this is
the right way to apply an offset in your
sample
so now that we got the basics of the way
let's take a look at the examples that
are a little bit more interesting first
one gonna look at
is a motion blur filter and this is an
example where you colonel at requires
multiple samples
so imagine we had an input image like
this and a colonel
we're going to compute the average up
and samples along a bi directional
vector
and in this particular example we're
just gonna play a horizontal
motion blur interview to run this kernel
on all the pics Elizabeth image
you would get a result the looks like
that
let's take a look at what the kernel
function for this would look like
so here we're gonna define our motion
blur turnout
a motion blur and return it back for
it's going to take to our units the
first one is your input image
at the sampler and velocity vector that
would describe that direction in which
you want a blur
and we're gonna arbitrarily defined
number of samples to take
in each direction in this case every 10
but which
but it may be larger depending on what
your Mac Miller radius is
then we're going to declare variable s
to a kingly dollar samples
and we're gonna first guard escort to
get the current destination at the
location a rendering to you
and we're going to slide of that at the
update and improve life for the better
then we're going to loop through
starting with one and the people of the
vector
take ten samples along the way plenty of
that in each iteration
take the center pixel which means which
corresponds to death for
and then take another ten samples on the
other direction
and what you got all your samples
accumulated you just need to average
tomorrow and we
and that will give your final result
so again you would put this all together
with the Seattle to subclass
to initialize that colonel with that we
just saw is costly I Curnow
colonel with string and after the source
that we just that we saw
earlier in the previous slide and that
string could either be hardcoded in your
objectives the file
or loaded from a follow up this
and then you're a fitness function for
this case are filter has two parameters
input radius and an inferred angle from
which you can drive your velocity vector
and then you just call apply on that car
no giving at those arguments
as well as a DOD and region event risk
other functions
which was the in a moment but first
let's take a look at how to cope with
the DOD for the softer
so again here's the input image with a
given extent
and if you were to focus on the pixels
that are just outside the edges that
image these pixels were initially clear
but because
those pixels and up sampling inside the
image
when the filters applied to let you
become non clear pixels
into your domain to definition here is
basically bandito
up in both directions that
is that distance of the velocity vector
in this case this is just the
along the x-direction but for the
general case your
the expression they can use for your DOD
it's just that
similarly for the our ally if you dare
consider
a region that we need to render to
that's all I can
in blue and focus on one at the edges
above the this region and imagine if you
do
you needed to render out that pic so in
a kernel we
sample along the by directional vector
and take and number of samples along
that vector
you end up with the region that you
would need for the input image that
corresponds to the region
red and so again the our ally
call back function would have an
expression that that is in this case the
same as your DOD
and the reason for that is because your
blog I know its metric in all directions
but now that's take the fat one step
further imagine you had
this input image where'd you do not want
applied the motion blur
uniformly across the entire image
instead what you wanted
keep the vehicle understand it's Nathan
Sharpe and blur out the background of
the image
and a topic that you don't wanna apply
the blur
in the same direction tropics those said
you want to learn about radially
to achieve an effect that looks like
this
console when we'd imagine this images
the
camera that anchored to the car at this
traveling for the road and the picture
was snapped and you get a blurry
background
and so in order to this effect what yet
you need is a mask image
that not only masses of the vehicle but
provides a vector field that describes
your perfect so
their velocity slept through the street
on the filter step-by-step to see how we
would implement it
they start with your input image and you
gonna generate a math from that
to Matt got the images the pictures they
do not want later
and then using that emit mask image you
can generate a
vector field that would describe on a
per pixel basis the velocity that you
want to clear your
apply a motion blur and in this case the
velocity vectors are encoded in the red
and green channel for this image
and the pixel that a great basically
represents is there a velocity vector
now you can that's you can generate this
mask image either offline
or you can even write a color current
generate this image
let the scene for the exact as this
example that we already have this mask
image
then you know colonel where you need to
do first is read from this mask image
to get your velocity vector and then
you with sample from your input image
and apply the same motion blur fact that
we had just saw
using that for pics a velocity vector
endeavor to run that colonel
that will give you the resulting image
that we just saw
so let's see how you implement this
kernel function
so here again was the motion blur kernel
that we saw earlier and the nice thing
about the as Colonel language
is you can reuse this function in the
new kernel by converting it into a
helper function
and the function had the exact thing
called that we thought earlier line if
the kernel keyword:
and then you can just layer on top of
that your new kernel function that we
have
call motion blur with math which in this
case were taken input image
as well as a mask image and a parameter
car radio style specify your bachelor
radius
an anchor know the first thing you do is
read from that nafta Mitch
which will contain the back to feel NRG
channels
and because those guys are stored in a
range of zero to one you need to do
normalize it
to range between -1 and positive one
what you got that directional vector you
just multiply that with radius to get a
velocity vector
and then you just past the velocity
vector into that motion blur helper
function
and I would do that calculation for you
and give you the final result
that you what and again you put this all
together with the I thought a subclass
which here is actually very similar to
the first example that we just saw
the difference here the difference here
is the flight a change in the DOD
calculation
where instead of a velocity vector we
have it we just have an interest rather
that basically represents the maximum
velocity vector in your vector field
and the other difference here is when
you apply the Cournot
the are like other function actually
need index parameter and is the first
example where we see that because we
have more than one input images
first take a look at what are like our
battles for that looks like
what such pretty straightforward you
just need to check the index parameter
for which
your for which there are lies being
called for
and it the index is equal to 0 that
corresponds to our input image
and you returned the same expression
that we saw earlier but if the next
in the index is equal to 1 that caused
by three masked image
and for this is that even more simply
just return the same incorrect because
we just take one sample from a mask
image using Southport
and so that maps 121 to the same
location
so as you can see from these two
examples we can implement
any kind of filter using general
colonels the matter how complex they are
and the reason for that is because there
was designed to be a death of Lazcano
type
that had the exact same language syntax
and semantics as those 10
and as a and as a byproduct that you can
actually the port the agenda colonels
back and forth between the
two platforms with very little effort
and in fact I love the new
felt new built-in filters that they've
been mentioned earlier we're actually
ported over to I'll with
using general colonels namely the class
the social filter
and the histogram display filter
thought the great flexibility that
general colonels offer you there are
some
performance American Federation to keep
in mind
with respect to performance one thing
you should be aware of his
in order to get path after object your a
general kernel
we have to render out each input image
to an intermediate buffers
and so effectively each input image to
your
the actor no at the next to render past
your photograph
and because we need to render out
intermedia buffers you may need to
decide what format is most appropriate
for a different situation
in the case of your work in space being
no by your color badge
and is off you can just safely use the a
bit
RGBA format without worrying about any
quantization errors
being introduced in your by image
pipeline but in the case of your working
space being the default DirectSound 09
you can use the default a bit format but
that would require
a conversion from the near to as RGB
space when writing out the intermediate
buffer
and vice versa when reading back from
the internet for
alternatively and this is new in our
state is the ability to specify a 16-bit
Apple format
so you can do that and not and avoid
having to incur the costs the conversion
at everything a pic so but it would
require twice the amount memory
so the right choice will ultimately
depend on what your requirements are
now with these considerations in mind
you should
be careful not to you think that every
type a filter needs
the be implemented with the general
kernel even if it's a complex one
consider for example a square
kaleidoscope
filter which by the way is very similar
to the cloud of smoke filter on the
photo booth
but instead of rigging triangles we just
everything squares
and like so so at first glance you might
think that this filter
would need a general kernel because it
contains both at geometric
transformation
that works the space that you're
something from as well as a
color cuando as well as the color fall
off
and so you cannot represent this colonel
with either a war for a color
colonel so you can use the general
kernel which is fine
but will see in this case that you
actually don't have to
let's see if there's a better way to
implement the
if you to break down this filter in two
stages you notice that the first aid is
just
the geometric transformation
for which you can just supply a worker
no
and then the second stage is the color
fall off or attenuation from the center
and for that you can apply a color
colonel
and so in this example you can see that
you can just came together a war been a
color Curnow
energy and get the same effect and this
is actually the
better way to implement still ther for
some other reason for some of the
advantages that we heard earlier
with using the specialized colonel types
so here the here's the kernel code
kernel function for the worker no
but in in the interest the time-warner
I'm not gonna bother walking through all
the math that's involved in this
but I recommend that you review this on
your own later or even
copy and paste it into your own custom
filter to cancer convince yourself that
it all works correctly
similarly this is the kinda function for
the college girl which you can review at
your leisure
but assuming we have the two kinda
functions re-written let that you take a
look at how you would put them all
together
the you start with the input image and
the first thing is to apply the worker
no
and Avira run that for all the pics
those you would get your intermediate
image
which has the geometric transformation
and for this example the
DOD for the filters actually an infinite
wrecked because
the repeating squares extend out
indefinitely in all directions
and the are like our back porch for
function for this is actually very
simple as just a constant threat
that is defined by this little orange
rectangle
in the intimate into an image
and that's because all the pixels that
need to be rendered just beneath the
sample from that
volatile region and then the next step
is to apply your color colonel
passing at input the result from your
work or no
and the result that you get after
applying that is final result that you
white
and again the DOD for your final result
is internet because to
worker no image was also Internet
so the key takeaway from all this is you
should only write a general kernel
when needed namely that the scenarios we
saw with the motion blur examples
but if you're not sure you can also rate
a general
initially for rapid prototyping but then
you should try replacing it with some
combination up or pink color colonels
to get the for the second better
performance and/or memory usage
and with that I'm gonna head back over
to Alex just this a few hours before we
wrap up
take it
you doing okay so
let's quickly talk about platform
differences
I have some good news there's only one
slide impact
the platform differences they actually
aren't that dramatic
there are some slight differences for
example what kinda renders are supported
also the colonel language NIOS
a mouse control floor so you can
expressed more complicated
things in the language we have three
kinds of classes
to do I kernels on iowa's whereas on
question we have just one you cannot
specify a
samper mode on I was but you can always
filter shape is different it's only a
rectangle on I A West purses /a
filter shape on West Ham pero i Function
the
on iowa's is done via block pointer
whereas on the west end it's done
as a I'm selector
from the filter and then there are some
tiny tiny differences
a CI filter set the faults gets called
automatically on a West whereas on
always 10 you need to do that explicitly
on your own
and then finally the custom attributes
method is a class method on
class method on I O S and as an instant
method instance method
on West End so
let's talk about what we learned today
first things first
we learned how to right color warp
and general purpose kernels
we went through a number of examples
that showed you
how to start thinking about what are the
main definition is for your kernel
and then also how to rate a region of
interest function
and what's great about the way we've
implemented things and I wes is that
you we are gonna force you to write an R
Y
function when you have to and so it's
not
something that you can accidentally
forget to do so
we think that's a great plus mery
function
one thing I would like for you to
remember is that it is really important
for you to do this if you want to get
good performance when dealing with very
large images
and then finally we talked about
platform differences very briefly
time between I O S and West End
some on that note I would like to invite
you all to
you have any additional questions you
can email Allen Schaeffer
we have some resources that DTS
and there's also the their forms which
we all look at
to see if anyone have questions with
core image
there are a few additional sessions
which may be of interest to you if
you're
interested in writing colonels have your
own including the introducing for a
frameworks
I'm which took place earlier today and
david stockman earlier that took place
I'm
just right here we're really looking
forward to
seeing all the effects you are going to
create using
custom kernels and hope you enjoy using
them on I always say
thank you very much once again I hope
you enjoy the rest the conference