good morning everyone my name is Jesse
bunch
I'm an engineer on apples
activity team in today I'm going to be
talking to you about improving the
accessibility
and usability a complex web applications
so my teammates and i have been hard at
work
improving the accessibility of my work
for I clout which is a sophisticated
suite
web applications designed to allow you
to create and edit
your pages documents your number
spreadsheets
and your keynote presentations all
across platforms in all from within your
web browser
well there's still more work to be done
in making them accessible
we found that a lot of the issues that
we were fixing and I work for I clout
are issues that are commonplace in web
applications today
and so we thought it would be really
great to highlight for use in the
specific accessibility challenges
as well as provide practical solutions
to these challenges
and give you tips on how you may be able
to avoid them altogether so today we're
going
to cover accessibility at a fundamental
level we're going to cover the latest
research in statistics regarding users
with disabilities
and they were going to cover web
accessibility standards
as well as some of the tools you can use
to help meet those standards
and finally we're going to apply
everything we've learned
to help diagnose and fix some
accessibility issues in a text editing
application that I've created
now even show you something new
accessibility debugging tools
found in the Safari note inspector
interest in Yosemite so let's get
started
this is the 1992 version the very first
website
it's still on the Internet today it's
just the page for data and links
they go out to other pages for data and
links and it was revolutionary in its
time
and while it was revolutionary it was
also very simple
in fact the argument can be made that
this website
was accessible by default after all it's
just text based
content and rather trivial to
disseminate surely text-based content
to screen reader but if you fast forward
to when applications today
modern web applications sometimes use
completely custom controls
they have real time content and data
communal the page
they used a these charts and graphs and
most in this content was initially
designed
was only the mouse user in mind but what
if you don't prefer
using a mouse what if you can't use a
mouse
due to some dexterity issue in your
hands well in fact millions of people
every day use accessible web
applications some love them
with only a single switch using switch
control software this lady control an
entire I less device
as well as your assist accessible web
applications
using only the single switch that's
mounted by her forehead absolutely
incredible
and accessibility is a broad field
that means different things to different
people but in short
accessibility is about supporting real
people with real needs
whatever those needs maybe and sometimes
we do that by providing an alternate
interaction model
such as a keyboard or switch control
it's more appropriate given the user
specific needs
and as web engineers it is our most
basic duty
to make sure that our web applications
work well with assistive technology
that's true and we do that by handling
the right
a JavaScript events by adding the right
mark up in our code
but what if we took it a step further
what if we design our applications
so thoughtfully that they would be
usable by everyone
regardless of whether or not they had a
disability the term universal design
deals with the specifically in the
quintessential example
universal design is the curb cut is now
required by law
and its crucial for someone who needs a
wheelchair for mobility
but it is just as useful for someone who
is pushing a stroller down the street
or movers moving you into your new
apartment another great example
universal design is closed captioning
here we have a baseball game
and the announcers talking about this
guy swing which looks beautiful by the
way
and we're using closed captioning to
provide a text based alternative for the
audio track in this movie
this is absolutely vital for someone who
is hearing impaired or death
but it is just as useful in an airport
or doctor's office
or somewhere else where sounds to be
regulated and therefore they may not
have
idea playing
for web applications a great example a
universal design
is for keyword access this is the idea
that your application should be usable
using only the keyboard if we take a
look at the pages for I cloud user
interface
you'll see that when the user hits the
Tab key focus is gonna go
to the button at the top of the page
this is in popup I'm
and you know this because in the blue
outline that appeared over the butt
and I've highlighted that with that box
now keyboard users expect to be able to
you select the button
using the space bar sometimes the Return
key so if the user hits the spacebar to
activate this button
you see that the menu is activated just
as if they had clicked it was a mouse
then we can navigate the menu with the
rockies and go down to the seventy-five
percent zoom level
and we get the seventy five persons in
level a keyword user expect to be able
to press the spacebar to activate and
select that menu item
and so when they do that you see that
the menu goes away just as if they had
clicked that with the mouse
and with the zoom level the page
obviously changes
and then use notice: an important detail
that we set the keyboard focus back to
the button to open the menu
this more detail is very important for
keyboard users to be able to save the
context where they were at
prior some interactive element popping
up on screen
in being able to interact with the user
interface a page %uh strike lot in this
way
is absolutely crucial for someone who
has a dexterity issue in their hands and
therefore they cannot use a mouse
but it is just as important for someone
who has a lot of document editing to do
in perhaps a short amount of time and
they want to be as efficient as possible
what we're mostly focused on the human
aspect accessibility
is worth mentioning that applying the
principles universal design
and making your web applications
accessible will make them easier to
automate
in automation has numerous benefits for
you and your organization
it for more information about automation
and how it relates to accessibility
I've included a link to previous years
talk at the into this presentation
so as you saw from the previous examples
the reasons for making your web
application accessible are not limited
to simply caring for those with
disabilities
rather all users can benefit from the
work that you do in this area
but for the purposes of this talk in our
topic and whether aP's
we're going to be focusing specifically
on users with visual impairments
that may or may not be able to use our
applications without some sort of
assistive technology such as a screen
reader
or braille device in fact that user base
is no small figure
$285 million people across the world
are visually impaired worldwide such
thing such that they cannot read
some or all the given content every
given web page
now that $285 million people forty
million people across the world are
completely blind
and therefore require the use of a
screen reader braille device
to be able to benefit from your web
application
so for more than 40 million people
around the world
accessibility is not just a nice to have
feature
it is a vital part of their lives and
for some
it is a prerequisite from being able to
benefit from your application
or the hard work the UN your team to put
into it
so now that I've hopefully sold you on
the idea of making your application
accessible
let's talk about some other web
standards that are out there to help you
along the way
and specifically I want to talk about
the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines
abbreviated work act for short
now the work at document is quite
lengthy but for the purposes of this
talk we can boil it down to four basic
principles
which are perceivable operable
understandable and robust and we're
gonna go through the for these
in more detail starting with perceivable
receivable basically means do I know it
is there
in this we're going back to the closed
captioning example in this
example we have you know some text-based
content that is
an alternative for the audio track and
in a movie
in this is just one example in fact
having tech space descriptions for non
textual content
is one of the most common accessibility
issues on the web today
specifically for web applications
because we like to use buttons with
beautiful icons
and we oftentimes forget to add the
labels for these buttons into the markup
operable means can I use it
this goes back to a4 key word access
example simply put
if you can navigate to an element with
the mouse and perform some action on
that element with the mouse
you should be able to get to that
element and perform the very same action
using a keyboard alone
now this can be tricky at times
especially if you're using custom
controls
but we're going to discuss a common
approach in a demo later on
you can take back in using your own web
applications
understandable should be fairly obvious
does your webs does your website's
content makes sense
does it perform in predictable ways
example if this would be a segmented
arco control
such as the one found in the keynote for
I clout the end-user
now this control might be perceived one
operable to a screen reader user
but unless it's marked up correctly the
user when they land on this control
might hear something like this
standard why so voice over on the Mac
said standard
wide that doesn't tell them all the
information they decided user sees
in that there are two buttons on this
page they are mutually exclusive
and one of them is selected instead a
better experience would be to mark up
this element in such a way
that the user hear something like this
instead
standard selected tap 12 wine tapped
into
so again voice-over said selected
standard selected tab
one of two wide tab to have to
which tells the user everything at the
site the user sees when they look at
this control
is a much better experience for
voiceover user
now robust as a bit more complicated and
we can really divided up into two
different parts
the first part of your bust is simply
making sure that your market is semantic
incorrect
such that it is displayed correctly
across user agents
and is more resilient to the changing
technology around it
the second part iv: robust is having
alternatives for the presentation of
your content
so a good example of this would be i
clad in general but let's look at
specifically pages for I clout if you're
editing a document pages
in you discover a bug that prevents you
from being able to access your content
you can simply open this document in
either the OS 10
or the IRS applications in use the
built-in accessibility support their
another great example having robust
content would be
exporting data for some sort of feed
like RSS are at a
in this allows the user to use any
number accessible applications to be
able to consume your content
and in other words no one bugger issues
she completely prevent users from being
able to access your content
not worth mentioning that having robust
content is not mutually exclusive with
having accessible content
they're meant to complement each other
and give your users options
should they encounter issues
so as we just saw your content should be
perceive a below
operable understandable and robust now I
want to get a bit more tactical
and talk about some other ways you
actually accomplish these things
starting with semantic markup
so using semantic markup is one of the
first things you can do to help improve
your web applications accessibility
here are two screenshots the very same
webpage
the screenshot on the left was
implemented using only div tags for the
headings that you see on the screen
the screenshot on the right was
implemented using semantic h1 tags:
for the headings that you see on the
screen now
two-sided user these two web pages are
going to look and perform an identical
ways
in fact the site to users not going to
be able to know it all that they were
implemented
one way or the other but your user
assistive technology
these two pages are going to appear into
going to perform in completely different
ways
in to find out why let's take a look at
the market behind the scenes
as I said the image on the left was
implemented using only added tax in fact
the style was actually in line in the
tag itself
now and assistive technology is are
specifically a screen reader user
is going to hear this when they land on
this heading
all about which is so voice-over said
all about widgets
and you could argue yeah so they got the
content that heading
but there's really no semantic
information that is conveyed here
were specially not conveying the same
information they decided user sees
in that this is a heading in fact it's
one of the most prominent
headings on the page so this is
obviously not the best experience for
the user
instead if we were to use semantic h1
tag
the user using a screen reader will hear
this instead
had a little one all about which is so
voice-over said heading level 1
all about widgets that conveys way more
information to the user
and is obviously exactly with the site
the user sees so this is a much better
experience
it's also worth noting that screeners
oftentimes allow a user to navigate the
page heading by heading
and so using a semantic h1 tag allows
them to quickly find their contact
especially on long pages and so that's
also a better experience for user
now next up is using standard controls
and using standard controls wherever
possible will not only make the
experience better
for users of assistive technology
because the controls will be more
consistent with what they're used to in
their system
but it also saves you a lot work in
making and usable
and accessible say for instance you want
to create a custom slider
misses the mark up that you might
actually years and with some CSS magic
that might be the actual look at the
control
now let's say you wanted to make this
control work with the mouse so
you would have to handle several mouse
events in order to make that happen
and mouse down to be able to start
tracking the mouse now to move to update
a controlling ass and
to finally commit that value back
tomorrow now let's say you want to make
it work with the touch device
so in that case you have to handle
similar methods
except you have this added complexity
that a touch can be cancelled if you
drag it
of the screen or up to the browser
Chrome and so you have to account for
that
you can begin to understand or think
about the kinder state machine you're
gonna need to be able to keep track of
this control
now so that's the mouse and thats touch
devices but let's say you want to make
this work with the keyboard as you
should
so let's grow everything up and let's
implement our keyword methods
we're gonna handle focus so that we can
updated visual style of the control
when the when the control gains keyboard
focus to show the user that they can
begin interacting with it
then we have to handle blur so we can
remove that visual style one focus goes
elsewhere
and then we have to handle key down so
that we can respond to a Rockies
home and page up page down all the
different key combinations
that a user the keyboard would expect to
be able to modify the value that's
lighter
this is a lot of work and you should
avoid it wherever you can
by using standard controls example here
would be using a native input range
control
giving a minimum and a maximum value as
well as the current value
if you do this the browser is going to
handle everything for you from mouse
events to touch events keyboard
its gonna handle state tracking observer
notification
and you're gonna get accessibility out
of the box see you literally have to do
nothing else to make this control work
if you just use a standard control but
you and I both know that HTML controls
can be difficult to style
I mean they're getting better but
they're still not quite there
and so if you couple that fact with a
really great designer who just handed
you a really beautiful visual spectra
slider
you're probably going to have to roll
your own and so let's go back to our
custom slider control and talk about how
you can make it
more accessible so this is the market
that we used to implement these
JavaScript advance
I'm but you'll be you may be surprised
to know that this control is absolutely
an accessible for someone who is using a
screen reader braille device
after all there's nothing in this market
that tells the user
this is a slider at all much less its
current state
with a minimum and maximum value as well
as a current value
and what's worse is that hTML doesn't
really give us
any ability to be able to to tell the
user this information
so we need something else and that's
where aria comes in
Aria stands for accessible rich Internet
applications
and it was specifically designed to help
bridge this gap between
HTML in assistive technology by defining
additional properties
that allow us to describe what an
element is as well as its current state
so going back to our custom slider Aria
allows us to give this div tag
a role a slider now it's worth
mentioning that
Aria defines over 50 different roles the
you can give an any
in many different situations in your
markup but for this one we're going to
use lighter
and for any given role Aria also
specifies a list
a properties and attributes that you can
use to describe what the control is as
well as its current state
so in the case in a slider we need to
tell the user about the minimum value in
the maximum value
using re-evaluate man and re-evaluate
backs respectively
we also need to tell the user with the
current value is so we'll add
re-evaluate now
it's worth mentioning that what we had
to handle all the JavaScript immense
manually
we also have to handle updating
re-evaluate now
when the sliders value changes so that
yet another thing that you have to keep
track I have
if you're using custom controls but Aria
has now allowed us
to give the semantic equivalence a
slider using
just a little bit more markup
now aria is not just for creating custom
controls
you can also use it to retrofit old
content without actually having to got
it
to going back to our headings example
let's say that it was too risky for you
to be able to change
your code to spit out in h1 tag instead
a div tag
in that case we can apply an aria role
heading
as well as re: a-level 1 to be able to
give this
tagged the semantic equivalence h1 as
far as assistive technology is concerned
obviously for other reasons it would be
better for us to use in h1 tag
but this gives you an option should that
not be possible
conversely let's say that you were using
h1 tag and
for whatever reason this is not a
heading which issues for styling or
whatever else you might use it for
Aria has this idea and implicit roles
and so in h1 tag would automatically get
a row love heading in an aria level a1
see you wouldn't need to specify in that
case
but if you are using h1 tag for you
didn't want to convey that semantic
meaning
you can give it a role a presentation
which would allow
which would basically strip all the
semantic information away from this tag
from assistive technology and give it
the equivalent to being just a plain
give tech
so that can be useful in times
next up is focused management now re:
allows you to mark up your content to
people perceive a ball and
understandable
well keyword accessibility is important
to make inoperable
but another important aspect and
operability is focused management
and if you're using custom controls like
interactive elements and menus
you're going to need to handle the focus
management portion yourself
and you do that using tab index
so HTML tab index property controls
are basically allows you to specify
which elements can gain keyboard focus
either by the user tap into it with the
keyboard or manually using javascript
in a tab index 0 means that an element
tab index 0 means that an element is
focusable with JavaScript
and it is in the default tab order
another words a user can get to it
simply by tapping to it with the keyword
a tab indexes -1 means that an element
is focusable a javascript
but it is not in the default tab order
in other words these are can't get to it
simply by tapping to it and finally
leaving tab index of your control will
mean that the element is not going to
get keyboard focus
either by calling focus on it with
JavaScript
or by these are tap into it with the
keyboard in fact some older user agents
were actually throw javascript error if
you try to call focus on an element
it is not focus upon as a big asterisk
there because native controls like links
in buttons in form elements all get an
implicit tab index
0 in so you don't need to specify it for
this kinda controls
now for example how to use tab index
properly
to achieve great focus management let's
look into it a common set up in web
applications
where you have some focus more content
at the top of the page
then you have a list of items and you
have some focus upon content at the
bottom of the page
now if the user hits the Tab key on this
page you can see the focus is gonna go
to the link at the top
because as you remember it has a tab
indexes 0
in the tab order follows the DOM order
and so this is the first element in the
DOM
with a tad index 0 if they hit the Tab
key again
focus will go to the link at the bottom
and this is because none of the menu
items have a tab index
inner just plain yes
now let's say you want to make these
menu items I accessible with the
keyboard
you can simply add a tab indexes 02 each
one of these menu items
but you can imagine it this mean you
were quite long it would be very
frustrating for the user to have to tap
through each and every item in the menu
to get to the focus on our content at
the bottom so a better experience
would be only expose the currently
selected item
in the tab order we do that by giving
every other element
a tab and exit -1 so now the behavior is
like this
if the user hits the Tab key focus is
gonna go to the first element in the DOM
that has a tab index 0
then it's going to go to the next
element in the DOMA has a tab index 0
in this case it's going to be the first
it's gonna be the selected item
analysts and then if they navigate this
list using a Rockies
you can see that we are moving tab index
0 to the currently selected item each
time
and making sure that all the non
selected items have a tattered exit -1
this is called the roaming tab index
technique
now if the user hits the tacky they're
going to leave the last
inskeep over all the elements for the
tab index -1
in go to the next element that has a tab
index 0 which is the link at the bottom
of the page
this has the added benefit of saving the
user-selected state
so if they were to shift abt from this
link at the bottom
they would go directly back to the
currently selected menu item in the list
which is a really great experience for
keyword users now
they only have to hit tab twice to get
all the way to the bottom of the page to
find
what they're looking for
so to recapture that we talked about how
content should be personable
operable understandable and robust
and we talked about how using semantic
markup in standard controls will get us
most of the way there
we also talk about how you you can use
Aria to fill the gaps
and make our custom controls and all
content more accessible an
understandable
we talked about how to use proper focus
management and key works s ability
to really clean up the user experience
but now we're going to apply all that
knowledge to diagnose and fix
several accessibility issues and
usability issues
in a text editing application that I
don't for the stock
so here we have a text editor that I
created
and if you look at it and click and
click around
with the mouse you can see that we can
zoom this is very similar to the
pages for I cloud user interface that we
looked at earlier I'm we can also
going here and we can add text we can
remove taxed
so to a mouse user interests visual user
this thing works
and you wouldn't even know that it is
completely inaccessible
now when you approach an application and
you start to look at how to make it
accessible
I like two divided up into two different
parts the first part is the keyboard
accessibility part
get it working with the keyboard alone
and then you can turn on the screen
reader
and start looking at something more
finer points for users who cannot see
the page
so to begin testing us with the keyboard
we simply to start hitting a tab key and
see what happens
you can see that I'm getting the Tab key
repeatedly
ants you just see that Safari address
bar is getting focus nothing on the page
is actually changing
and that's because none of these
elements are
are really interactive and none of them
have a tab index at because
if we look at the markup you can see
that the buttons I have here are just
made with
standard if tax and standard attacks
don't have an implicit tab index like
interactive elements
so to get these buttons working with
the keyboard we need to just add a tab
indexes 02 each one of those
so let me go ahead and just add that to
these buttons
see can see that as in Papa but now has
a tab index 0
and the Save button next to it has a
tattered exit 0
and so now if we say then we go back to
our application
and we refresh you can see now that this
improper button has this blue outline
at the top and so we know that this
thing has keyboard focus
but this blue outline is also applied
when you simply just click on
any these buttons and you can see that
it kinda looks weird and so R Q eighteen
and our designers are getting upset with
us because they want to remove this blue
outline because it doesn't look very
good
well removing a blue outline we get us
right back where we started
where these controls are not accessible
with the keyboard at all because the
keyword user we'll never know that they
have focus
and therefore they'll never know that to
be able to interact with them
into a better experience would be rather
than removing the blue outline which is
default on a system
what style it to make it look a little
bit better and so if we're
jump over to our CSS which is right
here this is the CSS for a pop up button
and let me just add in a little bit of
code
to style that CSS
so here I've added a focus
a selector to the button and I'm
removing the default outline
without line 9 so that gets rid of the
blue outline
that they hated and then I'm adding
bordercolor to the
to the button itself which makes it look
a little bit better so if we say that
and we go back to our apt and we hit the
Tab key
you see now that we have this really
beautiful blue outline on the button
in our designers and I Q a team is happy
anarchy where users are happy
so the next thing you wanna start doing
is looking at whether or not we can
actually
activate these controls at the keyboard
so far press the spacebar
I would expect that the many would come
up just as it did when we clicked it
and alas there is no man you coming up
so what we need to do
is we need to actually go back to the
JavaScript in add some very basic
keyboard handlers to be able to tap into
the same cody gets run when the user
clicks on it with the mouse
source do that now peretz we jumped over
to
are JavaScript for a pop up button and
I've separated this code out
I am so that we have kind of a clean
slate for working with the keyboard am
going to add
some additional handlers here
that basically just handle a key down on
the button
and then we check to see whether or not
the event is a
kiko 232 or 13 which is the space bar or
the Return key
and then when that happens we just call
the open method that
is the same method that is called when
the mouse click is registered
and so we're just tapping into the main
code we haven't had a really right
anything extra for this
rights every saving go back to the menu
with TAB key and now we want to hit the
spacebar to activate the menu
and you see the menu comes up so we're
we're getting there next we should be
able to navigate this menu with the
an arrow keys and I'm pressing them and
nothing's happening
so this is where we're going to have to
write a little bit extra code to change
the focus at the menu
as the user uses the rockies so
let's go back there and was just build
on this right here
and add some additional keyword handlers
to the menu
for focusing the next and previous item
says you can see here we're handling a
key down
and were checking the key code for a
downer or an affair
and when we get a downer or not there
were simply going to focus the next to
the previous item
and so let's jump over that currency
with that does
so focus next item just gets the
currently focused item
and if there isn't one focus that gets
the first item a cause I am
focus on item with the next I tend to
focus on the list
itself we look at that method you can
see that we're setting the tab index -1
and we're just calling focus on this
with JavaScript now
as you can remember from our talk about
tab index
calling focus on an element that is not
focus a ble I E
18 you know a are a normal div tag which
doesn't get an implicit avonex
could cause issues an order clients and
so we want to be sure that we have a tab
index set for this element before week
of focus
sore setting it to -1 and you might be
asking why not set it to 0
well if we set it to 0 as the user
navigates this list
those elements are going to be put into
the default tab order which
isn't what we want we want the user to
be able to navigate the list with the
iraqis
in if they were hit the Tab key we want
focus to jump away from the menu to the
next button in the toolbar
and so that's where we're using -1 here
to keep them out of the tab order
in let's just focus to manually with
JavaScript
so if we say that injured back to the
menu
and hit space bar so now you can see
that the currently selected item
is automatically focused when we open
the menu which is a good experience for
our users
then we can navigate this list using the
arrow keys and then
try to select an element with the space
bar and that doesn't work either so we
need a
again goin' hook into the main code to
select this menu item
but I wanted to show you quickly what
happens every press the Tab key from
here
every press the Tab key the menu goes
away and focus has returned
to the next item in the menu that's why
we set tab index -1
are so let's go back to menu and let's
get this working
with the space bar
okay so I'm gonna do is go back up to
you are
switch statement here that handles are
key down and we're gonna have additional
handlers
for both the space bar in the Return key
as well as the ex
escape key to be able to close the menu
okay so actually we we did not handle
the escape guarantee that
next so we've added space bar in return
32 in 13 in all we're doing is we're
selecting the currently focused
item so that just gets the currently
focused item in any calls the Select
code that we have from
the same code that the user uses with
the mouse
so we can go back to menu
yet we first page and then as we go to
say 75 prisons in a meeting hit the
spacebar and see that that works
but we're keyboard focus go the menu
went away
but there's nothing highlighted on the
page there's no insertion point
in the actual editor itself so in this
case we have no idea what he would focus
when did it probably went to the body is
the page
which is a very useful so the keyword
user if they want to change the zoom
level again
we have to tab back to that mean you
and then activated again in again keep
our focus is lost
as you can remember it's a much better
experience for us to you
focus the element that open the menu
after the menu goes away and so that's
going to be very simple
we're just going to add that code and
we're gonna go in
and when the Escape key is pressed we're
going to focus the button
that open the menu and we're gonna close
the menu
similarly when I am enter or return
is pressed we select the currently
focused item we're going to focus the
button to open the menu
in close the menu so very simple stuff
but it really improves the usability for
this code
going back to Safari we go to the menu
we select 50 percent and you can see
that the zoom pop up button is selected
now in the menu goes away
really great usability and now the you
can quickly change all the same levels
just by a couple a keyboard presses so
that's really nice
okay so now we've made this is in Papa
button
completely accessible which is really
great up for a keyboard user
but now we want to scan a switch over
and start talking about screen readers
in making sure that someone who can see
this page is able to interact with these
elements correctly
so the way I'm gonna do that isn't going
to turn on voice over in just are kinda
navigating the page
and seeing what I hear so I'm a turn-on
voice-over on your Mac
with commander 5
here you know okay so whatever came on
and told us that we are on the editor
HTML content
now we can kinda navigate through this
page in kinda see what's going on
I'm to quickly jump over to the gym but
and interact with tens to into 50
percent
clickable okay so we got to the Zoom
button and voice-over said
50 percent clickable now that does tell
us what the content is it that
particular death
and it tells us they can do something
with it but it doesn't really give them
any information about what this button
is really what it does
we want instead tell the user that this
is this is in pop up but
give its current value and let them know
that in when they
click on this button when i activate
this button that they're gonna get a
menu
and so left her a voice over and let's
go at some Aria attributes to this div
tag
to convey this information to the user
was overall
switching back to Xcode I'm going to go
back to our markup
and I'm going to add just a few re:
attributes to the markup
to be able to tell these are a little
bit more about this control so
as recovered earlier you can add a role
image added the role but
and we've also added the Aria property
has pop up people true
and what that tells the user is that
when they activate this button
a pop-up menus gonna come up and so they
can know that there's something else
that they can interact with
similarly for the Save button I've just
added a role but
that's really all we need to do because
the label is is pure text inside the div
tag
and so voice-overs gonna get that
automatically
right so if we jump over to Safari
and refresh the page we turn on was over
so far 100 percent pop
okay so voice-over said 100 percent pop
up button
and thats a lot better but we're still
not getting the actual
I we're not worse not telling them that
this is a zoom pop up button
so we're going to add some Aria labels
to the cinema show you how to add Aria
label
along with the current value the control
to make this control really
usable for a voice-over user we saw
okay so what at Aria label to the
control
and if we go back into here so here's
the JavaScript actually handle selection
and so we added this method called
sinking value
which basically what it does is when the
the selection changes for this menu
it finds out what the currently selected
zoom level is and then it modifies the
mark up to show the current zoom level
and we've hooked into that too also
update Aria label attribute here
and what we're doing is we're just a
pending the air pretending the value
along with a a localized string apps im
and that allows us to tell the boys are
using a lot more information about this
control
so click back over his fiery Jenna Bush
Hager was over on
so 100 percent soup okay so that tells
the user everything you need to know
about this control
now if we activated control you are
currently a problem
notice voice-over doesn't tell us
anything about this menu 50 percent
zoom problem but when the menus value
changes
we do get the updated value so the next
thing we want to do is make this many
more accessible for voiceover
Boys Over Law so we flew back over to
the markup
you can see that the menu is implemented
using only div tags
which is typically how you would use a
menu and so all we want to do is add
some Aria
mark up to this menu to get it usable
voice-over
so we added to the menu a row love menu
and then for each other items we at
Roland menu item radio
which tells the user that they can only
select one of these menu items at a time
there similarly there you know you can
use a menu item if there are multiple
things you can select you can use check
states that kinda thing
but for this purpose we're only going to
use menu item radio
in there were gonna at Aria checked it
was true for the currently selected menu
item
and again we're gonna update this as the
selection changes
alright so what's jump back to the menu
and see how this changes things
was over on so far 100 percent soon
problem
so that works out great one check 100
percent check
check mark 100 ok it's a voice overs
telling us that we're on the one hundred
percent menu item
that there are 5 items and that this one
they were currently on a selected
now if we navigate to say 75 percent 75
percent magnified
tell us that there are 5 items on the
menu and they were on 75 percent
50 said one check mark 100 percent
check okay grade 5 percent 75 percent
soup
so we selected 75 percent we just want
to go back into the menu and make sure
that the selection stay
was updated one check mark 75 percent
check 50 percent 50 overs one check mark
75 percent
check check great so this menu is now
completely accessible voice-over which
is really really great
okay so as you saw from the demo using
just a little bit of extra HTML markup
and tapping into our existing JavaScript
code in handling a few keyboard events
we were able to really improve the user
experience our text editing application
we were able to make it fully accessible
using a screen reader
in this case voice over on the Mac
so to begin wrapping up I'd like to
reemphasize for the most important
points at this talk
you should strive to make your content
perceivable
operable understandable and robust
using standard controls and semantic
markup wherever possible will make this
a lot
easier but you can use Aria to fill the
gaps
were aged email doesn't provide you
enough control
in finally gesture applications with the
keyboard
all mouse interaction should be able to
be duplicated with the keyboard alone
in fire up a screen reader in really
thoroughly test your application
in be asking yourself if I can't see it
does this really make sense
in my really getting all the information
it's here that aside user sees
and then use Aria to kinda fill in those
gaps and
make your user experience a lot better
for more information you can talk you
can contact check their answers are
everywhere to banja list
I've included links to the Web Content
Accessibility Guidelines
as well as the Aria documentation so you
can learn all about roles in properties
and also included a link to the talk
today promised you about using
accessibility and automation
and of course you can always reach out
to us to the Apple Developer forms
in case you want a little bit more
information these talks
I would highly recommend you check out
the videos accessible yet last 10
I O S in the more information about the
web inspector in modern javaScript can
be found
in a talk on Thursday thank you guys so
much for listening I hope you have a
wonderful day
and safe travels safe travels back home
thank you