good morning everyone a
p some hard for when people hear
specially on
you know the morning after the beer bash
know you're all hardware
I'm welcome to the designing responsive
web experiences
session my name is Casey and Ted
and today we're gonna show you how you
can build one website
that's gonna look great everywhere I'm
by the way
anytime if a website during that session
we mean
any wet media I'm on the iBooks team and
on the web gettin
I we want both your digital books and
your website
to a great everywhere so we don't have
to tell you that
your website is being viewed on a whole
variety different devices and screen cut
what we can do though is teach you some
really easy techniques that you can use
to ensure that your website looks great
on all
I would be very clear it up
what we are not going to talk about
today
is building multiple versions region
these devices back today fashion
it in the antithesis I'll the mobile
specific site
there will be no iNDOT domain name
here so instead arnold one website looks
great on out
an effect that had the design
they can adapt and adjust always look
good on all
all these different devices is usually
referred to
as a website that has a response and
design
responding design
it just just a buzzword it just means
that your website
its sensitive to its environment which
will allow it to adapt
in change just simply always look good
and so did a 10 denier gonna show you
not only what a simple
idea a responsive design is but really
how simple it is to implement
we're gonna look
at response a cock columns are really
great way to both at them
visual interest your website is well as
improve the legibility oversight will
also teach you about
on trial 2 units and how you can use
them to make sure that your layout
has been Belletti every font size and
intense going to show you how you can
use the S shake
to rap text around images I will make
sure that those
images are ready ready and for the
up larger design changes that we need to
make will use media queries
and finally the finishing touch will be
hairlines
we can really dive indeed and make you
so those beautiful red
so why are we talking about this anyway
no when he does a really great job
making sure
that your website looks just as great
on the iPhone as it does on the desktop
it just shrinks your site down
and makes a bit on the phone screen and
then the user can double tap or pinch to
zoom in to make sure
that they can be that text the text
becomes larger that and it looks great
notta lotta work Fri and when he does
the same thing
for more complex sites like this one
that had an i mean just shrinks all that
formatting and layout down
into one screen and it feels great right
can you read that text
barely at all not really in any
mobile designers our website designers
have looked at this in fed
I can't have that I'm gonna have to make
a mobile specific site
you know we get you want your website to
look great
you want to be clear and easy to read
without users having two double tap
and pensions zoom and pan around and
something you may be thinking well
of course it doesn't look great you need
to add a medic you portray
another great first step medically
imports gonna make your text larger
relation to the screen size but the
thing is is that your layout
still all Tinian shrunk down so now
you've got these big words
and shrunk down layout and it just that
what's up
right so lest you think
okay casey you know really we're gonna
have to make a mobile specific site now
please keep in mind that we're not
building web sites for just
the iPhone the iPad the desktop
and to prove it if your look at our
website
on the desktop looks great right we
designed it
we designed for this window size
basically but a I
shrink down the window who
I've got the thing problem here that I
do on the phone
so we need to make sure that we're
building a site that looks great
no matter what our windows so so far
I've laid out
just a whole lotta knows I said I we
can't make mobile specific site
I'm using a medical report isn't going
to get you on the way there
and you have to build a website that
works for
everything all possible permutation on
the desktop so
what can we do well done
our goal here is to use some simple as
hard as I and techniques
and seems like the best way to
foreigners just to identify
specific problems that we're seeing
right now
and has worked to the one-time sounds
good I mean the first one is obvious to
me is that
masthead atop become so tall
on the phone and I have to scroll to see
the content
and the other thing is is those columns
are just really skinny like
so it's completely legible and that
caption on our galaxy is blowing right
out of the image in
covering earns taxer yeah it's pretty
horrible where do you think we should
start
I think we're sorry the columns as the
protection of
okay but certainly cock I personally
really like all
I it love that they add both the visual
interest to my website
and that they improve the legibility
it's really the perfect combination of
form and function
and columns are great for this because
they're able to
I divide up big blocks attack
into more legible choc so what I we
might have had a big block a really long
line for tax I'm now able to have very
consumable
side ray now the problem we ran into
with our website and why those homes
weren't looking good
is because we define set number
up call that had to be there for every
screen size
right so when our window shot down those
homes had to be calm really narrow
and we were only able to have a few
words per line
soda make your columns responsive
all we have to do is instead a defining
a column count
where set number of columns on our page
we just to find the conduit
so to give you an example of this I have
to web page is here
a simplified a where one has the comms
defining column with
one has the comp to find the compound by
car like to add to my site
now when I resize that window
re says that window I the column
though the page that we define the
column with that
we have to call maintained that legible
with
whereas the column count had a shrink
down like we saw before
so responder homes really great
defining the column with is really great
because WebKit will automatically
add or eliminate columns as room becomes
available
hours removed and we recommend when you
are defining
%uh your column with that you use a
bond relative unit final two minutes
really great because
if your user resizes their tax the
columns with what of the resize
to match that to give you a simplified
example
here we have the alphabet right there's
letters on that first line in the first
column
ABCD any now because my columns with is
to find
and a pot relative unit when I make my
text smaller
I will maintain those five letters
across the top and the same thing goes
with the number words on your call will
maintain a legible bring
word so all this
great functionality in these responses
Kong's it seems like you're getting a
lot here right
it's just one CSS property you just to
calm with
to find home with and define it with the
bottle to unit in this case for using
15 min so to show you
how great columns are in real time
here's had the demo
okay thanks KC here we are so here's
this
website the case in adults and looking
pretty great at this
that's really fast at this window with
but as you saw when we make it 1 an hour
the column seconding harder harder to
read
and to the point we had hearings just
very logical so if they can sit in the
corner I have a little bit a javascript
showing me
what the window with this so I can make
adjustments as necessary
sup has cases suggested let's try
setting at home with incentive our
compound so and this code you can see I
have
the compound 3 skill that's
i sat with said in a calm with 215
around like a suggested
save that hillard
and nothing's changed are when they're
with the still wide enough to
accommodate three columns like we had
before
at this time as we get more now
will have a point but see her happens
right okay here
around 1100 pixels without that two
columns
still really logical and again as we get
even smaller
we're at a point around seven hundred
and
somewhat pixels where we go doubt one
call which
even at Nara sweater with still a very
logical
amount of tax I mean we're not on that
side bar stool is terrible
but that's really all I have to do to
get
support on Scarlett just single property
was done a little bit more into
the features a the Caesars columns
call model okay
so you seen the column counts and call
with properties
which are pretty straightforward when
you are
laying out a page with columns it's best
to has a white space between the columns
if you don't the lines can run together
be really hard to read
and this is controlled with the conga
property
are you might wanna decorative line
inside the cap you can
to find such lot with the car real
property whose syntax is just like the
border properties are you seeing already
and finally if you'd like an element to
pop out your columns
span across the aisle I you can easily
do this with the can span property
which looks really great
so to sum up making response columns and
adjust
two different fireman is super easy I'm
sees as get you a lot of that free
by isn't home with property
I want to expand a bit though on why
we chose to use Farrell to the unit
there
farrell to the units are exactly what
the sound like they're
CSS units that are defined in terms of
your car font-size:
or some other text metric that's related
font-size:
and it's very common to use is a Sep the
filesize itself
but you can also use them for any party
a layout whose size should be
proportional to the current excise
an obvious example would be the margins
are under paragraphs
as fun size increases you like those
margins also increase
in proportion to that
and the big benefit hears that by using
his
units your layout will automatically
adjust to different font sizes
now you set up a lot size are you so
much change it they could use command
passing
minus or perhaps they've changed the
minimum
fun size setting which is very common
for low-vision users
see should always make your layout just
to font size are you not expecting
there are four relative units and see is
a phat relative units and CSS
I'll there's the AM which I'm sure
you're all very familiar with its very
popular
very common on the web and and M is
defined in terms of the font size
other car talent which may be inherited
from its ancestors
less common as the axe which is
approximately half an hour
it's really supposed to be basically the
height %uh
a lower his letter on
this is very useful when you're trying
to size an element
inside a lot of Texel looks natural next
to the rest the text-align:
the CH is based on the
with I love the numeral 0 which may seem
random
a that is a typical character with
and so you can use it for sizing an
input element
where you're expecting save 30
characters you could say 30 ch
and will be a approximately the right
size and finally
we come to the RAM which is the unit the
cases using
a the RAM is just like the AM that
you're already familiar with
but instead of being based on the font
size a the current element
its always based on the font size up the
body at the root element
so I would you want to use Rams
incentive Adams you are using ann's
their great for you here's a simple
example
that a simple website with a header
hello on the left a size with aum's
on the right side with brooms
okay so far this is a they're they're
identical everything works the same
well few months from now I me to change
my website
added a container element happens to
have the center inside it
and because someone told me is how I
roll to the Nats
I went ahead and size that hot size for
them as well
so what i expect to happen is this I
want ok nothing to change
a but if I'd use Em's for my header
what happens the browsers as well this
font sizes and M's
okay well what's up air France is all
that stands and keep looking up until
find the country font-size:
and then computes the sort of compound
font-size:
and so the result is something way
bigger than I intended when I for size
Hatter
few months ago unlike that
in the case a friend's its always
looking back to the body element its
gaping asshole
and has a chance so I've never have a
different font size
than expected okay
so take a quick look at fun relative
units and
why I think the Rams pretty great
let's take a look at our website and see
where we are
offense looking pretty good and it's
definitely better
on we definitely stop the sidebar there
that a significant issue but I think
tackle that
later hi what you want to do next I also
what kind loving me is all that weight
tax
around the unknown right all that extra
white space I just I feel like we're not
making a good use
this been released a and just feel kinda
clunky
yeah I mean the whole point love
adjusting our call with in the first
place was to have a nice readable
alliance and our moon is really a
interfering with that wind is really
narrow
by the tech sector definitely so let's
take a look at that
so to simplify here's our moon we
floated it
in our column in those lines next to it
the fly-around
the image element and they look really
now
and well
and a whole lotta time to fix this so
the easiest thing
is you know we had to stop huddling and
that way there's no Nara lines extabit
looks pretty good rent okay at 10
you could do that on I have a feeling
though that you have a much
clever easy solution to that and
is just kinda feels like a cop-out it
okay
fair enough a so
with a new feature called sees the
shapes
is available in your sanity and I would
say
we can actually flow that text around
the courage to the minute look really
great
I'm so what's going on here CSS shapes
it's a simple feature that allows you to
flow text around
afloat element with uninteresting shaper
geometry
so in this case triangle
or circle like a moon or cases favorite
miss pacman come
soccer is this four-man so
like we saw before we have our militant
it's just an element of course
and we floated it within our call
now it just so happens that this image
to the moon is on a transparent
background
and sees the shapes has a great feature
where you can provide it with an image
and I will use here the visible are
opaque part that image
to the final shape into this with one
property
property is called shape outside and
this case for providing at the image of
the Moon
it'll look into the image data and say
okay here's the opec part
as you can see our by the text now
flying around the answer them
it's that easy critique or a course it's
not easy
of course it's not easy because I lucked
out my moon is on transparent background
already
but a lot of times it's not you have an
image that's entirely up a
and it don't on how to photoshop skills
to go and in
fix-up I certainly that actually love
you do share
a so I do now so as you can see I still
have a chip on side property
but this is a pic min so
shape doesn't have anything to go on
here
fortunately we can also in in addition
to using an image
as a source for the shape their we can
simply use some basic
geometric shapes as well and of course
the moon a
luckily for me %uh is a circle
so what I want to do is
somehow tell the season shapes model to
use this
circled for the text around and I do
that using the
circle function pretty straight forward
it takes
one argument the radius in this case I
use fifty percent because I wanted the
diameter the moon
at that the diameter the circle to be
the full with the initial
nice looking pretty good
there are other predefined shapes to
take one example
a you can use an ellipse
a course in lips with the same
dimensions
iXYS just circles I really haven't
changed anything
but you can get really interesting with
this too a
if there's a polygon function allows you
to define fairly arbitrary shape
so as an example I drew an octagon
around my man
partner function takes a sequence of x,y
coordinates
and it was pretty great actually
and all this was still again with just
one seize the property
okay cool we see how easy it is
to use CSS shapes to get a really great
visual effect those
basically a possible 24
we will do next well let's take a look
back at our Web site
so now we have the text going around the
moon really well which I
think looks much better I'm
the one thing that I i'm saying no is
those images look a little
by the on on the phone you think
I agree I mean look at that galaxy
yeah I I definitely think that we need
to make our site
ready at all pixelated yeah that's not
as having too many beers the burbs
so let's provide a high-resolution image
for this
I'm you know in the past a previous
study thieves we've talked about
how to rectify I think that's a word
right
retin-a by check it's working now you
can write it down
we're going to talk about how to rectify
your website so that you have
some brilliant clearer images on all
your website
and in the past we talked about and
talked about how to use kinda
alternatives images so long you know one
example that was like
instead abusing a image for gradient
you should use a CSS gradient right
the one thing we haven't talked about
though is how
like what I do which is just make boats
like
i've a web site with all my photography
when I do with that we having be an
attack on the image of me
yet what the heck right so own new
to OS 10 and I i say
we have image subset image source:
that's what you really
easily add both a standard
resolution image and the retina
resolution image and the WebKit
well just magically pick the right one
depending on what
type a screen your website being viewed
and it looks kinda like this so
here's my galaxy image on a standard
screen
it looks pretty good by here it is
on a Retina screen it's pretty pixelated
so fortunately it's very very easy to
fix
and all you have to do is to start with
the image on it
so here's a middleman she look pretty
familiar to most view
it hasn't really changed since the 90's
ray up but
because I'm always look for an
opportunity to tell up tax
I'm gonna go to walk you through it us
our first act review and they're is our
all
at review please always included because
anyone who's using a screen reader
need to understand what is going on in
this big beautiful image you provide in
and then second I have my source
attribute
which is just the location up the image
so to make this standard image element
into an image source at
all you have to do is add the source at
Acuvue
so inside my source actually view is
literally a second images I have
my standard Galaxy .jp hang am a super
galaxy
.jp for meyer et screens and the
difference between those is this
modifier
1x per standard in two acts for rent
rights and then
web pic think can automatically
understand which
images for which screen
now some love you who are actually
reading through my syntax
might have noticed some redundancy in
there
you're saying doubted if a twice yeah so
galaxy that a pic my standard resolution
images in their two-time
and you might think well let's just
that's the source rate but browsers that
do not understand source at
are not gonna know what to do it so for
backwards compatibility let's keep the
source
and instead we will back out every move
that 1x
resolution image from the source at so
back wake very little amount mark-up
rate
with just a small amount a mark-up we've
made our website
are image on it retin-a ready in
research that's a really
great they load only the right image so
you're going to avoid that double
download
there's no additional CSS you don't have
to go
in there in muck around with your
dimensions or anything like that
and is backwards compatible which is
this little amount as intact this one
after him
so so far I've talked to you about image
source: set
in your HTML it just so happens that
their
is another feature that we talked about
at BBC in the past that has
incredibly similar name and an
incredibly similar function
so we're gonna go over that real quick
to so that you can understand when you
use
which and why so images
source at which we discover during your
HTML
but image that living RCS that and their
intended
for styling your website like orders are
background
so image that for say I do have one of
those background images that I want
to make retin-a ready I'll just start
with my background image
you see I have my URL my galaxy .jp had
and to make it into an image that I had
a
second background-image: property and
with in it
is the image Sat function
and not functioning contains both the my
edges
it contains the Galaxy J Pak my favorite
1x
am a super galaxy Jay pag with to act
and then when kept from here what
automatically select the right one
I'd like to point out that you do need
to have both love your background image
properties there
for backwards compatibility so
image that image source: that they're
great
there easy they make it super easy for
adding both standard
and Brett images when people pick the
right one
just remember that your H your HTML
image source at are for your content
those big beautiful photographs we
talked about
and your CFS image that's are for your
style
so your background images your borders
so I think both are going to be a really
great solution for your website
juicy iraq yes
well it's way better really happy about
that I was worried that
they've had too much fun to the rest
last night okay so where are we now
we've got I read the image and
we still have a bunch of basic math
problems on this page
that we haven't dressed yet yeah I read
it image
looks good I S except that you can't
really fear right at the giant caption
over its ridiculous
suspects up some her remaining their
problems by using CSS me decrease
I'm sure love you uses all time a
solicits jump right in
and take care these remaining issues
here we are again much love from there
can see the
text loading their round on me now so
pretty good
big fan okay what's a and
as you know as we
maker his narrower the lead gets more
more crazy
in particular I don't like how the
mass had a by page here's taking up so
much vertical space
this caption as really offer the overlap
my image
in fact it's blown way out of it and
overlapping the heading below it
and then the sidebar is really really
narrow
artery let's fix it to these
also with the header
so as you can see at the corner like a
mess and I have that any better
JavaScript to show how what I would do
it
so where a does the header start go
go off it seems like between
650 and 700 pixels somewhere in there we
hit multiple lines
as is our earlier on the phone we have
like four lines of
text so I'm I want to adjust the size of
a header somewhere around
but 290 pixels or something
let's let's do that do this in many
years
the at media rule
so here I have in at media rule
this is the part css3 provide immediate
very in this case
max with the 675 pixels and then
inside braces you press the provide
whole style sheet of things you'd like
to change at that point
in this case I'm finding that masthead
header and adjusting its fun size down
okay so we made that change to refresh
nothing changed because this is wider
than that brake plant 675 pixels
so let's make their site were narrow and
there we go
I had a smaller and those great even
here at this very nice
walking next I think I'll take care love
this caption
so just like with the header I need to
figure out where it starts looking
bad it's looks great out here two lines
I'm still pretty happy with it here and
it seems to be right around where it
goes
four lines where that bottom right
corner
isn't ruling in spike out saying really
kinda ruining the mood
okay so where was that that seems to be
here between
seven hundred and 750 pixels
okay sold just like with a header
I use it at media rule this time
with the match with that said 150 pixels
and what we're doing here is
are initially my caption a
is absolutely positioned so that it can
be a overlay on top of my image
and its witness at 30 percent so that it
takes about half the size limits like
Sep
so in my military here I want to
override
both the position and with properties so
that
it will simply appear below the image
%uh and take up the full with the call
not that
so we'll save and Kyle
and fresh
and as you can see the site before
nothing's changed because I'm still
wider than
that may decrease test but as we get
closer to the bad part
there's a pop down it's quite legible or
image
and doesn't interfere with that no
matter how narrow in this screen gets
okay cool let's take care that site by
that I think the last bit but looks
pretty bad in our size so where does
that get unreadable
in this case I I feel like right around
here's where
the blockquote inside my sidebars
getting
to be you know one or two pair words per
line it's religion our
so let's make an adjustment around a
hundred a 50 pixels
but now I think you know the drill this
adjustment is exactly like the other
ones we have an admiral
for with 800 pixels apparently the
sidebar is floated over
so I'm disabling the flow just like with
my caption I'm
resetting the with so will automatically
be a
the with its container and killing some
in the margins we have their
so that the sidebar the %ah set from the
calls text
so if we come back and refresh
still there but as I get smaller there
we go
the sidebars popped and now in line with
the rest of your document
and even the really really narrow screen
size
start to look pretty good
okay
let's talk a little bit more about me
series
as he saw a reuse many crews and CSS
by using at media role which takes a
Munich Re test and then some CSS to
apply
when that military matches so here I am
fixing a caption like this are earlier
by using a Mac with military
and then I'm overriding the position
with properties
this is in general how you use it at
meteorol you have some rules somewhere
else in your style sheet
and then you say okay but and sometimes
I need to override this
in all three cases we use the match with
media period because we were just saying
for when things got an hour
there are several other media here is
that you know of money is
when doing responsive design there is a
corresponding
men with military a where you can adjust
things as the
seichas wider and also up
an exact with mediocre
when you're adjusting your site to be
retin-a reading
in addition to using the features that
cases showed you earlier you might need
to make some let it just means
and you can test for I read the device
by using
the device pixel ratio military which
just like with
takes min and max variance
when adjusting your lawn with a Munich
Re
there's a few things just keep in mind
first of the admiral is actually a very
blunt
instruments what you're doing is
making an entire altar in style sheet
that applies in certain circumstances
you have to duplicate the selectors are
using in here to fall style sheet to
over I particular properties
and as your site grows this can lead to
a really
a large maintenance burden you might
double or triple or quadruple the size
of your
style sheet
so instead
when possible should try to use CSS
features that naturally adapt your side
without having to duplicate all your
work we sought to earlier
a the calm with property allowed us to
adjust the number of columns magically
basically
without resorting to military and the
image that function
allows us to pick the right image for
our display without having to use the
device disarray share property
military it secondly
when I was adjusting early out there
I was doing experiments Lee a lot on my
side
fiddle with by screen have window with
and found where
each part of my lap when pat and then
made adjustments
for that I didn't look up the
dimensions a particular screen on
Wikipedia
I let my concert actually tell me where
it needed to be adjusted
this'll make your cut content more
resilient to
and ever increasing granger scenarios
where it might be worth it
okay so we've made her final and
adjustments with
so many queries and there's just one
little bit I wanted to address
before we can holiday
and this is
some of these borders on our site so you
can see up top there we have this little
byline of
the Friday edition of the Daily space
digest
and bottom borders around it and they
look great on live laptop
on but their little thick
on my phone I i mean one pic support
and I wanted it to be a one pixel border
a
but of course as yard now
when I say one picks on CSS I don't
actually get one pixel on let's play
the CSS pixel is defined to be a sort of
abstract measurement that roughly
corresponds
to one physical pixel on a pre read its
way
but now with reading device once is a
special actually contains for
by special
so I want to do is to reach into this is
a special and you speak
full use each other's device pixels I
wanna try
hairline borders
okay some right now
I'm dry my border a with one picks on
CSS
and when that draws on a standard
display
I get with an islamic past look at and
on a Retina display
I get this a line is twice as thick
as actually what so what I want to do is
really only use one
row or column are of device pixel to get
this line
so how to do it that's
look at our CSS here I'm sending my
border with one pixel
I'm not the only one who is what airline
borders love you have to
and I gotta say some other solutions
people have come up with are
amazing and horrified
here's my favorite says pretty brilliant
it uses a a inline SVG image annotator
URL as a background image
everyone got that it's really easy to
remember how to type this as I'm sure
you can see
art let's cut this out
this is ridiculous and now
I'm really pleased to say that in
yosemite and I'll essay
WebKit has an able to feature that we
call sub-pixel layup
now mostly this won't affect we doing at
all
it's a magical under the hood
improvement that just makes things a
little bit better
we can take advantage of it to get the
headlines we want
without having to do this sort of thing
okay
how we do it so here we have our 1 pixel
for center display
and out just like we saw before with our
media queries
write a check to buy space for issued a
CRO arianna redness pain
we r great and all we're doing is saying
we're on our readiness
display great just use a half pixel
remember the CSS pixel is
to device pixels innings to mention so I
have a pixel
corresponds to that beautiful thing and
device pixel
and now I can actually read this and
remember what I meant when I for it
that's exciting and here we are
got my right now iPad and if we use the
magic if he notices a min on that
you can see those lines are still as I
possibly get
who I ThinkPad re:
so our website now looks home much
better
minus are that engineering design field
and it looks great
on every device and when very little
mark-up I come
coming on the coded video I think we
actually own a chance about 20 lines
pretty good ray I'm yes
thank you all we had to do.
was maker columns response that we
define the with the bar column instead
of a compound
we also designed our layout so that it
wasn't bomb relative units which means
that
our users change their font size we are
going to have
fidelity to our layout also 10 show you
how do you see a
shapes so that now we have the text
flowing
beautifully around the curvature for
moon and
both our galaxy Inter Milan image are
retin-a ready
then we also covered how to use media
queries are blunt instrument
for did making larger layout changes
when necessary
and icing on the cake for those
beautiful
hairline borders that really reach into
the red screen
so from our information as always you
can contact Apple evangelism
and check out our documentation and thus
far Developer Center
are and participate in the wanna our
sessions over at Art Bell performs
it's Friday morning so
are line session was a course earlier
this week and if you missed it
that lets check out the videos really
great we've also
talked about several things with that
come up in previous studies have
releases
into
2012 we introduce the image set function
for CSS
in a great talk occurs in a
extreme depth and how to make a cartoon
retin-a ready it's really really
wonderful
and the last year we introduce several
new layout features
which we didn't go into here like CSS
regions
fluxbox and the some really great
advance let you can do in CSS
that will make your site really great
and
to please check that out I know
something to travel from hype are to be
here
hope you have safe travels home thanks
everyone