welcome
welcomed in green some great games
where talk about today how is something
that you can do in your game to make it
really really great but having a fun
game
is simply not enough there are things
that need
great games do at what I mean is games
the recognizes
industry-leading in the games industry
things that they do that you should be
doing
but we really need to be doing to make
your game great
and is a massive opportunity have him
talk about yesterday
there's 75 billion download an
application
and as everyone in this room knows shoot
for sure those
our games games are also reinforces this
but the 130 million monthly active users
last month that that is a huge audience
you can tap into for your game but and
to do that you need to start with a
great idea
obviously putting up hard work and you
need to follow some
reeling really your important key tips
to make your game great
so over the last couple days
yesterday and this morning we talk about
technology and their technology like
Open GL ES 3.0 which was introduced
since WWDC last year
and is the most advanced Open GL out bps
out there
we also have met all are low-level
highly optimized
GPUs PRI we've Game Center which
provides
that focal connection for your players
spray kit think it
you let us do the heavy lifting for you
if you don't need to go right OpenGL
metal
you can use my kitten think it ill allow
you
to do less programming and left left
without a fish in API on
underneath your game and game
controllers open your game up
many forms have in place of course is
also Xcode sex
was swept and playgrounds we have
tools like the open the metal for OpenGL
seen a Open GL debuggers we have
think it and Sprite kid editors and also
this week we have
mass amount of sessions about games we
have three on metal
we have 21 think it to on on Spike it
we have lab all all these technologies
all week
and we have sessions about development
tools but
technology alone is not enough you can't
just be
take the technology build the game might
have been expected to be successful
you have to go about the gains business
and the business to building a game with
the same passion
you would go about your game design for
choosing your technology
or your graphics API if you look at the
though winners from the Apple Design
Award
last night like three leo's fortune
device sex black are Monument Valley
they have some common traits that
attract engage
and retain their players anything gave
me is key to success
so we find our there are some common
thread
among the successful games things like
make it easy to buy
and play your game with by reducing the
friction
or refresher content to
continually a a be able to retain any
Gators players I said engagement is
really key
even invite these in other trade among
these games
and I like by Allen Schaeffer up on
stage to talk about
these key ingredients for a great games
fair
hello everyone welcome to BBC 2014 games
so my name is Alan Chi for I'm a game
technology evangelist at Apple
and as jeff said I'm here to talk to you
about some other things that we
see in from the best games on iowa's now
there's a lot of things that go into
making a great game
and a lot of different ways to describe
that process right attack go back to
what he was saying
we look at games we think about the
Apple Design Award winners over the
years
we start to see common thread some kind
of key ingredients that all these games
get right
and that's what I want to talk to you
about today so
I'm gonna go through ellipse I have some
of these things that just really stand
out to me there is a lot more
than what I'm gonna go through but here
is my the first thing on my list
okay is to remove friction
so i'm talking here about making a great
first impression
and I really frictionless first time
experience in the game
really streamlining everything
that gets in the way of the player
getting into the game as they start
so what do I really mean by friction
here so here's a
are imaginary game how many as 3,000 it
is awesome by the way
I'm but did have some other problems
with friction
that I'm thinking up here so let me show
you first the startup experience have
this game
player comes then loading
so yes still loading and it's going to
take about a minute to load because
that's how long it'll take me to get
through the slides so
you know the problem that I have or that
I see here
with a number of games is that they
really take i neva monolithic approach
to loading their assets and they preload
everything up front instead of you know
trying to just do what they need just to
get started
so your goal should be to get
interactive as quickly as you can
load just enough of your assets so we
can get up and running to your first
interactive screen
and the new technologies like Grand
Central Dispatch and so on to move work
of a beer main thread
high and so inlet that continue a
synchronously
then also use the time profiler to
really take a look at your loading
performance
I'm and it'll show you and a lot of
detail exactly what worked the app is
doing
during that time but even before you get
into the time profile I don't want to
just punted time for Oprah profiler is
my advice
you have to really think about it first
right why are so many things being
loaded up front
in isn't there something that could be
deferred
and made AC and loaded a synchronously a
a little bit later
but okay so it's downloading and now
let's go on
to our downloading some assets
okay so I'm you know a lot of you guys
do this in the game and it's fine it's a
you in many cases it's a good thing but
it doesn't have to be in something where
it makes the player wat so later in the
talking and I go through a couple other
things that you can do to move this off
to the side so the user doesn't even
have to notice it
okay next registration
when I like a pattern mania coun no
I would like to play paddle mania I'm
so you know when you think about the
registration
there's a couple possibilities here you
know maybe actually
that registration is needed maybe you
have us
game that is server backed and you need
some way to uniquely identify this
player
if that's the case then actually you
could just use the vendor ID that we
provide to the game
as the unique identifiers for that
player and get it so that it's out above
the players way
handle it automatically may be the case
isn't that you have a server back a
maybe you're just asking the user to
sign up for an account because you want
to
given new server special offers are just
whatever they're the reason maybe
well the first time experience in the
game is not the right time
ask for this yet they don't know who I O
you know why you might be asking so of
course you would need to clearly explain
it like is the mediators
just have extra and if it's not
really needed been differ in till later
so
I wanna play how you say no thanks
Mac shut configure my paddle with paddle
mania
I'm but still let me be clear you know
if this is my first time playing the
game
then I don't know the implications are
many these choices right as to go and
play
so if they matter then now is not the
time to ask me because I don't know
and if they don't matter then don't put
him in the way of the user getting on
board into the game
and you know not better knowing either
way sort of conveys to the players that
is not
really the experience your hand really
been thought through
so there's some real trouble with powell
mania actually
mm yeah there we go the last one here
please leave a rating
I'm you know this is fine right way we
talk about this all the time
I but you know at this point actually
I haven't even played the game yet so
you know now is not the best time to
come and ask me about rating and
I'm but I you know I think you guys are
getting at here right so
let me give you the takeaways this first
section so you've got to get the player
into the game
reduce the load time and any blocking
updates to get the game interactive
as quickly as possible them streamline
the registration
right provide an escape from tutorials
and long intros and all those things
that might get in the way
and I don't forced decisions about
something that the player can possibly
I know about yet and be patient no show
some restraint when you're asking for
feedback
so that number one remove friction from
the first time experience
K years number two to be a good teacher
so be it a good teacher is really all
about thinking through that on boarding
experience and really kinda making it
fun
cuz if you can help your players get I
get started it's more likely that
they'll become more deeply engaged into
the game
and you know it's almost easier to think
a bit on the other side
if you just leave it to the player to
figure out your game
themselves then you run a lot of risks
the risk people
just being a couple times and getting
frustrating
leaving the game or maybe no missed
something that was really important
to the gameplay and would have captured
the interest but they just didn't see it
they didn't know to go down that path so
yesterday during the design awards
ceremony john was up here he talked
about Leo's fortune
as his example I am use a different
example
I ending I'll Apple Design Award winner
from 2011
and that's cut the rope so this was up
of fun puzzle game
and spread a perfect example here to use
as a as on board in case study
so right away what you see here is that
they're using coaching tips to explain
the goal
which is to deliver can't eat on on the
character
and then they start to tell you about
things like the primary interaction
can cut the rope you swipe with your
finger to cut the rope
now you might be looking at this time
going like was totally obvious
but now it's only because you've seen
this picture I
had so the you know what people would do
without this they were tapped the candy
they were tapped on nom trying to get
him to jump up and eat the candy they
don't know what to do
and those aren't the right interaction
site the correct one is to swipe
cut the rope so than once
the player has that down then they start
introducing new interactions one at a
time
so each time is another coaching tip are
so here you cut the rope
the book they can be flows down it goes
into the bubble and in the bubble will
start to lift it up
and then there's another tip put writing
context once that happens
telling a player to pop the bubble with
her finger I embattled
release that and it'll come down to Tom
not
can't and then one more
really sort of subtle thing is that a
big part of the game play in Cut the
Rope
comes from I'm trying to get the candy
to touch all the stars
are before it gets down to on and
kinda routing it around that way in to
be successful at that usually take some
trial and error on every level
when you actually playing again so it's
actually
really important to the core loop in
this game
to show players how they can try again
right so in their onboarding they call
that out
specifically and you think oh it's just
know okay fine they're showing me around
the buns
but now if they had left that to the
player to discover on their own
some people might not have played around
with all the buttons and menus to
to go and play again for really pisses
cord to the gameplay
so that's why they should
but okay so to summarize now so start by
bringing the player
right into the game and show them how to
get started
and then introduce more complex
interactions one at a time
provide camps in context as you go along
and then help them discover the things
that will be important in the game as
they as they play through it
that number to be a good teacher now I
want to mention also I'm we're having a
related session
it's gonna be on Thursday very aptly
named making a great first impression
was strong onboarding design will spend
a whole hour
going through some examples that really
get this right so be sure to catch that
on Thursday
alright now I want to turn focus to the
gameplay itself
the number three is to really tune and
perfect your corlew
you know I talk to people all the time
and people asked me to
to take a look at their game give me
some feedback you know stuff under
development
and a lot of times what I'm looking at
is something you know they're they're
saying I just
it doesn't really feel fine yet and what
that really comes down to is the core
lid
so Corluka is a term that wraps up how
to describe the game mechanic in terms
are
know the actions the player takes in the
game the reward that they receive
BR as they're pursuing the a goal
I and the resulting expansion of the
game or the growth the character
I as that motivated them to pursue that
reward
and just in games that aren't quite
right what I often find is that there's
some disconnect
in this cycle or sum mismatch between
the parts
so they don't really lineup well but so
when we just
illustrate this by showing you some
typical examples from from different
genres
just set the stage so you're here is a
fantasy role-playing game
I explore the the dungeon I
I fight enemies defeating the enemy is
gets me treasure and experience
am and I use that treasured experience
to
to level up and to buy things and then
that lets me go and fight more more
powerful enemies
okay very clear for platformer
you know the basic idea platformers a
running jump okay that's player action
but their goal is really to complete the
level itself into
avoid all the obstacles in the bad guys
in collect the stars are power ups or
whatever is happening on that level
but then if you're successful the
expansion is to unlock
the next stage literally expand the
universe the game universe for that
for that can and where then you then
going fine
new things to run and jump over new
obstacles and so on
but okay so now to get a little deeper
you know it's really worth noting
that summer the most compelling games
are the ones
with more than one corlew and I'm
showing the side by side
but really they're meant to be
overlapping I'm so you're fighting
monsters you gain experience you
leveling up but at the same time
you're collecting clues you using the
clues to solve a puzzle
the puzzle led to all market or behind
the door there's more monsters the more
clues and
these are overlaid in the experience on
top of each other
okay so let me give you some more
concrete advice here so
know what really is the bottom line him
so the best games I've first are the
ones that really
I clearly understand their target
audience
and are able to put Center excuse me put
the centerpoint
a big corlew right on top of that
audience
and it's important that the core loopy
easy to expressing kinda be easy to
understand that's kinda
when I find games that that are have
these little mismatches
usually it's a case where it's difficult
for the developer tax and to express the
corlew these components clearly in terms
the action the reward expansion
now as I've been saying make sure each
basin this
feeds right into the next in sort of all
the energy that the player gives into
one part of it
flows around kinda reinforces the other
parts
make entered each iteration meaningful
and I'll talk about this will more as I
talk about
progression in the game I'm but then
also questioned your assumptions and
this is probably even
best advice for a developer sister go
back and really rethink innkeeper
iterating
until you know it you've done it well
and
you know how do you know how do you
really know he I could say play task but
thats
that's just a punch right it is like how
do you really no
that you did it well well you know it
by really thinking it through yourself
you know if you find the clues will you
be able to solve the puzzle without some
giant we for
we buffet or going online to Google how
to figure out this puzzle
well you know if you on walk something
would if you solve that puzzle is it
going to unlock the next stage
if you unlock the next stage while I
have something new or novel to really
look at
once I get there K to test it
but at the same time don't feel boxed in
I am NOT saying that every game needs to
follow
the same design methodology or I'm
you know kind of deal with its audience
in the same way
a lot of the really best expressions of
I've great games
are the ones that aren't afraid to mix
this up I'm
but so now let me show you just a a
quick example
I a game this really fantastic in a way
that doesn't score lou
is Apple Design Award winner last year
this is ridiculous fishing by playing
beer
I'm so it really has I think you could
break it down into three distinct
mechanics
the first one is when you are dropping
the
your line into the water you're just
trying to you're using the accelerometer
the gyroscope in trying to get the wind
down through the water
avoiding the fish get is deep as you can
okay then
once you run out of line or once you hit
a fish on the way down
everything reverses and now you're going
back up
and reeling and as many fish as you can
were back on the Giro
again and just trying to now to collect
as many other fish in try to run into
them
while avoiding the jellyfish in other
bodies that are better there
and then the third loop when we get up
to the surface
of course I'm we fooling the fish up
into the air and the new cap on them
to shoot them out of the sky right so
and collect points
and so AM in those points are white we
use to expand
as the expansion in the game we let's
get a better Leuer
longer lines and so on so the game is
really you're hilarious
and he didn't see it last year from the
design awards check it out
but so that's tuning your core loop
now let me expand out from there I am so
for the next few
parts for the talk I wanna go through
some aspects of this next ring
around the core lou I want to start with
the interaction mechanic
I'm because obviously you know how the
player interacts with your game is
completely fundamental to the success
on the core lead to a feeling fine and
if your players seem to be having
trouble with the controls this is where
to start
and is to design for touch
so sometimes when I'm working with
someone who's bringing a game over I
west from another platform like
a PC or console or whatever their first
instinct is actually to just bring their
core loop over completely unchanged
yeah including all their old interaction
mechanic
right and so you know if the game was
based on pressing buttons then they just
overlay the screen superimpose some
buttons
or if they used to use the d-pad then
okay great
and open a virtual d-pad on the screen
but the truth is that this is usually
not really
optimal these overlays get in the way
and the player
seeing the game field and but more
profoundly
their indirect their control that are
controlling that little Patil its gonna
go
underneath and and you know so bouncy
ball game right
and so you since the indirect
it relies on the player to really be
able to be in control
up the controls themselves but they
can't feel when their finger is in the
right spot and therefore so they kind of
have to look at their finger allied
in order to be confident in their
actions
okay now if you step back for a moment
and really think about where all this is
coming from
you know if the game was designed with a
different interaction mechanic in mind
then a lot of the assumptions about
other mechanic
just get built into the game may become
have implicit
and ultimately kinda for gone and when
that happens
the answer isn't is unjust to retiree
map
some controls on to a virtual joystick
virtual buttons
you really need to go back and re think
those assumptions
and yup go back and redesign for touch
and if you're not sure what I really
really mean by this then let's just go
back and look at some other design award
winners over the past couple years
Monument Valley tap the PAP and that
directs ida
around to walk around she's main
character in menu
or you you do the float with gestures
and that'll turn the crank soon move
beyond the walkways
so it's based on taps and gestures
black you make a shake with your finger
and that's the pattern that the stroke
this generated is going to follow
you try and get that to repeat and and
try to hit the dots
by the way I'm gonna hang this picture
in John's office when we get back
so but it's about stroking a pap
three games so in 30 push the trials
against the walls to make
no matching numbers I join together in
very kind of physical you're pushing the
tiles
they're coming there's squeezing
together against the walls and so on
but it's all based on short strokes and
swipes
Infinity Blade you swipe the screen just
control how your character is going to
swing a sword
then there's some buttons you press to
dodge
I'm and there's ever race you put on
your user shield
I'm and there's some gestures he used to
to cast the spell was so it's taps
swipes
and gestures cut the rope we just showed
you use swype to cut the rope and then
you tap
things like balloons and you tap on the
bubbles and so on to
to blow a rounder pop the bubbles so
it's taps swipes
where's my water you guys are getting
this you know you take your finger
you drag your path drag have through the
dirt
and that's where the water is going to
flow so you feel your finger touching
the glass you
instantly get audio feedback when you
when you touch the screen you feel the
friction
as you withdraw that path move your
finger around and you
instantly see the path you drew so it's
a game against
everything right everything is in think
so
let's take all the same sort of distill
it down and summarize what I mean by
this
so the key to what that pic all those
games and others
the nerd all doing is to design their
controls around direct interactions
reinforced by instantaneous feedback
so direct manipulation is the key to
that interaction model on Iowa s you've
got to embrace the idea
that the best i OS games are the ones
where you reach
through the glass in touch the game
elements themselves
right so it's based on touches and
perhaps in gestures and swipes
and panning and drawing pads where
those interactions are the ones that
define the gameplay
and then it's critical that you provide
instantaneous feedback so these are the
visual cues and audio cues so that what
you see
and what you hear and what you feel all
reinforce what you did
and they reinforce each other
okay so with all that passion
now has designed for touch
but the people seem to be having a lot
of trouble with your control
then go back to those principles and
really redesign your core luv around the
idea of direct interactions
that are reinforced by instantaneous
feedback
okay next to foster in gage mint so
you know this is about keeping the
player coming back onto your game and we
use a lot of different terms to describe
this
you know it's a huge a huge area but all
this is done because just hopefully
you know having a really deeply engaged
player is gonna generate word of mouth
and viral discovery
more business for you more of a fan base
and so on
and there are a ton of things to talk
about here but
on yeah I know get to some specifics in
a minute
but i wanna first say something else
it's a little deeper
about this so it's really easy for any
of us to kind of get
wrapped up in the details of the Corluka
me on boarding and so on
but its it's important for you to be
able to rise
above those details the game and really
see the game from the players
perspective
and understand that the design process
here
is profoundly fractal the same patterns
amor chat every level would detail and
there are resonances
among them so even if you get big game
loop completely right
if you can't rise above that it won't
resonate with your medicaid career
progression
if you get the progression ride but you
can't rise above that
it won't resonate with the storyline and
so on and so on
but OK so now taking this down a notch
back to her
just a moment I'm you remember how a
couple love
moments ago I i said that you know a lot
a really interesting games
overlay multiple core loops well that
holds true for the progression is well
and so one way that you can really get
hold the players interest is to provide
layers of progression or overlays a vid
I've progression and expansion with
multiple goals model perhaps some goals
I mean
multiple paths have challenges and
different pasa
giving different a balance between risk
and reward
that's something the players will find
very very compelling
you can even game of ID expansions
themselves
so this is the opening the essence of a
lot of crafting games
is the you make the expansions
themselves into choices at the players
have to make
that our strategic to the future of
their gameplay and then in you ensure
that you take them down different paths
depending on I what they've done
but OK this next one now so this is
particularly important for anyone who's
making free to play games
and after provide value for everyone
both you're paying players
and your non paying players so work
through
the entire experience for both those
audiences
and to ensure that those who are playing
your game for free
can can progress can expand
and sure they can see the benefit show
them the benefit becoming a pain player
but if you try to force them then you're
losing gauge min
with a fair number and on the other side
ensure that those who are paying in your
game
I'm will feel that they're getting
properly rewarded in the game and
getting something for the money that
they're spending
the next candice is holding the players
interest
so really do what you can to incentivize
repeat play so enable and motivate the
players
to try one more time enable and motivate
the player to see what's next
enabling motivate to see how it ends
right and if you think about where the
spirit again
one more try is about the core loop see
what's next is about the progression
see how it answers about the storyline
right
K now let me talk about on a bit about
reengage min
so providing really you know coming out
and providing relief
fresh new content out after you launched
is a great way to keep your momentum
going and in many cases he meant to draw
help drive new growth
to really think about how you will
continue your story
to provide new content or new levels are
new goals are challenges and so on
worth seasonal content around holidays
or regional content in different locales
it's all good give your players are
another positive reason to come back
into the game
and it's important that you plan this
out before you launch
because the people who have had
catastrophic success
are the ones who a game takes of in the
realize people are done
and they need to scramble to get more
content out
your most engage players are going to
are going to consume your content very
quickly
so habit ready have it ready to go so
that you're really deeply engage players
can have something that's gonna bring
them back into the game and you attract
new players to come in as well
now it's also important to really
measure and understand how well your
retaining your players
I'm in starting later this fall in will
be providing
a retention information to you through
iTunes Connect
so this is gonna show you how many
players have downloaded your game
by day by region by platform by
stores and what percentage to them kept
playing in the days that followed
that their download and so this is just
a takes
okay so we'll show you a lot more about
this
I in the iTunes Connect session tomorrow
morning
so that's number five to foster
engagement
so now let me turn the focus the other
way and get into a couple things on the
technical side
and so this is number sixty use
background transfers
I'm okay so you remember back in their
first section where I was talking about
friction I talked about downloading
updates and I said that that was
something that we can move out at the
players wait that's what this is about
more or get into here
so in Panamanian 3,000 we have no
thousands have image assets because we
have so many levels right we have
and for all those different different
assets we have one for retin-a
non retin-a iPhone 5s iPad iPad air
right now we have all bar sounds ACN mp3
for our soundtrack we've got linear PCM
for for audio effects with opening L
we've got thirteen different
localizations right
so English French your a pig's Japanese
traditional chinese Simplified Chinese
brazillian Portuguese in a few more
IM and we have a binary compiled three
different we are three ways
rb7 rb7 as an arm 64
kept so a lot of stuff in power maybe
three thousand
I'm and you know putting all that
together is putting us over the limit
for downloading over cellular so what he
did
well I'm you know a lot of times a
discussion will begin
and you know quite often will be
somebody who will chime in with advice
like this
one-size-fits-all just ship one star is
stretchered
stretches to fit on all the platforms
order shipped one localization they all
speak English right
now they really don't I'm
so don't sacrifice quality and don't
shortchange
your Global Audience realize that what
you could prop you could probably get
your game under a hundred megabytes if
you use background transfers
you and let the user download the main
bondo love it now
but have more content that gets
transferred down after they've run at
the first time
so was a couple things to do is now so
the first step is Roy to take a good
fall look your gaming the game design
and and determine if there is some
content that isn't really needed right
up front you know I'm games especially
games with any kind of a linear
progression
are perfect for this right you put the
first couple of hours or whatever you
know the first 20 30 levels
in the bond a lab for quality MN
that's gonna provide enough time for the
user to be playing and then you
use background transfers to download the
rest while they're playing those first
twenty
so houses dot okay so an issue I L
session is an API that we introduced
back in Iowa 7
I and its the uses to upload and
download data from your own server
and this is intended for large datasets
so
game levels big images sound files
Tech's route was is all that kind of
thing
right now the transfer itself happens
outside of your process you just set it
off your kid
notified when it's completed the player
can continue or the app can even be
termed no quitter terminated and the
download is gonna keep on going
map if its running all be notified or
it'll be woken up
I'm when the transfer is done and it's
just enough so that you can take the
content thats been downloaded
and kinda unpack it and put it into its
permanent location
so it's really useful it does obviously
and add some complexity
right cuz you're gonna have to handle
some corner cases now
he didn't have have before like the
player running out of disk space
or are now reaching a level that you
have been successfully downloaded the ad
I'm and it's important also that you
follow the Iowa State a storage
guidelines
I'm so these will tell you exactly where
to play
any downloaded assets and also remember
this is about
assets no new textures new levels
newfound and I kinda thing
but not code if you're making code
changes that has to go back up through
our preview
as an update to the app but a case that
number six
to use background transfers and you know
if you're going to be targeting I was 7
and above like now is the time right
because you can move
cleanly up to are all appear supported
devices with a and if you were all
session
K number seven optimized graphics
performance
so you know I mention I meet with
developers all the time I probably met
with some other people in this room
I am yet to give people feedback on
their games I
about one of the things that just very
very honestly that I love to do
I is to run their game through our
performance tools
kinda views that too figure out I what
optimizations they need to be may
me to make in Open GL and so on describe
what I eat for breakfast
right I'm now so as I get into this
section though the first thing to
realize in to say about it
is dead optimizing graphics is
totally white matte all is all about but
or get a medal in a second
I want to talk first just about
optimizing the games that are already
out there
so you know every game is different
right and
most remember actually a pretty well
optimized are okay
are but in the games that are having
performance issues with OpenGL
it's usually because for some portion to
the frame at least for maybe all over
the frame
they're trying to do a lot of draw calls
with a low number of triangles to be
processed in each draw call
and the worst case scenario isn't
is actually fairly common I i see it
sometimes there is particularly
in 2d and isometric games that I'll find
the sometimes
is that they're just there in a loop
where their binding a texter
drying acquired and then repeat blind
drop by drop on dry and that's how they
draw
their entire scene with one draw call
for every quad
want extra fine for every draw call
and you know for OpenGL yes there's just
there's a fair amount of CPU overhead
that their
the that's involved here in the
validation in the processing draw calls
I'm so you know the theory behind this
is it becomes very important for
to optimize the state's it's super
important that those developers
find a way to amortize that overhead
over more triangles
I'm now this is something that I can
help in your view with or are
in will we have you know times are
people in the lab this week so if you're
falling into the situation
I'm we can help you Wed these 15
recommendations that are up here cover
most of the cases but I run into this is
the solutions that we apply depending on
the the game depending on the
the structure and how other what they're
doing an open GL
but and I'm not going to go deep into
any of these but so
more broadly what you need to realize
is that optimizing graphics former
performance is really
in primarily about identifying the
bottlenecks
that you have MN addressing them taking
some action to address them
okay so bad lets me talk about the tools
you know we have these fantastic tools
that will help you identify exactly
where your performance bottlenecks are
indifferent bottlenecks that might be
happening so this is a screenshot from
the Jeep you perform in scraps in Xcode
I'm and the this along with the Jeep you
frame to bugger
in Xcode and be open gles analyzer
instrument
are kind of the tools of the trade you
should familiarize yourself with here
was so now a museum in so what you see
here
section at the talk you see this sorta
speedometer on the left up to the top
the purple bars with utilization in the
in the middle that showing my GP you
utilization man over here on the right
frame time
I how much time the CPU is working on
this frame and how much time the GP was
working on his friend
now in this particular screenshot it
would
this is a little different than what I
was just talking about with pine drop by
drop by drop
I'm in this one what it is I can see the
renderer utilization is that a hundred
percent
and that's pushing the device
utilization up to 100 percent
and that is typically a sign actually
have a very expensive fragment shader
okay and so down in the bottom here you
can see I i love you here now
I'm where I can is showing me the cost
of eat
%uh everyone to buy shade urs that was
used this frame
and I can turn down these disclosures
and see the specific draw calls that use
that cheater and how much
each one of them cost as well and then
I can also go and drill down into a
particular shade or I'm not gonna walk
you through all
Buri but once you get to the view where
you're looking at your shade urs
facing bad in again
K XO know what this is showing me now
look at on the right hand side
these little bars this is is taken live
from the device is able to see the
performance data
and its in its going line by line
through the shooter to show you the
performance costume each line
and so here I feel that okay 59 percent
on the cost
on this shade her was going into shadow
projection
and there's probably something I can
optimize I can use a lower resolution
shuttle now for something
because remember this was the most
expensive cedar
in the app and the renderer utilization
was at a hundred percent
so this is this is the bottleneck the
shadow projection and so it's exactly
what
in this case needs to be optimized out
but so the point though is that the
tools can be used to exactly pinpoint
what's going on in your app
I'm now you know if you're not familiar
with a tool or this isn't
this isn't something that you know your
way around the edges come down to
collapse
we have so many people down there who
would love to help you out
to sort this out was so obviously
there's an opportunity here
right for open till yes based games the
kind of use the tools
optimizing get better performance but I
also want to be super clear
you know that seeing so many developers
struggle
I and Phase these kinds of issues are
a big part of the reason why strike it
and sink it were developed
right their purpose is to provide you
with the capabilities that you need
right cutie
games who I was bright kid 3d games with
scene kid
are now they can be mixed together right
but they real key is that once you're
using them taking revenge about
their feature set they take on the
burden
I've rendering optimally in Open GL and
you don't have to worry about anymore
and if you think about it one more step
you know since
apple provides the entire technology
stack from
these API's all the way down to the
hardware
it means that everything can be made
very often more
in a way that you don't have to work on
and then okay speaking about optimal
right
now there's mad 0 right so this this is
for those who view
with games are engines that need to push
a lot more draw calls
and really allow your code to have a
very efficient
access to the GP you to interleave
graphics in Comput
and so on and really take control
yourself over how the frame
is being rendered so that his number
seven
optimized graphics performance
okay number right now we're lifting out
at the tech in just a couple
really kind of quick and light it some
advice here
on this is a real super quick one is to
make a great gameplay video
notes or earlier in the talk I talked
about the important to making really
great first impression
well wide web didn't really get into
then was that from the pot users
perspective your player's perspective
all about is gonna start on the App
Store and
you know as we talked about yesterday
you know when people are really coming
onto the App Store they're looking for
something that's cool in New
you know they're going to be looking for
some way to kinda understand what your
team is doing and you want
to have something that's going to stand
out and
and exactly explain it and so that
they'll be more confident in
and more ready to to get your game
okay now as we talked about a little bit
yesterday so in Iowa
8 I was tenuous amity you'll be able to
create the short
ap previews for game previews to demo
your game
you should use this to show how the game
is played you know you did
tell a story with this and and really
appeal to what makes the game play so
much fun
you know here's how it'll look when it's
on the app on this App Store
we show this a Monument Valley example
yesterday
I'm and how it works is that just the
app review just
appears as the first I first image there
along with the screenshots
user taps on that they can see this
gameplay video
but now some details about this okay
so good the app review needs to be to a
video of your gameplay
it's not intended to be an ad it should
convey the real
experience in playing the game it can be
up to 30 seconds long
you provided as the H 264 %um pick for
encoded file that you upload into iTunes
Connect
you can have for you should have a
different video for iphone
verses iPad I'm and your content itself
can be captured directly of a pure IO
West device
i an on your Mac that's running I was
ten years somebody
the Mac to see you thought I was devices
a video camera
and you start playing the game and you
can capture it using whatever to you I
QuickTime Player
I and so on iMovie is where you can do
your editing and they just put it all
together and get it up on
iTunes Connect you're ready to go
mm this is really just sort of one piece
building a great
App Store presence rights are having a
great
icon compelling screenshots
localizations
description two keywords and so on
UK so about app review there's a whole
session on it's also on Thursday
afternoon
a check your schedule to see that
and make a great video this gonna show
players who were interested in your game
a what what the gameplay is really like
K number nine to localize
you know the App Store is a global
business
it's available in all 155 countries in
languages right service this is a
opportunity that is just phenomenal and
you should
think globally you know you need to
think about the distribution up your
game
as a global opportunity on
now so the first thing that you should
do you if you haven't already done this
is to localize your App Store president
right
just so that when some a player in some
other region is coming in and looking at
your game it just stands to reason that
will be
more interested in it if they can read
the description and these other things
in their native language
rights to localize the name the
description
the keywords the snapshots and so on
right and then the second piece of this
of course is to localize the app content
itself
so by that I mean to you really go back
in structure
your game for internationalization you
need to do what you can to separate
text from artwork I and textures so you
don't have to make
copies a big images for every language
that you support
and then go through you your you why I
and of course
right and translate the text in tall the
different languages the you want to
to support and finally you also consider
things like whether your game is right
to provide
some cultural eyes content where would
be appropriate
for example if it was a driving game
maybe you would use local road signs for
different locales and so on
local license plates from different
locales
so now here's the list I've some other
languages that we've recommended
I before it's certainly not exactly
exhausted its a big less
I and it's a good place to start though
so
for SES effects right English French
Italian German Spanish
then I many regions area in Asia upset
so Japanese Korean traditional and
simplified chinese:
them branches out from there so
brazillian Portuguese Russian
Turkish and Arabic are what we would
recommend that you really put some focus
into
and there's a great resource online
developer tied up on a complex
internationalization
so this will take you step-by-step
through the process of
internationalizing and localizing your
app your game
and it gives you some links the third
party
localization vendors if you don't have
that expertise
in-house but so that is number nine
to localize I am so
number ten target the state-of-the-art
so if you think about some of the best
games
that are on iowa's you are real common
thread as we've been saying is how they
consistently aim high and consistently
target the latest and greatest to
differentiate themselves on our device
so to be state-of-the-art means really
taking advantage of the capabilities of
the latest hardware like the a7
right and target the feature set up
those devices
so that you stand out I mean you guys
use all those demos yesterday
right during the keynote the state of
the union they were armed
this hardware you know you you've seen
what it can do
so take advantage a bad that power
that capability that's their
then hand in hand with that is that
state-of-the-art abs
support the latest versions apply a wet
and I think that this week should be
that turning point for you
words time now for you to realign your
project
to aimed for the release a bioassay and
API's and the frameworks that you'll be
learning about all this week
mm bring your minimum OS up to Iowa
7 that is our recommendations support
the latest
n and n -1 so when I was
8 is released you probably want to be
looking at seven and eight
K now something in you know
something that we do hear from
developers actually more often than you
might think
I'm is that they're telling us that
they'll stick there's
deciding to stick with an older version
of Xcode are in order a CK
because they think that if they move up
to what's latest
they won't be able to still chippy game
that supports anything older than that
but obviously thats not the case
so you can adopt the latest SDK version
by setting your base SDK
what is current and then setting your
deployment target down to the lowest
a OS version that you want to support
and
dropping support for the rest and then
handle differences between 7-8 in your
code
you know check for the existence of
hardware capabilities
or check whether classes are defined or
check whether classes respond to a
particular selector
and so on now for those of you who are
coming over to Iowa esiner just not
as familiar with that process we
actually went through it all in
pretty good doubt when we went out for
our I was seven Tech Talks
I last november december I am so those
videos are online our developer web
sites you should check them out
then also stated the art games for the
ones that integrate with our built-in
game technologies
as jeff talked about boo
so we're providing just this incredible
foundation for you
was built on a lot of different API you
know likes bright kid
Game Center Open GL seeing and game
controllers and so on
and the new API's like metal and seeing
kid on iowa's
right and these are just a few the
technologies you know this
but the point I wanna make is about the
other things
you know the tools and the API's that
are available to you as
game developers is comprehensive on
iowa's
and you should learn the entire stack
oh my god has a lot of learning to do
were really what I mean is to
familiarize with yourself with the
technologies that are
on iowa's rather than just taking a
project that you were working on
maybe on another platform or on an order
OS version
and just shifting mad over and fitting
it into the equivalent
your target should be to go for the
latest and greatest
target the top target the
state-of-the-art target the a7 target
iowa's
eight and its capability right
rather than just coming over and just
spitting and
with an older something that's older
but so that's number ten target the
state-of-the-art
before I finish I do have one more thing
that I wanted
talk about so yet let's save you
done alternatives right you fix your
onboarding
your he chewed up your core loop your
optimizer localize just a the art
Sarah of that so where do you go from
here
yeah well go to 11
really give it that extra push
go the extra mile his here is my
observation about this
you know we heap innovating we keep
enhancing our
game technologies we have this thriving
ecosystem
right where we're investing were adding
performance and we're adding capability
you guys you can't stand still keep
inventing
people earning keep current get started
on that next update for Iowa State Bank
you up with us because we love to shine
the spotlight
on developers who can go one
louder alright so thank you everyone
that is my list
and you I'm I had to wrap things up I'd
like to pass the stage back to
jeffrey just a moment so thank you thank
you I'll
so thank you very much Alan
and I think when I step back and look at
this
we see a tremendous fun games look
around the room there's a lot of you are
interested in
building games and there are a large
number game in the App Store we're
talking about how you can make
your game standout it isn't good enough
to just go up and I i've great idea
score game on a caught up in the App
Store and see what happens be it is a
very big pond
so use what alan is told to use these
ten steps and use the 11th step
really make your game shine these are
the things
which may not be apparent when you look
at it may not be apparent when you look
at the
design award winners that they do these
things but they really do they spend a
lot of time
cut the rope was great example spent a
lot of time I'm going through
with people who have played the game the
foreign say pay
what what do you when you approach the
game what you need to know
is not to fly guy came to open in an
hour so take the time with your game
take the time to go that extra mile take
the time to adopt these 10 items
and the 11th really bring your content
up so it stands out and we really hope
to see
someone is rumor many people in this
room on stage next year at the Apple
Design Award
thanks very much enjoy the week