welcome everyone welcome welcome to TTC
and welcome to our introductory session
about working
with metal now we are incredibly excited
to get to talk to you today about metal
we believe its
literally going to be a game-changer for
you your applications
and for Iowa's as you've heard
in the keynote metal is our new low
overhead
high-performance an incredibly efficient
Jeep you programming API
provides dramatically reduced overhead
for executing work such as graphics and
computer on the Jeep you
and with the support for precompiled
shakers
an incredibly efficient multi-threading
we designed it
run like a dream a seven chip now today
in this session I'm gonna talk to you at
a relatively high level
but the background how and why we
created metal some the conceptual
framework
for the API also touch briefly on the
metal shading language
and our developer tools sessions that
follow will go into much more detail
about exactly how to use the metal API
how to build your applications looking
things at a high level
for this session so first a better
background on metal itself
they also heard in a keynote that metal
provides 10x the number of dropped calls
your application and what does that
really mean
well it's important to think about rock
calls
in this way each draw call requires it
own
graphics state vector so when you're
specifying
you would like to draw something with
the Jeep you you also need to tell the
Jeep you
which caters which states how you want
to configure the textures and the
rendering destinations
this is very important in order to get
the fact you're looking for from the
Jeep you
but unfortunately previous API's
changing state vectors
extremely expensive you have to
translate between the API state state
that the hardware is going to consume
when ice expensive I mean not for the
Jeep you
for the CPU because the CPU that's doing
that type of translation:
let's take a look at a quick example
if your application is setting up friend
rock all
you want to specify the Shaytards in the
state in the textures for each
drop operation and I'll do that each
time you want to specify and Rocco
and the CPU gets involved and spent a
bunch of time
translating state changes and this
request to draw
in the harbor commands before sending it
to the GP you
so we had a way to make that much less
expensive
we could give you a lot more dropped
calls per frame you might ask your
supple
why do I want more dropped calls per
frame or more dropped calls
but you build much better games and
applications you can build
many more unique objects have many more
bad guys
or other characters in the scene you can
add a lot more visual variety tears
games
a probably the most important reason is
your game artists and designers are
going to thank you profusely
because you can give them more freedom
to realize their vision without having
to
jump through all types draw call
gymnastics if it
what they'd like to see on screen into a
tiny number dropped calls
I'll take a little bit of a look
what what life was like before metal now
now Apple has a long history a jeep you
programming API
both implementing them maintaining them
developing we supported standard APIs
like OpenGL an open CO sport it has
across a wide variety of the main spot
at the high level and the low-level GP
programming for things like tutti
3d animations and image processing and
we supported
a wide variety up architectures in the
hardware
across platforms computers devices
phones iPad and a wide variety
GPS and during all this time as we're
supporting all this variety
we realize that their something pretty
fundamental missing
from all of these API's and that
was the leveller deep integration Apple
brings to its products
Apple as you know provides the operating
system
the hardware and the products at the
complete package
they're designed to work together
seamlessly and so we thought to
ourselves
what if we could take the same approach
to GP you programming that we take to
our products as a whole
if we could build these to work
seamlessly we knew we could do the same
for GP programming and that's what we've
done with metal
as I said we have a long history looking
at these different types of programming
APIs
and we realized that if we wanted to get
a ten-fold order of magnitude
improvement in performance
we're gonna have to do some pretty
radical things
we decided to take a clean sheet
approach
to this design and the key design goals
that we had
were outlined here first we knew
you might have the thinnest possible API
to be that we could create
we wanted to be reduce the amount of
code that was executing
in between your application energy you
to a bare minimum
we knew it needed to support the most
modern cheap you hardware features
we didn't want it bogged down with the
Croft twenty years a previous GP designs
we wanted a focused
entirely squarely on the future
we knew that there are some expensive
CPU operations that needed to take place
we wanted a carefully control when those
happen and make sure they happen at
infrequently as possible
and we wanted to give you the developer
predictable
performance so you would know exactly
when and how
those expensive operations to take place
we wanted to give you explicit control
over when the work was
executed on the Jeep you say you could
decide when and how
to kick off that work and never be
surprised by what the implementation
might be behind your back
and last but not least we knew it had to
be highly highly optimized for the a7
CPU behavior at this week I'm key a few
moments
so how to think about metal where's it
fit
well let's say you have your application
here represented the topic this diagram
in green and you like to talk to the GP
you
apple provides a wide variety API's to
do just that
but they come at different levels
abstraction different levels
a conceptual distance between you and
the Jeep you
so at a high level you have of some
API's like scene kid
and Sprite kit to get high level
services foreseen grass for
2d and 3d animations and they're great
provide a lot services
but they're relatively far from the Jeep
you in terms of abstraction
then of course we have our 2d graphics
and imaging API such as Coronation
core image and core graphics and he's to
provide a lot of services
and if this is the type of operation are
doing these are perfect API for you
and as always we have a standards-based
3d graphics approach
with OpenGL ES but when we wanted to do
something better
and give you high-efficiency GPO Access
at the then as possible a bi-layer
that's where metal comes in
so how do we do this
well first thing we wanted understand is
how most modern games
try to manage their CPU and GP workloads
so most games will target framing
oftentimes it could be 60 frames a
second
sometimes thirty in this example are
using thirty which works out to about 33
.3 milliseconds for free
on this time and you can see how most
games will try to optimize
for this type of time
I'll try to balance the amount of CPU
work type
GP work to fill the entire frame but
will do so offset so the CP will be
working and generated commands for one
frame
and the Jeep you will then consumers
commands and the next spring
and while the CP was doing at the GP was
busily working
on the previous frame and you later sat
on a time line and you can see how you
get
relatively perfect parallelism
let's look at one frame in particular
you notice in this example
worsening completely balanced bring for
the CPU
energy you are occupying all the time
now fortunately real-life is not quite
so balanced
and oftentimes you'll find that the CPU
can take more time
to generate these commands energy P does
to consume them
and it's unfortunate because it often
leaves the Jeep you
idle you're not even using the system to
its fullest capacity
and if you were okay like having a fifty
percent faster Jeep you
but just getting their dark to save
yourself
I'd like to fix this problem I'm just
gonna give more work to the Jeep you
unfortunately what a fine is that to
give more work to the Jeep you
yet the first spin up more work on the
CPU
and if you are already bound by the
amount of work you could do a CPU this
pushes out your frame time even further
an hour below or 30 frames per second
target
and to add insult to injury the GP was
still I'd
because now our frame time is actually
longer energy you can tell that work
either
so I understand what's happening here
it's helpful to realize that the CPU
workload
is actually split into two parts you
have the applications workload what you
guys are providing
and they have all the implementation
work for the GPO API itself whenever you
make a note
a whenever you make a jeep you
programming call
we're gonna have to translate that in
the way I described earlier
well it's this Jeep you programming API
time on the CPU that we're focused on
with metal and metal dramatically
reduces this time down to a bare minimum
and this example with actually freed up
additional CPU time now that the CPU the
title
and a frame time has become limited by
the Jeep you and are actually beating
are 30 frames per second target so that
was your goal you cannot render faster
than 30 frames per second
which have another option you can
actually use that CPU time
to improve your game and make it even
better
you could at my physics army more hey I
or other types of Cebu were close your
application
we have a little bit a CPU idle time
here left we can actually choose to go
back to our
30 frames per second target and add even
more dropped calls
metal providing up to a 10x increase
inefficiency
and you can either drawn more things
with the Jeep you or maybe
just draw them in a much more flexible
manner you can get more visual for it.
so that's what we're trying to do with
Mel
now why is this GP programming so
expensive on the CPU
understand what we did with metal
helpful to take a deeper look here too
and are three main reasons first
you have what's called state validation
some people think state validation
is just having implementation verify
that you're calling the API in the right
way
and that's certainly true but it also
involves encoding the state
from the API to the hardware and
translating
and oftentimes looking at different
aspects of the state and different state
objects in the API
and for you how to combine them into
away harbors when I understand
this can be expensive and perhaps the
most expensive version of this
actually the shaker compilation itself
you take your source code shares for
your vertex and pixel shaders and they
have to be compiled runtime:
in to generate the Jeep use Machine Co
what's worse is that in a lot of API's
perform at all
state and the shaker code was not
described in the API in a way that
really map wealth with the hardware
actually
was going to expect and so when you
change certain states
you could find that behind the scenes we
actually had to go back in a recompile
your shoulders
causing even more CPU work and last
they're sending the work to the GP
itself and this can be expensive
the resources the memory the textures
have to all be managed and given to the
Jeep you
in the way it can expect and because
those first two items are so expensive
we often have encouraged you with
previous eight guys to patch up lots of
work to send
to try to amortize these expensive cost
across the fewer number
draw call just give more per truck all
the GPO
of course this tends to work at the cost
of flexibility to you the developer and
to your game designers
but it also increases latency because
now the GP has more to work on a single
charge
so we wanted to fix these three key
areas: expense
for GP programming to do that we thought
about three times
3 occurrences in the application life
cycle to focus in on
there's the application built I'm but
when you're loading the content
your game and then when there's when you
drop and they occur at different
frequencies
so first application built I'm it's
basically never occurs
I see some surprised look on your faces
because as developers you think you're
building your application
all the time that's true
but from your customer's perspective
from the people using your application
they never see this so we can move
things to occur application built I'm
if it eliminated the sixpence from
experience if your game
and your content loading time which is
relatively rare
again from a user's perspective throwing
a low to level a few times per play
yep draw calls on the other hand you
gonna do this thousands ideally
thousands of times for free and perform
at all
unfortunately all three of those
expensive thats operations for that
CPU occurred in this last time
at your local time thousands of times
per frame or more likely
a few hundred times for frame because
that's all the CQ could absorb
now with metal we've moved is expensive
operations to occur
much more optimally so but shaker
compilation to occur application built
I'm
again out in the field of view for the
users have your game
and content loading that's when we do
state validation
this again is relatively rare this means
the only thing we have to do a draw call
time is the most important thing to do
would rock all time
just kick off the work GP you
so that's the how and the why we created
metal
now wanna take a deeper look at the API
itself
and we'll take a look at some a
conceptual framework for the API
starting
with objects the API
the first object to talk about in the
middle API is the device
and this essentially just an abstraction
on the Jeep you think that's going to
consume
your rendering in computer commands
those commands will be stored and
submitted to the Jeep you a command Q
and the command Q its job simply to
decide and let you specify
what order those commands will be
executed
those commands themselves are stored in
what's called a command buffer
the stores the translated Harbor
commands ready for consumption
by the GP you and command encoder
is the API object that's responsible for
that translation
when you create a commanding KOTOR and
you use it to write a new command buffer
thats the translation
the state of the API it described in a
series of State objects
for things like higher frame buffers are
set up higher blending in
and your depth and your sampling stay to
set up these are all described to the AP
I
objects which will talk about in all
three sessions today
and you have the code your shade or
silver texture
pics shares
and last you have your data your
resources
your memory the the textures and and the
vertex
offers and the cheater Constance those
are all stored in resources
so let's take a look next and how these
objects fit together by walk
walking through a bit about how we
construct the object any
the first thing you have is the device
37 this if the device is the Jeep you
think it's gonna consume your commands
from that you create the command Q and
typically you have one of these
your application from the command Q you
create
wanna Markham and offers to use to store
the harbour commands
and right into those commands with the
render command in Kotor in this example
now in order to generate those commands
you need to specify some information
render commander
and you do that by attaching various
objects
to the random encounter before use it so
for instance
you specify your data buffers and your
textures you want to use
to do this rendering operation you
notice in this diagram
we also show something called the
texture descriptor and texture
descriptor is used to create the
textures
it specifies all the necessary state
used for texture object creation
probably the biggest state object is the
render pipeline state
and it too is constructed from a
descriptor
and the descriptor in this case
described all love the 3d rendering
state you need to create
single render pipeline
similarly have descriptors freed up and
stencil state that use to create those
objects
and we have syriza state
for describing render past self
how you're going to output directory now
the reason we split the state up into
descriptors
and state objects it because once you've
specified what all the state combination
should be
metal bakes all of these into a small
number
state objects that now all the state has
been translated all the shares have been
compiled
and system is ready to go you can now
issue your draw calls
incredibly quickly without worrying and
that the implantation
gonna have to come around to do some
late binding translation or figure out
what you're trying to do is valid in the
first place
a couple more notes so the source
resources the textures and buffers here
you can change those as you go
the render targets themselves are fixed
forgiven render mankiller
we'll talk more about why that's
important in just a moment
now and bring this diagram a little bit
we can see how objects are actually
sending data to the device
you have one or more render commanding
coaters one for each rendering pass
writing into the command buffer you can
also
interleave different types of commands
in this case I'm using computer commands
in the middle
my in the middle my friend
and as we said metal support efficient
multi-threading you can actually
construct
multiple command buffers in parallel
using multiple threats
let's talk a little bit more about the
command submission model itself
understand how this works
as we said man decoders will in code API
here one called the FBI command into the
harbor state
and the store those commands in the hard
work a member for
are three types a commanding voters for
generate three different types
work on the Jeep you we have render cue
and let and we'll talk about each of
them in detail
but important unrealized fears even
interleave these different types of
operations
in a single command buffer and within a
single frame very efficiently
and is it because the commanding coaters
themselves in caps like all the state
necessary
so we don't have to do implicit
transitions between different types of
operations
and behind the scenes we don't have to
try to save and restore
all the state necessary for using these
different types of operations all
on your explicit control
members themselves are incredibly
lightweight and most applications are
gonna create
a large number of these in their frames
and you control exactly when and how it
submitted to the Jeep you
once they've been submitted metal
signals you the application
when this command percent completed
their execution energy you to get
very fine-grained control and clear
notification about exactly what's
happening
one point I'm and very important to
realize that these commanding cutters
they're not they're not just sending
some work of it later is going to be
consumed
by the CPU they're actually generating
these commands immediately there's no
deferred state validation
essentially like you're making a direct
call to the jeep driver
as I mentioned you can also
multi-threaded man according to get even
more
performance multiple commander first
being put in para la crosse
threads and yet you get to decide
exactly when
those commands to be executed so you
have the controlled about to split out
the order in which the command will be
constructed
while maintaining order you wish for the
execution on the G
and we've provided incredibly efficient
implementation no atomic clock to make
sure you can get scaleable performance
across CPU cores so that's the commands
next gonna take a look at the resources
the memory
the objects in the API for specifying
data
now we designed the resource model in
metal
explicitly for a7 unified memory system
this means that the CPU in the Jeep you
are sharing the exact same
memory for exchanging data there's no
implicit copies were not coming in
behind the scenes and
and and taking the data and moving it
somewhere else for the GP to see it
we also manage the CPU and CPU cache
coherency for you
you don't have to worry about flushing
caches between SEP in the Jeep you
you simply have to make sure that you
schedule your work to occur such that
the Jeep you
and the CPU are not writing to the same
to commemorate the same time
you don't have to do anything to manage
cash is and
are you taking on this responsibility
for synchronization
between the jeep in the CPU we can offer
you significantly higher performance
because we're not implicitly
synchronizing things that didn't
necessarily need to be synchronized
they're two different types resources
for you too
to use in your application the first is
textures
which are simply format image data that
you use for
rendering for Sat for source data or for
rendering destinations
and our data buffers which are
essentially on Form added ranges
memory you can pick them I just a bag
bites to store your vertex data your
share Constance any output memory
from your GP workloads
the important thing to remember metal is
that the structure
above these resources is immutable you
cannot change it
once you create a texture a given size
are given level ever given format
its it's baked and this let us avoid
costly resource validation
that would previous have taken place and
other API's or we have to figure out
hey now that you've changed how a
texture is structured is it still valid
we still use it
as a rendering destination is it on that
map complete we have to do any of that
because you've specified at all
up front if you want to use two
different textures
with 322 different formats retexture you
simply create two different textures
and this is actually much more efficient
we can rapidly switch between ease
I on in the middle implementation
course you can change the content
textures buffers
and to do that provide several methods
so you can update data buffers directly
is simply get a pointer
to the underlying storage there's no
lock EP I need because again
running on a unified memory system and
for textures
we have what's called an implementation
private storage now that doesn't mean
that we're copying the data and moving
it somewhere else
this simply means that we will reformat
the textures for efficient rendering
on the Jeep you we provide some blazing
fast update routines
in metal to do that
if union a synchronous update routine
for your textures are buffers you can do
this to be the bullet
encoder and we'll talk in just a moment
about how that works
and one other thing you can do with
resources and textures in particular you
can actually share the underlying
storage
across multiple textures and reinterpret
pixel data
differently in each one so for instance
if you have a texture
that is using a single 32-bit integer
pixel format
you have another texture which is using
a four component RGBA
8 pixel format and they can actually
pointing at the same underlying storage
because the pixel size at the same
between the two
and you can also share the texture
storage with data buffers
the this will i you direct access to the
underlying storage with the CPU and to
use the underlying storage as a data
buffer
and we simply assume role in eel role in
your pics order in this particular case
okay those are resources now I'm a talk
briefly about the commanding voters
themselves
as I mentioned there are three basic
commanding other types
you have your render computer
template commanding cutters and I talk
about you to these in sequence
the first of the render mankiller have a
better communicator
you can think about this as all of the
harbour commands necessary for
generating
single rendering pass and bypass I mean
all the rendering
21 frame buffer object one said a friend
or target
if you wanna change to another set
render targets
to another frame buffer you simply as
another render
mankiller and its all the state for
specifying the vertex and fragment
stages
the 3d pipeline
it legit in early the state changes the
resources
and rock also net surfer instructing
your your pass the critically
there's no draw time compilation
you get to control the app developer
exactly when and how
all the state compilation an expensive
validation actually takes place
and you do that the series API calls and
state objects
and I'll show you just a few those here
as we talked about you have your depth
and stencil object
sampler objects the render pipeline and
they describe various aspects
love the 3d rendering state
basically almost everything fits in the
render pipeline for you
that respect for your shade urs your
your plan states all
higher for text as actually specified
and all that can fit into the state
objects
important to realize and metal is that
not all state objects are created equal
some other states are actually very
expensive to change and for these we put
them in what's called
immutable are unchangeable said objects
and can't change the state's after
you've created the object
these are the types of things that
affect expensive operation for cause
recompilation to occur so things like
the freight the shakers themselves
we don't want to be you don't want us to
be recompiling them all the time
so what you specify those interstate
object
can change them but other things like
the viewport says are actually really
cheap
to specify and really keep the change
and so those remain flexible
I talked a few times about how the API
was designed
with the a7 in mind and what are the key
ways
you can see this is and how we handle
framebuffer loads and stores
a seven GP you is 8 I'll days
deferred mode render I'm going to go to
the details of what
this means but one important peace that
is that it has what's called a tile cash
and it I'll cash is used at the
beginning and
and the beach rendering pass to to load
the contents
the previous frame buffer or to write up
to memory
and so you need some explicit control
over the style cash to get
optimal performance and make sure not
doing needless reads and writes the
memory
in metal you can specify load and store
actions on the framebuffer
to make this incredibly efficient and
I'll show you an example of how that
works here
so let's say as an example this is
before metal
you had one frame for what you wanted to
do to rendering passes
and this example your gonna pick the
color frame buffer gonna reader the
beginning
in a ride it out one pass through many
the same for the second pass
and you probably want to use a depth
buffer as well
to perform at all you can actually see
here there was quite a lot a memory
bandwidth taking place across these
passes
you end up with two reads and two rights
preacher the color
and the depth buffer which is a lot
memory traffic
well with metal reaction let you specify
which are those reason right you
actually need to occur
so for instance you can say well I'm
gonna render every pixel
love my friend anyway there's no point
in loading but I'll catch the beginning
a frame
I can say that family and and if you're
right out that the pass and then read in
the second pass
you probably would need to actually do
that but when you look at the depth
buffer you can see a lot
unnecessary reads and writes and so you
can specify that we should probably just
clear the depth buffer at the beginning
a frame
you're not gonna need its previous
contents and you don't need to write it
out at the end. a friend but you're not
using a second pastor simply gonna clear
it again
and then you don't need a ride up there
either and we can get some dramatic
reductions in memory traffic as a result
this you can you can reduce the overall
manner reads and writes
to a fraction what it was before you can
gain significant performance for your
application
this is just one of the ways in which we
design metal with the 87 mine
right that's rendering now in a look at
the next area we
interviews with metal functionality
which computer
so when I can I spend a lot of time
today talking about general-purpose
data parallel computation the Jeep you
but for those that you have done this
type of operation before
you're gonna find that this is a very
familiar runtime and memory mall
uses the same textures and data buffers
from
the metal graphics API's at the same
basic kinds a
memory hierarchy barriers memories and
love story you might find
other data parallel programming API and
you can scan figure in specify exactly
how
the work group for your computer
operations will be executed by the Jeep
probably more important to realize with
metal
is that it is the computer operation are
fully integrated with graphics
this means you get a unified API single
shading language
and a single set a fantastic developer
tools both graphics and computer
operations
on the Jeep you and probably more
important for performance
we can efficiently Intelli these
operations between compute rendering
and at a copper operations and bullet
similarly to graphics there's no
execution time compilation
with the computer operations you control
exactly when these
expensive compilation activities will
occur
and probably a little bit different from
how graphics looks
in metal there's very little state in
the computer commander
there some state for specifying exactly
which computer knows you're gonna using
and i cant figure workers and that's
pretty much it
and that's it if the computer command
cursing some parts because yes
and that brings us to our last command
in Qatar but commanding her
and this is what you use for a
synchronous got a copy between resources
on the GPO and this can happen in
parallel with your computer
and graphics operations you can use
estoppel textures
the copy data between textures and
offers or to generate your met maps
can also update the data buffers
themselves again topping to and from
textures are other buffers
and actually fill the buffered
themselves with constant values
simply man alright
that's a pretty API high-level summary
I'm a take a quick tour
shading language itself
alright so the mail shading language is
unified shading language
this means use the same language syntax
construct or changeable graphics and
computer processing
and it's based on C pas plus 11
essentially a static subset
this language and its bill out love LVM
incline which means you get incredibly
high performance an incredibly high
quality cogeneration for the Jeep you
the only thing we really had to do
was add some syntax for describing
certain hardware functionality
such as higher and control texture
sampling restoration
and we've added a few things to make
share offering much more convenient
such as function overloading and basic
template support
but that's it if you know C plus plus
you understand metal
shading language
they said we added just a few data types
and some syntax for handling graphics
and compete functionality
some basic data types you're probably
find very useful for just a ler
factor matrix types
and we use what's called the attributes
syntax to specify a lot
the connection between amelli PI and the
Middle shading language
so things like how do you get data in
and out of your shares you specify those
with function arguments and used
attributes and tax actually identify
which textures and buffers you want to
use or
how did implement programmable blending
initiators you can actually attributes
intact to specify
pixels you wanna read from the freemen
for
and I'll shading language itself is
incredibly easy to use its
but multiple shares in a single source
code file and then we will build those
source code files with Xcode when you're
building your application
into metal library files and the Middle
library files are sensually just and
archive
every male skaters with the metal
runtime API
you can actually load a metal library
and then you can finalize the
compilation into this device is
machine specific code we also include
awesome standard library very commonly
used an incredibly performance
graphics a few functions
one other thing to realize about the
metal sheeting languages you need to get
data in an out if your shoulders
so it's best buy use a method called
argument tables
to let you specify which arguments which
resources
which data needs to move between the API
and changing environment
so each command in Kotor will include
what's called argument table
and it is simply a list have the
resources you want to use an API did you
wanna read an access and right
in be share themselves there's one table
for each type resource
and then shaker and the host code
simply use index ended at able to refer
to the same resource
see an example on the right here
I simply have representation up one of
the commanding cutters
could be render commander for instance
and
you have a table in the command encoder
that describes
the resources so you have a allister all
the textures you want to use
initiators civil
tables exist for buffers & samplers I
simplify this little bit because there's
actually wanna be set the tables
free to the vertex and fragment later
stages let's take a look at an example
share
so this we have a vertex shader and a
fragment shader in metal sugar-coat on
the left you'll see
it looks quite familiar you'll get a lot
more information about how this works
and in accession
but you can get a good sense of how this
works just from looking at the code
itself right here
so in the private shade or were simply
referring to
texture at index wine to identify that
we would like to use the texture that we
set up
in the command in Kotor to read in this
fragment shader
and some early in the vertex shader we
can do the same thing with the buffers
and use those as imports to the vertex
shader and refer back to
the argument index table in the
commander you set up
the commanding coaters argument tables
with the API
and simply refer to those resources
initiators using attribute syntax in
function arguments cells
and that's it shading language actually
pretty simple
we think you're gonna really like it the
next I'm not talk about how to build
your mental application using our
awesome
developer tools and probably the most
important those developer tools
is the metal shooter compiler
now ideally you don't even know this
exists because we're simply going to
build your shaker sources just like we
build the rest your application sources
application built I'm there's no need
for you to separate
out your shoulders and specify them at
runtime you can actually
ship them with your application Rd
having been precompiled
there's no source code that needs to go
through application appreciators
probably more important from the
developers point of view as we can
actually give you errors and warnings
and guidance about your shoulders
at the time you're building your
application you don't have to wait
and tell your customers are running your
your game to find out that you have an
air and one on your shoulders
this is awesome O'Shea terse will then
be compiled
into metal libraries by Xcode and then
compiled to
device code at the time you create your
state objects themselves
so again there's no drop time
compilation and
we will cash this compilation spinal
device machine specific compilation
on the device so we won't be continually
doing even as last translations
now for those of you who like to specify
your your source code
at runtime perhaps you're constructing
strings on the flight we do provide
runtime: share compilers well that's not
be really useful for debugging
it too has no drive time compilation
overhead it operates just like
the precompiled headers but for best
performance
we generally recommend you use the
offline compiler we can give you the
most information
to help you build the best possible
shakers if you do it this way
let's see what this would look like so
here's an example you're building your
application in Xcode
and have a series love metal share files
and share files are past to the middle
computer compiler
compiler the mail share sources at the
time you build your application
and a metal library file is generated
that metal library file be package with
your application
and so then when you deploy your
application to a device
metal library file goes along for the
ride that application runtime
when you're constructing here pipeline
objects
you specify which vertex and fragment
shaders you'd like to use
from that metal library metal
implantation and will look up those
traitors
Steve Rd cash them once before and if
not will compile them for the final
machine device and send it to the Jeep
and that's it most this happens
automatically for you
critically exactly when you want it to
you
now few views are open GL yes debugging
tools in Xcode
you feel right at home we have an
awesome set GP programming
debugging and profiling tools integrated
right in tax code
and give you a quick tour those now
so this is an example application inside
tax code where you get
visual debugging tools bill right in the
same environment you're using to build
the restaurant location
on the left hand side we handle what's
called the frame Navigator which shows
you
exactly which metal API calls draw calls
I you you issued and in what order they
occurred and the Middle
you have the frame navigator sorry the
framebuffer view where you can actually
see
the results those draw calls and state
operations
happening live as you're constructing a
frame
we also have research few where you can
see all the textures resources
data buffers everything you're using a
constructor frame inspect them
and make sure that they're exactly as
you set them up
and at the bottom you can see the metal
state inspector where you can see all
the API state
and all the important it's a control and
information you have
about your application metal
we also provide some really fantastic
profiling
and performance tools so in this example
showing the metal performance report you
can see things like
your frame rate or how much you're using
the Jeep you
you can also see exactly which shade urs
are the most expensive
and you can see how much time they're
taking per frame
this is awesome you can you can also see
42 the shakers
in milliseconds which how much time
they're taking as a whole
but you can get a feel for exactly what
are the most expensive lines
each shares so if you wanna really
optimize your shares
you can find out which line is taking up
the most time
and focusing on that and all built for
you right inside a tax cut
now gap
glad you like it so you can also build
your
your shoulders as he said Incitec said
you can actually edit them as well you
get all the familiar syntax highlighting
& Co completion and you get warnings and
errors
right for you if i text to we think this
is really fantastic it makes
writing and editing and profiling
shakers a much more natural part the
process
and we design metal to work seamlessly
in this environment
alright so that's that developer tools
the API concepts
and shading language as you heard in the
Keno we've been working
with metal some leading game engine
providers
such as Electronic Arts epic unity
and Crytek and we've been amazed at what
they've been able to create
in just a short amount of time I'm very
happy
to introduce up on stage Sean Tracy from
Crytek was gonna show you
but they've never create with metal just
a few weeks John
thanks Roger
Crytek is known for pushing the
boundaries and for developing
blockbuster hits such as crisis arise
for the consuls
the CryEngine is going mobile and our
latest game the collectibles was
recently released on the App Store
integrating medal in a game gives us
opportunities and we didn't have before
and the other performance changes the
way we think about creating mobile game
play
and mobile game content today we'd like
to show you the next version the
collectibles
and show you how we use metal change the
game let's take a look
in the collectibles you control the
renegade team mercenaries in today wanna
during hit run mission to take out the
enemy artillery
as you can see the environment is
incredibly dynamic and very rich with
wind effecting education and more
looks like the enemy set up a roadblock
had pick up the Chiefs RB
Korea see can see that level up
cinematic destruction simply what
awful on mobile for when those jeeps
exploded over 168 unique pieces that
come flying off
the tires windshield engine block and
more
using the power metal were able to
leverage orgy on cash technology
at CNN rise on consul and there it is
our objective the enemy artillery it's a
pretty big mother so let's go ahead and
call in our AC 130 gunship prayer sport
T
geocache uses cash based animation
to realize extremely complex simulation
and special effects
advice on the destruction and those
buildings so other players make their
way to the next objective
take a look at another example of how we
can use this power
to turn the what environment into a
weapon
four-player something trouble ahead
yeah they got a tanker right we need to
block out that road get out here we're
gonna be toast
start taking up the chimney
and battle you stop a tank collectibles
when that building and Jimmy come down
there's over 4,000 raw calls on screen
4,000 draw called on an iPad up they've
got another tank and now im
we're at a chimney so mission
accomplished the get out here
at you to perform again with metal gives
us a ten-fold performance increase
that allows us to bring the Crytek DNA
alive
on mobile we look forward to seeing you
guys in the game
thanks a lot
alright thanks John that's really
amazing so four thousand rock also that
ten-fold increase
are was previously possible before model
we're truly truly
excited to see it in action alright so
that's metal
metal is our new low overhead
high-performance
Jeep you programming API which can
provide you with dramatic
increase inefficiency performance for
your game
we designed it from scratch to run
like a dream on a7 chip and our I was
products and we've streamlined the
feature set
and the API footprint to focus on the
most modern GP features
such as unified graphics and computer
and the most modern sheep you game
programming techniques
such that require fine-grained control
in addition multi-threading
support for precompiled Shaytards and a
fantastic set a developer tools
we believe you're going to have a use
metal great entirely
new class games for your customers
we're really looking forward to what you
guys gonna be able to create
with metal we think it's just truly
truly
fantastic thing for more information
about metal
you can come see are evangelist fill up
and Alan
and we have a amazing set of
documentation about metal
honored Felber Relations website you can
also check out the developer forms we
can talk with folks
about metal and you can come to the next
two sessions which were going to meddle
in a much
lot more level detail you can see how
Metalworks in your application how to
build your first medal application
how to build a scenes at a metal and and
used to control the Jeep you
how the middle shading language itself
works and and we have a second session
re cover some more advanced techniques
such as using multipath routing
and compute we're really looking forward
to what you can get to create this API
thank you very much for coming