low my name's Norman I like to give you
a quick tour
does on what's new in spike it so last
year we have announced break it
at a conference a high-performance 2d
game engine with building physics
support
we also built walls writings have axe
call to help developing improved their
in common
you to recent I'm like the particle
editor and automatic pactor outlets
generator and this year women's bracket
even better
we have awesome graphics technologies
like cedars
lighting their shadows the help you
really bring all the liveliness of your
game
we also have good simulation
technologies like per pixel physics
closure
physics feel in risk animatics and
constraints
I really allow you to build reach user
interactions so that's not all
UNESCO sex really is we now have a spiky
editor billion to the ides that allow
you to create
game scenes with a rating any cold I can
use the very same
editor to give iraq with any of the new
and existing spray kit features
talk with that so for the adapter for
the study session we're gonna start
looking at Hull to use custom satyrs to
customize the drawing behaviors of your
sprite how to add light English saddles
to your scene
and we have a lot on your physics update
I like to give your
update on and the uruguay show a scene
kid really bring
new possibility of writing to the games
he also blurs the lines between
the actual 20-game a three-game
implementations colossally I'm going to
give you a quick tour
and demo of the new spec editor and
some old improvement already existing
ATI's
so the first thing i wanna talk about a
shade urs
spray kit does a fantastic job of
distracting
the lower level platform peep and
graphics API is away from our users
but from time to time does this always
a very special effect the one achieve
see a custom Bloor
or a you keep the signature win a trough
or movies and the
the posse fact or when you build a space
game
where the space ship it taking a damn
and you want to have a custom were being
a factor
on a sprite cedars become a more
relevant solution in this case
and for this release we do give you the
ability so here we have a spectator time
all
we actually does run during a single
sprite without any pictures up but it
just but despite itself is running a
commentator's
so the sooner does a lot of things here
is running all the stars in the
background is also drawing the grade of
Applied working in fact off the grid
and also when the tax use user part is
any of the screen
areas as gonna provide a and the fact
solved is
a dong initiators too so to do this we
also passing
the actual touch locations topple the
Cedars uniform so initiator
Cedar Knolls okay you there just touch
this area now let's run to the working
here
i render the energy fact associated with
it so let's have a look at what overview
of a shaker look like
so seder hope you're really caught my
eye the way to spice it wrong
you have a hundred percent control of
whole every single pixels are gonna be
all put on the screen
the seders impact use a very few like
to. SL syntax
and they are very powerful tool to have
any of the the powerful you fact
image processing or to all the way to
fast motion blurs that the
that's been using 3d games I whether you
are new to strike at
or existing spiky users you can drop
this custom scenery and with just a
single line of code
sought to use custom cheaters
we create a brand new object SK cedar
object it is actually a cop a nod to
hold the G all
at all open Dr yes fragments later so
we're falling 30 0 SL
doping di oh yes 2.0 standard and
the ones here I to say they can be
deployed to both always 10
I'll ask so heroes are the list of a
know that's being supported and Spike it
so as case right now support custom
traders
ask a shape note now support custom
cedar samples
drawing the stalking and failing and
ASCII middle
so with the particle the fact you have a
custom changer
run the art every single you made a
particles in a scene
colossally the fact know to ask AC now
support custom cheaters
so that gives you the powerful ability
to not only use the sky filters
to have a force manufact but also you
have a sea turtle have any possible
in fact that you want to implement so a
source the Cedars getting uploaded to
the sprite is being run at the pixel
level
we also passing a lotta building
actually feels to a seder so you'll have
to
set up a brand new attribute our
uniforms and pass it in
so for example here we're passing that
you texture they give it to you as
what actors being used for the current
sprite as well as well as well as that
packs a cornet
and the size of the sprite that scene
pixel size
so hard to say to work in sprite kept
once you have
you know about after Taylor Potts now
eight
has to possible actual bills that you
can start of the first one is the Cedar
source
you can create a share from two
possibilities by attacking the source
why is creating the Seder from a a file
and also you can
said the Seder from us track & Touche to
resolve also have a
are real uniforms these optional by the
if you're shade or actually requires any
of the external parameters that being
said
your game you can use at ASCII uniforms
on the uniforms property so now once we
have the school property set
the Seder is loaded and is ready to go
and we have a saying here for example SE
has three separate sprites
you cannot find a satyr directly to the
scene you can I find
at the Cedar to any of the sprite and
the pick up the fact right away
in an xterm in an extreme
so create a seder will have the new API
I S case a dirty cash
cray with the file esposito was found
name way passing like blurred a FSH
by Seder is actually look like energy
opened OpenGL fragment program that has
a main function
I in the return value seventy of red
collar and it was a tourney than any
other custom uniforms
you can just set uniforms are a here we
creating I ski uniform uniform
I with name you give it a name here we
call you read
that's a floating type and the next one
we setting are your tax /url passing in
a sec the second retexture
to the concentrator so the supported
types are float
taxer back to two three or four and
matrix
to buy 2303 and format for
and for the full list of the Customs and
Border were passing into the Seder %uh
soon as you see there is getting run
here's the full list so in from the
uniform you get direct access to this
to the texture of the sprite the Spry
sizing from in pixels
the global time and continue to any
other animation from the callers are
shaped
and you also have access if you're have
custom cedar that's running on a shape
to the ship path land in terms of
varying
we passing the tax for cornet the color
makes
as well as the distance of the path and
we also have a very company a method in
a satyr so you can call directly
call escapee for sharing this is as if
you work let's break it to run their to
current sprite
and gimme the pixel value
of the car behavior
so the shooters are cool there some best
practices I like to call out
so number one I like to recommended
using
believe uniforms as much as possible so
we do passing a law to you too far for
you to use that gives you a lot of
raw at abuse of what we draw what we
doing at the open to: level
but if you do need to access all the
same uniforms
please use their building 12 minimized
the moderate honesty
and also or would reckon man to avoid
changing the status or so
in a maid of a frame because there were
four such a to recompile Asian happening
at a backhand also when the Cedars being
loaded
and you will recommend to loss at all
the uniforms Apr on
and you can change uniforms every frame
that's nice and fast
but adding or removing uniform also
called another Cedar Creek a politician
also in terms of drawl call performance
would like to share
the same same shade or yes there's as
much as possible because
the same say they're running our
monopole drawing yes there's gas to back
together
and will recommend to initial I the
Seder a long time
and unify the shade or using a file name
rather than
initial I say they're using string
because if the satyrs are
model traders are sharing the same
shooter source as practical pick it up
as a
a identical satyrs ok top at Dhaka
batting performers
will remain high so the summary of using
custom satyrs
allow you to completely customize the
way sprite
are being rendered on screen you have
brought access to a lot of the building
actually feels
that we're passing dow arm to the Seder
and he could create even a number of
kuwait uniquely fax for a game
next I wanna talk about lighting sash
adults
so lightings eyeshadows really play all
the liveliness of your game say if I'm
building a Dodgers game I'm walking in
the long corridor
all of Southern the area gets dark and
all is an ICA
at very p.m. a shaky light at the end of
the hallway that kinda
bring out that really scary atmosphere
and mood for a player
so too cradle I'd in spike at we
introduce
a new pipe cut XK light note you can
added to see you and position to
anywhere you want
and they can apply to any of the spray
that's being participated
in the car light you can change the
color
shadow a fall of all the light and with
support
up to having 8 life like for singles
right
and the bottom line is SK light no they
just another as keynote
you can move it around parent it when
another sprite if you want to lie to
follow wanna be a sprite
you can write actions on it have a trial
for all paths
is really cool so now let's look at some
other basic
at properties for SK like an old so here
we have a scene
it's very bland we at a light source in
a scene
now if we can't into the light colored
if it's a bit like a lot to be yellow
as a yellow camp to the collect collar
and now if we set a shadow color to be
gray
and now the boxes star casting shadows
and lastly if we wanna see a little bit
more of the scene
with seven Indian caller to really bring
in a sea of op
a little bit more so let's look at the
Addison your actually feels for ask a
line on
number one follow-up fall of controls
the the radius of the light
in bed in terms are be at the fact and
with also picked what works really well
with our physics
properties with the category B masks so
with sprite
note now you have individual big control
of whether the sprite is participating
in the lining
whether it's casting shadows or whether
it's receiving channels
you high-flying control of exactly how
you want to control these three
attributes
for each individual sprite
and now it seems we're talking about
spread out sprain old also have a brand
new property called normal pack sure
which you can I find all attacks or Web
so usually normal character is were
happily using 3d games
and not what actor accused the pixel RGB
a value to describe what a normal factor
for the services
on it works so the lighting calculation
can be can be used up all with the
normal
factors so here we using the exact same
for Miller
so to render the scene with a normal map
we use the traditional a plot be equal
see for Miller which means you supplied
the picture
supplied a normal catcher strike a chord
with magic
and gave you the result which is
lighting up the scene where
with the bumpy service that's being
mapped so here you
you as you can see I kinda sad normal
Patrick directly on a ask a sprite note
by loading at from the normal top PNG
file
to now be in spy kids: we like to make
oral
users live as easy as possible so in
addition to the a plot see
be equal see for Miller we get your
directly from able see
you do not need to supply and any normal
map so all we do is we take the source
packs for image a perform image analyze
Asian
on every single pixel one based on the
premise of each pixel
we have a multi-pass ok with them that
generate the best
normal map that describe the current
picture
so if you give us a picture that you
take from the beach was part of
rocks in the air rounded ads is really
sharp
yet the surf Israel remain very small so
here is very easy is magic one-liner
all we need to do a just sprite nah
attacker be called
generate a normal map from the existing
sprite picture
that's not all there's not a solution
or a one-size-fits-all solution so
e-edition would provide two more
problems for you guys to change the
dynamic behavior of the generate a
normal map
in from los mas mas in terms of contrast
which is whole
Pompey you wanna may surface to be and
this will give in combination give you
if in a number of lockhart for example
or cops tall
I just have to call for help running on
these two primers with 1 second delay
as you can see he actually change the
look you can get if in a number looks
all over
and the best part about automatic normal
map generation is
you can't do this on dynamic content if
you to take a picture from
all side and decide to put her in a game
guess what you can't light it without
any normal taxer
we can't do they all orders for you
so to summarize lighting and shadows
they are very easy to use
as K Line Road is just like any askin
all the camera animation on a
comparative
you can set up collars and everything is
a one-liner automatic normal map
generation really provide is dynamic
look for you you don't have to span
time sitting down with art isn't trying
to figure out how to hi I'm paying them
normal map
always purple facing all were dark grey
facing to the left
you don't have to do any of that we
would take over the nitty gritty detail
for you
either some best for practice in terms
of performance I like to play now
it's okay to have multiple light in a
scene under runs reasonably fast
but if have the number of flights
that's riding the very same sprite
actually matters
and you have more than two lights
lighting the same sprite
you mice not be able to stay our cost is
$60 on certain I O S on mars
just something to pop point out
Nexus I like to point out all the new
physics features that we have so that's
a look at them
number one per pixel physics updates we
have a
constraints allowed on remove the
boilerplate code
your updates we also have inverse
kinematics allowed to
field biomechanical way I we also have
physics field that
applied his forces are allowed to build
the next space game simulation
so let's look at the perfect offices
body creation
with the current implementation on the
left side if I wanna
build it cures game I kept
the best thing I can do is using parking
circles
I create the bombing circle are on these
boxes the skiers
they will actually quite each other and
appeared only in Turlock
okay maybe I configure the late a bit I
reduce the reviews on the fifth his body
for the
to keep my overlap but they still don't
toxic exactly and also the but the
the angular velocity don't transfer from
one cure to another
but now with a single line of code you
can generate from
go from there too give you a physics
I up pics pixel-based fit his body
it's very easy some
so will your trust back the source
cement a base on the alpha mask
we generate iraq shape and based on the
shape we generate exact shape that's the
minimum all
yell to fade occurrence right it's very
accurate
and now the bill gears them all you can
just have a couple one-liners
have the same code in there just changed
from using bombing sarcos to using
image-based his body and the you are
good to go and they can be
can't they can be transferring an
interlocking it's really fun
so let's look at how we do it so
with the curry PI to create a fitness
body you with the bombing box
visit was busy body and the body with
rectangle of size would give you our
exact on the box of the dimension that
you have specified
now with the new API as the same
initializer coming in
instead you just passing the texture on
the size of the texture
for example a hammer here we give you
the exact camera body that tree through
the all I you no longer have to
do that yourself or title bill any
opossum Mason on the faces body
just like the automatic a normal map
generation there's not a one solution
fits all
if you have a source are the has a lot
of semi transparent pixels
we do allow despised by the of us finds
of a threshold
which defines which part pixels being
interpolated during the process as a pic
or not
so in some rain per pixel fit his body
is read very easy to create and they're
very accurate
add whether you are existing spiky users
are new to
the API's it's just a matter of setting
one line change
you're a code to create really actor
physics simulations
so again like to point out the
performance tips
spike it does a really good job
optimizing this algorithm
I we provide a good balance between
performance at accuracy
by the picture size matters so you if
you are passing year a2k by 2k taxer
ask you live down to 10 percent
rendering
a twenty by two hundred by two hundred
sprite we do have to walk down the hall
to kept by 2k pics
pixels in order to figure out the exact
shape
I so just something to think about
next a brand new API the cost range to
help you
really a simplified a game up the logic
the country and motivational training
cost reprises to really im removed a
boilerplate
cold in your update so a lot of times I
wanna move a character
but I want healthy indicator to follow
the character that exactly five pixels a
ball
to pick those behind I need to put the
end of the summer
and you have a camera you wanna Auriemma
can learn the following airplane
guess what I need to add a cold and to
calculate the angle and
figure out the Delta translated bit of a
rotation as a translation
or the airplane wanna land on a runway
and you don't worry in that first
we do all that work for you can with do
it with simple contract
so now we add because the cost rain is
being added
we need to add some new features in our
update loop
so in up little expanded to some new
selectors
number one right after physics
simulation now
the scene start kicking in the
constraint soul customers are not
limited asx:
to physics anymore so you don't have to
worry about all with the character
expanding on a conveyor belt is gonna be
pushed over
because the box is right beside it
constraint take care of that for you
and right after class rank update user
have another chance public
doing another update we do gave use or
call back up did apply ka strain
so here you have a chance to do any
other last-minute cleanup
and the bases and constraints again have
a new object to ask a cost rain object
and is used to wrap around this
mathematical cost rain on the properties
of the know the one enemy
so the cost rains at their attached a
note via the new cars trains
RA and the scene will apply the cost
rains
to the attacks no so what kinda
construct an effect on a note
you can set cost rate composition or an
tation
and distance and can quickly able and
disabled between frames
so for example it will go quick example
of Bob Holt who
Korean to note cost frameworks so we
just call ask a constraint with
Warrington old initializer
and follow a note so here DA rotors for
following the circle and we're just
passing the circle yes nevertheless
keynote
and the reins of Saturday's 0 and you
can send I wanna leave the circle
following and/or
lacking at you have that possibility
so once the cost rain is created i jus
directly soccer sat on the air earth
arm cost ranch property
next call to reset positional constraint
so here we create a personal rains up
far minus a hundred to a hundred we can
first
set the limit of constrained on the
x-axis this will limit the moment
in the x-direction of the No now we can
also sat on the y direction they will
give a limitation on the y-axis
and if you combine these two together
you are limiting the movement of the
current node to out to 100 back 200 box
very very simple to use you no longer
have the right all these update code
that will manually snapped the object
back in the box
so in summary it really hope you remove
a lot of the boilerplate cold
making sure you just try to call the
focusing on building the game you want
rather than
having to fix up things and also the
because the cost ran to the is our rainy
that
you care add the ER the cost model
constraints into the same Iran and order
of evaluation happens from
well is based on the order of things are
going to direct I we also offer a lot of
varieties of constraint position or
orientation
and distance
next I like to talk about numerous
kinematics is usually a very strange
word for people who doesn't have
I are a mechanical engineering degree of
people happen
returner animation engine three members
kinematics
allow you to use can manage the
equations to solve
the joint problem occurs if you have a
drawing hierarchy trying to reach for
things
in a 2d space so here I am trying to use
the robot arm reaching for where my
mouse cursors pointing
and I want to set up the exact behavior
of Hall robot will move
I magnin to do than your update yourself
and try to do as every frame okays easy
to move the hand and now what does the
the lower Hannah's gonna do
I followed by what is our brands gonna
do to provide a realistic
behavior so you can do this for arms and
you can't do this for lax
you can do it with plan with the
animation
so number one abusing a schematic thing
you have a joint hierarchy
so for example if a look at a robot arm
it's a drawing of three pieces
we start with the our problem that's
the root node followed by the lower arm
which attach as a child to Darbar
and I'll have the claw which is attach
other child
to the lower arm to not use of these
joints to create real estate look
I need to set up some cost rain for
example
my are my all bull probably opens at 180
degrees
and close up 30 and anything beyond the
Rangers gonna snap I can't take it
anymore
I am so you can set up the cost ran for
each individual notebook
create that really realistic behavior
so with bracket how do you do inverse
kinematics all the way I set up the cost
rain how do I setup the parent-child
hierarchy
you don't have to do that because we use
the existing single out there already
have the parent-child relationship
and we are good to go the only thing in
your set-up a setting up the cost reins
of how each client's open and close
create a realistic look that you want
and we provide actions to drive these
cars trains
other track so that's why Israel case
there are you think a point
so by default Inc appointed .5 .5 I may
live
realistic format shoulder obvious at all
0.5 r0 land 0.5
so the cost rather we sat as call ask a
risk of strain of Dec
is simply have to property the lower
angle Amanda upper angle limit
once you have the school angles
specified
you can attach that to any of the SK
know that in the scene
and now we have a perfectly working
drawing hierarchy hauled away
drive it to drive it would provide SK
actions we have two variants reach to
know
I reached to position so if you wanna
restore
a moving target on a stationary position
within the scene
you can use I they're all the variants
that's being specified
so here have a quick example of
one-liner
writing running the ASCII action of
reaching
a constraint so here we have a simple
Ford three joints
constraint is constrained a 2.0 have
across rate of opening from 0 to 180
degrees as you can see when the mouse
moves
he actually obeys the cost ran a tight
not to over ban
and but really give you that realistic
look of
mechanical Bell mechanical me I
and now we also take the same embers
kinda Matix
calmer too sweetie a place much much
more interesting but it's also very
closely implemented just like this by
Cape
API's we have escaped I see I K cost
rain
and he still has a ask it cost rains RA
you can say discuss radar
also have a animation influence factor
so here
just give real a quick demo have a 3d
scene
with the 3d character playing a part
animation
nothing is and nothing else and running
but now with I K running I K Camp
Blanding
are top of the animation playback at 60
frames per second
making sure the hand is always Ponting
and a red party
so now imagine a possibility of I'm
building a pennis game
all I now need is 20 nations why is that
back panel and for paddle everything
else are light
I keep a caravan so I don't have the
field but given the number of animation
combinations for the game
also have the realistic a lot so that's
really open up
a lot of opportunity
so in summary I you working americans
really easy to use
you don't even need to set it up the the
scene crop take care of it
at a cost rains can be set on every
single drawing they have you got caught
on the opening and closing angle
and to drive these chains users run a
single action one-liner
tell the going to resell for position
Arnold
next wanna talk about physics field
now physics feels our type of your
forces
the applied the generator forces to the
object that's being part of the scene
so here I am having a space cannon
launching of cannonballs
that interact with two different real
gravity field
as you can see as the cannonballs gets
closer to the planet
the thank D Alene your where at the
linear acceleration gets covered in two
angular velocity and
star orbiting the planar shows how
so we use the feels personally Anne
physical feel forces
and feels can interact was the fifth his
body that's in the region
and the reason is the place where we
define the field effect area
and we have a lot of different feels
less provided as this release
but the ball pen of them so when does
feel
get updated so number one I need to have
feel knows
in the scene graph they're just like any
ask a naughty cat add them to a scene
you can run action on them as well you
can pattern it when other sprite
so you want to have I really big cookie
planet
you to add every to grab the field as a
child a move that could be planned in
Iran and India
the field is gonna for follow it and
even after this body that's located
within the region
and a bit mathematics is the interaction
was are happening
now the cutoff feels feels would provide
the law to prohibit ers are you
allowed to get the exact look and
different interactions for you
what you can't control number one reason
that's
the area of the fact of whole big of the
area want
the field to interact with you there
with
now the strength you come by in
combination of all of
controls what's the magnitude of force
that's being applied to eat some
individual object that's in the field
I minimum radius as just a clamp 3ds and
a bit
mask can be used to differentiate which
fits his body you want to interact with
this field or not
now let's look at the region's that's
key regions defined the area of the fact
for this particular field
the reason defies this DC area in 20
space
by default it is infinite and you can
create a rectangle circle are you ok
with region from CD path
began to a lot of complicated operation
on them like
in bird from track Union intersect so
far from here on building
I'll earth here and their real gravity
are on earth
is you can see is pouring everything
towards the center
so you have this into physics bodies
feels kept also interact with
bracket particle effects so as long as
you said the field bit mask on a
particle in fact
every single minute object particles can
interact with the field so here we have
a noise field out playa coherent noise
force
to you so that you made a particles
now let's look at some other the basic
feel that's been provided so
everyone can to get a feeling of what
feels
are really looking like
so by default would provide the
basically no gravity field this is just
to simulate Earth's gravity
in one dimension I can change in the
direction many times only for co-op
they were attracted the object at a
correct location
a second if I wanna similar laid a space
game have a plant ariane
gravity a fact we have the real gravity
of you know they can't get you can use
for example here too object carries a
linear velocity but I when the rates
close to the orbit
I billion a gravity coming into I
angular velocities org BRK actually
Korean I get around the
the planet we also have a Springfield
this is imaginary fielder the demanding
every single object in the scene
in the field actually have a spring hook
from land and attached to the north
so here you can see there being of the
late it back and forth
I we also have noise field that apply a
coherent
noise force to every single object
that's being
participate in a scene
an elective feels a particularly cool so
imagine YouTube dog have targeted
positive charges a negative charges and
here we have
a you like to feel that carries
positive target and positive charge
tracks
objects with negative charges i repel
object with the same card so here rad
particles
are red can answer actually wanna carry
positive Kartik at repel the way
and the green ones carries the negative
charge and being a track and
in Iraq with the electric feel
to feel that would provide physics you
with us building blocks is like Lengel
see
feel free to interacted with the I'm
build combine them together
to get combine them up together to have
a big building blocks
I eat on the field to interact with
different field
so for example we found wanna
implemented one variation of the Lorenz
a tractor I can simply have for magnetic
feel sitting right by each other with
opposite charge
and what happens if I send a particles
through the field that's what it look
like
for which is very cool
thank you
so in some rain the feels a very fast
they're very efficient
we have a brand new implementation for
and we actually have a lot of
spend a lot of them as a cipher on this
feature
and you can use fielding interact either
physics bodies a party cause to have a
really fine interaction experience for
the user
and you can also use feels to interact
with other feel to have a comp
combined effect next i wanna talk about
integration I think it
we work really closely together with the
sink a team to make sure we have the
best possible experience
a brain 3d content into 20 games
so here we have a demo spaceship is in
3d object that scene that will be seen
as a mother to
same as the asteroid last seen a 3d 3d
optimal brain
into debt to the background
so the immigration bring your
possibilities to
developing to the game so we can now you
can't official E
includes week of animals fighting games
you can't control
any of the 3d object just like any other
ask a naughty can run action on it and
run scale
you can make it fall path are you make
any 3d manipulations
aids deeply integrated of the two
Fremont yet we remain loosely coupled
as two independent I am solutions for
the game developers
so is render very efficiently together
think it is rendering
directly into the open GL contact when
are passing when are rendering to
texture and the passing tax R&B
financial framework
this is a very efficient solution
so the bring 3d coffin into toward the
base games
we create a ask a 3d known it is the
toll free bridge
allow it to incorporate any 3d
continental spiking based games
so once you have sk3 naughty cat
attacked any of the st. in scenes
to this ass case we know you know the
fight to render in this
SKC once you have the as he is seeing
you can set
essence in property I S case we denote
and the all-star using this
CK render in our in the past
so how do we create as case we know we
have the initializer create a scene old
where three or four sides you specify i
sat excise
you can attach to any of the ass unity
in a scene casings are sinking of Jack
through the as he has seen property
you also have access to Essien no which
gives you the point of view all were two
people camera
all if there is a camera where's the
pointer why the camera looking at the
current scene
and everything doesn't have any lighting
you can use a one-liner automatic
although we enable the for lighting that
will to wrong at the fall I to the scene
so all the objects a property let
so here's a quick example gonna add a 3d
a Leo from a COLLADA following to ask a
scene
we just call it gets really know
initialize without the fall your part
Lauder St Encino that said a senior
added to
added to the SKC now the 3d alien object
is going to appear
now you think we should also gold both
ways spike in now powers all the tax a
need for C can as well as South
so you can use any spray kit texture
object directly all seen care
but including all the tools we build
from the last version
which is the automatic tax for Apple as
generation with an axe or
as well as that procedurally generated
lot of normal map
weekend you to automatically generate a
normal map but iraq any 3d object
and the fact looks really really cool as
regular I think it also share the same
audio playback interface
so having the innovation within the
toll-free much really really
add a lot of possibilities here you can
have another level interaction with your
user for example have a cough and
background of three also the UCR 3d
object flying on the screen
is actually making user having of a
third perspective
of what a game look like last year i
wanna talk about
tools here so for ask 06
we have released a brand-new spiky
editor
it is part of actual release and you can
use it to create
any of the game scenes without reading
any coal you can also use it in Iraq any
of this bracket features
international everything you have seen
here today
can be down instead of biking editor
without writing
any lines of code a forces you also
switch to are thank you
he also be able to you to ride the
data-driven
a model raining games usually deal with
a lot of data
and we want to shift focus from focusing
on designing one level
rather than have a generic approach of
data oriented programming model
so now always cranky at a fair we
actually separate the game content from
the game logic
so you no longer have to manually add a
spaceship
Saturday be a tent and along to the game
compiler
lost a game and I'm about five petals of
maybe I'll
at if I pixels and it picked all the
getting work all of your uterus and
process
I we also provide a simplified game
template
that simple so swift and objective-c
so although the box your good ago and I
have a brand new
seem created for you ready for drag and
drop in play create your level
and making sure your game is running on
day one
not only you can use Preki added her as
a editor you can use it as a bee partner
as well
so if you're in the middle running your
scene wanna be your ship becomes missing
you can use this one line of code is
paid the in the debugger
you gather SKS file I guess what you can
load that back in ice cold I see what
was going off on ice in the neutral back
exactly we'll see her ricky is
so in the case of say if the spaceship
to hear them because it is the order
you can totally see that within the ACO
and if you have existing game that not
even written
for the door in a programming you can
use the same line of code of your life
out
and even you to retouch it or adding
new features dragging the waco and use
the editor and add new features and
they are ready to go
so some other basic features that would
provide respect the editor allowed to do
basic object manipulation a placement
they include position
or am patient and scale you can set up a
fifth his body is
Bonnie box pong sarcos are you in a
brand-new per pixel physics
set up you can bring a 3d content from
qualified
directly into a $20 seniors saving and
loading game
I see the 3d object and ready for ready
to be manipulated
an we can set up your shadows on
lighting your fax line numerous
kinematics
because I mean a schematic a joint
hierarchy right inside
echoed and preview that a factor right
here
we also providing integrated shave your
editor allow you to have a Weezy where
give fact
of adding your shoulders and 20 share
uniforms
so I'm gonna give you a quick demo
so from Monday's talk busted up the
Union demo hopefully you have see how to
use Pekka editor to create
his body set up for pics of ethics have
illusions and also in Iraq with few
forces
and 3d object so from Monday's talk
busted up the Union demo hopefully you
have see how to use Pekka editor to
create
his body set up for pics of ethics have
illusions and also in Iraq with few
forces
a 3d object so today the topping I'm
gonna cover is how to use
spike it added her to set up lights
shadows
using inverse kinematics haha use the
building she there at a tear to quickly
to reduce haters
with us have a look so here
we have a brand new lighting thing so
nothing here
and ready to go I'll if you click
in the Object Library this give you any
existing textures that in the current
project sorry fighters dragging ok
almost all
and I can make it slightly bigger
anatole see any of the spike it with it
you just open
object library here and because we're
adding strike a scene is contact
sensitive
no's these artists backing of Jack
that's relevant for this
others editing experience now as drag a
light im
doesn't know quite what I want yet
because I haven't let yet
as you can see the lighting mask that we
have on the sprite
a cobblestone is not set here for said
to be one
you see there right away no colder
writing nothing
sorry for saying this file loading your
scene this is exactly what you're gonna
get
because spec added her actually use a
spike it writings on tobacco
so now we can move to see around will
delight a row
as a defining a fact and now it's kinda
to the yes camp Landis
maybe we can change that texture so we
can automatically generate a normal map
on the fly
say from my make stole a base sharp but
also have a big contrast
I can do that as a two numbers
and if I wanna make a slightly in the
name and
too sharp my look very discomfort walk
all
so fire want to have lower that that's
slightly more subtle look and if I moved
at
object for ron is can see the light real
feel like the mouth let's go ahead and
add
a storm object here
a little bit to bake that make a smaller
and I want the stone to be lit as well
so let's settle any mass two-b_-one
same as the same object
okay am because the law we want to have
a maybe a
a 3d Lockhart as maybe stone will need a
cash adl's we just need to
sectional mask on that move it around it
and now weekend change some properties
applying so I can change that light in
color
well that's a little weird
something normal ish warm color is the
way to go
so there hustlers you hear the File Save
the scene is ready and you are good to
go you don't have to
to ask a line 0 the in net added 14
position he called
non-black so very cool
from necktie washoe is humor schematic
so here I have a pre-assembled robot
I'm just gonna give you a quick a review
so here I have Armada Jack
Armas para they directly to the scene
for the RR
the lower arm as attached as a parent
for
upper arm and have a claw where iPad
to the lower soul to what are set up
humor schematic for this robot I just
need to start simulating
solak these object
an ACA I can run in a schematic on the
robot
reins of the editor and to see how a
setup
and if you want that doesn't look quite
right maybe and you to set a little bit
of constraint on their
maybe annual limit to say ninety-degree
200 ATT grateful dead right
and you can have the same effect
as you can see actually respect many
will not over a band arm
the all so that simmers kinematics
very easy to set up again you don't have
the right any lines of code
to see the quarterback on use any of the
features here
but i wanna go over a shade urs your
shoulders
is very easy so here from that which it
lybrand I can does polling
a solid color of Sprite here happened
have
hey custom share Nana can run Holloway
said a concentrator
specchio added automatic process the
workspace a figure out how many FS it
file that you have
so here have a single one I said that
ample
I'm good to go so
this is only half the equation to
actually
the the eatery shakespeare's is even
better
to hear if I wanna make a change to the
satyr
I just Colleen the assistant editor
if I just click on the object n knows
what shade or use
a bring up the sheeter source side by
side ready to
added you ready to make changes a
monetary whole workspace
so now if I know this the the
3ds are the center of the circle I wanna
shifted a little bit
save exchange 2.2 I'm point2
and then what happened usually you need
to rebuild your application
injury run the application the
application will upload new cedar
to open to: drivers to your driver will
compile whether
if you forget a semi-colon guess what
you start the process again
here you just needed to file safe
so if I make of an automatic say for me
reverted back to .5
5 File Save see the live change right
here
I what if I decide to add a brand-new
uniforms
to the shade or so here I wanna at a be
the primary so I can control
the fact that I'm having here so if I
save that
guess what you have real opened y'all
penalties in the air
Writing Center max code so here because
I introduce a new uniform
that is not being been cleared for the
decoration of current I'm fails
Anne the two the to other places that
reference
talk aren't I'm will fail as well so how
do we fix that because we're at his new
uniform
at school had at that in a dictionary
so because we calling it you speed will
make sure to name matches
you speed and has a value of $0
and about change that one I see that
live in fact a ride
in the editor and make a spin faster
both ears okay let me go slower
saw live CD ratting riding subway
the less the demo of all respected
editor
lastly I wanna go over for me additional
improvements that we have done to the
existing spike a priori API's
so for those available and Neal to spike
it here's the brand new
updates clock that we have done for this
year
as the frame starts we start with up
they function so this is where you can
sample game logic
after that see more starting value
actions
after the actions i evaluate it user get
a call back
thing okay if I animate are moved as of
Dec from A to B
do I need to do anything else after the
actions
physics kicks in and set up the
physically step in for the Frank
once physics simulations finished user
get another call back with this
personally physics
this is where you can set up say and the
player gets pushed off
maybe I moved back by another five
pixels
and now with the brand use sconce crazy
P I we adding
a scene will apply ka strains right at
this moment
of the cost trance are being applied
user get another notification
up with did cut apply constraint and now
we also add one more selector for user
to react on cockpit finish optic this is
absolutely the last stop before us break
a package everything up and send it to
the
graphics to view for the conference
let's break it renders the car frame and
the same loop continues
sixty times a second now asking texture
got delayed the revamp here weep
introduce a new type of picture
commutable taxer
you can create from data can be modified
very efficiently
every frame we provide a call back block
allow you to make
modification to the raw pointers so here
if I'm just
make it tended to the raw pixel data you
can set that
so if you have a really core CPU based
post-processing in fact you wanna
modifier
attacker you have the freedom to do that
if you want to have a custom
data you wanna Senate wash Eder as the
input by setting up a
all the betas taxers you can do that as
well
also SK taxers can generate nooit noise
textures now
degenerate coherent noise that gives you
that lard and noise factor farmers fear
so it's a for both the noise generator
in the crease kill color
grayscale or the color of it events
generate some noise factor
we have to stay in there that the color
of what specs but here to create the
that noise factor just call picture with
noise with you can control the
smoothness
as well as control the size
nice kiss shape known also receive a lot
a revamped this year
so we had a calming and constructors for
commish a plainclothes rectangles
circles eclipse and splines
we also allow you to set picture
shade urs football's the skulk and fell
for the actual shape you can use shape
no to interact with your physical well
if you build up is a very complex com
complex shape
are using shape note you can just access
the past property directly
and then get a CD past send it directly
to physics faces or quit his body for
you
we've also made creating can join much
much easier
for with ask a physics bawdy we now have
a new property copy and
to can object to
another object you just need to set one
property so here I have a big year
I wanna pin it to the board I just set a
property to yes
speckle figure I'll all the parents the
commercial space on whether the other
dog has his body with Pixar followed
that detail for you
very cool now in addition to can join
well sold make
creating well joined really easy so
well joining a just the same as pain
joint which means Pennycook yes
by the fact that allow rotation my means
I'm
welded to my parents here have small
beer
they'll be welded to the big year so we
set to properties
and the physics on Mac is set up for you
e-edition Phys body can now be created
using
copies as bodies on you to do is just in
SK
for the body where the new nikolai the
car body with bodies you pass in RAR
the different phases body shapes and for
example hammer here
is campaign always two rectangles of a
top 10
and handle
now ask it after Alice aids our
one of the key component to allow user
to you have efficient
graphics performance so anything that an
attacker Alice
we allow OpenGL to do you fish in
batting here
so it's now support football's spike in
sync and
with poor balls right now a non-resident
not resolutions
so if you have a game and have all the
asset putting in my folder
the tax for Apple a generator will
separate them for you so you don't have
to pay the memory overhead
if you're loading the passer alors on
Iran a device
and you have to lower their now reno
asset also support
the for 32-bit pixel format and also to
compress 16 for Mac
now one of the big changes way announce
a prop 24 K by 4k resolution so it's a
simple
are changed in the axe call settings for
your project
yet this shit we support runtime:
patcher Apple as generation
so if you have a downloadable content
same use a dollar on a new level
everything is coming along files or user
take
go out to take some pictures and decide
to use action game askew map
you can to simply passing to basket
after Apple's API
and we'll automatic a stitch it for you
and tremble to not turn
trim to mop too transparent pixels
so in summary we really have a lot of
new features packed in this year's
spec a release we have a lot of cool
graphics technology like
compensators lighting and chattels we
have really course immolation the fact
like inverse kinematics physics field
per pixel physics and cost right
all of these features can be down using
one-line
are no lines at all if we use the spiky
editor
for the spec editor is a new edition to
tackle family and is really cool feature
how in car to
use it and it's also a good learning
experience to see how any of the new
features in iraq was eat with each other
within a scene
and we can't wait to see what you can
come up with all these technology and
tools we provide
for this release so with a Sat if you
have any questions or feedback or
anything you wanna see in the future
you like to you can't feel free to
contact our
developer evangelist Alex Shaffer have
Philip
ily ask you and we have a revamped
revamp the spike it programming guide
that's on the developer portal
so you wanna pick up the documentation
for these new features they're already
there
and for release this session right after
the session is the best practice of
beatings bracket games
we gonna go into stepped-up what are the
best performance practice as a whole set
up a game right in order to use these
new features
an set up for scale ability
and as I said before we worked really
closely with the sink 18
making sure think it is also a
high-level arm 3d API just like spike it
highly encourage you to tackle the
stinky sections for tomorrow in the same
room for two sessions
and with less at thank you very much
this at the end of Sakha
we gotta have the address above great