hello everyone my name's sake I have the
pleasure of managing the scheme
modest team I'll I'm here to today to
start to offer the best practices from
will expect
game so we're gonna start this off with
talking a little bit
but this respect it one-years-old I am
you guys from eight thousand news
bracket and I'm sure you've seen from
successful ones out there like
100 balls for example even achieving
that the top on Fri spot
so what you guys have done with it is
absolutely amazing
and we hope that from the new features
without it really gonna help you make
that next game
so let's go through with the stocks can
you about
we can discuss
skill-building best practices to help
you save on costs you develop your game
and also set yourself up for the future
we can talk about
game structure best practices and then
nikka go talk to you about performance
prospects
so did Australian to skill ability to
strike sis
so what i'm talking about here is
setting yourself up
so that you can add content to your game
with the smallest possible cost
so you can collaborate with the rescue
team
and also perhaps work better for the
future
learning polytechnics so all the
problems vacancy as a as a
beginning in developer I used to be one
of those
is you get really excited and so you
start on this idea that you have
in a mean the ideas right you want to
get your game going as fast as possible
sea diving hard code everything's done
in one scene
all orifices done in the one placing
code
a hard code level 1 level 2
was be more work to make a difference
level 3
looks the same cuz face it you just did
copy and paste
and well you probably stuck on all four
you thinkin different asking time
probably going to copy and paste again
the second problem is you tend to get
tempted
to write data as code
and here's just an example of some you
could get stuck doing
even inspected on suspected as is
actually probably look fabulous but
you like a circus another API your
encoding things like the position your
nodes
inside code your including rotations
you're probably when encoding the number
of objects you have
in code maybe encoding properties like
me.
point to get what types units are the
colors
in code and we end up with is that
you may change Rs its meaning in the
coat
right so now the artist and the code
above admitted to the same time
the only visual feedback you get miss
you build run
radiation talisman worsened and you're
forcing you to sign this reprogramming
scares
the data code 22 games I'm on the second
level here
you also duplicated structural code and
court date is not very efficient I
they're they're better way to describe
data
namely they up I'll and also targeted
collaboratively because
you're probably doing this at its in the
same and more mm file
for all the changes so artist has
changed and our asset
11m file change so when you first tosses
to look exactly the same as
game designer changing browner so
the solution while
you get a separate game content from
game logic a storm touched on earlier
you wanna separate few structure from
assets
so structurally she might be different
from the actual artwork delivered
annual separate data from code we also
wanna make sure you visualizing as early
as possible building on its not the best
system in the world done so
implement solution
consists of opening game logic in my
scene but I am referencing that here
because that's what you get
template you for two games structure
inside the think it's your life up
the my scene SKS anybody seen
affect in several SKS files but you're
referencing and if you can decide car
dealer
we are fantastic former cop you lift
which is XML
on at and buy me when you deploy so the
tools that we provide for you to do this
in Xcode 6 israel's have a strike a
template both objective-c
and swift editor as long as or earlier
let's give your feedback official
editing she because media
and you can also add a.m.
simulate if it's clutch
we also have and have had for a long
time the ability for you to add a purist
files
inside Xcode as a simple screening
appeals follow
adding a raise dictionaries to them and
reading them back in you could a super
simple
so no show you a demo love respected
public
and how easy it is to get set up but the
wrong way and the right way
okay so let me show you here
my very rushed example making a
sorta topple over the towers game
so I made a a little hammer throwing him
here
a store that totem and I get score
are so excited I'm making this so I just
threw everything
its overusing Inka
I'm sure another you ever see this for
arm
you see here on reference York right
inside the scenes file
I'm sitting positions things into new
properties
so I got this going to quickly and it
seems is totally wrong for you to do
whatever you do to make money and get
success is great
I'll just can provide an alternative so
this ran that the job that's great
however you could structure this
slightly differently so here have a
scene
which first-world with Richard operate
in a similar fashion
okay yep
the same stuff used to using game
what I've done here so use the spark a
template
which provides you start of
Sebring code and affect
lucky you're gonna see is right on this
line here
game scene archive from file seems kinda
cool
what's actually happening well the
template here has set you up with
something to meeting you guys that we
have the already using from foundation
school and is keyed archiver the value
load
save all data this release see
perspective so
this a super special people magic that
we doing here
we're telling Ricky darker to replace
any instance
SKC with their own class
listening for any occasion that you laid
you can make it automatically load
on own info so now is time logic
together with assets
even the time separately
okay I was going to the actual games
here
noticed the setup level one here is
markedly smaller than it was in the
previous example
soul what's happening here well we're
using
spike its powerful search features to
Newry
through the continent seen and by green
upon no names and conventions with you
artist
you can make it really easy to pull the
logical a metallic sheen
by name and her team up to code here
we've said this total and we can attach
children
based on level 1 so let's go through
senior
this is the basic structure over this
first
fee it's a base it's got a background
political empty note here which I mean
totem
so in code I'm going to load up the
scene
in effect the node called for them
at that node I'm going to tax level on
level 1 looks like that
so separated out the structure the theme
which is like game
with the content too little on which is
just stack
and continuing the stream land
I do my game logic I keep using names
in order to value whether or not enough
to totem
this means that artist in that incident
what Dec not mean totem
I'd love to see the don't affect the
scoring game
just just a simple example what we
should do
to separate out game logic from the
dealer
okay pics
okay
let's recap so you saw spec a template
what we're doing is
we're taking see file which in this case
is my feelers care
and your basic code files from isolates
mice in the a.m I was a free Apple Logic
from the assets
the key here season is keyed on archiver
something you might not be familiar with
already you insert
the class replacement in this case part
that class my senior class for class
lame
sqft this replaces any reference
between inside the scene for with your
own class and to support up
so it's going to be in such a
perspective
you see an example motivation here's
course get your game running on the
first day how are you know
games fun if you're not playing soak it
up a million for state you want do this
without compromising on
skilled earlier don't rush into it and
set yourself up to iterate
collaboratively
designs from the designer supporters
from the artist coaters
on me all the above so
make a genetic level assertion example
make it simple you designed it to commit
to wear
the general gameplay is gonna happen
what objects interacting with what
add place all the content go through
that shortly
a competitor action so this is you as a
coder
and the designer working out when it
records from it to be there it again was
working
and then of course easiest part of to so
finish the game alright said
make your to next level this should be
logically up only
so if you don't have the art work right
now don't worry about
place markers what you think conference
meant to go
so if you have action going from left to
right well
struck UCLA please mark as we think the
heroes going to begin
name Mr Trujillo place market for you
think enemies are gonna start out in
seem
pollen in the NE and any logically
enough
for just platforms on the the background
when measuring Opportunity Act that the
in the background when you move on
you place on the content is often what
we called red boxing
so pick a colour
but you like for your heroes blue
perhaps is perfect at them
colored sprite nodes don't bother will
text you right now
just put them in the right spot right
size
is the key to your artist but you saying
I want this to be
roughly the size over here like this
artist going on the cruise yet
okay now make her
Childress ca2+ soap ArticleMS locations
if you're making a train game
is highly likely that's ok is gonna
clouds look back
and that's what should probably leave
with the train set that up as a parent
child relationship
next up
hook up the attractions so this is the
past
where you're going through the physical
attraction from the sure they're right
so for example if obviously topple over
argument to stay absolutely put on the
hit by
hammer for sale sort out the collision
of
which are determined to track which and
make sure it's in like this
right within the scope right from the
start the league game logic working
and this is really in this lets you see
lodging in large together so you using
those names that you set up in seen
you hooking them up to search code
within your
actual game code and
we had a placeholder inside the sample
before
with totem we loaded the level seen in a
place that where the totem empty locator
was
this is where you wanna do that so
here's a sample of me having the scene
structure following
on one side little secret on the right
and I'm just making sure that I
Michael matters what I think the
structures so
of course just taking up the probably
not gonna make you gain great and fun
you can make sure those to him what its
need to be doing and they've got units
that floated
scores and similar things there to lodge
complaints
within you seem to do this is one which
is on first load
which called in it with coder and is
going to get called automatically
by the key to knock over second one is
did move to you and this is when you
present yet as
seen on the rescue solar
jump into the details that so on first
load as a set automatically
called by a mosquito not cover as
reloading fight Chordata
sound for example AI or any unit stats
are gonna change
it's called in a coder make sure you go
super in it
in it with coated depending upon we
should pick of the
and load up the enemy stats here had
sliders and
a slurry from Felix very simple as the
one-liner
next up you can move to Europe
on first shown in the slices point this
is Colin SK view
present scene is called with your scene
and this is a great place to cash your
visual elements
so SBC is gonna
it loaded by the King archiver and all
the visual elements
PNG's the reference again the allotted
well before you get to hear
so you can actually be quite a bit of
work inside new to you
without worrying about a lotta loading
costly things if you have a lot of
visual on its a contract with
catch them right here in this case I'm
finding all the enemies
and unseemly in Miami re
some motivation
for doing this the site you want to have
a simple way taking a logical com1
and have a lot to code they're two
different methods for searching
child node name fursuit for finding a
filament and enumerate child nodes
with name from I'll and test results I
really cast
you saw
in the previous lives just a quick can
Research Center
might not have been parent to you first
we have an extra
style search you seen which this case
will slash slash
any what that means is fine
all enemies from the router personally
down
examples here hero which is find a child
called here without
percy flashlights hero would find all
the notes and hero
in riker's order we can also search by
class not a single class
sickness last session with the node fun
all the middle notes
in your city and you could also use
club style partial matches such as the
wild card here
where it's anything any known named
starting with P
super powerful and this is going to be
your best way lodging up
of hooking up your logical seen with the
actual game code
and obviously that's what we did
in the sample so before you can see
child not remain
being used extensively find it objects
within the scene
inside the gate code is very fast you
can do it often
but we do recommend cash results if
it possible from but last step on this
great loss over the phone
easy they'll is the game
that's totally up to you course at the
artwork
you can then replace the Texas red boxes
hopefully artist delivered them at the
right size at levels that you need
which should be easy for the point at
any effect
Norman showed you how easy this at
Cedars two things because he's Korean
midfielder Sulley affect not
at that special image post-processing
effect and of course
play test iterate I can't stress this
enough and
have fun this is again is all about
sure you have been following me again
okay
when we head over to Nick now to talk
about forest prospectuses
pixels of a shock
am today i wanna talk about my two
favorite things
an but two of my favorite things one
which is
improving performance and order to
squeeze down the amount of time that
your game takes to
execute six times a second and then
increasing
the awesome that you can squeeze into
that space that you made by improving
your performance
so I have a bunch of topics to go
through an
to stir quickly give you a preview and
talk about
understanding what is involved in drying
where the
time is gonna go in a taco actions and
constraints
how their secret window into the
underlying
spray can Jen an physics there's a cost
hierarchy theirs is very helpful to
understand
similarly for shape nodes talk a little
bit about a fax
and some good to know facts about are
lighting systems
so drying performance
Christian things that impact your John
performance
in a big big way 1 is there
choice dry order how it is make your
sprites to the engine
and to years sharing the resources
thirty years to accomplish that drying
now
spray kit has by default
a sibling order drop rule which plants
that standard painters under them
there's two roles your parent to paint
us first
very curses down and draws the children
and their children and so on
as it goes children are rendered in the
order that the appear in the child away
now in this diagram here obviously the
helicopter
has got its very bottom missiles dan the
body in on
and the rotors and its straightforward
to create this in code just by adding
the various parts
now this is very convenient for
prototyping but what is it due to drying
performance
so here's my amazing game scene
and its can have a bunch helicopters and
the each peace as we workers down to
draw order
comes an one at a time followed rock all
and for individual dropped calls you
take some time
and you get the idea Field mall in there
now
let's break it gives you in order to
avoid this problem
years the magical
third dimension so
let's have a look at what we can do with
that if
we sat ignore sibling order to yes
which means death to control order
that's gonna be pretty helpful so we've
got a helicopter re organ arbitrarily
set it on
level 100 let's stretch out the rotors
in
pulled him towards the camera an at
level 1
now was pushed missiles back like that
so now the stock now
spray kit knows what you intended with
your composite
it's not based on the order was added in
code or anything like that it's based on
something absolutely
which is where is my current space
so does that do for drying
well bit by bit you can see that we've
got
a lot less struggles because we're done
already so that's
great and you've got a whole bunch
performance back right away
especially have lots of objects but you
can go further course
use texture analysis so here I put all
of the sprite Fanta
one texture and house I can help me
well here's my magical Union force
helicopters
and boom I'm done spray kit can
know that's one texture knows what order
all the bits have to be drawn an
he's bashing a lot for the Jeep UN
blasted on out
an potentially of one single call that's
pretty awesome
now this whole bunch of other things
that can be shared
and should be aware of those things we
have
and you normal map generation scheme and
you can see that their arsenal flower
block an
because spray kit textures keyed of a
name
an and normal maps were generated
on-the-fly
and with out a name and just to find
somewhere if you can ease that normal
map
on the block you need to know let the
engine now that its
genuinely shared thing so generate
your normal map start on attack sure in
a sign that tax roll this breakthrough
any user
as opposed to you every time we have
that block asking for it to be generated
similarly we've got some cool procedural
nice which might like
like to use initiators sir to provide
some serve you know television star
factor something like that
if you can reuse the noise at the scale
that you've generated
cashed out of because every night
structure that you make is gonna consume
memory and once again
break it won't know unless if you tell
it by sharing a variable in a
cash winter somewhere that yet it is
actually the same texture now
and you won't be able to batch
couple of other some more points if you
reference shooters from files
spray kit will now that were textile FSH
is for texts or FSH everywhere you
reference a so when you're prototyping
its often very convenient to reference
cheaters from strings
so go ahead and do that during
prototyping let's break it doesn't
really have any way of knowing that
genuinely these two shooters the same
even though the source code might be the
same
if you reference it from a file going
into account to Premium houses
beforehand just cash it all off and its
gonna go that much faster
because if all those helicopters have
the same sheer once again
it knows it's just passed them off like
that and then
finally slightly esoteric point on
bashing your is
we offer a number of planned modes
searchers an
additive for multiplicative or whatever
because changing a planned no changes
the GP state
we have to actually interrupt the drying
every tiny change that state
in order to allow the buying to occur so
trick you can use
you can imagine for example if you had
some sort of a misty forest scene for
layer
treason and layers creatures in a not
earlier
trees in the trees have alpha and I'm if
you put all those things
on the same Z like literally exactly the
same Z
let's break it will know these things go
together with their black and mild
and for example olive trees in the front
can go out
in one drop call with 11 mode and that
may or may not be just that will extra
bit you needed to get a little more time
to squeeze in that little more awesome
now their stools to help you evaluate
graphics performance
so you don't just need to have Lake I'm
serious mental model if these things
an there's actual you know
quantitative things you can do you to
get some insight into what's break is
doing behind the scenes
the first ball there's a number of flags
on the view which you can turn on and
off in order to get some
insight there's a obvious frame counter
FBS frames per second there's a draw
count
which is actually gonna tell you how
many batches did I get
an there is your note count which is how
many
ask a light spray kit nodes actually
went down the pipeline
and finally the five-count if you're
using something like a shape that might
be comprised
have multiple sub quads
so its gonna tell you that and I have
just quick little thing here to show you
that I have all these gears
an it's showing 12 nodes you'd have to
inspect my scene graph to discover why
there's 12
but there's six years you can probably
guess sort of what might be going on
there
the heck of a lot of quads like really a
lot
have 12 draws but it's running at 60
frames a second so
I'm pretty happy with that right now
from my magical your game
so the other thing you've got is that G
of RAM
Joe friend better so there's all kinds
of cool gauges
an tell you what proportion of this and
that is happening striker frame
and I'll give you some insight into what
y'all calls being invoked on fly
an had a lot of documentation
information %uh this is a really
fantastic tool
for understanding the runtime
characteristics of your game
nope notice as you run this thing what's
going on in the hardware
and correspondent what's going on in
your game and study that
I'll give you did insight into but the
engine is going for you
so to kinda rolled out a lot
the idea here is pose your seems as
layers
Commons the values are gonna help you a
lot for reasons I mentioned
overlapping things in different layers
order control
the draw order instead of using the
sibling order
an something andrea's share your stuff
line modes go together and use the
hudson profilers turd
really understand but the engine is
going
alright next up actions and constraints
as I mentioned and in the introduction
cool thing about actions is they really
are
and magic window into the very got spray
kit execution engine
deep down inside we continuously improve
the performance
other various operations to spray kit
provides
actions Rd little objective-c things
that might think
that might be heavy but it's not it
really cute such instructions for the
execution engine
just couple bites here and there to tell
you what's going to happen
and then it puts it off in turn turn
accuse and what not
to run so
make an action here I've got an old
and I'm going to rotate by hi parently
for one second
you can change them group down reuse
them
here well airplanes that you may not be
familiar with
and the rotating continuously for a
period of a second
am they're moving around in the scaling
its really simple to set the stuff up
execution engine is ticking
it over its almost re it's great to let
this break engine do stuff for you
rather
encoding it all up in your update so
little bit about sequencing say I've got
something that I have got waiting off
stage left like the secret monster who
make is
parents in less than one second an I can
have it way
and ann milf so that's like a sequence
also man my monster comes might rotate
and scale and feet away
he is merely a ghost
so thats the use if I can ask a Action
Group
and then you can compose those things as
deeply in complex
complex Haveli as you like my love to
make up words
right so and this case my monsters gonna
move his scale rotate and its gonna fade
away
now St action I teaches your friend is
the documentation here
am like you all to carefully read these
all down
actually go look at the documentation is
a lottt now
there's a ton of power and there's a lot
of fun to play with constraints
and you're here for the previous section
and
non-interest quite well and I have just
got a quick little
summary slide here constraints for
another sang an
which gives you access to the high
performance engine running underneath
break it in this case it's running
inverse kinematics
and this full scene was set up in Xcode
an
very quickly just an looking
and setting up couple grounders
here's another one that's actually new
and cool
and you can create a follow a path now
which seeks to see
after a and if you've ever spent any
time with Betty spines and what not
the math is kinda scary especially
making things move
at a uniform speeders particularly hairy
so
if when hadn't given you and ASCII
action to follow a path
along the spine the create account
morons line if you care
an and will move things along at a
constant velocity for you
click your
right Korean to node similar sort of
thing
you don't need to bother with York
tangent in a lot sorry thing
the blue balls moving around the arrows
following
and the other really cool thing about
actions
is the kind of blatant in memory when
you create them
build them once take advantage in the
fact that the copy on dad
and that the run when you add it to the
scene mine
example here City might have spaceship
our Monster
its gonna enter from stage left in the
same way every time and maybe follow a
path and then leave
if you create that node with the
spaceship and the action
cash in on a pointer and then cokie it
an ad to your scene it'll run every
single time
and exactly the same way very very
little overhead
and another fun thing that's easy to
overlook
is the purpose naming your actions
so in this example here
what I've got is the idea that I have a
spray tan
basically gonna do something like they
follow a touch point
I might run in action that is like move
two points I give it the name
move now I can override that action in
time I want
just by using the same key so it might
be in progress
around the action again with a new point
it'll immediately segue without a hat
your starter
onto the new action and continue on and
finally
if I monsters coming in here and then he
saw that I had you know the big monster
re repeller 2000
and he decides he doesn't want to go all
the way into the scene
we can just use a move action from key
with his move
key and tell counsel that action right
away
and he can go into something else we
don't have to wait for the ex fusion
at play out the ant
right next physics
physics a lot of fun I really really
love
there new simulation tool that we've got
an Xcode because
the hardest thing about working with
physics
is getting the parameters right now
which set things up good
defaults for example he said a massive
wine and a strength wanna
on rigid body in a strength one on a
field the gun interacting kind of an
interesting way out as the bad
but that's just the starting point for
your iteration
so rigid bodies are just mentioned ready
should bodies that's all things your
game there
passing falling ruling sliding an
the things that the physics engine has
to do each frame
are you a rigid bodies handling
collisions and letting you know that
they've occurred
and physics feels now
a primary thing for getting access to
iteration
and understanding what's going on years
the new physics visualizer
so was just go back to mine years came
here I'm
dropping in these wonderful years and
wait a second his key for
acting properly what's up with that
the other ones are interlocking just not
that one
so I'll turn on the visualize earning
can see 0
that was a circle I made a mistake
somewhere so I can go
your tax code in click on my thang are
its procedural
I can look at my code I can find out why
did this one slip through the cracks
so this is here this is a great first
line of defense for just understanding
what the dynamic behavior is
it's not what you expected you can also
use this mild
for identifying quickly am what is the
cause
physics performance issues an object
might be stuck in a wall
and it might be an invisible all because
it was only there is a physics body
now you'll just be able to see that well
it's continuously pushing
in and out of collision encounter escape
and
the next steps to solve that problem
will probably occur to you
so in order to take best advantage in
physics
in order to get performance you can
squeeze down the amount of time spending
key squeeze in more awesome
is to understand the cost hierarchy
first of all dynamic objects
cost more because the clinicians need to
be resolved
and they need to be moved outta
intersection
then objects that are static like
hopefully the stage than standing on
so if you can set an object
dude dynamic equals now
you're gonna get a lot of performance
back right away
at most efficient and at the scale our
circles
you have dozens of circles for every
other kind of shape
that you can have and she circles might
work
really really good for a lot of things
especially if for circular
hurt their small issue not really notice
that the interaction house
circle doesn't fit very well on the
hammer
that's a bit better the hammer at least
you know has edges and stuff
this is more expensive down the circle
we could have doesn't the circle sicken
have maybe I don't know eights these
just
will build its leader an polygons a
better
this is probably gonna be and the one
that serves a lot of complicated shapes
the best
it's more expensive than a rectangle
because is more edges to compute
camp on objects an
need to be iterated through all the way
for all the pieces
lotsa circles compounded are a lot
cheaper than a lot of boxes compounded
and finally there's the an perfect
pixel often ask bodies these
are potentially cheap if it was a circle
going to be cheap actually but if it's
got a convex
a complex convoluted shape and iraqi a
lot of cum
computation involved there so just be
careful with these
you need to pick the representation the
past two starts here
serves your game you might find that the
per pixel thank is actually better
dan having like say twenty will circles
to describe something
but prefers things on
the fish inside of the charge as much as
he can
serve you can play
alright collision masks is another thing
that you can use
to regain performance
especially in a case like yes I've got
these two jars
late charge my marbles green jar
with green marbles now the funny thing
about this
it's a pretty close together and you
might be hard for the engine to actually
understand
that the white marbles have no way
getting in the green journ
vice versa see you can help the engine
out
this is what the engine sees like
for everyone others green marbles
every one of those white marbles are
they hitting so
just imagine how many comparison site is
putting the jar back again now
if he is a collision mask give the white
marbles
mask wine and a green marbles mask to
you
you're gonna get a halt on a performance
back this is an order and squared
problem
and so by cutting the number of
comparisons and half
well dude the mouth
a lot of computation that you can get
back just through this temple experience
right none introduced force feels very
nicely in the previous ones I'm not
gonna
and labor what all the different force
fields are in there feels and things
like that
but I am gonna point out an that they're
building blocks
use them together and use actions
and to fade in and out have a big nasty
particle system here and what I've done
is just made a whole bunch a force field
throughout the center the screen
and just using an action to modulate the
strength
%uh each force field so they smoothly
said way one into the other
that's a lot nicer than just turning
them on or off an
well I love playing with these things
are mostly at
for that slide n now here's another
example
have how for skills to help you out in
reducing game logic
and simplifying updates similarly to the
way that
the actions 30 window into the engine
force feels are another thing that you
can use
to replace game logic so even
kinda tell without me even telling you
what kind of game this one is going to
be
but was just your looks like for second
in Seattle geyser following house cursor
around
and doing their darndest not to run into
those
green planet things I guess spacious
nearly as big as a planet that's kind of
amazing
an
its hypnotic
okay I think I can stop staring at that
now alright
will wait that's the big reveal let's go
back to the pictures the
me if you can or maybe not
before I show you that next like an what
I want to tell you
is using Xcode I made that level so
I Houston idea like that I like to call
prefabs
likely fabricated objects to make a
little scene graph
with the spaceships picture and a force
field right underneath it
I gave the force field on the spaceship
a negative strength we push each other
apart
I gave the planet child which is a force
field
with a negative strength so that it
pushes
little space ships away I made the
planet's not dynamic
and I made spaceships dynamic okay now
we can look at that
re: so this is the whole entire
that game aside from the bit that I
built in Xcode its
next to nothing and you're getting the
same sort of behavior the scene classic
RTS is like your Starcraft or whatever
so but is doing from top to bottom this
just
the target is where I tap the screen
an my not the ship's position as I'm
calculating
an I don't divide by 0 some checking for
that little minimum length I'm
getting the velocity from the physics
body I'm finding out
what direction the velocity is an will
arc tangent gives me an angled
slap on the rotation
I'm taking the position difference
where I wanna go from where I am
subtracting
the velocity multiplying it by a magic
number
which I arrived at by iterating
and then I just applying an impulse
using
back out with magic number and you
basically get looks like artificial
intelligence
for having done nothing at all now gonna
learn more about that stuff you can
like search the internet for blades
there's a
wonderful body of work around these
kinds of techniques
now just like physics debug drying
can give you insight into what's going
on
here's you know the wizard behind the
curtain the
I've turned on the field by drying you
can see the fields around the ship's
the fields around the planet and how
they interact and
I don't know it's a crazy amount of fun
for like 10 minutes coding
so yield of mathematical spaceship games
free download and play
I don't like that's like a way because
I'll just watch forever
okay so physics choose
I don't know which is:--what's gesture
how I had to keep down at the
that side of the screen and she is the
cheapest one
and that scan best serve your game
use the expensive ones judiciously to
serve you can play
separate your group with mass see engine
knows what your intent is cuz
that's the only way that it can read
your mind an
feels replace up the logic
fuel creative thinking imagination
and the debug drying Skyview all kinds
in sight
into what the engine is doing for a
behind-the-scenes
so my next topic
shapes had little refresher here
on the difference between it now part an
sector UN carry gas which is the factor
now there's a cost iraqi shapes
just like there's a cost hierarchy
physics
you know what I can say they're she's
won Best service again
these guys in particular squares
and rectangles are really cheap
I'm to say that sprite are way way way
off
the cheap steel beyond these guys but
not that far off
you can use these things a lot worse
appropriate
these are just a bit more Spencer you
can use them a lot
be's have had a tire on love put into
them in this iteration stray cat
an you can dry so many maps in
you know compass roses all kinds of
things like that
with factors that in previous iterations
this break it
you might have had them in the judicious
column now there in the
d-licious column
alright stroked Kors now
I wish I could have no hockey sticks to
show you the cost here
the same look really great and
use a few of them and you not gonna
really your performance at all
is by inch now may get a call from on
finally feeling the man costs even more
so as full a bracket there see you now
which is the cheap ass in which is
expensive half use the thing that's
perfect your game
just because I can't stop myself I made
a fractal
space point curving with tens of
thousands
points in at an just kinda say
K they're cheap use them
alright affect notes use
a fag nodes when you want to have a
subtree
sprites or whatever that our goal going
to gather
how some kind of a fact apply to them
such as
tenting or blurring
they have to be drawn off screen and
then
brought back to the frame buffer for
feeling so
there's a cost you can get me
powerful car image support even run
very sophisticated filters an all kinds
of amazing things
by its expansive use them when you need
to
shade urs are an awesome option
whenever you don't need to have things
composited
off-screen particularly a can just go
ahead and rock
shares will save your performance bacon
if you want to just tent everything
green that's a really simple shaker
you just bypass you know the whole
processing stock just go
right now to the hardware so learn about
that
an should Rasta rise just
gives us a hand about what can be cashed
in hangin'
will hang around for a while and what
needs to be be composited
every screen
if you've got things that are going to
be static for a while
for example maybe you've got some kinda
had displayed only updates once every 10
seconds but you might have
you know and cool glows and blurs and
real starts in all kinds of things going
on
last redoubt there's a couple of cool
things he can do here
you can create a texture from an old an
just
specify the note ask give you a raster
for United gotta textures slap that up
soon cost almost nothing
have CI filter there's the other and
writer
right that's what I have to say about a
fax
now for lighting
we have sung introduction from Norman in
the last section about lighting
sign a talk about the performance cost
so
the first thing that you need to now is
a
well we're gonna compete the lighting
per pixel
so the cost is there for proportional to
the amount
like blue pixels you can optimize that
with
it now if you say some things are going
to be wet
thing and I can pay that cost so that's
what that's all about
and the inlay is free
you can have eight light for sprite
now your to pay for you know eight times
the processing
per pixel spray so way if you want to do
that
and keep the cost down with that now
normal maps archie she did you see sews
up so
stick on maps on they'll agree remember
to share them
shadows are cost
proportional to the number of flights
it's pretty much constand
so if you turn on one shadow that's
gonna cost you
wine to shadows is in a cost you to you
so keep the number of those things down
you potentially have to shadow the whole
entire screen
so they look really great you can add a
lot of impact an awesome
use them don't abuse and
alright so we talked about
drying performance understand what
controls batching and dry order
an learn about the tools to get insight
into what's going on
actions and constraints are your window
into this break it down Jan
we improve the efficiency all the time
the more you use actions
the more you're gonna get performance
back over time this week generate
frameworks physics
understand the cost iraqi choose
appropriately to serve you can play
same with shapes a fax understand the
cost
use them wisely and lighting is a cheap
easy way to extra awesome
and i'd like y'all maker games awesome
as possible
right so today
we talked about structure and games for
scalability
understanding how to setup scene graphs
and scene graph snippets the can put
things together in a data-driven way
and we talked a whole bunch about
performance
for more information encourage you to
contact Allen Schaeffer
and Philip yes Q who are a games
evangelist
spring kit programming guide recently
refresh has a tiny interesting
information and
and of course there's always the forms
and tomorrow i'd love did he call come
visit us in
the labs an talk about what you've got
going on in
you know say hi and with that
and thanks very much and I'll see ya
later