good morning welcome the 770 to managing
Apple devices
of I wasn't expecting that enthusiastic
a welcome this early in the morning
on top Fernandez and I am very happy to
be here with you
even at this ridiculously early hour
protectees like me
although for some %uh view this may be
the middle if your day
if you work in schools are otherwise
have to wear a tie to work many of us
are far more likely to see this hour at
the end of a long native coding
than at the beginning of our day now
open by recognizing our differences
because the sessions content is intended
for a diverse audience
from MDM vendors need to learn how to
take full advantage
the powerful device management
capabilities that we've built into I was
8 and Austin your sanity
to app developers who want to understand
how the app's may be used in schools and
businesses
to administrators who need to know what
changes are coming
in the US releases this year when I
stand before you here last year
I was thrilled to announce two huge
leaps forward imagine Apple devices
in addition have managed distribution to
our volume purchase program
and the introduction of the device in
rolling programme
which create highlighted in the air
price action yesterday's keno
hard to believe there was another price
action at the keynote that was very
exciting to see
when we
set out to create the device in Roman
program we did so after wondering
why does it have to be painful to do
that initial configuration of your
devices
before handing them out to the user's
and we started by asking a simple
question
why can it be as easy as just unboxing
that device and handing iPad or that
iPhone that Mac to it's User
it turns out many you are asking the
same question
am very pleased to report that our
customers are just as thrilled by the
transformative nature this new service
as we'd hoped one noteworthy example
is a macchiato with a high school in
Florida who
believe that we in the indie turned this
dream into reality
and they proved it by completely
replacing their free to buy pads
with 600 new iPad airs including
restoring all this to naps
and data from my cloud in two and a half
hours in a wonderful video showing just
how they did it
and if you've never seen the device on a
program in action
I highly recommend checking it out since
we last met
we've been very busy launching match
distribution last fall
the device are on the program a few
months ago and we've also been busy
adding all these features to fill in the
gaps
and smooth out the inconsistencies
between I O S and I was 10
so the vendors like some %uh view
creating device management tools
and administrators using those tools
have a much easier time
managing all their Apple devices this
session is going to cover the entire
life cycle device management including
both new tools
into existing tools and technologies and
all the changes coming in
I was 8 analyst in Yosemite and we'll
show you how they all come together
to provide a great experience for both
the administrators and their end-users
from enrolling devices in your
management solution of choice
to distributing content all those
devices
to the day-to-day ongoing management
tasks that come up
as time goes on and needs change so
let's dive right in
talk about enrolling devices a course
management
fanart I'm on advice from a program the
best way to do this
also at talk about Apple configurator as
an alternative way to enroll your device
you also need to be aware of how to
manage activation lock on supervised
devices and be thinking about that and
Roman time
and then I'll conclude with what's
coming
in this year's OS releases so before we
go any further I want to make sure that
everyone understands what advice from
program is and is not so every Latino
audience participation with going
although I appreciate all the responses
already
the Viceroy program is not an Indian
server
might say with me the Viceroy program is
not an MDM server
thank you though you know they're both
three letter acronyms
those are you with legalized note
they're not the same three letters
in fact the device loan program is the
best way to get your devices enrolled in
whatever Indian solution you're going to
use
it's an easy button to get your devices
in your MDM server
it's really two parts a way for
administrators to specify which settings
they want to use when their devices are
enrolled in their management solution
and the integration of the completion of
that enrollment process right into the
normal setup X
assistant process that the user will go
through on those I less
analyst 10 as a I mention we launch this
in February
with devices eligible that are purchased
via direct sales in the US
and we've heard all the feedback loud
and clear that you'd like to see is
expanded to you
additional countries and channels so I'm
very pleased at all that we only
launched this
a few months ago we've already expanded
access to our neighbors to the north
and create Canadians here I'm so sorry
about the Canadiens
but in fact the Rangers not my Flyers
out in the first round cell
get it next year
we've also made a number of other
changes already since launch you know
what I want to point out
devices are now eligible up to three
years in the past if you purchase them
up to three years ago
Anderson enhancements the portal that
allow you to set the fall
and %um server so that a new device
purchases will automatically be assigned
to that Indian server without you need
to take further action
you can also now see which
administrators assigned which devices
with to which and %um servers and
another coming soon
expansion eligibility is that when
devices that are in the device on a
program
are replaced by service those devices
will soon be
remaining the device on the program
including retroactively
devices have been replaced over the past
three years we think customers will
really appreciate that
you quickly recap exactly how the
this service works before I go into
details especially for the Indian
vendors
customer purchases devices that
information is fed into the device on
the program
when the customer are provides their
account information to their MDM
solution and %um solution can download
device information from the program the
administrator can then specify the
settings
upload those to the program then when
users
open the box and start working walking
through the Setup Assistant
the device receives its settings from
the device from a program
which tell to enroll with the MDM server
now so again want to emphasize that once
that happens the icing on the program
has done its job
out of the picture and your MDM solution
is the only thing that's talking to the
devices
three talk about three topics a few
moments here
related to the national program how best
to integrate this into your nvm
solutions
so the first concept is where should the
ultimate repository the truth
relating to you the program the devices
in the settings for reside
the device information should really be
in the device our own program a treat
that is the truth you can always fetch
that information from the service to
your Indian server
but the settings that the administrator
decides to apply to certain groups
devices your server should really
further
out tree itself as the truth for that it
can always upload new settings to the
program
one caveat here to keep in mind though
and is
what I explain the previous lied even if
the administrator changes the
the settings they were in the device
Roman program for particular device or
devices
those devices will not see those
settings until the next time that they
go through activation
after wiping and going back to the Setup
Assistant the device is already enrolled
and you happen to change the setting to
say well now I want to be supervised
that will take effect until the next
time the device is set up
alright so disowning devices you may be
thinking what does that mean
well this is removing a device in the
device a rolling programme
and I'm here to scare you
a recommendation is to not implement
this feature
why is that well if and if you're gonna
break rule number one
you need to really really how many
released put on
really make sure they understand the
consequences that they will not be able
to undo this action and get that device
back into the program
so again we recommend following rule one
alright a final topic is thinking about
the combinations are to the type
have to have the specific in Rome in
settings that you can configure for
device
whether a supervisor not and whether
that and %um enrollment
can be removed or not by the user on the
device
and their at our own profile managers
taken the approach
have not separating the settings that if
you
choose to supervise device it
automatically the Indian enrollment
is not removable that top right box
the bottom right box is forbidden at if
you try to upload settings
where devices is not supervised any
Indian ron is not removed by the user
the service will reject those settings
the lower left but may be interesting
again profile manager doesn't a welp
that's what profound does if you don't
check the supervised box that it's
completely open
it's not supervised and user can undo
the and the enrollment
those two are really interesting ones
they're kinda half one in the upper left
is allowed but
probably not super interesting to
supervise the ice but still allow the
user to
on Raw from MTN
so thats couple notes about the device
in on the program
let's talk a bit about Apple
configurator so again Apple configurator
is also
not an MDM server wanna make sure it was
clear about that
but it is an alternative way to
installing Roman settings on
a particular I was device over US P as
an alternative to using device in on the
program over-the-air
once the settings have been lodged
device the actual request to go to Union
server to
complete the enrollment are
indistinguishable from whether they were
done
the settings got there over-the-air or
over USB
however you can teacher server to
distinguish between the two
if you check to see if that particular
device that in rolling
is in the the list that you got from the
device running program
also if the device has already gotten
its settings from the device running
program
configure will not overwrite settings
one additional caveat is that delivering
your own settings via the device in
Roman program
is the only way that you can make your
Indian Roman not removal
user another recommendation and one that
we found ourselves in profile manager is
that it's probably a good idea to offer
administrators the option to disallow
installing settings over USB if you want
to ensure that they only get there
your institutions devices only get their
settings that you specified
that that will prevent
a user from using figure to you install
like settings that allow enrollment in
European server without supervising for
example
let's now talk a little bit about
activation lock management
so by default supervise device does not
allow the user to enroll
in active are to enable activation lock
but there is no way that we introduced
her in in the spring that
and EM can request a bypass code that
allows
Union search later or the administrator
later clear activation lock without
needing
the user's password
at that time there's also an Indian
commander can tell the device walking
now you can allow the user to enable
activation moxie
want to do all this at enrollment time
if in fact your institution wants to use
activation lock
which is great feature
we also recommend that once your tree
that activation
by activation lock bypass code that you
provide access to the administrator
to a in you live because it may be
useful to be able to enter it manually
on a device that for
whatever reason is not currently
reachable i dnt answer
there are three new Indian commands to
retrieve the code
to then delete it from the device so
that no one can can grab
of the devices they get physical access
to it
and then of course to enable the are
allow the device to enable activation
lock
then we strongly recommend that when
you're completing the and the enrollment
that at that time you always retrieve
and then clearly a
the bypass code from the device because
it's only available for 15 days after
the device was supervised
you should also say that bypass code
even if a particular device is on a roll
from Indian because activation lot may
still be enabled and you may still need
to clear it
and the device can later re in roll and
there won't be another opportunity to
get
a bypass code until the rice is white
and angry supervised
says the pops I wanted to cover on
enrolling but I'm
I'm also happy to tell you that there's
an important change how device
responds when the enrollment been
completed and setup assistant
and I know your servers all really
excited the mysteries have no doubt
specified lot settings and absent all
sorts things they want delivery devices
soon as its unrolled
however the device isn't ready to
respond all those requests while the
user is still completing Setup Assistant
so now when any of these Indian commands
are sent to the device
while it is still in the Setup Assistant
will return the not now status
so your server can no hay devices
already on their way
until it returned turns successful
enrollment
and then you can start completing your
in aromatase
configuration tasks so that further ado
i'd like to show you how this works
and I'm gonna invite my colleagues you
sit back and mark up
to show you a demo other rowing devices
alright are affected so you we have and
out a box
freshly delivered new iPad basically it
was
or a purchase by the institution and did
go through some both the room
it was just handed straight to the user
and are proven to server
business R&D answer for palestinian are
knows about this device because
be time between devising Roman program
and program manager
and the device the purchase was made
through the channels so we know that
this device is configured for
our services so I'm going to walk
through the setup but as usual
I'm gonna pick my language Park alike
pick my country
connect to my network so at this point
the device is no
talking to the Apple services and our
attending its
activation information and it's part of
that information is the notice but
we are no in the EP and reader Tom
prompted for in rolling into Indian
server so
just in a second we are we're still
returning something information
and no we are talking to are server
so this is as far as DP has talked to
the device
now we're talking to are Indian server
and I can find more information about
some
for instance so if I need to know what
to do next I can call the I can help
desk
and up no I go to the next and you see
that
when I go forward I'm not prompted for
username and open password
I cannot bypass so I do have to enroll
this
so disturbed this device has been
configured to be supervised
and the Indian profile is mandatory so I
have no way of bypassing
this step so I'll provide my leg
information
and move on and no we don't want the
profiles from our Indian server
so again the the DP face has been has
been
complete I know we're talking to our are
management server
and Marcus said some screens to be pipe
last year
so we're not seeing registration and
other pieces and while I complete my set
up by looking into my ipod account
well have marks are you the set up in
the box yep
so answer using at their centers iPad
and I want to walk you through
how in profile manager we've implemented
you I to support configuring price wrong
program
so on left side you see the devices that
my server has
retreat from the National pretty much
there is configured to
download these devices and then I have
uses iPad slighted here and you can see
the enrollment settings
that I've got selected your our first
option
is whether turn on this configuration
for this device or not you can also put
these configurations
on device group as well so you can get a
whole collection devices get the same
settings
so we have checked on she wants and the
settings down the next option is whether
or not
the user is allowed to skip in Rome it
an
I just on the case uses device is not
allowed to skip enrollment he's can be
prompted for credentials country's first
directory server
our next option is whether I wanted you
over-the-air supervision of the device
now in addition to be on the supervisor
devices
when you surprise device you also have
the option locking the MDM profile so I
can't be removed from the device
in our case we've combined those into
one options within our customers
whenever the supervisor gonna want to
have locked in the AM if you're a
third-party Indian developer
you can always break that out and have
it as a separate option
the next texting is whether you want to
allow pairing
so I have that a No so the price
comparison Mac you want annexes to you
request credentials for enrollment
seaside you see
prices prompted for credentials and then
there are various things that we can
skip during the setup show or sleeping
step assistant I'll
in our case we have Apple ID enable
because you want to capture
uses about we get activation lock in a
month am
so you see is finished actually setting
up his device
so I am going to you
show you our security thanks for the
device right now show that activation
lock is unable but I do have the
activation like bypass cuz this is what
a provide major grappling device was
rolled if I
update my info now that he's done
we'll see in a moment here that
activation like a change to yesen
and by my phone is enabled is is set yes
so
I'm so when this device comes back to me
I'll be able two runs clear activation
lock if activation like is still unable
and I can clear that and him this device
out to the next user
so back to yes
so you see mark just showed you how you
can enroll in supervise and I was device
using device in Roman program
and how to configure the enrollment
settings that were used
using profile manager but of course that
can be done with any and %um solution
that supports the icing on the program
will help all
you mark show you how profile murder had
retrieved the activation lapse bypass
code as a complete enrollment to that
device
and then a provider actually
automatically allows active care there's
a setting and Roman setting which I
don't know that mark showed
that the measure can choose always
automatically allow automation
activation lock 16 retrieved by
successfully retrieved by passcode
let's move on to our the next section
are talking talk about streaming content
to our devices
records gonna talk about the volume
purchase program in mass distribution
we'll talk a little bit about manage
taps and then conclude with
the significant enhancements in I was a
analyst in Yosemite
to fill in some gaps here
so again to recap mass distribution
allows
the administrator to buy licenses
instead of codes
which can be Rep revoked and reallocate
to differ user
for both aP's and books
and we provided ATI se nvm solutions can
integrate the service into their
their solutions and it's currently
available in 10 countries
so again refresher exactly how this
works the initiator can purchase
like absent books in the people and
information stored in the iBookstore on
the App Store
when they provide their account
information to their management solution
it can download information about which
absent books have been purchased
intervale for assignment
it can send assignments up to the iTunes
Store in credit a particular app or book
to you a
a user account when the user configures
their Apple ID on a particular
Apple device they'll see those
assignments in their purchase list
and can download the bits directly from
the store just as if they had purchased
them themselves
and also the administrator can send
command and %um commands from the server
to the devices to say
download this app to make sure that it
is actually installed on a particular
device
again dive into a number of topics
relates the vine purchase program to
give you some advice on how to best
integrate these
this program into your solutions
starting off again with
where should the different pieces a
truth reside
and the DVD service itself should really
be the truth for
the status user romance whether a user
has accepted an invitation
and associated your Apple ID with the
user
which licenses have been purchased as I
action on the previous slide
as well as tracking any irrevocable book
assignments that have been made
you're in the answer should actually be
the truth for everything else
including revocable ap assignments and
you may be wondering why shouldn't that
be in the BB service
well if you're and in solution supports
group assignments you need to keep that
information your and %um server because
there's no way to store
group information in the DPP service so
you're gonna be able to reconstitute
that you can you have all that within
your database
let's talk a little bit about account
management when particular administrator
provides their credentials their their
VP account to your solution
and you want to stab the initial
connection with the bond purchase
program
you're going to you need to check the
client context attributes and if it's
empty and
that means that no other server has
claimed the counter is using this
account
and you should go ahead and claim it by
providing the hostname your server and a
unique
a I do it so that you'll be able to tell
whether your server still on managing
if their look like context as a value
and it doesn't match the good that you
have for that server
some other server is actually using that
account and you're gonna want to alert
the administrator that some other server
is managing licenses tied to this
account
and ask them to confirm that you have
they in fact one the server to take over
that account
that may in fact be the right thing if
their chance transitioning from one
server to the next
and further whenever you reestablish the
connection to the service
you need to check my contact again to
make sure that your server still the one
that's connected to this account if it
doesn't match any longer you can
need to start making request to the
service an alert the administrator
that this other host name has now claim
this account so they can take
appropriate action
nationalizations already thats apart
bootstrapping this program is that
mister needs to
invite each user to link their Apple ID
you
this particular the PP account so that
licenses can be a sign
we strongly recommend that you do this
invitation the NDM you can
easily send that invitation be an Indian
command directly to an Android device
it's much more secure
and are reliable email is a fallback
if you have a user you need to invite
doesn't currently have an Android device
but there's a concerning need to beware
that because the invitation URL there's
an example on screen
country as for the Apple the Condamine
many
mail servers will treat an email coming
from your servers domain
including a URL from a Apple dot com has
a phishing attack
and the filter them out their number
alternative ways to avoid this problem
you could create your invitation email
URL that brings these are first factor
in the AM server
before redirected into the PP URL or you
can integrate innovate invitation
process right into your User Portal if
you have one
first spend a few moments talking again
about user ID's
relating to bond purchase program I sure
the slide last year
there are really three ideas have the
user is
from the perspective of the MDM server
from
perspective at the BP service and in the
end users Apple ID
which your Indian server will never see
directly by
will see a hash other to protect users
privacy
now this will be very simple if we lived
in the ideal world
where each user had one and only one
Apple ID associated with
your VP Account and would never change
that Apple ID
in this case be a simple one to one
mapping between all three these
representations that the user
sadly as many you may be aware we don't
live in an ideal world
in the real world multiple VP users can
accept
their individual invitations with the
same Apple ID and need to be aware the
implications are
the sharing about ladies specifically if
you've assigned a license to a user that
then is connected to that particular
Apple ID
if you revoke that assignment it's going
to look at from every Apple
every user sharing that Apple ID also if
you try to assign
a Napper book to you I EP user
that's associated with an Apple ID that
already has
that a ap or book a sign that second
assignment will fail
another issue in the real world is that
users can
after accepting invitation with one
Apple ID can
dissociate from Apple ID and associate
accept an invitation with the different
Apple ID
this becomes a problem if you assign any
irrevocable book
licenses to you that happen like that
retired Apple ID
you have to keep track of that and think
about whether you want to allocate
another irrevocable book license to the
new Apple ID or not
so the NDM service representation of the
user the client user ID string
is something that's under your control
and we strongly recommend you pick a
value that will never change
for example the user ID from the
directory services where you're getting
your
user and group information Shinshu
something like an email address which
can change
and it's very simple I had to have a
slide with some people on I'm sorry
at it's very easy then to look up which
EP account that that particular
and the end user is associated with
whether it's just registered and you
sent the invitation or actually
associated
where the user has accepted
and finally the representation have the
users Apple ID accepted the invitation
takes the form and
I can store ID hash and you to track
this
as soon as a user has accepted an
invitation
new and I was a there's now an Indian
query
not just in I would say it's also
interested in your sanity
a query to get that hash values so that
you can now with
whether the Apple ID thats
configured on a particular device
changes you won't know exactly what the
Apple I'd
ideas but you'll be able to tell if they
dissociated angry associated with the
different I D
as I i mentioned already on the previous
slide you gonna want to track those
retired
values if the user switches to a
different Apple ID
again see cue track any irrevocable book
assignments
another new change that will allow your
you and your vendors provide a better
user experience in your tools
for users outside the US that we now
report the country code
that the account is tied to you when you
get your information down from the
service
so that you can fetch the proper at
midday to artwork
description at name from the correct
iTunes Store
so mashups is not a new a new concept
with her for a couple
I was releases its away for
enterprises to keep better control over
their data and documents tied a
particular aP's
it works with both App Store and
enterprise aP's
they manage that must be installed the
MDM
with the install application command and
with the management like set on the app
itself
one limitation is that if the user is
already installed an app the Indian
server cannot
converted to manage retroactively
however the circuit court's detector
up is unmanaged and then alert the
administrator so they could take
action outside any and if necessary to
you
have the user to leave that up and nvm
server push it out again
mashups work with managed to open in new
feature in I was seven to help again
prevent
data leakage from managed up to %uh nine
ish taps
so if you have a particular app that has
sensitive documents
you can't read it is managed turn on
managed opinion
and then users will not be able to open
those documents in other APs like
I won't name any so you might imagine I
talked about filling gaps
and learning in skin inconsistencies we
have managed apso
what are introducing in I was a well
course matchbooks
and just like managed aP's matchbooks
works with those
both iBookstore books where you can
I just like mash taps tell the device to
download
a particular iBookstore book entry is
managed
that that book must be published
persisted
DPP even if the user has it
one I'm difference between matchbooks
and mashups is that
you can rack retroactively manage books
in contrast to manage aP's
even if the user has an install this is
be very useful in schools to ensure that
a particular title is installed
make sure the students have all the work
in the doc didn't need it
turning to enterprise books
you can just like enterprise aP's can
install the and %um
and remove PS eap jobs and iBooks Author
books
these documents are the these titles are
stored in a different location for my
book store books
with classy data protection there are
also a number restrictions are
introducing I was a
to again give institutions more
confidence that the sensitive data will
be protected and not
escape their control they can disable
I called backups are these enterprise
books
they just stay on the device whether
install and also disable
the user's highlights and notes on that
title from being synced other devices
for you and the others out there it's
any pretty straightforward implement
this
just like there's an install application
and %um command there's now an install
media
and UN Command where if it's I managed
iBookstore book you to specify the
iTunes Store I D
and if it's an enterprise book you
specify a URL back to your server to
download the bits
you need to specify persist in ID under
control so you can uniquely identify
each
enterprise but this being installed and
its kind
and then the matching remove media
command
there are few limitations just like
manage taps
it requires the app installation and the
enrollment right to be able to install
manage books
and managing iBookstore books requires
that you again purchased
the DPP and that the App Store is
enabled on the device that you're
pushing an enterprise but you
another distinction between managed ups
and Nash books
is that the and the inquiry to attain
the listed in Starbucks
will only show managed books and not
every book that's installed by the user
to preserve user privacy and finally
against you allowed institutions to keep
control over these enterprise books in
their sensitive data
enterprise books cannot be sent off the
device using iTunes
returning from what's new and I would
say what's new in I was ten years so
many were gonna fill another gap
and we r have added the ability to
install on App Store
ups the NDN on Elliston
in thank you see when he gets back up so
it you can specify a sign flat package
containing a
years and AM committed install
application and UN Command which is now
supported on August 10
for night at Starbucks and in fact your
Indian solution can do this
same thing the profile name has done
that you can support the
administrators providing you with just I
got up on the low as long as you
package it up as a sign flat package and
send that over
the and the in command so without any
further ado i'd
instead of talking more about this i'd
like to ask you see mark come back up
and show you
installing and removing enterprise
absent works
alright thank you cards and I just moved
into my books library
so here we have some books that we were
diverted I've been a keen
reader a very Human Interface Guidelines
apparently and we just ordered a swift
so its books over gonna learn some new
things and marks not going to push
a PDF for for the device so this is
going to be on
enterprise so enterprise book and
this will have the same open rules I saw
us or any other
manage data on the device will have data
protection between applications
and we won't we won't be able to showed
through the book in a row so this is our
fans in you PDF I just got installed
and snow since this is a managed book
I'll controlled by Indians
and im our solution market can also
remove the book
so mark and no remove the app remove the
book and it disappears from our
from a box of so that's a managing books
on no oren
by your side and
I'm on Iowa so we've we've had be able
to install enterprise applications we
have our
fancy use with application here acne hub
but I thought mention wheels up support
for installing applications and all this
time
so you re going to our launch pad and
mark is not going to install our
fancy backing up going to be our
standpoint
and no hands this is all our all
installed by
by the system so sparkles fly and the
acting up but landed in the system so
here's all standing committee happens
so thank you mark and now back to top
I thank you very much guys that was
written using Swift right
they stayed up all night all rights cell
mark easy to show Dad installing a PDF
on I was a
device and removing it as well as
installing an enterprise app on a Mac
running OS 10 yosemite
so let's proceed onto our final section
and talk about ongoing management
devices
we're going to complete the the
activation lock story to show you
talk about how you use that bypass could
you change at an aroma thyme
talk a little about integrating and %um
solutions with external data sources
talk about something new rock called and
%um service can signal
come onto that a few minutes and then
again conclude with what's coming
in this year's OS releases
so one thing to keep in mind with
activation lock is
its it's a little bit different from
some other services
when you get the device information
query and Mark show this in profile
manager when he re fetched
the device information on it reflected
the changing activation lock status
there's a key that tells you whether the
device thinks its activation lot
and there's a a request that use and not
to the device but you
our activation server to clear the
activation lock
and specify the bypass code that you
have
now because that request doesn't go to
the device
the device isn't checking with the
activation server it's not gonna know
that it's been cleared so it's going to
continue to report
that its activation locked year and the
answer
also even after you have cleared it on
the activation server the user if they
lockout or the remove their Apple ID in
and login again that will really able
activation lock
so you wanna definitely keep hold up I
pass code even if you cleared it
this isn't gonna in the real world gonna
usually be an issue because typically
you can use this when you have the
device in your hands
but you definitely want you to bypass
kurds because you might need to use it
again
alright so one of the most important
external data sources the journey in
server needs integrate with is
directory services there are a number of
different ones that your server probably
supports
however compared to the database that's
back in European solution
most director services have some
capabilities which make unlimited
in this context usually you can't get a
phone operation other contents
and there's not an easy way to discover
the changes in the last time Feb some
subsection
contents they can be intermittent leave
a long slow
so you want me to mere Sai information
into your your server
in contrast redesigned both the device
Roman program service and the volume
purchase program service to be
simple efficient to mir that data into
European solution
you can molinari the licenses for VP
your the device list for advice in Roman
program
and it's easy to get the changes from
the last time that you got an
enumeration
she definitely near this information
down in your database
and not use those services for live
access
similarly you know when a mere in the
directory services information to get
better performance reliability and
all the benefits your database but
definitely the authentication peace in
directory services
less frequently used in you need to have
a single source of truth for that
also you're not gonna wanna near your
entire directory services into your
database
course you want to just mere in records
that are related to you in the AM
next hour talk about a new concept that
those you familiar with the store back
from iTunes we can also call this the
URL bag
it's something that would make it much
easier for tools like Apple configurator
another device management tools to you
just asked the Indian server
what information they contain from the
from it
we specify this new you are I and the
inservice confetti
that any to look at them making art on
authenticated HTTPS request to your
server
and ask you to provide in UCF Jason
could hash
for example the URL for your and %um
servers device in Roman program
enrollment
this would allow a tool like Apple
configurator to make it much easier for
administrator
to use it to configure settings because
they were not the type the entire
enrollment URL
they don't have to type the demand have
your server and it could then
after sir what's your URL and complete
that for the user
so we're gonna be it plain that sinn
profile manager and we struck we would
really like to see that in your Indian
solutions as well
again let's turn to what's coming knew
when I was 8 in terms
NTM commands inquiries we've seen some
these already
is now possible for supervised devices
to tell them scepter device name the MDM
you can also clear the restrictions
passcode if the user has themselves
configured in
settings you why restrictions and set a
passcode
that would have prevented in the past
the administrator from overriding those
restrictions
now you can send in NC and command that
removes the settings and allows the MDM
server to you
configure its own settings we've already
seen the new install and remove media
commands
as well as the query that allows you to
ask which
iTunes account is configured on the
device via the iTunes Store ID hash
but it's also now possible to query the
device to ask when it last backup to I
cloud
there are a number of new payloads and
additions to existing payloads and I was
a
there's a new VPN connection type
we added new plugin content filters to
expand on the built-in content filters
that we shipped in Iowa 7
there's a new paler called managed
remains which were gonna show you a
little bit later that you can have
managed email and web domains
that work in conjunction with manage
taps and books and managed opinion
and help institutions keep their data
secure
I think they actually mentions Craig
actually mention the per message
s months which in mail yesterday and
it's possible to configure whether
that's available to the user for both
email exchange you can specify
certificate in the single sign-on
payload
that allows automatic refreshing at the
Curragh
potentials without the user having to
take any action
and their number of new restrictions
both
for unsupervised devices 5 at the top
including
disabling than the it's really cool
feature hand-off but
that also me worry certain institutions
about
data that they're consider sensitive
transitioning from a managed device
to another device outside their control
we also Artie Saul the restrictions on
enterprise books
and there too new supervised
restrictions
that you can prevent the user from
erasing all content and settings and
lighting devices undoing all that hard
work you did to configure that device
as well as a pair for the Indian command
that once you clear the restrictions you
can disable the user from
actually configuring them
using the US the like you I in settings
speaking at the device you line settings
the Irish team has done a lot of work to
dramatically improve the end-user
experience
to see the effects other than in the AM
enrollments and
any configuration profiles an Indian
in relationship is now represented with
a single item
that coalesces all the profiles are
installed the Indian channel
showing all the settings abs and books
that have come down view that in your
relationship
with the most important things like
accounts and absent books restrictions
at the top
what this also means that users cannot
no longer cherry-picking remove
individual profiles that the Indian
server has delivered to the device
just not shown that way
another improvement in the settings you
why is that if their particular features
like the camera in the restrictions you
I
in settings it will indicate to the user
that
this particular features been disabled
due to a profile being installed
so that they don't they are confused
need to come to James Barath
why the camera is disabled
it's also much easier to see all the
certificate details have been delivered
and %um and finally pro provisioning
profiles no longer appear at all
in settings because its handle
completely automatically the device will
automatically
through expired provisioning profiles
when they're no longer needed
one less thing to worry about turning 20
s tenure seventy
you'll see that we've support we have
support for a number the new pillows I
already talked about I was eight
as well as the query to you determine
which
iTunes account has been configured on
that particular Mac
and we also have have for another gap in
adding the commands that tells a Mac to
initiate AirPlay Mirroring to a
destination
so without further delay of the guys
come back up and show you a few things
that I just talked about
and completing the the device duty cycle
so we go to the settings and we'll see
what we have
active up us manage settings from the
from
R&D answer to notice that to you don't
have a profiles
are setting under general anymore is
called device management
if I just heard are regular
configuration profiles installed
this would be called profiles if I have
both
device management setting and profiles
and started called
device management and profiles so but
since we only have the Indian aroma
profile here
I'm going to conduct and as you notice
art this is no
a non-renewable indium Indian profile
and you notice that every every single
profile that the the server has pushed
is no colour did into some sensible
category so we have restrictions they
can tell which restrictions have been
convicted by the server
and we have applications that have been
installed here
and we have also accounts that have been
configured so we don't show the
individual profiles but
that actually configured these we just
call it all this information so that it
some more pretty accessible
and discoverable and in more details
attention we have better
better information about certificates we
can actually see the fall
our signatures and %uh public you did up
so it's not just like dot dot dot
and you can also have are information
about other
settings that come down and here we have
manage domains
so I'm gonna show you much demands how
those are working email
so we are in back
in Acme to private and I'm gonna start
are composing an email I'm gonna pick
our market and MADD com
and this is no market address us this is
not something that I should probably
send email to
so it's so its own marked as read if I
use a different address
use my me in private mail that's marked
us
a valid e-mail that meets our are
you know a lot rules and this also
applies to my center console
since I have configured this device for
i Kant I also have my i card account
so my I quote account is also marked
that's not something that I should be
sending met with
so to are managed a man's inside
now and
then we are basically done with the
device so know we can return this device
to service
so the next year is gonna grab this
machine aren't worth much going to do
he's going to issue a erase command onto
the device
so basically the user has left the
company or perhaps I graduated from
school
and magic happens no so we're gonna
unplug the device and look to a
different device
so here we go
and know we have just received the same
device
and we're back in the squad back in the
home screen I'm I'm going to
us a new user I'm gonna walk through the
setup screens
and configure this device third the
devices come back
for the duty cycle and I've got the
activation lock bypass code for this
device
and he's gonna walk through go ahead
and and set up and when he encounters
the fact that it's locked
I'll be able to clear it and you'll be
able to actually finish activation
and continue on right so assumes the
post talks to be a couple services again
I'm I'm getting prompted for some random
Apple ID because the previews user
had enabled I quote even though this was
a supervised device we had a lot of
people to use
fight my Find My iPad and no I have no
idea
WordPress users account is so marc has
just issued
a activation luck unlock comment from
from profile manager and if I know go
back to
the activation phase no I'm going to be
prompted to
in rolling to my Indian server again
call acne help desk for any issues
and my next user is no going to get
prompted to
and to their password and read it to go
so that's the duty cycle over
love using iPad's with Andy and to a
similar program
so thank you mark and doc
just briefed or new easier to understand
user interface in settings and I was
eight
make it easier for you understand what
the impact that and the relationship is
on their device
get showed you how managed email demeans
work to help
users prevent data leakage sending
documents the wrong email addresses we
also showed how to use the activation of
bypass code we captured when rolling
device
to you enable the device to be white and
returned to service
by completing the cycle and again
getting that devices right device in on
the program settings
to re enroll in here and the insulation
that brings us to the end of our session
like to sum up for the
again the different audiences for the
session if you're an administrator
you should use the writer on the program
if you want to Android devices
wirelessly
or Apple configurator if you wanna do it
wired
you should use the bond purchase program
and distribution and manage absent books
should be content to your devices if
you're in the a.m solution provider
we support all the services device in
roemer program
bond purchase program an activation of
Management
as well as all the new features we
talked about today in both I was a
analyst in Yosemite if you're an app
developer
I where your enterprise we've got this
great new page that talks about how you
can
use I West that's the fact within your
enterprise doing an in-house development
we have a number resources again for
developers both nvm an app developers
documentation rndm protocol the
configuration profile reference
the developer forums for MDM and if
there are any administrators out there
we've got documentation for the device
in Roma program
and Apple configurator and a number
discussion boards that a great place
ask questions and get help both from
your fellow administrators and
Apple representatives their number
additional sessions this week including
to following the session right here
Pacific Heights
summer colleagues that their help make
that great new line I lesson
malai these features and with that I'll
thank you for your attention
and hope you have a great rest show