good morning everyone my name is Jeff
I'm an engineer vector in america
a mix of framework exploit free-market
the collection a
13th which deliver huge range of
functionality
all the functionality is going to be
extremely fast
and be very energy-efficient today why
introduce some new features and
functionality killer framework
which are designed to release a simple
by the way that you access
this high performance functionality so
what are you gonna find in the XRF amor
to break this into four broad categories
the first image processing
here you gonna find convergence between
various pixel format were
shears convolutions et cetera we've got
digital signal processing
I fifties the FT's bike rides very
specter
operations vector math functionality
so a lot of the things that you can find
math that age for example
operating on factors so sign a factor
cuz I'm
vector era and then finally linear
algebra
on solving systems of linear equations
I get values matrix matrix operations
a lot of functionality in here as well
de klerk from work with a lot more than
just functionality to the table
I first it's extremely high performance
when we say this there's too many
metrics that we pay a lot of attention
to you
the first speed it's going to be
extremely fast
there's two key tools that we use to
achieve this
the first two short back to you meant so
on Intel were taking advantage of the
agency
in-ad act and on armor taking advantage
in neon
also in some situations were utilizing
multiple cores
we're gonna do this automatically so
we're really gonna take advantage of all
the processing
that's available for you the other
metric that we spent a lot of time
looking at his energy efficiency
so where increasingly relying on our
portable devices
I it's important that we keep an eye on
this I
generally when we improve speed and
performance I
energy efficiency in improved as well so
when you'd optics alert from work you're
going to be fast
and energy-efficient the killer
framework is available on both the last
10 and I O S and it's optimized for all
generations a partner
so when you adopt the X or a framework
you're gonna write one
you're gonna get code that runs
extremely fast and as energy-efficient
no matter where it ends up running
that's really convenient for you today
wanna talk about the
the new features and functionalities to
make it easier to get to this
high-performance
we've got some great new features in the
image which really round out what you
can do with the image
and i wanna spend the rest of the time
introducing
two new pieces at work the first
designed to
really simplify the way that you access
high-performance linear algebra
we're calling this linear algebra
departed the XRF amor
the other piece is not actually a part
of the axillary Famer
on it's a collection of vector program
in Providence
it's found in sandy Doddridge and
for those view that one earlier on
high-performance specter implementations
there's going to be some great great
tools
in here to help you do that so now let's
jump right into the image
this is our high-performance enterprise
image processing library
it's got a huge range of functionality
I wanna show you some of the things that
you can do with a short video
you can perform
alpha blending dilation erosion
you can create so both filters to at you
edge detection
convolutions for blur and Deibler
you can create multi colonel convolved
there's min and max
filters various color transformations
and worked and cheers
this is just sum up what you can do with
the image
really you can do almost any of your
image processing needs with the tools
that are available and
the image I wanna move now in to use
them work that we introduced last year
and
this is about getting your image into a
format
the image can consume specifically for
coming from a CD amatuer
so until last year this was a this is a
difficult task
if you didn't know exactly what the
pixel format abuse the gym a giraffe was
for whatever reason it could be
difficult to
get it into the 8-bit air GB or whatever
format that you saw on the image that
you wanted to work with
the last year we introduced a a single
routine that allows this to happen
I'm just gonna move through this at a
high level make you wear that for
further details please see last year's
talk
I'm but all you do now is you create a
structure
which describes the pixel format that
you're trying to get to you
and then you're gonna make a single
function call the image buffer and it
was CD image
mistakes in on initializing the image
buffer it takes the structure describing
the format
and the CD image I at the end of this is
gonna return in
fully nationalized the image buffer and
you can now do whatever you need to do
the round trip is just as easy single
function call so now we've
performed all the operations on the
image buffer I stayed in the same format
so you can use the same structure
describing the the pixel format
and this is gonna return to CG amatuer
so some really great interoperability
with
I with CD image ref: it's really easy to
get your
image data in an hour the image this way
last year we also see a introduced some
a high-level I entry points you
some really amazing convergence for and
this is through the image convert any
time
it does exactly what it sounds like it's
going to do allows you to convert
between
nearly any pixel format and any other
pics format
again just a high level for further
details the last year
stock I'm but the way that it works is
your gonna create
to the structures describing the pixel
format one for the source that
for the source format one for the
destination type
when you create a converter and then
with that converter you can create image
you can convert between the two image
formats convert as many as you want with
a single converter so
this allows you to convert between you
know any pixel format to the power user
this means that you can get
almost any have your image formats into
a format that
the image can consume very easily very
efficiently and its gonna run extremely
fast
you got that some really great things to
say about these two new features
I one Twitter user said functions that
convert the image objects
the CD image objects and back thumbs up
another Twitter user said the image
convert any to any is magical
I threaded and vector as conversion
between nearly any to pick the format
we really appreciate the feedback I'll
we're very happy that you guys are using
this and find it
useful please keep the feedback coming
through that I want to introduce I video
support
to you the image this is new in both
ilsa and OS 10 dot 10
I'm gonna start with a high level
functionality
from I see the pics about forever so
this is a a single video frame
and we're introducing the same
interoperability the same
easy views that we saw with core
graphics
to know if you want to get your CV pics
a buffer rather into a format the VM it
can operate on
it's a single function call you use the
same structure which describes the
format what you're trying to get to you
and the recall the image buffer and it
would see the pics about for
it takes in uninitialized the image
buffer
it takes the structure describing the
format and the see the pics a buffer
there's some additional arguments for
the power user which will see a little
bit more about and second
at the end of this you've got a freshly
initialized the image buffer
and you can perform any operation on
the round trip is just as easy serve the
image buffer back to see the pic soap
operas
is the image buffer copy to see the pics
a buffer
takes the image buffer that you just
finished working with the buffer format
describing this
the pixel format and then the CP pics a
buffer that you trying to come back to
you
so some great interoperability now with
core graphics as well
to support the high-level functionality
that we just saw
there's a lot going on behind the scenes
all this expert is exposed to you as
well
so the lower level interfaces there's 41
new video convergence which are
supported
you can through some of the other
arguments that we saw do things like
manage the chroma citing
I work with transfer functions and
conversion matrices
there's a lot you can do with this
another one that's really neat if you've
worked with video formats before his RGB
color space is
so there's some subtleties and some some
a it it's just it's a little bit chicken
complicated
to get an RGB color space and the image
makes this really simple and easy to do
the image converter any to any is
extended to support all the video
formats now
and there's two great new convenience
routines which allow you to commit
create converters to convert back and
forth between core graphics
thank or video so now the video support
in the image we've got great
interoperability with both core graphics
core video really fast convergence for
for both image and video for pixel
formats
and really fast operations once you're
in the image
I wanna show you some typical
performance I thought I have here
is performance from video toolbox
this is available in core media
and what I've got on this graph showing
the
the speed in mega pixels per second on
the y-axis
to convert from BRG a 8-bit
pixel format to the picture format shown
on the x-axis
the Graybar is always turned out nine
this is before
video toolbox had adopted the image
and the blue bar is a standout 10 after
video toolbox
adopted the image we see if you think
here
first we see some really great
performance improvements
soviet image conversions are gonna be
really fast in some cases were up to
five times faster
the other thing that we see all the way
at the right the v2.10 image format
was even supported before even supports
a wide range of formats and it made it
really easy for them to introduce new
features
ob once they adopted the image video
support
so this is what you can expect out of
the image great performance
simple easy to use I get
interoperability with calligraphic
Concordia
now on a move on to linear algebra
this is a new sub framework annex or a
primer
it is designed to be simple access high
performance linear algebra
I want to begin with the motivating
example
how do you solve a system of linear
equations I'll
let's look at how you do this with the
way back also available in excellent
primer
and this is saying if we've got a system
of equations
and some major a and the right hand side
and some metrics be
how do we find a tactical be
so with the way pack it's gonna look
something like this:
it's not terribly straightforward
the naming convention in a way pack use
a short names
so you're gonna have to figure out that
STEs
the means thought system of linear
equations
what you there the argument names are
not going to be much better
the you're passing by reference here
and all the argument types are still a
packager
so there's gonna be a lot of explicit
cast
additionally there's gonna be a lot of
memory management that you need to do
explicitly
work spaces or in this case a pivot
factor that you need to create
so there's a lot to just finding the
right routine and then using it
correctly
we think it should be much simpler than
that
let's look at how you solve a system of
linear equations with linear algebra
it's going to be really simple it's
simply going to be LA Sol
all the details are going to be managed
very behind-the-scenes
so with that let's dive into what
exactly you're going to get out a bill
in the Rajya Sabha member
so its new in both I O S 8 and other
standout
10 is designed to be simple
with good performance
it is got single and double purses
precision support
I'm so it's not going to be mixed much
like Basel a pack
it is a got support for objective-c so
the object is going to be a native
objective-c object
what are you gonna find in linear
algebra
there's a huge range of functionality
we've got element wise operations
add subtract matrix products
me in our product out a product matrix
matrix
chance poses their support for norms and
normalization
a spur for solving systems of linear
equations
and into pieces which are unique to the
lineout reception marking
and other supplies and splat we'll see
about those in further detail little bit
later
let's begin with the lineout project
winner other object is a reference
Canada pic object
as I said it's an objective-c object in
objective-c
still works in see though
it manages a lot of things for you so in
here
in that initial laid-back example we saw
that for each argument you're tracking a
pointer
the row and column dimensions leading to
mention our stride there's a lot of
things for each argument
means you have a lot of arguments
there's a lot going on
here the object is gonna keep track at
the data buffer
its gonna keep track in the dimensions
of each of these objects
errors and warnings are attached
directly to the object making really
convenient
and then finally scaler type I so it was
in a way back we've got all the API's
duplicated
one for single and one for double week
collapse all that down to half the
number BAPI
memory management for these liberals
were objects again is a reference
counted
objects there's a lot of documentation
about reference can object there's
nothing new here
just very briefly from C are you can use
LA release
and Ellie retain you do not ever free
these
from objective-c I they take the
standard release retain
messages and then finally objective-c
with are
which is what we recommend just let you
read exactly where you want with no
explicit memory management
from here on out all the examples that I
show are going to be objective see
are using our so there's going to be no
memory management
so how do you get your data into one of
these linear algebra objects
in this example we're gonna allocate a
buffer
it's going to be some number rose by
some number cons and we know the
the bro Strider number elements we're
gonna feel that as a row major metrics
then to get that matrix into linear
algebra demand we're going to just call
LA matrix from float or double buffer
it takes the pointer the dimensions of
the matrix
the roast ride and then him
which will see on the next slide a
little bit more details about those
and then attributes which are attached
to an object
these attributes allow you to do things
like enable additional debug logging
in this particular case the data is
copyrighted a to the user's retained
alright stay
in this case they needed for it
so hints when you're passing data to
linear algebra
there's some information I can be
beneficial to the framework to deliver
the maximum performance
I so hence are designed to allow for
this to allow for you to you
give us details and insights about the
buffer
so that we can use the right routines
behind scenes
so for example if you know that your
diagonal or triangular matrix
we can leverage that either him
so if you pass the wrong hint it's not
gonna give you wrong result
just may add additional overhead I if
you don't know just use LA no hint
the next piece i wanna talk about it
ways evaluation
I wanna do that with the fairly large
example for slide
I'm so it's not important that you
understand exactly what's going on in
all this code
I just one walk to lead a high-level the
you can understand what's going on
behind the scenes
%uh when you're out for use in a
valuation graph when you create an
object
evaluation is not necessarily going to
occur it's going to be added into this
valuation graph so the star this
function we've got to valuation graphs
with a single node in each of them
and as we stepped through this code
we're gonna create additional objects
so in this case we create a transfers we
add that to our valuation graph
that we take this summer on elements
attacks and and the
even elements attacks again we just add
that to the valuation graph
and we continue at this time the product
the
eighty and next to you
all skill by 3.2 all this is just added
to this valuation graph
at no point has any evaluation occurred
or
any temporary data structures been
allocated
I'm so no competition is going to occur
and tell you trigger
this allows us to not perform a lot of
frivolous
memory allocations and computations
right now we don't
trigger a competition to you explicitly
ask for data back
this is gonna happen with LA metrics to
float or double buffer
or related activity for or double buffer
so again creating the subject is gonna
be lightweight we're gonna do a lot of
work behind the scenes to make this run
extremely fast
and we're only going to compute the data
that you request that the and
I want to show you some performance
results for the routine that we just saw
before I do that I one introduced that
would blahs
this is an open source implementation
applause I so if you weren't aware
that was is available next oratvnetwork
this is probably the implementation that
you would find yourself using
so now let's look at the the performance
that routine that we're looking at four
on the x-axis we've got various metric
sizes
on the y-axis we've got bigger flops so
hires gonna be better
here's the performance the early as a
reformer
we can see it's pretty good let's
compare to the XO requires
the eight an extremely high performance
benchmark here
what we see here is the router is
getting most of the performance that the
X or
from work and deliver much simpler to
get all the performance from running out
for
there is a discrepancy on the small and
are there are fixed cost
associated with these objects which are
magnified for smaller
matrices but overall you're getting most
if the performance
with a really simple clean API
I just wanna put this performance
comparison into perspective
with you had used that open source
network implementation
laws performance would look like this
you can see you're getting a lot of the
a lot of the possible performance
from linear algebra
next on talkback air handling so I've
got here's just a sequence of operations
with linear algebra
after each operation we're checking in
their status
we don't recommend doing it this way
what we recommend doing is checking
their once at the end
so errors are gonna be attached to you
and propagated through these valuation
grab
so if we have an area in the first
statement that there's going to be
attached to the object
AB some is going to see that there's an
air they're just propagated through
additionally with ways evaluation is a
classic errors that may not be triggered
it will come
computation time so it's always best to
check the status as late as possible
in this case were trying to write back
to the buffer before we even check the
status
the way you we recommend checking the
status is I
if status 0 or LA success that
everything went well
in this case you got it in your buffer
if its greater than 0 there are some
warning
are you gonna have dated there but you
may not have full accuracy
and then finally less than zero some
harder occurred
in this case there's going to be no I
did in that buffer
this might be something like that
dimension mismatch or something that you
just can't recover from
to this or begs the question: I do we
debug this if we've got all this
a later checking lazy evaluation
the way the best way to do this is to
enable debug logging
with LA Activia enable logging when you
do this and you encounter an error
warning
you're going to get a message like this
to standard air I this is good
this is going to help you determine what
the air was and where it occurred
which really helps you quickly narrow
down where the problems coming from
i wanna talk a little bit about the
details have the SOL ass if you're
familiar with where out for a
I'm workable a pack for you know that
there's a lot of options here
so I just wanna talk about what
ourselves doing at this point
so it is square nonsingular matrix it's
going to compute the solution
to a tactic was being it is square
and its singular it's going to produce
an heir I'm
so right now it's pretty straightforward
to do I'm and this is what you're going
to get out
the next piece which is unique to linear
algebra is slicing
this listing is lightweight access to
partial object
I say lightweight access so there's
going to be no buffer allocation and no
copying things that you can do with
slices are for example taking be on
elements vector
we shouldn't have to allocate a
temporary buffer and copy those are
elements out into that but for
we don't need to you
and when I say that there's no
allocation and no copy don't confuse
this with lazy evaluation this is that
evaluation time
we're gonna do everything that we can to
just access that data in place
this three piece of information that you
need to create a slice
that is of that stride and dimension
let's look at an example I would say we
wanted to slice
and get some arria some of the elements
out of an existing
actor already the first argument is
going to be the offset
zero-based offset asserted start with
the 80 minutes gary 7
stride is the the direction and
number of elements that were going to
move in this case it's negative to you
so we're going to move back to elements
and then finally
the dimension is three so we're gonna
have this view
30 min vector which is really elements
out and some larger vector
again no copy no allocation here just a
lightweight access
developments in some large object
what are the ways that you might use
this is to create a tiling and Jim
let's just look at a simple example you
wanna some two major cities together
where the ways that you could do this is
with us a simple nested loop
I'm and you put your slices
inside the room and you're splitting the
two operands A&B in this case here
and you're creating a partial results
see just using that the
getting the next partial some
so you can do it this way and it's going
to work
but we can actually do a lot of this
work for you
so instead what we recommend doing
is hoisting that some out a little with
a lazy evaluation nothing's gonna happen
here
and instead it just put the Flies on the
result
SAR pictures change a little bit it
looks like
something different is happening here
but behind the scenes you're actually
getting what you saw on a previous life
you get exactly what you want we're
doing all the work for you behind the
scenes
so it's really easy to work with the
slices
and the rule of thumb is to put them as
close to the result as possible
the next piece is a splat aspirants away
to you work with scaler values with the
I'm actor
vectors and matrices so it's the one at
to to you every element vector
the whether you're gonna do this is your
call LA some
with your vector object and then you're
gonna flatness killer value to you
so it's really easy to do certain
operations now it's killers
on matrices and vectors
so that a high-level summary linear
algebra it's got a really simple easy to
use API
got some great modern language in
runtime features
and its gonna deliver really good
performance
without I want to turn it over to Steve
to talk about went back
thanks Jeff some Steve cannon
I am a senior engineer and the vector
numerics group work with Jeff
and I mean it talk about our
other new features shortly but before I
do that I thought we have a little bit
of fun
and just talk about went back to quickly
so Linpack is a benchmark that
originated in high performance computing
community and what it really measures is
how fast
are you able to solve a system of linear
equations
now this might seem like kind of an
arbitrary benchmark
but it turns out that lots the
computation we do every day
boil down to solving your problems so
this is really an important thing to be
able to quickly
now when you talk about when pack it's
important to keep in mind
the twin pack is measuring disputable
hardware
and software you can't have
great performance on Linpack without
good hardware and without good software
it takes advantage of hardware the half
the past few years we've shown you
a shootout between excelerate running
and i OS devices
and what we like to call brand a
last year we showed you a chart to look
like this
comparing excelerate running on the
iPhone 5
against the best Linpack score that we
were able to find anywhere
for any friend a device so this is
performance in gif of the double
precision did it
saw it on the iPhone 5 gives you about
three-and-a-half bigger flaps on when
back
which is a really impressive number it's
great
now the past few years we showed you a
chart like this and then
the next year brand a hardware would
have improved enough to make the
comparison
more interesting and then we could blow
you away again with how much faster
salary us but sense last year
find a hardware hasn't change that much
and so the great software primitives
that we give you an accelerator
well assist on the iPhone 5 and you can
see it's not
that interesting comparison so this year
we thought we do something
different we can find some new
competition
instead of comparing current IRS
hardware against brand a
we compare accelerate running on the
iPhone
against accelerate running on some other
device
what should we pick we chose to look at
the 2010
Mac Book Air this was a sweet laptop I
had one of these
fantastic this was like the first one
that we shipped with the current
hardware design on the outside
to really nice machine it's just a few
years old you can see it's more than
twice as fast as the iPhone 5 watts
so how do you think the iPhone 5s tax
well should have some clue I probably
wouldn't be showing you the graph
if it wasn't at least gonna be clerks
but on the other hand this
this is a pretty sweet laptop from just
a few years ago and we're gonna
compared against the phone that fits in
your pocket like so
I don't know who thinks that the that
the iPhone 5s its master
who thinks that the MacBook Airs faster
okay so let's see what happens the
iPhone 5s
we give you 10 .4 Giger flops
double precision Linpack and we have
other islets devices to
on the iPad air we give you 14 points 6
double precision get a fox and
you don't need to be expert in high
performance computing
in memory hierarchies in vectorization
in multi-threading
to get this you just use simple
primitives we give you for matrix
operations
and you get this kind of performance so
I think this is really cool
that I'm gonna move onto our last
new feature for the day just called
Cindy
now simdi traditionally is a a name used
to talk about hardware stand for single
instruction
multiple data and that's not exactly
what we're talking about here
this is a new library that we're
introducing in iowa say
and almost any assembly and it has three
primary purpose first one is to support
2d 3d and 40 vector math and geometry
the second purpose for seventy is to
provide
a lot of the features of metal in C
c plus plus and objective-c running on
the CPU
so it can make it easier to prototype
code maybe you want to run the CPU
before you deal with you
stuff maybe wanna move code between the
CPU in the pew
makes it a little bit easier to do that
and finally
Cindy library provides an abstraction
over
the actual hardware Cindy and types an
intrinsic state you often used to
program against
the making easier to write your own
factor code when you need it
so I think the most interesting thing
about this is the vector math geometry
and I'm gonna dive right into that there
are already
a couple love vector math geometry
levers on the platform
there's all the features accelerate
which can do just about anything you
want
there's GL kit spray kit scene kit the
physics library that goes with them
so if we're going to do a whole new one
we had better
get some things right so my wishlist
love well I really like the should look
like
is a is is kinda like this first of
which have in line implementations
everything we possibly can
because when you're doing you know a
forty dot product or something
there's not a lot of arithmetic it's
just for multiplies and free at
see have to actually make an external
function call
to a jump that's not what you want to do
you're only gonna do seven arithmetic
operations
and because this essentially everything
and Cindy
is header in line so just get inserted
into your code
if you really nice performance next
which def
concise functions don't have a lot of
extra parameters
if you want to do a dot product 3d dot
product using blogs
it looks like this got all these extra
parameters
we are things you need to write this if
you're going to do it
using GL kit which is a great library I
love D ok
but the compiler should know that X&Y
are
three national factors you shouldn't
need to tell it that in every function
you call
with Cindy you just read this
factor dot X&Y functions overloaded the
sport all the different vector types
that we have
it just works it inserts the correct
implementation and your code
be a great performance if you're writing
C plus plus then
we have even shorter names 170 namespace
and these look
just like metal so you can take mail
code
move it India at the using namespace MD
and a lot of it will just work using
Cindy hatter's has really can be anyone
reading on code
the last feature there to i think is
important is that
arithmetic should use operators so you
on average two vectors
rather than needing to rate this
you should just field the right 0.5
times X plus Y
knife the average defect has a lot
easier to write
it's a lot easier to read Xcode more
natural
let's let's let's dive into what
actually available here we're doing
first the basic types we have a lot of
vector types
available in Sandy but the ones that
you're gonna used
most often when you're doing vector math
geometry
are the two three and four dimensional
foot factors which are just vector float
to sector 43 and vector float for if
you're writing C plus plus code
again we have the the names that match
metal they're in the same the namespace
you can just say
flow to 43 for and these are based on a
Clank future: called extended factors
and that gives us a lot of functionality
for free that made writing this library
really pleasant
so first off arithmetic on factors
pretty much just works
you can use all your favorite arthritic
operators on vectors
and on scalars everything is nice
in mexico DC to read and to show you
another example right now
so a pretty basic function for graphics
library is a vector reflect
so we take a vector axe and we take
a unit vector an that unit vector
determine to play
and we're going to reflect acts through
that plane this is a really
common operation graphics and there's a
simple mathematical expression
that gives the result now before we
might have
had have a lot of promos function calls
to compute this expression
but with Cindy it's really simple we
just right X minus
twice the dot product affection the
normal vector
times normal actor says just as simple
as the mathematics is
it makes your code again really easy to
write really easy to read
I think it's its it's much nicer they're
a bunch of other features
that we get with these factors without
needing to colony functions or do
anything
we get access to vector elements and
some factors really easily
array subscript in just works if you
wanna pull out
the the second home in a vector you just
subscript it just like you would if it
were an array
name sub-sectors just work so if you
have a factor of four floats
you can get the lower half first two
elements by just using
the name in the vector dot low the high
half is just are high
you can get the even elements to get the
on elements and I should point out the
some factors
and elements the LWC can assigned to
them as well
as reading from them and this is really
useful when you're
writing your in fact especially fitting
perspective coordinates or something
like that a lot of times you need to
just
set some value in the fourth quarter net
for example
this is really nice if you go totally
hog wild with this
it will make it harder for the compiler
to generate great code for you
but use sparingly this is a really
powerful feature
we have some other thats that's about
what you get
for free with the types now we also give
you lotsa functions
attack that give you the operations that
you want
we have three haters that have tons of
stuff that comes up all the time for
math and geometry
math common and geometry
in C and objective-c those functions
look like this
she noticed the math functions look just
like the math functions that use for
scalars
they're overloaded so now they work for
floats for doubles
for vectors afloat for all earlier
floating-point vector types
just works you want the square root
vector just call square root
everything is is there the common
functions you may be familiar with a few
furnish a darker before if you've done
a lot graphics programming these are
operations that are really useful when
you're dealing with coordinates are
colors
you have a dialogue before them may be
new to you but don't worry about that
their
easy to understand there's a lot of
documentation for them hatter's
and then there's the geometry functions
as well
now in c plus plus and metal again we
have shorter names available in C pas
plus these are under the same the
namespace
at these exactly match the metal
functionality so
again this makes it really easy to move
code between CC plus plus
objective-c and metal when you need to
I wanna call out that some of these
functions
come in two variants there's a precise
version and there's fast furs
now precise is the default because if
you don't know
which one you need its it's better to be
safe and give you the
the most accurate when we have but their
is also
a fast version if you compile with fast
math then you get the fast ones by the
fall
the fast ones just may not be totally
accurate the last bit
about half the bits in a floating point
number with the faster
now even if you compile the fast math
you can still call
the precise ones individually when you
need to by just
introducing precise into the name and
simile vice versa if you don't have fast
math
specified you can always call the fast
ferry and and C plus plus
we do this with namespaces there's a sub
namespace called fast in a sub namespace
called precise
the you use you can just override the
default really easily
now last when we talk about vector math
and geometry
wouldn't really be complete if we did a
major cities
so we have a set matrix types char
matrix float
an by M it could be two three or four
and they don't need to be square you can
have it
for by two matrix or to buy three matrix
I want to point out that n is the number
of columns am as the number of rows
if you're a mathematician this may be a
little strange to you to buy free
matrix has two columns and three rows
instead of vice versa
but if you come from a graphics
backgrounds is very natural as follows
the precedent
that metal and open CL India axe and
GLSL in all of these
these libraries have have always used so
that's that's why we do it
there are lots of operations available
on matrices as well
you don't get the operators for free in
C++ and objective-c sorry
you do have to make some function calls
but we have and I said a function to
create matrices
we have no cell functions operate on
matrices and matrices and vectors
this is just a certain the broad
overview we have some other stuff as
well
it c plus plus you get operator
overloading so you can
you can add and subtract multiply by
scalars multiply matrices and vectors
you have we are some nice constructors
the make it easier to create these
objects
really nice to work with really easy to
write your record
so that's that's where the vector math
and geometry story
and now I wanna talk a little bit about
reading your own city code
using library so we also have
lots of other types mention the the
beginning vector float
is just a few of them we also have
actors doubles
doctors have signed and unsigned
integers 8-bit 16-bit
32-bit and 64-bit integers Wii sport
longer vector types
8 16 32 or months this is really useful
to rate just a little bit of code and
have the compiler effectively unreel
your lips for you
we also have online factor support all
of the
normal vector types are aligned by the
fall
which is great when you're doing
geometry because
you're not usually getting the data from
somewhere else you know
we just want to align we want to give
you the best performance you can
however when you're right here on vector
code usually your operating on data
buffers that came in from somewhere and
as buffers may not be allowed
so we also provide online types for your
work with
I'll show you an example that a little
bit later
now just like floating-point factors I
showed you
you get lots of operators for free you
get the normal arithmetic operators
is just work you also get that was
operators those just work on factors
they work with actors and scalars
you can shift every element vector right
by three I just writing
factor shift right free we also have
a big set of conversion functions for
you these let you convert
from one vector type to another I want
to point out that you should use the
conversion functions
don't cast vectors because all surely
doesn't do what you want to do
when you cast factors reinterprets the
data in the vector
as the other type this means the you
can't even
cast say a vector a four 16-bit enters
into a vector for 32-bit integers
because they have different sizes so
rather than casting them
call the conversion functions which will
convert one factor type
to another factor type for you give you
the right behavior
you also get comparisons so comparisons
just work on factors
a little bit strange though because I I
can't really talk meaningfully about one
vector being
less then another factor right that
doesn't make sense to magically
so comparisons produce a vector results
where each lane of the result vector is
-1
all one's if the comparison is true in
that lane
and its zeros if the comparison is false
and that line shown in Example
here's a vector for floats May compared
against other vector for floats
see if X is less than why so in the
first line
0 is not less than zero parents false
results here
now one is less then 3.1 for 159 so the
result is all one's
saw to was not less than mice infinity 3
is less than 42 now
I I just went through this but it's
going to turn out this doesn't matter a
lot to most at the time
because almost always when you do a
comparison you're gonna consume the
result of that comparison
with one of three operations vector any
vector all and vector but select
vector any is true if the comparison is
true in
any lane of the vector vector all is
true
if it's true in every lane the vector
and it select
lets you select between the elements of
two vectors
based on summaries of the comparison
so most of the time these give you the
functionality you really want from
comparisons anyway you don't need to
worry
about the theory details love what the
type but the result is
now I'm gonna show you an example
abusing this trigger on Pacha
I'm you choose an example that's
something that we normally
don't really think about actress it's
not that hard defectors
but it's something that you know it's
outside the realm of third
floating-point computation things that
we normally think
we look at string up so here's a simple
scaler implementation string officer
right out kNR
and all we do is we iterate through the
bites at the source
and we copy them to the destination and
when we reach a bite the 0
we stop copy at complete implementation
right there
now as I said this isn't too hard to
vector ice
here's started a typical SSE intrinsic
implementation string copy I haven't
pulled out
all the crazy stuff here but this this
is sort of a a reasonable accommodation
and this is fine it wasn't too hard
right it's a little bit ugly
I I find it kind of a pain to read on
the big problem with this is that this
works for 32-bit and 64-bit Intel
but we might wanna now runner code on
army after right
of either right a whole new
implementation or just
fall back on the scale occurred so we
want to give you the tools
track fast implementations that you can
run on all of our platforms
here's with us in the implementation a
string of it looks like
first off it's a little bit shorter than
the than the assessee intrinsics version
and I think it will be cleaner I'm gonna
walk you through it the first part here
we just go buy buy buy: until the source
has 16 byte alignment skin able to use
aligned words from the source
from that point on I am I'm not gonna
get too much into the nitty-gritty
details why it's important to do this
but when you're dealing with implicit
leg data objects like strings
you you do you really need to light your
source offers
having aligned are sore spot for now in
its gonna cast
the source and destination pointers into
pointers defectors
you notice I used two different vector
types here number I aligned
the source buffer so it's a vector hair
16 that allied has 16 byte aligned
the destination vector is not
necessarily want
there's no guarantee that by allowing
the source did the destination is allied
so instead I mean use this packed car 16
type
which is a unaligned vector type for
this nation
so now that I've I've set up my types
the actual
meet of the copy is really just these
two lights
all we do is low defector from the
source compared to zero
if any lane is equal to 0
then we stop the copy itself not
any when a factor 0- we're done
week we continue as soon as they relate
to zero word on
so than in the copy we just copy that
vector
from the source to the destination and
advance both the pointers to expect
really simple
and then finally if we did find a zero
if we found the end of the string
in the neck 16 bytes well was just copy
bite by bite from there
until we reach the act is a really
simple importation
it's not the best implementation it's
possible right but it was really easy
and its gonna give us a nice performance
let's look at that
we look at the performance measured in
bytes per nanosecond
for a variety of string lights now this
bytes for nasa
how fast were copying so that more data
we copy
the the better off we're doing higher is
better on this graph
we start with that scale occurred we had
Nancy we get up to about
half a bike for a nanosecond which is at
but still
500 megabytes a second we're moving a
lot of data
but we're gonna do a lot better let's
look at that same the implementation
that you recall is just if you want code
it's almost 10 times faster
and as I said it's possible to do better
if you really part the stops
here's the parents that we get from
Lipsy on the platform which is it's also
a vectorized implementation
and it does some really clever things
about edging an alignment to get
more performance but you notice we're
getting most of the performance of lives
we got nearly 10 X when we're within
eighty percent of the performance of
Lipsy
furlong vectors we got that with just a
few lines of code
they were really easy to write Lipsy
contains an assembly
we wrote four lines see basically to get
get the performance we see here
and that's really what are our message
for today is
that XLR has always given you
really fast vector good
and what we're doing now is try to make
it even simpler for you to get at that
to make it so that more developers can
easily take advantage
but the performance at the hardware
offers now I want to know
the linear algebra and Cindy are both
brand new libraries
they do have some rough edges I'm sure
you'll try to do things that we haven't
far
but that also means that you can tell us
what use cases are really important to
you
and will take that into account you can
have an enormous impact on
the way that these libraries develop
if you want more information about
excelerate or Cindy if two great
contacts
hold and bold and George Warner there's
a budget documentation available for
the image invidious p online
I would also recommend looking at the
headers and accelerate if you need
documentation
the image and the DSP linear algebra and
Cindy
all have lots and lots of documentation
and headers it's a fantastic resource
if you want to know more about how
things work the developer forums are
pretty good place to ask for help with
things
I'll if your gonna file any comments in
the developer forums
the place to file this under core OS
that's that's where your
you're most likely get the attention you
want and
the bug reporters also a great way to
report issues
make feature requests you'd kill you
don't only need to use this
if there's a bug in the conventional
sense you can say
hey it would be great if you know I
could do this thing that's
a little bit different what you're doing
or make an entirely new feature request
or say I try to do this and the
performance wasn't quite as good as I
thought it should be
those are absolutely bugs in the things
we want to look at so file bugs early
and often we love to get them and we
love to get feature request from you
guys
but on other stuff that we've done in
the past two years has been motivated by
feature request we got from external
developers
related sessions that are worth checking
out if you're here you're almost
certainly engaged in the middle sessions
there tomorrow morning
was a great thing to check out thanks
love to come I guess