morning
either
welcome the session 704
building aP's for enterprise and
education my name is David harjo
I'm a software developer and I West and
today I'll be joint
I'll by Alex Parkin who also works with
me
on I S device management so
building aP's for the enterprise and for
the education market
really is not that much different from
building aP's in the App Store right
you've got a cap a nap you gotta get an
app that solves the problem you have to
have a nap
that is well design and it's gotta be a
pleasure to use
for the user but in an enterprise
you've got some unique requirements
usually your clients devices are very
likely
going to be manage under mobile device
management these devices may be
supervised
and if you're not familiar with what
supervise means we'll talk about that in
a minute
and they may be special use cases that
are kinda peculiar to the business and
education market
so today what I'm gonna out present to
you
is some tips and tricks to help you to
write your next enterprise
and education aP's I'll so that their
done much more pleasurable to use and
makes you a much better
developer in this field so let's get
started by talking about
mobile device management so
what's mobile device management mobile
device management
is a protocol that's built into OS and
OS 10
that allows a server
to remotely manage that device a server
that's managing a device using MDM
can install network access such as VPN
or WiFi it can install celts
such as email calendar contacts and so
forth
a new NIOS 8 they can now install books
such as PDF's he pops and iBooks offer
as well as books from the iBookstore and
manage them
they can install single fine on
using Kerberos and in New NIOS
8 Kerberos can now use and identity
certificate
so that their identity can be renewed
without the user ever having to type in
a password and most important to you
today an MDM server
can install and configure your app's so
this is very important
and here's your first trip for
today allow MDM to configure your app's
and we'll talk about how that can be
done
exactly in a few minutes so little
device management let's talk a few
minutes
about manage aP's and accounts so this
iz
little bit of a terminology that we have
anything that MDM installs
on i OS we call managed
these include everything that you saw
from the last slide
manage aP's managed accounts and I was 8
as you know you can install third-party
keyboard extensions the way you install
third-party keyword extensions
on Iowa State if you can't spell is gone
ap that has an extension and
if that app was installed using MDM
that keyboard extension s then
considered as manager as well
and of course
in Iowa State we have this great new
feature call
document providers thank you
it's a really powerful feature and
if you install an app that happens to
vend
document provider extension
such asan ap like give access to your
internet
your intranet resources or your
your network file storage that app
also becomes quote-unquote managed
so this is in contrast with things that
the user install themselves
sold if the user goes out and installed
app from the App Store
on their own BYOD device for example
those things are
considered not manage so
we have managed switches the stuff that
and %um installed
and you have not managed which is what
the user installs
I so why do we do this
well it helps I O S
to restrict dataflow so that your
enterprise data
doesn't flow into your users data space
and vice versa
so for example if you are in Manish at
and you are looking at a document and
you cap open in
you know that list app that shows up on
the bottom of your screen
his all the app that can handle that
document
I that mister aP's will be filtered down
so that because you start from a managed
ap only other managed aP's
and and accounts will show up in that
list
and we do this automatically
conversely when you are in
on unmanaged ap I
and you tap open in the list of gaps
that you see
will not include manage that so in that
way
without the user ever having to do any
switching off
you know work and home I
we protect your data and we do this
everywhere
emails so you can't Fort a corporate
email using
dry cloth account for example we do it
in calendars
in attachments we do it a in Iowa State
we have managed remains in Safari so if
you specify
certain domains in Safari as belonging
to your corporate
intranet documents that you download
from those domains
will only going to manage that
XF
and manage aP's get access to per app
VPN
this is a feature with happen sigh I O S
seven and has proven very popular
a and what this is just a review
is that Manish capsule get that data
tunnel through this VPN but not anything
else
not the user's data so your VPN
carries your data and not the user's
data
yet another way two separate enterprise
and personal data
so what's the takeaway rely on I O S
to manage the dataflow between aP's
and accounts don't try to do it yourself
I O S has a great way of allowing this
to happen
in a very clean and intuitive way
using the fact that you're managing a
device over India
right so that them
next let's talk about supervise devices
so what's this a supervised device
is a device that has been activated into
you know so supervision
it is it health I O S that the device
is owned by the enterprise this is in
contrast to a device that owned by a
user such as bring your own device
right supervision can only be set
activation there are two ways to step
back to us supervision
reactivation the first way and
you sought you saw this in the keynote
yesterday iOS device and rolling
programme
with DP a devices that your enterprise
purchased from Apple I can be configured
so that they're supervised and enrolled
into your MDM
right out of the box you don't have to
touch it at all
you Hannah shrink wrap up to the end
user the on boxer
you walk through the the Setup Assistant
and they're supervised and enrolled
the second way is Apple configurator
which requires you to take the device
out
and plug it into USB depending on your
I use case in your scenarios wanna be
should serve any
so why do we supervise devices
well tell you why you can access the
whole bunch of different
restrictions and controls that we only
allow
I on enterprise own devices
such as always on VPN new in Iowa State
global GDP proxy Third Party Content
Filter
also new and Iowa State
single app mod which lock your device
into a single ap
perfect for kiosks
I'll will see some examples of that
later
we've got restriction to prevent the
user from erasing their own device
anyone with students here
and preventing enabling restrictions
also students
your local you your settings and many
more
so the takeaway here as: police
supervisor
enterprise on devices if you own it
supervisor you won't regret it
okay
so for the next
part of our presentation
I'll we're gonna show you some example
aP's
that may illustrate
some of the use cases you may face
when developing aP's for the enterprise
the first ap we're gonna show you is a
document access ap
and this ap is I designed
to access a secure document like a
sensitive documents
may be over your intranet and stored on
the device in a secure
matter
the second app that we're gonna see is a
point-of-sale
ap this may be something like you use
in a retail store to check out customers
you know buying items and the third
will be something that education may use
an assessment ap
where the student uses your app
to take exams rice 03 example ap
document access point-of-sale an
assessment
and along the way I we will illustrate
some of the things that we
we talked about earlier
so let's start with the first ap
k secure document access
again this ap a retrieved documents
securely
and displays it to the end user
alright so let's talk a little bit
about MDM ap configuration
so you remember a few minutes ago I
talked about
allowing an MDM server to configure your
app's
well how do you do this
it's really very simple all you have to
do
is to watch for the special key in Ennis
user defaults
com dot Apple da configuration
don't manage when you read this key
from Uranus user defaults you get a
dictionary
that magically appears when the MDM
server
pushes configuration doubt your so the
MDM server
pushes down a dictionary and you can
access it
using this key
your app can then respond to
configuration changes
so why do you want to do this well
what's the first thing that you wanna do
when you install an app
you want to configure its URL probably
had some server I am you may have a nap
that this deployed in more than one
branch
of your business and you want to
configure it
for that particular location
instead of having the end-user
reconstructions
and say all pappas and perhaps that go
here go there
type this URL in what could go wrong
you define your own keys and
say hey a if you
install my app over MDM push down his
keys
and I'll see them and I'll use them for
my app without any user intervention
right at configuration so
you are also great so in this example
you gonna do some your URL configuration
and AST I'll trust that list of
server root certificates it's also very
important I
it helps you to prevent man in the
middle attacks
and I will show you how to do that in an
example in the code examples
so I am I were asked Alex to come up
here
and is gonna show you a little code
example
that demonstrates MDM configuration
good morning developers so we're going
to switch
over to our down a laptop going to look
at some comps
SAR first application that we're looking
at today is our secure document access
app which we've called secretive
in our example so with MDM afton
figuration
the most important thing that you need
to do is to make sure that you register
for the NS users did user defaults to
change notification
this is the notification that will be
sent out when an MDM after figuration
is pushed down to your device see you
need to be listening to this
notification and then rereading the
default when you receive it
so in our example I have a few troller
when the big stroller leads I'm going to
register for this notification
am every time I received a I'm going to
call re default value so that I can
get my values back again an in this
example on going to load up
re default values as soon as I get the
view up so that I can get the first
initial lead so in my example here
so you remember we talked about that
Honda Apple dock configuration dot
manage key
this is the key in NS user defaults for
we're going to be stuffing BNF
dictionary
with your configuration and sell your
notice that
suggested some other keys here on in my
dictionary I'm going to have a key which
has a string
for my server URL which is going to be
the URL for the document I'm going to be
retrieving
and your awesomeness that I have to keep
or configure a for a server
root certificate we're get to this later
in the presentation
but that also one going to be pushing
down in this and your map configuration
and so you know simply default all I do
is I call on tennis user defaults
I make sure I call into that
configuration key
and then from the dictionary I pull out
the relevant
on information I need such as the server
euro
an important thing to know is do you put
error checking on this
make sure they are not loading bad
values
and sell was now what we're doing is all
switch over to the iPad not push down
an example MDM at configuration sup
you nurse at my AppleCare called secret
I secretive
and when I open it up I don't have an
MDM ap configuration
here currently I've installed the match
dapper you right now I don't have my
server URL
sup over on my MDM server I've loaded up
a command to send down
the match.com om and ap configuration
sa mga send that notification down
and you notice that we when I received
the notification for and this user
defaults to change
on a Mac we've started up a session and
retrieve this document from the server
you're all that was given
and so that as MDM ap figuration and
were returned to their
thanks Alex
it's like magic your app to configure
correctly without having your user do
anything
it's Corey I hope you caught that little
the
remarked that Alex made please validate
the input that you get
from the server because as far as you
are concerned as an ap writer
the server isn't unknown network and the
T
and they're gonna be pushing down keys
that maybe miss format it
or of the wrong type up so please
validate
the keys make sure that your I
understand what they are
also publish what you understand so that
the server
that means can configure you correctly
so that's MDM configuration
next alright
let's talk about single sign
on a single sign-on
is I Baker Bros we have operate Kerber
single sign-on
on I West that can be applied
by the MDM server across the entire
system
so that once you login a
you'll be logged in across several
different aP's
when you're accessing the same network
resource so using single sign-on
couldn't be easier are you just have to
use
HTTP or HTTPS which most of you probably
are
if you use Ennis euro connection or an
issue oral session
Kerber a single fine on is free for you
so here's the takeaway don't do anything
in and it works it's great the MDM
server
will apply the configuration and your
caps will either get a £200 okay
or a 401 fail it was a 2-under okay
assume that the resources available to
you
and just use of course
your aP's may provide alternate
authentication such as you know HTTP
digest
I and Kerberos authentication
will be attempt at first and if that
doesn't work
I A West will fall back to reporting an
error to your ap
and you get the chance to authenticate
using
a difference scheme so
don't do anything no example next okay
here's something that a that with gotten
asked several times how do i download
files securely all the way from my
server
down to the flash on IRS I
was s you may or may not know all files
that you create
from your app already get this I'll
protection level protection complete
until
first user authentication so just a
recap
this means that the file is a cryptid I
unreadable after you restart your IRS
device
once you enter your passcode the device
the file is readable and it remains
readable
across device lock until
you restart the device again so
what we wanna do is we want to upgrade
the
this file so if you do nothing and you
use you're just writer file to disk
this is what you gonna get but we won a
great that so we want to have
I the file be a specify test data
protection complete which means that
whenever you lock the device
the file because unreadable
cryptographically
and with the next time the user
enters the passcode but have the file
because readable again
et cetera so
we're gonna use an issue oral sessions
data task to do this and
as a little a bonus years old maybe this
document is extra sensitive
I you don't want this document to appear
in your users backup so
I called back up or iTunes backup so
we're gonna show you
how to mark files so that they don't get
backed up alright so let such or back to
Alex
and is gonna show you some code to do
this so
back on our demo machine your notice
that we have on our view controller said
it as
implementing the delegates %uh NS you're
all session
and and that's your obsession data and
the reason we've done this is we're
going to
over we're going to use as Stella get
call backs during
our secure download cell down here in
secure your /url session that I have set
up here
I'm going to take that use server you're
around I pull down from
MDM ap configuration I'm going to create
an and that's your all session
data task right here you notice that
left the completion handler at the nail
and the reason I've done this is by
setting now for the completion handler
I will get the don't get call backs for
the day to task
and that's the most important thing for
me sup
in URL session data task did receive
response
I'm going to get this call as soon as we
make the connection and I'm going to
create
a file where I'm going to download Mike
strategic plan pdf
and sound your nurse I call NS File
Manager default manager
create file path contents and
attributes:
and the attribute I'm going to pass into
it is this and that's file protection P
and in that and a spa me I'm going to
specify that
I want and a fire protection complete
myself and what this means is that the
file will be
unreadable when the device is locked in
left the files already
ok them when the by when the device
walks and so while I'm downloading
I'm going to set the attribute to that
and sell
the other important thing that we
mentioned already is that we want to
turn off
on file backup and so why I'm going to
do is I'm going to sell onto the file
URL
up resource value and resource mana the
key
I'm going to set it on in is and this
URL is excluded from backup key
and this key will make it so that this
file will not be backed up in iTunes
or and I clout and so were gone on
inurl session data task then received a
net this delegate math is gonna be
called every time urge the
new data from my server I'm just going
to store all into that file
I create earlier and then at the very
end in your all session
testing complete welfare I'm gonna make
sure there are no errors in
if there were no errors I'm going to
then change it so that the attribute for
an s5 texan key
is changed to complete because at this
point I decided you know when the device
locked I want this file to be
unreadable and was it that's
pretty much it arm I would show you the
demo but we've already shown you that an
MDM ap
the rations them let's go back to Dave
thanks Alex
so downloading to a secure file here's
how you do it
you create an issue oral session create
a file
when when the request begins create a
file with
data protection complete unless open
so that you can continue to write data
to that file
after downloading it even if the device
is locked
when the file has completely downloaded
upgrade their protection
to file protection complete and up
as you can tell third as you can see
there's an in a swirl method you can
call
to Sep a bit that says don't back up
this file
to iTunes and I clout
alright next
HTTPS certificate pending
so I we all know that
HTTPS is a way for the client to tell
weathers talking to the correct server
I'll this only works if the certificate
chain
is trustworthy so one of the things that
we usually do
s Wiese we can specify for this
connection
that only the certificates are to be
trusted and not any other certificate in
your database
that make otherwise we trust the Ford
for example Safari
I and to do this of course you meters to
the PS
you need to specify York trusted root
certificates
during HTTPS authentication
you'd and you do this to prevent man in
the middle attacks
that pretend to be your server
and here's to take away you certificate
pinning
instead of doing things like SSID
detection
especially in you know like retail a
scenarios
lot of people use SSID or some
other kind of your respect to tell
whether or not there you know they're in
there
you know talking to the correct server
instead of doing that
make sure you are talking through the
correct server regardless
of the environment that you're in
alright to show you a short example of
how we do certificate pinning
let's switch back to the to alexander's
code
sell your will remember that I mention
that we had that
root certificate key that I set so when
I push down the MDM
ap configuration I push down the data
for my server's root certificate
because I want to check to make sure
that are not connecting to the wrong
server
and verify that my users are connecting
to the server I want them to you
so journalists that I have here MFN that
employees called you are session
they receive challenge with completion
handler and this is going to be call
when I try and connect to my
HTTP ass server and when I try and
connect
I want to double check that the
authentication method that was
in the challenges protection space is
and that's your all
authentication method server trap if
cell
I'm going to get the sack truss raft
from the server
which is in challenge that protection
space that server trust
and then the next thing I'm going to do
is under load up that root certificate
I got from india Mac figuration I'm in
this example I've already loaded that
why did they
and its user defaults re back I put into
a variable called self
that into server root certificate data
some girl up that data
and I'm going to create a sec
certificate with their and I want double
check that the certificate was create
correctly by making sure that's not
normal
and if so I'm going to then that be
anchor certificates
on the servers challenge trust that I
got
and resided this is I wanna make sure
that I
only trust the research I've got sent
down I don't want to trust
any ob the default search it gets there
included in the eye West bikes
and by saying the route anger
certificates I can extend them
you know side call also have this method
Sectra set
anchor certificates only if I wanted to
make it so that I also trust that the
fault certificates installed on the vice
I would set this yes value at the end to
now
arm if you are only selling it for the
incur certificates
that you trust you do not have to set
this avoid I in this example show you
how you can
trust the device assertive gets if you
want you and sell
the last thing that I'm going to do is
I'm going to do a sec trust evaluate
with the servers challenge trust and I'm
going to get Russ resulting from that
transfers on I'm going to make sure that
you know
I didn't receive any errors and make
sure that the sect Russ result is your
unspecified
or Percy on and then if I find out that
I do trust the certificate or five
turned off certificate pending
I'm going to I'm actually just say camp
call the completion handler
with and this year all session of
challenge use credential and give it the
green ensured that the server gave me
if I don't trust the surgeon get I will
call once their completion handler
and this year all session of challenge
reject protection space
and that will tell the app that no I'm
not going to allow you to download
sup in our example on were go back to
the iPad again
sup you know Safari download this file
in settings upset up the lair
can hear concert if company and I'm
gonna turn in on
this and the next thing I'm good to you
and
a right mess want you there so let me
just reset this
sup when I call into the a
yeah sup your nurse ignore the crash
I this when I called back into the app
it tried to load up the document again
from server and your notice that it's
telling me that my certificate
can buy the server the certificate
presented by the server is not say as my
concert at get
so let me go back to my server and I'm
going to change it so that it presents
right certificate
cell have set up my server at pics the
certificate
everything's getting I'm going to click
on my refresh
and wiry fresh as Penn certificate was
cracked this
comments I was able to lead the document
and so that is how you use a kit kat
dennings
thanks Alex issue TPS certificate
pinning I assures you that there's no
man in the middle attack
with the connection for your trusted
server
so what we have we learned from the
first example
ap the document secure document viewer
I'll be learned ever that MDM ap
configuration
is awesome right magical
server can configure your app's just
right
the user doesn't have to do it and you
can offer keys
to the server admin to configure up
at to set up your ap just the way they
like it and by the way
at configuration can be delivered
ass you're installing the app so there's
no race
between app installation and
configuration
I'll we also learned that single sign-on
is also awesome because you don't have
to do anything
and it works all you have to do is use
HTTP
osha TPS and if you if you're administer
configured
single fine on on the device then it
will just work
or you'll get an of failure
we learn how to download files securely
using an issue oral session day the task
and setting
the correct protection level at
different parts of the download
as well as excluding from backup an of
course
we saw how to pin are HTTPS
certificates that's our first
alright next ap point-of-sale
for this example we are going to show
you a little
I maybe a device that a sales associate
might carry so we have a scanner on the
left-hand side here in the cab are
which will scan barcodes and we have a
catalog
that left them look up prices for
products that are
peebles so
the first thing i wanna talk to you
about is
sale at mod so single at mod
is a wave that MDM server
can't lock the device into just your
you can sent a command down and
tell the device just run this app if the
app crashes
relaunch as the app the user press the
home button
just got stuck in the a so that's on
some level will show that later
in a in a letter example but first
I'd like to talk about I beacon
so ID can I beacons awesome
it gives you context it tells your
device
attend a culture ap that you're near
something
right you something that you specify
up so you can use ID can to provide your
app with context
in this case for the point of sale at we
want to provide the app
the knowledge that you are actually
using barcode scanner
near the checkout register right so you
take the device
elsewhere I it what you do will not
allow you to scan
prices at the scan barker's
so using I V can in conjunction with
other car location technologies
such Justin or GPS location gives you a
relief
fine-grained control over how your ap
used
I and it gives you an ability
using Indian ap configuration to let the
admins configure at your app's
so that your racket only be used in this
particular retail store
or in that particular contact right
so here's a tip use I beacon to verify
your location sensitive operation
so I'm gonna head of out again and is
gonna show you a little example
so for our point-of-sale ap I have
letter app called Miller
which is for selling baby clothes and
sell in my example
why I have is I have this app does again
this after we get I'm going to create
a CL location manager object and I'm
going to set the app delegate
add the deli up for the location manager
om
in the important thing for the IB chem
where we're going to this method here
a star Mark for redshirt began as that
what I need to use I need to set up an
and thats UUID for the region that I
want
this work in and so I might sample let's
imagine our point-of-sale example that
we have we want are
people at the red shirt to be you know
in a general area we don't want them in
the back room scanning things and
selling
things without the speaker security
cameras around them
so for our region I'm going to create
you ID specified here
and I'm going to give an identify your
for have the app some
line this case and decree feel beacon
region
using the proximity you idea created and
the I don't fire
and I'm going to call on to the location
matter to start monitoring
for this region answer why the important
things that you need to make sure you
implement
is this method I've location manager did
determine stay
for region this method will be called
when your app
is not is in the background so that your
app can receive region notification
changes so that say you now
they close my register ap they walked
out the store and then they open
I'm walked out store you will get and no
you will
receive this met they call back when
they leave the region
and so in this example I'm just going to
you I have it so that when you are
inside the Beacon region
I want to start figuring out how far
away they are from the IP can cause I
wanna make sure that my cashiers
are right closely BB can I don't want
them you know
all the way on the other side the store
South I'm gonna start
range in the beacons in the region and
why the things I'm gonna do some good
implement this method
I've location manager did range begins
in region
and I'm just going to get the closest
pecan cuz I don't particularly care
about which I begin their quest
hairstyles are close to one
number check the proximity to make sure
that's not far on now
if it's not I'm going to say that
they're near the register otherwise
they're not near the register and I set
that variable appropriately
are more the air things are nurses I'm
also implement the method publication
magic did
enter region and location measure did X
a region which will be called when the
ap is in the for gramm sup for my
example I'm going to go over
in the trust the iPhone I have over here
you nurse I have my moolah at here and
get a pinata
your nurse right here I have my stamp
barcode
view and you know it right now it's time
them the to return to the register area
cuz there's no I begin that concurrently
attack sup back here on my demo machine
zamka startup in I began
and so you know it's there as soon as it
detected that the I became what that was
within the region and that was range
crackly
I got this nice layer Barker view cell
have another nicer camera
my cashier scanned just run through the
park adds
and do that and sell this view only show
up while I'm
in the rat in the near the I began
that's appropriate for and so when I
turn this off eventually this app will
receive a notification that
I've left the region and that this you
should probably be turned off
and was it in your nose I also have a
catalog section
South you know it's now that I turn off
the I began that I'm no longer near the
register and so the view is turned off
and that is how years I begins
thanks Alex there's so much you can do
it I beacons
out that can provide a really
awesome user experience both for your
admins
and for the end users alright next
I'd like to talk about network
reachability
network reachability Sasaram API's
that lets you know whether our server is
reachable at all
on the network and a best the mall
it actually tells you when the server
become searchable or becomes unreachable
so for the following example
I want you to know you can use that word
reachability
to provide intelligent offline
behavior so back to Alex and he's gonna
show you how that's done
sup back in our Mila
I have this method so I call I Crean
ASEAN network reachability flags
and I'm gonna create reachability
reference which I do you buy
as the network reachability crate with
name and the name and a pass into here's
a domain so in my example
up above I've defined Apple dock
comments the domain I want you
watch for and see the reachability up
and so once I do that if the
reachability is no
I can call SC network reachability get
flags and then once I do that I can
check the flags and I'm going to check
that
SE network reachability flags our reach
is reachable
and using that Pagano when I i can not
then a network operations because the
users and airplane
for example now this is nice and get but
this is just one of matt that I don't
wanna be calling this all the time
so why I really want to do as I want to
register this
so that every time the reachability
configuration changes
I get notified and so what I've done
down here
as I creatine SE network reachability
contacts I'm which I'm feeling in a nice
little block that created check the
flags and
if the flags say that it's not reachable
on going to set my
of wine bearable appropriately and one
good years I'm gonna call
s the network reachability sec call back
and get feet at the reachability
and I have to give it this method which
billy change which is written in C
on the reason I put earlier in that
context that im falle
with that call boxes I wanna keep all my
code in objective-c South all I'm going
to have my seem at their reachability
change due up here
as I'm just going to have it call that
block that feed into the infall
so that I don't have to mess around with
seek out that much sup
with the SE network reachability I said
call back i sat the theme at the time
calling into in the context and then the
next thing I need to do is I need to
make sure I schedule there so that this
gets called every once in a while answer
the way I do that as I call
SC network reachability fat dispatch
queue: I give the reachability reference
that create and I'm not going to call
this on the main kya my example
you can do this another cues I've chosen
this just for simplicity
and so now if we return to my iPhone
example
your nurse I have this nice where
catalogue baby clothes that I can buy
and so why why do you is I'm just going
to you switch
the Anna into airplane mode my switch it
off you know it's there FC network
reachability has changed my label to
inform the user that they're currently
offline and so you can use if the gate
behavior that you don't want users to do
while they are offline like
try and added document that you want to
sync up between multiple users
and so that as the network reachability
full
thanks Alex network reachability allows
you to you provide
intelligent offline behavior without
having to send a request and timing out
and things like that you know up front
that the network or your particular
server actually is not
reachable and you can take the
appropriate action so
in summary our second app example shows
us
I that you can put it happen to single
at mote using and EM
against example to follow you can use
I beacon to provide context for your app
and changer app behavior depending on
whether it's near something
you can use this work or location to
allow your admins
to really configure your app's to a very
fine grain
and finally network reachability allows
you to behave
intelligently when a server snot
available
let's talk about a third and final lap
example assessment
so this is your typical example King ap
I there are several modes of operation
here
I for exams I
but far for our example the flow that we
want to show you
is a student operating on an iPad
I taking an exam and
we're gonna download the exam packet
from a document provider
from your school's filesystem okay
once the user begins taking the exam
the exam have a lock them in and depict
the exam
and I'll submit and students will be
allowed to use the iPad again
so let's start with
document providers so doctor providers
as I mentioned before is a really
awesome new feature of Iowa State
it allows you to exchange documents
between acts
when you install ap after docking a
provider
you are actually installing network
access
for other APs
to access document providers use the UI
document picker view controller
this is the same one you use for iPod
dock folder
you stalking a providers to get access
to enterprise
network resources don't build in
network protocols into your ap
instead rely on the admin to configure
network access maps that allows your app
to access those network resources
alright so let's go back to Alex and
he's gonna show you a little bit of
example
sup your nurse that I have an
application which have called pencils
down and
what pencils downs good years that when
did a user starts the path
I want them to go into their high school
enter their high schools ap
ap document ap and I want them to
retrieve the tasks and then I'm going to
proctor the exam on behalf the high
school so in this example
when I do start s I have this UI
document picker view controller
now I'm going to create one internet
with document types I'm going to allow
in this case
some good shoes HTML tax in RTF
and I'm going to set the mode in this
case I'm going to use you I document
picture mode import
because I want to get the file in keep
it in my app bundle
and the RPM going to do use I'm going to
set the delegate
on DUI document pay-per-view controller
to myself
and I'm going to present that the
extroverted user now
when they go into that document pic I
can get two different call backs if for
example they failed pick something they
quite done they don't find
the test file that they won on their I'm
going to get this document picker was
cancelled call back
and in this case I'm just gonna send a
notification on the console that you
know
a I can find the document if for example
they actually depict a document I'll
call this document picker
depict document you're all will get
called by the system
and while the use of double check that
there's a natural your own then
I'm going to open up the document and if
I'm successful
in opening up the document I'm going to
request single atm
and load up the task for them sup if we
go over to the simulator we have our
example here so
I pencils down I go into my apt
you know sadness knife where testing
view some get a quick start tests cuz I
wanna start
it s with that my high school's given me
so I don't a location
your nurse that I have the MHS stock
which is a document provider
and so I'm going to go into here your
nurses have this view this view is
actually coming from the
MHS docs apt I have installed in
simulator
issues not created by your apt and so in
this case if I want you I can login
MHS stop to check my credentials make
sure I'm actually a high school student
Thunder's girl login with someone
credentials and I'm worse like my
program to thank you to do
it so your nurse that once I selected a
my
after got that document back in I loaded
up into my nice their web the ins
and started the test and so that's how
document providers work
alright
doctor providers are very powerful but
they're very easy to use
as you can tell necks
let's talk about on a single at mod so
we've mentioned before that MDM can put
your
ap it put your a device into single app
mod
which means that it will only run one ap
but in the case of this exam ap we want
the apt to be able to put itself
into single app mod so this mode of
operation
is called autonomous single app mod
your app has to be pre-authorized by the
MDM server to do this
and this can only be done on the
supervised device
but once that's in place your app can
offers of the hey I want control of the
iPad for now
so use a condom a single at mote to lock
the user
into your ap but please do it sparingly
because the user will get stuck in your
app if you don't get them out
your Apple crash and restart crash and
restart
and the user will not get out of it so
please be careful when you do this
but it is a really powerful feature so
alex is going to demonstrate how you can
do this
so we're back to my pencils down
application your nose that here at this
requesting a lot mode
method that period and what I'm going to
call into is you why
accessibility request got it access
session
this is the method that will star up
single at Mad
m wide use IP temple in a whether I want
single at mod
honor of and the earthing of feed into
it is a completion block which is
Boyd cool did succeed and this Wally and
I get will tell me if I was able t
successfully enter or exit signal at my
depending on which Matt I set and the
other Boolean arm it's very important
and to balance your calls cuz
as we mentioned you will lock the user
into your at
if you don't call back into their to
turn off single at night as well
another important point is to make sure
that you register
the DUI accessibility guided access
status
did change notification this
notification will be sent out when
single
at mochi changes and sell why I've done
is like our
create a layer math a call guided access
to change adaptation
and when I received that notification
I'm just going to update my
single at mod arm was it state and so
your nose here at the have
guided access that's changed I set you
know I'm in seeing a lot
if I receive this notification sup
remove over to
are iPad and on this iPad it's a
supervised by slavery setup
I've also pushed down and MDM profile
that to find that
pencils down giving it's by no ID is
allowed to start
arm single at mod autonomously so if I
go into pencils down
and get start my test I'm gonna skip
over the fire provider section for now
and your notice that I am now in my test
if I tried exit the app
by pressing the Home button nothing
happens and locked into year
so let's add I don't know I am
discretion some justice met the test
an at the test was successfully some and
sell your now nurse if I press the home
button
I'm able to accept because I bounce the
call
thanks Alex apart in a single at mod
very powerful use it sparingly
measure the user can get out of it
eventually
so okay summary of the third ap document
providers
super powerful new feature an IRS a use
it
to gain access to network resources in
your enterprise
at a nap equals at network access
upon a single at mote allows you to lock
your own app
into single at Mon so the user cannot go
to a different app
so what have we learned today
I we learned that we should assume that
MDM will be used to manage your absent
devices
when you're writing aP's for business
and education
assume indians gonna be there and as
going to configure
the environment for your ap
you can safely assume that enterprise
own devices
will be supervised so check up to check
out the list of features that are
available to you
when the device is supervised and use
them
I on the other hand if you're writing
for bring your own device environment
you can re-live that you can assume that
the devices will not be civil rights
so if you're Abbas wanna work in both
environments
be aware of the features that are
available in each case
and finally rely on i OS
to provide a great set of system why
features that your aP's can leverage
single sign-on VPN
global proxy manage data flow between
the Manish aP's
and the on Minitab some accounts single
at mod
both MDM driven an autonomous
document providers I beacon
and core location for context
alright finally I wanna call your
attention to a great new portal that
we've just
put online developer to Apple com slash
enterprise
May for developers just like you
for more information our eventual assist
bald and bold
there's that enterprise portal again
find most of what you need in there
and of course the developer forms is a
great resource
some related sessions
this morning we had managing Apple
devices the check out that video
we have distributing enterprise aP's
right here
following this session and where if
you're interested and
out big into doc providers talking to
providers
building a document based app is a
must-attend
Thurs 11:30 thank you very much