good morning hello
welcomed the session 705 distributing
enterprise aP's my name is Dave Archer
I'm NIOS of or engineer so
tell me if this sounds familiar to you I
you're in charge of a team
that's developing an I O S ap for your
our business
offer your school okay you're in charge
of everything
including managing developers
contractors distributing App Store MDM
I making sure that Iran on a whole bunch
of different
regions and I make sure that it keeps
running
for years and years to come so if this
sounds familiar to you
the session is for you I
I want to give you a kinda burnt
comprehensive
overview of everything that you need to
know
to successfully develop and distribute
and deploy
I O S ap in an enterprise setting
so we're gonna do that
by focusing on for major
areas about that are that will sound
familiar to you if you've ever done this
first managing your team next
using Xcode server to provide a hub for
development
then some
ap distribution strategies that'll keep
you in the clear for years
and finally custom b2b
and how that fits within your
organization's deployment plan
rights of four major topics
some let's start with the first one
managing your team so
let's start at the very beginning how do
you get started
developing enterprise absent all what's
really simple
you need an enterprise developer out
it used to be
that we had a five hundred-member a.m.
500 employees limit
for and before our enterprise ap
accounts that's gone
no minimum company size s long
as you have to do %um this number for
your enterprise
your eligible this program
is 299 a year to get started
you need to create an agent account
and then at admins and team members
to the book developer portal so
let's talk about these roles and agents
if the person who is authorized to
accept
legal terms I'll with respect to the
developer
the Developer Program at menace
manage team members and they prepare
aP's for distribution there can only be
one
agent but multiple admins team members
are are those people who actually
develop
and test coat under the program because
agents and admins are able to produce
things to represent your company so
agents
sign contracts admins published aP's
with your code signing certificates
they should be
employees of your at a price
team members however
can be employees or contractors
and we'll talk about the kind of our
workflow here
for contractors and but first let's talk
about at Mintz so at minsk and
add and remove team members from your
roster
they can create ap ID's in the developer
portal
the can request push certificates for
those ap ID
the cat at devices to the team
development provisioning profile
which everybody else in the team
including the party members
used to actually do debugging on I O S
hardware they
get to manage the distribution code
signing certificates
which is a special certificate a
coaching certificate that you need
in order to publish the app
they also create the distribution
provisioning
profiles this is in contrast to the
development provisioning profile
which is automatically manage by Xcode
and finally they are the ones who
package
the actual aP's for final distribution
so as you can tell admins up a lot of
power
in this program most of the
administrative
tasks and with respect to developing and
distributing aP's
of all under admin accounts
team members are coaters and testers
this should have their own personal
copes signing certificate
each one should have their own code
signing certificate
don't share your private keys between
developers
during the development cycle I
if a developer loses their private key
you can just read another one as long as
nobody is using an older version of
a and at a an app that they
produced its fine just create a new one
don't share the code signing
certificates use
the team development provisioning
profile to debug
a on aisle at hardware and this is done
automatically by Xcode
if you set up tax code correctly you
never have to worry about this
team members can distribute aP's to a
limited extent
they can create ad hoc distributions
which
are I am ap bundles that can be
ap packages that can be run only on test
devices
this is this is great for Q a for
example or alpha testing
but they cannot be run outside of their
own little group of devices
and all contractors I many of us at
half contractors to come in and out of
our development circle
so the way that I you should tree
contractors
is they should be enrolled ass
team members in your program you
should invite them using the email
address
and then they should get their own code
signing certificates just like any other
team member
at the end of the contract simply remove
them from the proper
from Dr member portal and
and that's it you'll invalidate the code
signing certificates the can get another
one for another project
next time art so
let's walk through a little flow of
inviting at
key member a including contractors
to join your development team so here we
have the developer
our website here member center
and have a list of people in your
development team including a some admins
and some members
what you do is click on the invitations
side a icon in the sidebar
and you'll see this you can invite one
are a bunch of people into your
development team at once
click invite person
entered the name an email address this
is just an email address doesn't have to
be the Apple ID
any email address that baby can be
reached at
and they will get something like this so
you've been invited to join the Apple
Developer Program
are so the reason they don't have to
receive this
email over Apple ID is because when they
click on that
about blue underlined link their
they will be taken to this portal where
they can then sign in with their
actual developer I D I if they're
already
at developer like the 99 dollar app
developer
the can click the top button and log in
with that
if they are not part of any development
program
they can't click on the register button
on the bottom and they will get access
to the developer tools
and the rights as a developer by virtue
of joining your team
okay
once you do that the next thing
you should 2s 80-member
is to go to Xcode and type your
registered Apple ID in so you click
Register you register as a new
a developer for example go to exco
hit your preferences good accounts and
at this
this is the key to having a really nice
flow of
you know love artifacts between your
team members
your admins using Xcode
when you log in Xcode will show you
what development teams you belong to
down there on the bottom right
in this case and is a member of the
business markets
and our price: program a
team when you click on View Details
you will see this so you start out with
no code signing identities of course
to know provisioning profiles first
thing that
the new team member should do is to
click the plus button
and request a new I O S
development cosigning profile I could
cause I certificate
when they do that all the admin from the
team
will see this if theyll they they will
see that
and has requested a code signing
certificates all you gotta do
is get approved
and Xcode will get the signing
certificate
installed on your team member and key
members computer
the same thing goes for provisioning
profiles out when
dairy fresh the provisioning profile
after they've done this they will get
the latest
Iowa St provisioning profile so most of
this
what you set this up much of the details
as
taken care of for the developer by exco
art so let's switch gears a little bit
I so
want to set that up you can actually
start developing
but what I wonder recommend for your
admins to do
is to create ap ID's right at the
beginning of your app development cycle
so if you want to develop you know some
a nap and you have some ap in mind go
ahead and go to the developer portal
here
and click on certificates identifiers
and profiles
click on App ID
and plus and create your new App ID
I create this at the beginning a good
development cycle
I'll tell you why the second
use the team ID prefix for your app
their maybe some legacy entries if you
are a developer for
out don't use those used team prefix
tell get you the happiest path
and use an explicit App ID you should no
longer use
I am while car to buy these because this
will get you
a lot more features a if you use an
explicit App ID
so the reason that I ask out admins to
create up ID's
at the beginning of the development
cycle is because
many of the apt to develop today require
entitlements
a in there provisioning profile so you
have I clout
a I cloud entitlements for extensions
you would need special entitlement
sometimes
I and now if you or your app needs push
notifications
you would need to have a nap I D
register first
before you can get a push it difficult
et cetera et cetera
so because many of the app that we
developed
day use a lot of modern I a
additions that need provisioning
its usually easier to just put entered
the App ID first and then just keep
checking boxes as you need
I'll on the developer portal that's why
so in summary I n roll
NIOS developer enterprise program to
begin development
your agents in your admins should be in
place
your contractors can be treated ass team
members
you should invite their team members ass
you create your program
and you should approve their code
signing certificates
requests remember each team member
should have
their own code signing certificates an
best practice create your app ID's at
the beginning of the development cycle
that gives you the most leverage ass you
continue to use
features that require entitlements
so that's managing your team
hope that's helpful next I'd like to
talk about
Xcode server Xcode server it's a great
hub for development
up to install Xcode server all you have
to do is install the OS 10 server
I app from the Mac App Store
and then install Xcode on the same
machine
when this happens the new and she will
show up in your server got
ap a sidebar to enable
Xcode service so here's how you set it
up
for enterprise development
the first thing you want to do if you
want to log in
with your enterprise account on
Xcode server so at that
login you can login with any admin
account
on Xcode server when you do this
Xcode the ex got server will
get its all coat signing certificate
rightly if you look at the key chain
there this data servers doesn't belong
to any developer at the servers own
code signing certificates and this means
that the server can produce
ap packages for you and we'll see how
that can be useful
in a few minutes once you're logged in
you should create a user for each of
your admin
and team members on on
Western server I
you don't have to give them home
directories you can
select services only so you this
basically creates directory entries
for your team members this greatly
facilitates the rest of the past
because you can create groups out of
these
a entries and then
create access controls based on that
group right
so that's really at for or stepped up
for our tax code server
on the west end until later we'll talk
about
let's talk about code repositories I'm
so you can create code repositories on
Xcode server also
we support get or subversion
I'd recommend get distaste
I'll you should create one repository
per app
and because that makes it easier to
integrate your code repository triggers
with pots later on and
create access controls on the server it
really is very simple all you have to do
is
had the plus button create a repository
that simple
now on your developers machine you can
actually
at a server efforts own entry under your
preferences
under your accounts so here's a server
if the servers
visible on on jury will show up here a
at that server to you your Xcode
environment
and you will get this
check out an existing project on your
Xcode welcome screen
when you click back Xcode automatically
reach the server
and figure out what repositories you
have access to
this world that house come into play
click back and you're good to go
stop box so a great feature
of Xcode server is box
so warbucks box
give you continuous integration
they will run unit s on devices
connected to the ex co server
they will generate reports and it can
create archives
4q08 so I'm gonna walk you through
how you create a bot using extra
so anyone can create a box
doesn't have to be an admin as long as
you have rights on Xcode server
the first thing you wanna do when you
want to create a bot is open the project
that you're interested in
and create a share scheme go here
click Manage schemes most of the time
you already have a scheme that you want
to use as a template for the box
scheme so go ahead and duplicate that
scheme
right there and call it integration for
instance
and make sure that the shared checkbox
is checked
have to be shared and remember to commit
the third the scheme for your server
with the source control and check it in
otherwise of course the server can see
your skin but you just made
next on the server connect
your test devices so if you plug and i
OS device into a Western server
will show up here the shop at the bottom
if you click on add to team
ex-cop sir will pick your device and
automatically at
that to your provisioning profiles to
grab your device you did
go to the developer prop portal and and
create a new product development
provisioning profile which can be
downloaded by your team members
so why do you wanna connect test devices
to the server
this device is actually used for the
unit s
will actually run the unit s on the
device
so connect a variety of test devices if
you can
and iPad iPod Touch iPhone to get the
best coverage for your test
and like I said the development
provisioning profile is automatically
updated
s you connect your device is and at them
to
the portal what you've done that
back to exco create your body
under product remember this you few open
you still have the project open but
you're interested in creating the bot
for
under product go to create bought
under to create but dialogue choose the
scheme that you've just made
the national integration scheme and
called bought
a given name to the Bach so we have to
dash it all commit integration
so for this example we won the bot to
run
when I and you commit is made to the
repository
and that set you can choose
when you want to perform the operation
you can choose what actions you want to
do and a life
test archive and which devices
you want to run this bought on
but creation succeeded and the bodice
ready to use step simple
so what you get
when the bot runs it keeps a database of
its run status
and results you can see the history
I of the bills which bills failed in
past
you can see how many of your unit test
past and failed
you can even see this on a web browser
by going to the server name slash
Expo last book
your bot will work will produce these
results
wilbur's test results unit test pattern
fails
%uh static analysis results will produce
logs
from your build and test sessions
you'll produce Xcode project archives so
you know exactly what code are compiled
for that run
and here's where the servers code
signing comes into play
the box will actually use Xcode servers
code signing
certificate to create ad hoc sign
ap packages wish cue a content download
straight from the web server
or Xcode and install on their own
devices to do
regression testing it's great for Q a
so that tax code server it's a hub for
development
install OS 10 server an Xcode on the
same machine
sign in with your enterprise accounts
any admin account will do
Hosur code repository there
connector test devices and you spots for
continuous integration
segregate hope for your developments
that's Xcode server alright
app distribution strategy distribution
provisioning profiles
when you're ready to publish your app
and distribute them
to your enterprise members you need to
create
it distribution provisioning profile
the way you do that is go to the
developer portal certificates
identifiers
and profiles again and click on the
distribution
item on the sidebar
the next step click in-house so this is
available for enterprise
accounts in-house distribution will
allow you to run
your ap but you signed on any devices
without limit of UT AP
selector App ID your provisions before
right there
that it
you can download the provisioning
profile and then go to Xcode
an open the project
and archive product archive
right there when you click archive
the project will be archive and will be
ready to
distribute that this not ready to
distribute yet you needed
do one more step you need to click
distribute and
save for enterprise or ad hoc
deployment right there
and then choose the provisioning profile
the distribution provisioning profile
that you've just created
mother team provisioning profile but
this one that provide via in-house
provisioning profile
distribution provisioning profile
and then save the file
if you're using MDM to distribute your
app's and you should
you have the opportunity to create the
manifest file
that can be provided to your MDM server
over here
I you consult your MDM server and you
can
enter the URL and app icons that will be
used
to download the enterprise ap and
that's how you package your app's for
distribution
alright so next topic it's something
that's
near and dear to all our hearts could
finding a provisioning profile rules
alright
code signing certificates are valid for
three years
thank you
I
I you can have up to two valid
certificates at a time
right so they can overlap
but you at any particular time you can
only have two valid once
you have to update your abt binary to
update your code signing certificate
because you know it part of the code
bundle
provisioning profiles
provisioning profiles a valid for
one year but you can renew it at any
time
there is no need to update your abt
binary
in fact it is the a best practice
to update your provisioning profile file
in the over MDM
so that the Apple continue running
enterprise
Apsley both of these to run the need to
have a valid code signing certificates
and a valid provisioning profile
at the same time to run on the user's
device
so out to illustrate the kind of
farm strategy that you might have to
build around these rules
I've got a little chart here for you so
the vertical bars in this chart
are years so this is years earlier one
year to year 3 author
and the arrow up there is where you are
in time
and where disc describe to you the kinds
of things that you might have to
consider
after app is deployed over the years so
let's start by assuming you're going to
publish a ap years00
you've never done it before here we go
ap a 1.0
years00 we're going to distribute it
well the first thing you gotta do
it you got to get yourself the cosine
inks certificate you do that
and you sign your app for that great but
not enough right
you need a provisioning profile you need
a distribution provisioning profile
that's
so this three steps are what we've just
seen in the flight abuse life ago
when you go through and got your
archives and disregard for enterprise
this is that
you got a cosine certificate use it to
find an app
and then you have a provisioning profile
so that the provisioning profiles are
embedded in the app so when the user
downloads the app automatically get
whatever provisioning profile you choose
you chose when you distribute it that
app so everything's great
ap strutting fantastic I
six months go by you go hey there's only
six months left in my provisioning
profile
I better refresh this before some sum up
my users run out of
provisioning profile billeted so
you create a new provisioning profile
remember provisioning profiles
I can be renewed at any time so just do
it and push it out using MDM
and for users are good to go for another
year from that point right
so
everything is going fine and now you
want to create another
abt a version must do a nap a 2.0
do the same thing again to sign a bill
co signing certificate
but you don't have to include another
provisioning profile in ap a 2.0
because the ap identity the abs but the
lady didn't change
but that's a good idea because
provisioning profile for free
to out to renew just make another one
bundle it in with ap a
2.0 so that when the user downloads at
that time to get a full year's worth of
Use
are the provisioning profile and
time goes on and you keep doing this
over the years and everything is great
all the users are getting the
provisioning profiles pushed by MTM
they don't have to do a thing app
continues to run art so now you're two
and a half years into your first code
signing certificates validity date
you decide to create another app ap be
1.0 you could sign a be with your
current co signing
certificate but you're going to get six
months of use
are a bit so many of the of our
enterprise developers will will
perhaps local threshold date where they
say
if there's less than this number of days
left in my original code signing
certificates
I'm gonna create a new one so we're
gonna assume six months is too little
they're going to create a new code
signing certificates and fine
ap be with the news that cause I
certificate
because you're signing Abbey with the
new code signing certificates
you gotta have a new distribution
provisioning profile for Abby
which include everything's great
everything works
happy continues to work with the old
coastline certificate
and Abby continues to work with the new
code signing certificates
everything's fine until
we reach close to the end of
ap base coat signing certificate
validity date
what do we do now well ok
you can reuse the whole court thing
certificate but you have a new coaching
certificate that's good for another few
years
however in order to update the co
signing certificate in your app
you must distribute a new version of
your ap
that assign with the new code signing
certificates
okay and because the code signing
certificate has changed
you also need a new distribution
provisioning profile
or apt a which a bundle with abbe
and you distribute and now everything is
good for another two and a half years or
so
notice to Cosi the expiration dates and
use the newest code signing certificates
but you have on hand embed a new
provisioning profile
every time you distribute a new app
I host your in-house after the issue DPS
this is just a little note because
a we made a recent change NIOS that
requires HTTPS
in order to do that to download your
in-house aP's
and then you send DM to distribute your
app's
into refresher provisioning profile of
silently
remember that a nap must be updated in
order to change
its coat signing certificate
art so that's little bit about app
distribution strategy
alright now let's talk about
custom b2b so what's custom b2b
have to be to be are aP's there are
host that in the Apple App Store
but are only visible to a limited
audience okay
because they're hosted in the App Store
the are reviewed by Apple
but when you install a custom b2b ap
there's no provisioning profile required
because there are considered app store
apps
to publish a custom b2b ap you have to
be in App Store developer
not necessarily an enterprise developer
you follow the same steps that you do
for publishing
irregular App Store app however
all you gotta do is check the little box
that says custom b2b
it when that happens you get a field
that allows you
to specify what Apple ID's
can't see your app and these
Apple ID's are Apple ID's
for v VPP portal volume purchase program
portal right here
when you're when a the custom b2b app is
published
an Apple ID is put in there the
purchaser of the app can see this abs
listed at the bottom
up their VPP portal where they can then
purchase licenses
and push this abt out using MDM as
though there are
App Store aP's
so why would you use custom b2b
if you're an enterprise custom b2b is
great
if and leave the if a customer Abbas
made for you
contains code that you don't own when
you buy a nap
tailor-made for you from some a for me
out from a summer company for example
you can asked them to publish the app
after custom b2b ap
which you can then view and purchase
using your own portal
and you will know for sure that nobody
else gets access to that app
K they're also great for subsidiaries
so if your company a if you're
enterprise
happens to be a conglomeration of
subsidiaries many of them have different
PPP programs a different requirements
about creating a custom b2b distribution
may be easier than developing an
enterprise app for them
art so a couple b2b app does not require
any code signing
a provisioning profile watching for
cosigning X provisioning profile expert
expiration
because they are App Store app and
you can create promo codes for beta
testing your app's
so that's custom b2b
so today we've covered are several
high-level topics here
managing your team and the roles in the
program
we talked about Xcode server and how it
can become a great hub
for your development team we talk about
app distribution strategies
and we've talked about custom b2b how
they can be used in your enterprise
some key takeaways agents and at Mintz
should be employees contractors
should be team members use Xcode server
for continuous integration
and q/a and keep an eye out for the code
signing and certificate expiration dates
and use custom b2b if you don't own the
code
alright I wanna call your attention to a
great portal site they were just
launched
developer dot Apple com slash enterprise
made specially for enterprise developers
are evangelist this fall down bolt
and a developer forms are always a great
resource for you
some really the sessions this morning we
had manage Apple devices
please check the video out we have
building apt for enterprise education
earlier today with that thank you very
much