hello good afternoon the
welcome to our session on what's new in
car location
my name is Steven Rea and I work on the
car location framework
support occasion is available
both I O S and always 10 but today
the new features that we're going to be
talking about today are specifically for
I O S now some love you
maybe new to court location or even i OS
in general
this will not be a review existing car
location functionality
for that we recommend you go to our past
WWDC
presentations online or check out our
great documentation also available
online
also we'll be having a lab session this
Thursday
so I recommend you all come out and join
us there with any questions that you
have for us
however I think that today will still be
equally applicable an interesting to
those of you who are new
to IRS incall location to those %uh view
foresees an app developers
familiar with but I O S incall location
so what's new
incall location and IOSA today we're
going to be talking about location
authorization
visit monitoring and finally what's new
is indoor positioning
however we won't have time to talk about
that in this session
but directly following the session here
in Marina they'll be a dedicated session
to indoor positioning so I recommend you
all stick around for that
so before we go on
I like to start with a brief history
publication IRS
location was first introduced in i OS
two
and then I O S three we added the
ability to get heading updates and I
hours for
with the introduction of multitasking
came a whole slew of new functionality
for location
including continuous back on the cation
which allows your app to get continuous
location updates while in the background
and region monitoring also noticed your
fencing
which allows our apt to be launched and
notified when the user enters or exits
a predefined region to significant
location changes
which also allows her out to be launched
and notified when the user's location
has changed significantly
and I was 5 we introduce new APIs for
geocoding
both forward and reverse it allows you
to take a position
that is the latitude and longitude and
covered it to an address or place mark
and vice versa in Iowa sixth
we introduced a power-efficient means of
getting location updates
referred to as the forward-looking Asian
updates and which locations will be
batched up
and delivered to your application at a
app specified
time and/or distance interval and just
last year
and I i seven we introduced ID can
technology
which is really been taking off this
allows you to determine proximity
be arranging and region monitoring API's
which brings us to Iowa State which is
what we're here to talk about today
as you can see in location functionality
has been growing
and I O S as have the number maps that
you guys have been developing
in fact there are over 600 80,000
ups using location I O S these are all
kind about
ranged from navigation to help users
find their way home
to travel app top users find interesting
things to do
around them the fitness app to allow
users to tractor exercise sessions
and shopping app to help users find
stores and deals around them
to social app to allow users to interact
with their friends
and even gaming out to allow interesting
uses
their location so what is location look
like on the device today
there's a visual indication publication
in use fear the status bar
location arrow icon this can be solid
as we see here an example of maps which
is displaying the user's current
location
jelly the solid arrow indicates that
or ranging or significant location
changes is a news
here even on the home screen here
even on the home screen if there's an
application using location or
significant location
changes in the background the solid
arrow remain lit
in addition to the solitaire oh we have
the hollow arrow which indicates that
region monitoring
is in use here we see a traditional
example a bridge in monitoring the
reminders ap
with you this region monitoring to
deliver reminders
when the user has entered or exited a
predefined location
and again on the home screen if they are
still app using region might run a
background
the hollow arrow remain in the status
bar indicating that region monitoring is
still in use
next user control and get a finer
picture
publication usage you know location
services settings
this is in the Settings app under
privacy location services
at the top we provide global control
publication services
and down below we provide individual per
app control
publication in addition per app
we provide an indication obligation
usage by that up
this can be indicated by solid purple
arrow indicating that location has
recently been used
to install a gray arrow indication
indicating that location has been used
within the last 24 hours or a hollow
purple arrow indicating that region
monitoring is in use by the app
so what is authorization look like today
authorization is a single request
that is it prompted implicitly on first
usage publication by
you're out this is for all occasion
functionality
including location directly in the app
location from the background
location used to be a region monitoring
and significant location changes
the taxes also customize all by the app
here we see
camera would like to use your current
location with a description of why
camera user's location
one location was first introduced their
requests for the user's current location
was pretty clear
however with the advent of multitasking
and all the powerful location
functionality that we talked about was
introduced
allowing you to create very cool and
powerful aP's
we felt that the user can use more
clarity a one location is being used
and more importantly we felt that you're
asking benefit to
we don't want the user to disable
location overall
either globally or for your app
disabling some the core functionality
that you develop
developed using location we want them to
understand exactly how location is being
used
so ultimately they can make better more
informed decisions
and we believe that this is better for
battery and better for privacy
so to that end we're changing the way
that location services works
and Iowa State we started by looking at
first
and all the functionality that location
services provide
and categorized it into continuous
update
which includes location background
location and ranging
and also location monitoring our bank
which may launch the application
to deliver call back this includes
region monitoring and significant
location changes
and we broke it down into two operation
types the first
being always this is just like what
location operation provide an Iowa 7
it provided both access to continuous
updates and location monitoring
even when the app is in the background
but then we also introduce twining use
which is only for continuous updates
and it's only when the app is clearly in
use by the user
so let's take a closer look at back on
location
starting with continuous back on
location which is specified statically
by the app
either via the capabilities have an
Xcode for back Ryan Moats
location updates or via your abs
information properly list
he had a UI back remote key specifying a
valuable location
the SS before must be started in the
foreground otherwise
or if your app is using significant
location changes
and this is available with one in years
location authorization
because now in Iowa State will provide
an indication in the status bar
that your app is using location
this is just like the status bar for
navigation navigation is running in the
background
here will indicate which ap is using
location
and if there are multiple will indicate
the number back to the location
and the user can tap on the status bar
to quickly return
the most recent app using location in
the background
OneNote is that if the application is
authorized for
always look Asian access the status bar
will not be presented
because the user has granted access for
that app
his location at any time which is what
is needed
in order to access location any time
from the background
for example when your app is running in
the background data back on
at refresh or did the region monitoring
or due to significant location changes
this requires expertly always
authorization
so on the topic of multitasking I'd like
to clarify
location behavior when the user quit an
app from the App switcher
this will immediately stop continuous
back on location
however this will not stop location
monitoring
such as significant location changes our
region monitoring
this latter point is the behavior as a I
was 7.1
and now NIOS a disabling background at
refresh
will no longer disable any location
functionality
because we believe with the introduction
of the new notation authorization types
the user is now in complete control
publication usage
so how does it all look like to the user
absence now expressly request operation
via new API's
will get into the exact details of what
this looks like in just a bit
Afghan request for either one in years
or for always authorization
here we see an example of the operation
dialogue presented to the user
for compass it says allow compass to
access your location while you use the
app
and below we see that customizable tax
that your app can provide
indicating why it is that you're at
user's location
this tax is now mandatory and no longer
optional
this dialogue will be presented only
once the user
for either request to location access
for
waning years are always
as we said that taxes customizable and
is mandatory to provide
quickly we see an example the always
authorization dialogue word States
allow whether to access your location
even when you are not using the app
again the text description below
describing why it is
at the app would like to use the user's
location
says we see this always authorization
which is what users got
and I 07 is pretty powerful because at
this
if always authorization was granted by
the user user will be asked to confirm
a few days later on only if they're
always operation was exercised
that is that the app did you look Asian
in the background perhaps
in a region monitoring or significant
location changes
here we see an example of what that
dialogue looks like ford says whether
has been using your location in the
background you want to continue
allowing this and again we see that the
pact is customizable
is the same uses description provided in
their original quest for location
authorization
so now let's take a look at the new
location services settings pane
African support one in years and or
always authorization types
and in this is specified statically by
the app
again what are the details on exactly
how you can do this in just a bit
and now in the settings pain for each at
next to the location you syndication
it will have the text describing exactly
what that app is authorized for
in addition user can tap on the app to
see what operation status types are
supported by that up
with a text description below indicating
describing that current selection
here we see an example for when you stop
and quickly another example for tap that
supports always
note that in this pain we don't show the
apt description a why that would like
Houston be
location in the currency however
US developers to prepare for this
because we believe that this may present
another great opportunity to inform the
user
why it is that you're at user's location
now also knew and I always say when the
easier
when the user goes to the Settings app
for your app specifically
a link to privacy will be included which
also includes willing to location
services
if applicable here we see an example
fitness app
the app settings pane we see the privacy
the user can tap on that
and get to the location services pain
specifically for
its ap right there and change the
operating sys that is
immediately now this is going to be even
more powerful for us. app developers
because now
in Iowa State your app has the ability
to programmatically jump directly to
your app settings pane
this is done with the existing up in
your arm at it i knew i application
providing the new constant and I i say
UI application
open settings URL string will see
exactly how useful this can be
later in an example so you're probably
wondering that looks great in all
so what is it that I the developer have
to do
well starting with the actual interface
changes there are only three changes
that you need to be aware
the relevant info key in this case that
we talked about
the authorization status: you know
values and finally
the new authorization request API's
so let's dive right in for starting with
the info pls keys
previously we had and its location uses
description
which was option all and allow you to
customize the text displayed to the user
why it is that you're at user's location
this is now deprecated and replaced by
tune your keys
and its location always uses description
and and its location whining use uses
description note again that's best find
one
are both these is now mandatory
depending on which operation type it is
that your application supports the value
is a string
describing to the user exactly why it is
that you're at user's location
we believe that this is really going to
help users understand how it is
that you're at user's location
moving on to the co-operation status in
town
previously there are a number of values
one of which was KCL
operation status authorize now
this is deprecated and replaced by two
new values
authorized always and authorize wanting
use
depending on which operation was
requested by rap
and which authorization was granted by
the user
accessing authorization status: for your
app has not changed
this can be done either be a the class
method
on CL location manager opposition status
or be a delegate call back the change
authorization status:
on the co-manager delegate however
requesting authorization has changed
which brings us to the third interface
change request authorization API
requesting authorization is now explicit
either for always
or for one in years your app can make
calls
to this request API's repeatedly however
it will only prompt to the user the
first time
and not per type so if you support both
operation types you need to carefully
consider
which you want to request in your app
well before dawn this an example in just
a bit
so putting it all together there are
three simple steps
to adopting a new authorization and I i
say
first you want to decide which authorize
a shit is that your app supports
by asking yourself these two questions
what location functionality does your
app use
and is that a mandatory functionality or
a nice to have functionality for your
app
second a you one explain it to your user
exactly how you're at user's location
and third you wanna make the right call
to request authorization
and you want to do it when needed
for example when you're out first
launches don't make the request
you access location because the user
won't understand why it is
your app is requesting location
authorization and they may be inclined
to just deny that instead do in response
to a specific user action
so that they have contact and in
addition to the user's description
string that you provide
wire at user's location these are can
then make an informed choice
whether to allow or disallow location
access to be a
let's go through some examples first
let's say you've developed this great
fitness app
that tracks users runs you want to start
by first determining
how is that location issues obviously
this app is going to use location in
addition is going to use back on the
occasion
in or that the user may home on your app
and switch to the music app
and play their favorite tunes
so back from okay background location
can be enabled the Xcode in the
capabilities tab
making sure that back Ryan Moats is on
and that location updates to selected
alternatively
you can edit your information properly
this for your app
specifying the UI back remote key with
the value of location
second step is to add their property
he raps information properly this here
in Xcode
will go to the information properly this
editor
and add a new key for and its location
whining use uses
description providing the description to
the user at your location is used to
track
Iran and third the final step
is to make the appropriate API call to
request operation
and do it when needed so here after
crying your location manager setting a
delegate
and right before making a call to start
updating location
all you need to do is make the call to
request one in years authorization
pretty simple right let's move on to
another example
let's say you've created this great
welcome home now that's going to
automatically turn on the light
and maybe even unlock the front door
when the user has arrived at home
again you want to start by determining
how location is being used by route
in this case is using region monitoring
didn't act 1 the user has arrived at
home
next you need to add the appropriate
uses description key
to your apt information properly list
again you go to
the information properly editor in Xcode
and this time
a key for NS location always uses
description
providing a description to the user here
in this example your location is used to
determine
when you arrive home and finally
you wanna make the appropriate call to
request authorization
and again do it as needed in this case
right before the call
to start monitoring for region you want
to add the call to request
always authorization again pretty
straightforward
how about if you're up actually supports
both authorization types
that saved about this great app for
amusement park
in the general use case it'll show the
apt current location
in the amusement park map but let's say
you've developed this cool feature
that war additionally deliver a call
information about nearby attractions to
the user
and in this case you want to determine
exactly how it is that your app is using
location
obviously for the general use case
displaying the user's location on the
map
you're using location but for that cool
feature that tells them about cool
attractions nearby
you're going to be using region
monitoring
so again we followed the same steps
first one to add their proper uses
description case
to the apt information properly with
again by going to the
properly this editor next code of our
start by adding a key for NS
location one in use uses description
specifying that your current location
is may be shown on the map
in addition to that because your app
also supports always authorization
you add a key to and its location always
use a subscription
again provide a description to why it is
that you're at user's location
here this app will use your location
information
to identify nearby attractions
so in your abt information proper list
you actually have
both these uses description key is
because your app supports both these
authorization types
and finally you wanna make the
corresponding operational quest API
calls
again you want to do this when needed
for example
in the map view that displays the museum
part map
you want to right before start updating
location
y'all make the call to request wanting
you see authorization
and for that power user use case still
in response to user action perhaps the
user is now
enabled the feature that enables the
automatic
attraction in for mod that delivers
information about right
times for the nearby attractions or
store sales
or restaurant specials but in this case
you may want to check your apt
operations that its first
because if it's denied or when in use
you need to tell the user that they need
to authorize your app for always
operation
and in this case you may want to present
an alert indicating that
an offer to take them directly to the
settings ap
for your app's settings pane using that
mentioned open your all matted with the
new UI application open settings you're
all strain
and then finally right before you start
the call to start monitoring for region
you make the call to request always
authorization
some additional details what if you
wanna support both
Iowa 7 and Iowa State with your app all
there are three things that you want to
consider
that line up with the three interface
changes we discussed earlier
first you want to continue to provide
the deprecated
and its location uses description string
if you're doing so before
in addition to specify one or both
the new always use this description or
when in use your sister ships in case
next you want to guard the request
authorization API call with response a
selector
so that your Apple still work on iis7
here's a quick example of exactly how to
do that
and third you want to continue to use
the deprecated
Casey authorization status: authorized
value
in addition to the new authorized always
an authorized running use values
so I bet you're wondering what about
legacy of support
what if you don't update your app but
your user upgrades
his system to IOSA what's gonna happen
well your Apple still continue to work
but
it will use always authorization
so you don't want to rely on this
because 1 the user uses your app in
user's location for the first time
it's going to pop that dialogue asking
for location access always
even if your app only uses one in use
location functionality
such as location and the app or
background location
arranging so you use them at that point
decide to disallow location usage so you
don't want this to happen
you want to update your out now and you
saw exactly how simple it is to do so
so what about updating your out you can
change it supported authorization types
any time you update your app
and so on your user updates the version
of the app
version of your app on his phone order
or device
it will preserve the user's
authorization if still supported
otherwise it will go from
always 21 in use for example if you're
at no longer supports always operation
but now supports one in use and it'll go
from one in years
to prompt again for example again after
at no longer sports when used in this
case
and may now support always authorization
but again don't wait to adopt because if
the user denies location access to your
app
it will stay denied even if you
subsequently Changer app to support the
one in years
authorization type
so what about other frameworks for
location is used
let's go back to the example welcome
home out let's say
you don't want your apt to automatically
turn on the lights
or even more dangerously unlock the
front door automatically
instead all you want to do is notify the
user
and let them decide to choose to take
action on that notification
in this case your app actually doesn't
need to be launched just the
notification is to be provided
and now and I O S eight we've added a
region-based triggering
to you I local notifications via the
specification
are the see all region property on the
UI local notification
in this case here at doesn't need always
authorization because your Apple not be
launched
in response the region monitoring
instead the system will provide the
notification that you specified
to be provided to the user on behalf
and only one the user decides to respond
to that notification
and launcher app we are at actually be
in use
so you think this API requires either
authorization always are one in years
but only nature ap to be supported for
wanting use authorization
and the steps to use this API are the
same as any other location functionality
you want to specify the desired uses
description key
here in populous with a text string
describing how is your
app uses location and call the
corresponding authorization request API
as needed
what if you use and came out to you and
your app to display a map view
what the user's current location year
the show's user location
property on the MK map view class
again this requires either authorization
for your app but only needs your apt 3
authorized for wanting you
authorization and the same steps as
before
you need to specify which authorization
your app supports
in your perhaps information property
list
and make the corresponding API call to
request operation
when needed one last 1i like to talk
about web views
to allow web content that uses html5
geolocation
to access the user's current location
this one also requires either
authorization but again only needs the
one in years
authorization again you specify
in your abs information properly this
uses description key is relevant
with a text description why it is that
your app would like to use the user's
location
however in this case the authorization
request will be made automatically for
one in use
on your behalf because you may not know
when the user navigates to a web page
that uses geolocation however
if your app users of always operation
you want to make that operators in a
request in advance
if so desired
so a quick recap get ready for the
location of radiation changes that are
coming and I i say
by following these 3 simple steps: first
think about how you're at user's
location
second explain it to your users
and third and finally make the call to
request authorization
don't weigh do it today and then if you
have any questions
on Thursday you can come to us in our
lab session here this week at WWC
with any issues or questions that you
encounter
next I'd like to introduce Brad is here
to talk about
visit monitoring thank Stephen I'm Brad
Jensen
I'm a core location engineer and I'm
excited to introduce to you
visit monitoring but first I wanna ride
a nap with you
see Apple engineers aren't allowed to
publish shops and i really wanna
journaling up so you're gonna have to
help me out with this
journaling ups are really interesting to
me but more importantly
they're a great example visit monitoring
it's a great
type app that makes use of this new
technology so what constitutes
a journal yep well first and foremost
it's got to provide the user a list of
locations
where they've been during the day but
more importantly
that list of locations needs to be
relevant to them if
we list every time they stopped at the
intersection or stop sign
then they're not going to find that list
especially useful
finally we want to make sure that our
journey up
can last all day if it's gonna drain
users battery and
two to three hours it's not going to be
very useful
so let's take a look at the different
qualification API's that exist today
and you'll see why none of them really
work well for journaling aP's
if you're working on a check a nap you
might find this of
familiar first up
is a standard location service this is
where we provide your app with
periodic location updates as they become
available
naturally if we're going to be providing
updates throughout this requires the
phone to be awake
and even more importantly the radios
have to stay awake
we have to periodically scan for WiFi
networks
for cell towers or GPS
now all this is fairly expensive and
that means that
the app is going to be consuming a lot
of power
in addition the app is going to receive
a lot of irrelevant data
you're going to have to take this stream
of locations and try and make sense it
try and identify those locations that
are probably significant to the user
so this isn't really a good fit for a
journaling up
but if we were instead writing in
navigation app
this would make a lot of sense you need
the most up to date information
available
in order to tell the user went to make
their next move
before we totally throw out standard
location service for
a journaling ups their couple
improvement we might consider
a while ago we introduced the automatic
pas feature
this allows qualification to save power
by
parking location updates once that's
determined that the device probably
isn't in motion anymore
this is really exciting because it means
well we get to save power
device gets to keep journaling longer
unfortunately
once the user starts moving again your
Apple have to resume those location
updates
and so we won't actually help
or this one actually save standard
location service in terms of writing
during
caps if we were writing that navigation
app however
this would be a huge win once the user
stopped at a gas station
automatic pas will save their phones
battery
another option we might consider is the
first location updates
this one is really interesting as well
it allows call location to save power by
weight
waking up your app less up wake up
scoffed power
and so fewer app launches means more
power saved
unfortunately generating locations is
still quite expensive
and so even though we're saving power by
not watching your ap every time there's
new data
were still generating all those
locations and
not especially great sup
for location updates aren't exactly what
we want
however if we were writing a fitness app
they would be great if you're writing a1
Tracker app
you don't necessarily need the latest
location the moment it's available
you might be OK to receive it every mile
or every 15 minutes or so
art what else do we have for us well
there's the standard are the significant
location change API
this one is a lot more power efficient
than continuous location updates
but there's a cost to this instead love
getting
all of the data you get very course
tracks where the user went
specifically you only get location
updates every few hundred meters
device moves this is going to make it
incredibly difficult for us to identify
places that the user stopped at
sense when the user stopped we stop
getting updates here up
if we're writing a different app for
example one that showed the user
the path they took home maybe identifies
them freeways they drove on
then significant location changes would
make a lot of sense
but we're working on it turning up today
so we're gonna have to keep looking
our last option is region monitoring
region monitoring
is really cool because it's highly
power-efficient
region monitoring can continue while the
phone is asleep
and Europe only receives information
that is directly relevant to it
unfortunately you have to specify which
locations are interesting here
and that won't exactly work for our use
case because
we want to know about all the
interesting locations these are my go to
and there are far too many interesting
places to monitor for them all
so that's all that core location has
today to give up
I have to give up on my dream ap not yet
there's another one
we're introducing today visit monitoring
what makes visit monitoring different
from the other core location API's
is that it monitors for destinations
so instead of giving you information
about a how the user got from a to be
it gives you information about a and B
it will launcher app when it detects
that the user has departed from a
location or ride a new one
and so naturally this will require
always authorization
visit monitoring is incredibly powerful
chant
we employ all sorts of neat tricks
behind the scenes to ensure this
for example while the device is asleep
periodically performs wifi scan
if visit monitoring is active were able
to harvest all those scans that would
otherwise have not generated locations
and use them to enhance our visit
detection
visit monitoring is also opportunistic
so
if you're up is using his monitoring and
use our polls out maps and start
navigating
all the locations that maps request are
fed into the visit detection algorithm
and so you're ap benefits from other app
seems
location finally
it utilizes information from across the
entire system
for example suppose the user arrives
home and plugs in their phone to start
charging
it's much more likely that the user
would consider this location where they
started charging
to be an important part of their day and
so will use that as a hint
that the user has just arrived somewhere
when we see
hence will trigger a rival events much
more readily
finally I'd like to point out that visit
laundering is not tied to
landmarks I mean when you receive
information about a location
it's not necessarily an intrinsically
interesting location
it's just a location which is
interesting because the user has spent
time there
or we've seen some hints which indicate
the user might
think it's interesting so
let's look at what a visit actually is
suppose your user has a turn on his
monitoring through your
and they decide they want to go get a
cup of coffee so they start walking from
their home
to the coffee shop at some point core
location will get its first location
on the user at the coffee shop I don't
know about you but I can't see the
future
and so court location is going to have
to wait a little while before can say
for sure whether the user is passing by
the coffee shop
or whether they're they're to stay for
some time after we get a little bit more
data
it becomes clear that yes the user
intends to say at the coffee shop for a
while
maybe it's time to notify synapse at
this point
Core Location launcher app and provided
some information about the arrival
most importantly however it will do its
best estimate the true arrival time of
the user
at the location departures work
similarly
after some amount of time we'll get our
last location
a the user at the coffee shop but core
location will
wait until it gets a little bit more
data and totes sure that the user has
left
at that point we want wake you up again
and will provide a departure
notification
doing our best estimate the true time
when the user left the location
sup let's take a look at the API we've
added two new methods to the location
manager
specifically start monitoring visits and
stop monitoring visits when we have
information to deliver to your app
will do it through the new delegate
method location manager did visit
some of you may have noticed there's a
new class and that method signature
specifically field visit let's take a
look at that
sealed is it is a fairly simple class
it's got four properties
the first two our arrival date and
departure date
these described when the user arrived
and departed respectively
the cornet which represents the place
the user was visiting
and horizontal accuracy which is an
estimate
the air on the location on the court in
it
a few things you might want to know
about this monitoring
the values the pores on 20 accuracy and
corn it may differ between arrival event
and a departure and this shouldn't be
too surprising
these are estimates based on the data we
have seen and as we get more data
will be able to produce better estimates
you should also note that horizontal
accuracy should be
no worse then the horizontal accuracy on
a wifi base position
so if you find wifi dispositions are
suitable for
your app this monitoring will probably
produce things people value
naturally since this is a background
monitoring service well launcher app
even if it's been quiet as Stephen
mentioned
in addition if the phone is rebooted or
your app crashes
will still launch it and provide it with
this information
you should also know that there are
cases in which visit monitoring my
detect
multiple visit events at the same time
and deliver them to you up
in a single large so when you receive is
it
you should be prepared to handle
multiple
you may have noticed that field is it
doesn't had a is arrival or
his departure property so let's take a
look at how you can determine whether
visit represents an arrival meant
or departure vent the secrets to look
at the arrival date and departure date
properties
on arrival notification the arrival date
will
unsurprisingly be our best estimate when
the user a ride
the departure date however will be an
estate distant future
our departure notification the departure
date will be our best estimate
the arrival date I I'd like to point out
could be distant past
this happens if your app wasn't
authorized for the arrival moment
so how do we check if 8 cyl visit
represents an arrival or departure
you simply compare the departure date
too distant future
now let's get back to that app there
should be a
four steps implementing it first
we need to adopt a new authorization
model that Stephen described
after that we need to create our
location manager
writer Spartans taught math its and
finally
handle the visits that are delivered by
core location
adopting the new authorization isn't too
difficult the hardest part
is coming up with a great way to
describe your users how you intend to
use their location
for this example journaling up we might
say this at major locations
automatically detect the places you
visit during your day
after that we create our location
manager
I went ahead and did that in the
application delegate
because it provides a great main thread
context for us allocated in
the Spartans methods are fairly simple
the only catch is you have to remember
to request
always authorization and the stop
is even easier you just call stop
monitoring visits
finally the delegate this is where
you take over
please keep in mind that background
execution time is limited and as I
mentioned you may receive multiple
visits
so you shouldn't kick off some
long-running computationally expensive
processing task here for a simple
journaling up it might be best to just
record this visit
in a database and then save it for later
when the user
actually launch is your up
if you're writing a check a nap now
might be a good time
to take a look at the location see if
it's accurate enough for you to actually
determine
if the user's at a specific restaurant
for example
and then maybe fire offer you our local
notification saying
would you like to check in
before I give the stage back to Stephen
and like to give you some advice from
the court location pain about this
monitoring
visit monitoring is not a replacement
for region monitoring
if you're currently using region
monitoring to receive useful information
about the user riding after departing
from specific locations
you should continue to do so region
monitoring is more power-efficient
and will give you more timely
information about those events
in addition visit monitoring is not a
replacement for significant location
changes
they provide you very different
information significant location changes
is about
the path the user took whereas visit
monitoring is about
the destination
so what do you do when you encounter new
technology you should try it out
and evaluate it for your use case see if
his
monitoring cover something that you the
rap needs
then on Thursday we're hosting
allowed you should come to our lab
session bring any questions you
might have any problems you might have
encountered and we'll do our best to
help you get your app
up and running finally
please respect our users privacy this is
an incredible technology that will give
you up
a new level location awareness but
you should try to respect our users
privacy
just because you can obtain this data
doesn't mean you necessarily should
if you have any questions there's going
to be a session about
security and privacy later this week I
highly recommend you attended
with that I'd like to invite Stephen
back up onto the stage to tell you about
what's next
thank you Brad so what else is new
incall location and I i say
although is that they're bullet point we
talked about indoor positioning
unfortunately we don't have enough time
to cover that in this session
in summary we talked about location
authorization and changes
and recall that there are just three
steps and you need to follow to adopt
the changes and I i say
first you want to think about how your
app uses location
second you wanna explain it to your
users and third
you wanna make the call to request
authorization and you try this out today
because come Thursday you can come back
to us if any questions or issues that
you encounter
in our lab session we also talked about
this in monitoring
take the opportunity to assess your
app's needs for location
and see if this visit monitoring is cool
technology is something that your app
can take advantage of
but again remember as prime mention to
respect your users privacy
and also on this one give it a try see
what you can do
and then come back to us on Thursday
what sample code or any issues or
questions that you have
regarding this new API for more
information
check out our great documentation online
we have the core location framework
reference
which is updated with everything that we
talked about today
we also have a location and maps program
guide which is always being updated of
new and useful information
and as always visit the Apple Developer
forms
for related sessions we have a number
that we highly recommend
the first on the modern like it API
unfortunately is at the same time is
this session said thank you for joining
us
but for more information about web views
go check out the videos online
afterwards also as we mentioned directly
following the session
taking court location indoors for more
on what's new incall location
also tomorrow I highly recommend part 2
writing energy efficient code
which will cover some good practices
when using location
in addition to other technology in your
app's
also tomorrow what's new in IRS
notifications
for more on the region based UI local
and more and on Thursday
visit the user privacy and I always and
always 10
for more details on location
authorization and privacy
and other privacy related topics on both
I O S
and always 10