welcome to this afternoon the this
year's addition
and what's new information network
ng permission networking is a course for
layer up networking is available to
application developers
on Mac OS 10 and I O S I it's our goal
to provide you guys
where the protocol and networking
support that you need to make great
applications on a platform of course we
use the VPN herself
here's a standard picture
what framework for like honor system I'm
your application for fun top and now in
danger also having extension
are better sitting on top while these
frameworks and extensions are
particularly interesting
for background networking be Karen when
your extension terminate you might still
need to have worked on
news background networking to ensure
fashion to get that worked on
looking up different levels but actually
make
up foundation networking let me start
with you know that the corner where
I'm BFT networking where this is from my
with my wallet fokker
it binded address in it kinda like
building a car from a cat
and back to my question started
we took be foundation layer
things from next app I and we said well
we need from interfering PI in
CoreFoundation came out and see if
networking at
but as time has gone on we find more
more developers want a higher level
approach
felt foundation and foundation
networking provide
Anna URL session
replacing initial connection and if
streams in an ethnic services
and a Coco style
ATI for developers to use on Mac West
Ham
and I'll believe
a pure serve different purposes arm and
stream is the PRI back you think bite
into the system in various places would
receive by out
when you maybe don't have an idea how
many bytes rar you have a final on day
asking you know there's a certain signs
so you could if I Olympic animus input
stream from a file
or you could really feel even if input
stream from the PRI
don't know how big it is for your
schedule this treatment and you start
reading bite out of it
and ethnic services in the PI
that allows you to do peer to peer
servers
and client are on your machine on your
device
talking to other devices so it's it's a
great way of publishing work what you
want other app still
every hero fashion provide
observe a message beef delivery you're
talking about
putting a request on the network
everything response and and Erica
on in the stock wanna talk about birth
API seventh stream and if it's a reason
for natural session
when reviewing mister a fashion which is
what we introduced last year
so there will be a bit a review here we
have a new protocol support
and if you saw a be Craig
talk yesterday parents are on one fly
there is no mention of a new protocol it
will talk about
and lastly were gonna spend some time
talking out the best way to use
amateur of russian background networking
but get the new API family first
and officers who have anything only
thing I arm
but it's not really knew me even have a
level last year and I are 7
this year include you to pierce the veil
on Mac OS
can your family on hardware that
supports it which is
reef in 2012 or later Mac hardware that
really only you can change available by
it is now available for use NF
stream get through new API now
extreme in had toll-free bridged with
yep stream which means that there's a
lower level API that this works with
but at some point we lost the ability of
just creating
extreme to a host on the Internet
threading back
and we can get streams to to host with
name
bring a portent the host community doubt
it I P
IP be fair or a regular internet host
name
the result is an InputStream InputStream
but you then
open schedule and read and write from
as for Strings get open work you have
fun to another layer
so for instance if you had an audio
streaming app that wanted to read by
of a network resource that was providing
you with are your data
you 33 P IIT get and and if input stream
from that
and path but anything but stream of to
be on a player well
if you had bite you were generating you
want to defend internet
audio player or if you want to filter
the news bites you might need to
implement your
own in a stream unified some pressing a
stream
where the preferred way we want you to
do a in
preening what we call a bound hair back
return input and output stream in a
buffer
so you're right by into the open stream:
and the
audio unit or whatever it is will
consume a bite at the input string
corrective a couple new API's in and if
not arisen
and stream not talk about
amateur fashion and a lot of fun for you
from last year
and assure a session for the big machine
backhand a lot of moving parts
ominous picture can look for a couple I
am
it an object but you create with a
configuration
and references storage object storage
object are needed
to supply information about how to
perform a world
well with Bo the capital is your
delegate but you bind
in to the 50m and the purpose of this
ballot and that's one long
is to take data in request and to
produce responsive
and data object out so it's like
carrying passengers
and duty-free shop out the other side
were you get everything here
getting right very confident an issue of
session buffet Russian object itself
the API upon initial session the main
factory class is common emitter of
fashion
arm and editor of freshman class has
created with an initial session
configuration object the configuration
object
in Fig dictionary of properties that
the keeping flight the how many
connections we can make to a server
what kinda after filming use what
storage object you can use
the session create task object to be
used to represent
the certain transient speed
ivory sorry for the be loaded a task
object is created from a request or your
L
and its initial three is suspended
resume
I it doesn't work within the fashion
conferring with your delegate as needed
and then he ran the catholic and
finished
are and you're done you got your data
okay the delegated fell at it from a new
supply
the delegate in arm
African 100 bunch of different protocol
their purple session preparing for the
various
have someplace there are
storage object back exist in the system
by fall
arm parents any keychain be credential
store
various a cookies store a cookie jar
cookies are
for the general form a authentication
arm be through the thing purposely
identify you to a website
in 1122 communicate with you in
waiting for your way
protocol are objects back you can
register
women fashion back overrun the default
behavior or provide additional behavior
so your outlook right
HTTP colon your protocol could be am
00 F home run and you deal with move
protocol
everyone arm including rewriting them to
become
HTTP protocol
i think is the Euro cache object which
is what we're able to console
in order to avoid going out on the
network at all
in emotional fashion your configuration
object you can specify your own
subclasses for following through an
object
the configuration object itself arm as I
mentioned
it basically in the dictionary although
it be its comparative a bunch of at
property attributes
when you create one when you get a
configuration object you modify it
however you want
you to create a fashion with fact
configuration once you've created a
fashion with a configuration
you can't modify it again user from the
attributes
you can change within a configuration
he left levels whether you want to
support the latest your life I'm
are restricted to bad working while the
previous one
whether or not mile you are requesting
over the network
yeah film our arm network service type
in
well I'm doing video data and when a
higher priority effect available
I'm I won't try in with all over
configuration options because there are
quite a few more on the header file
so to get a configuration object you can
after the default session configuration
from the factory method that returns an
object
back captures the global the framework
if you look at the foundation for
workers in classes like ms. Tina
have a a class map it and if the Red
Deer with content for the URL
and if you're a pair for each CPU around
into that it will use
all the global fall Family Foundation
framework in order to go out on the
network
and get back data never call many PRI be
that block
and it will and hanging whatever
Frederick sitting around
I but the point is that bad
configuration
is with the default session
configuration represent
if you get a professional preparation
and modify it you're only modifying back
configuration you're not modifying
but global configuration there's a
factory method for an ephemeral
session immigration this is set up for
that
none other storage object actually
persistent data to death
arm new users to implement programs in
print
the third factory method is used to
create a background fashion
I'll you specify and identifying which
is a string
that when your app is relaunched new
the fame starring are in order to get
refreshing it with accession in the
background manual for receiving a ban
threat session there's a factory method
for infection because you shared passion
we shared fashion you
swell going back a in a speech TV a
n/a data be there with content URL
example that would be using the shared
session to do with work
it representing the global environment I
it's a very heavy thing to use a when
you just want to get a resource of the
network
once you have a configuration object but
after you might want to create
profession
all your own that you have only your own
resources and
and maybe on your own storage questions
you don't have to pay W because if we're
going to talk about a few minutes
their them you think or if convenient 13
better-known
require you to implement a delegate with
your with your
an extra session but if you do
specified delegate which you need to do
for background transfers
the you can use session with
configuration
passing a delegate I am a BBQ don't
think you can be a concurrent cue
for past object themself session creepy
half object need to be square after
objecting to pick up a pattern
I kantle spending with him when it have
to object is created
it is suspended you have to infinite to
resume message in order for it to start
working
there to them questions which are really
only available
for the purposes both providing hunter
them into glue
currently very a delegate
ford direct path but there's no
delegates perfect for
download for a bloodbath but if there
were in the future
we would have the ability to
differentiate between the pipes
there's also a download half and all the
fat and Papa
the normal past object if cancelled by
producing resume data
when a downward if cancel if you use
this API
were able to cash in a favor to download
and at a later time
you can create a downward path using
everything better
and avoid having to download all the
banks can if the server support
NF conditions warrant and lot of other
authors reasons why that might not work
by if you wanted to have a chance of
working with help you get there is
indeed a
could create a past object profession
added half URL you have given a are
referring URL
HDPE our move whatever in
gonna be supported by the protocol data
with require
which Nathan an issue or request which
is through the alder
way of specifying arm
finding a URL with a method or
however your protocol is going to
interpret that request
up might have are similar except we
don't
a loan agreement apart after you're out
have to create an upward path
from request read specified the method
like poster put
you the option a performing a quote from
a file or from a data
interviewed great are but we also give
you the option
premium about half with me green isn't
with a friend request
that means we're going to after a
delegate for you stream
when we're ready right the by view or
upload to the network the reason we have
to do that
is because sometimes we will open
connection to server start reading by
from the Federal come back an of
challenge I from
and we'll have to talk with you delegate
but at that point bernie from
by along and if we're doing a upward
from a stream
we're gonna have to through extreme away
and ask you doing it for a new one
if we did the upload from a file or from
a data object
we know how to restart bathroom without
him and asking for it
if you're ending if you're trying to do
arm
upload from background transfers you
have to do it from a file
because we want to capture a file so we
can up on in the background
download have to summer you can download
from your own I wanna copy
I wanna you're all victims from you know
my big file back to GV
I'll or from an initial request I
porn created from from resumed in a pop
and they give you back
had downward path which you can read
them
for the life cycle over data cache for
them to spend their
referencing the request that we're going
to be aware
you tell it okay resume the speakers to
running
and I'm a delegate stricken car did
receive response occurs
inherited respond and response is also
available as the property on the cast
object
as day to come a.m. will call you did
receive Derek delegate method
mirror more time
effect half a is in a fashion that would
enable
better than even hashing we're gonna
call you will catch a spot for
gives you the opportunity to face for a
particular resource
I don't wanna casual are or you want to
modify the crash response
but we recall that at this point before
we call did complete with error
and if they don't ask us to finish one
thing about being complete with error
and a final
thing biggest fan to your delegate on
behalf of the path
the error is going to be near all if the
server game
a valid response a valid response would
be
200 OK but a valid response is also 404
from I found because body that came back
might be interesting
you might want to display that party me
air perimeter here than in strictly for
transmission errors
Mike the host cannot be resolved or a
I'm not occur
or you can follow the path while I was
in flight
for when you look at me here here it's
going to campaign
well the reason why the transfer failed
and you should assume it to respond
and the data got back invalid
download tariff works for a summer when
you create download have
I am this issue reference from file
you're gonna get
and it starts to its workers to use a
river yet you something new method
so close to running and it will
periodically call be a great day don't
tell you your friend making progress
on this download it going note that this
in also what's gonna happen for a
background download if if passed we
created for a background downloader app
is running
you can receive did write data call back
finally we've written all by file to
the filesystem women broken did finish
downloading
URL message and we're gonna give you a
file URL
in your container you have to move into
a more permanent location
move the file to a more permanent
location in your container
because when you return from a family
get we're going to leave the file
then we will call did complete with air
with nil beacons we successfully got the
final only to death
so creating a natural fashion tariff can
be done
just no protector are requesting in cash
cow
but they're from convenient 13th in
really handy especially when you have a
session that doesn't use a delegate or I
should say
particularly you can only use these with
affection they don't have a delegate
are so you think didn't have to TRL
completion and you give it a completion
handler
be tariffs tarjeta comes back have to be
resumed
by it doesn't bother calling and have a
delegate message in
back might be in the fashion or might
not are
and when the work is done in russia
completion handler arm
this is true for you know within upload
be a file
or Dana arm or download
to death mackey for completion handler
reference file and like the delegate for
did finish moving to file
you have to move that file away so this
is what the mccracken in 15
am very simply just create a a URL but
you're gonna
request up a network in this case for
you to create a configuration object
using the ephemeral
session configuration prototype object I
don't wanna
store anything and and when I wouldn't
know about this resource
I'm gonna cry a private session and then
I'm gonna create a cat
with a private session and with that
you're out right over fashion
I didn't have to be around using rail
here's why completion handler
the signature for the completion hammers
data response and air
there will be no lift a response or
valid
I resume a tariff and then I go back to
running around one
if you were just exit right here nothing
would happen beacons
we're not doing anything we have to run
the run when poor dispatch main
an order for with completion it called
you get called in re will be or could be
never came back
delegate that you profession with ban
is comprised of a number of different
protocol
the fashion level delegate for many
information
about the fashion wanna fresheners
created
here in my become invalid given seven
invalidate message in which case
profession in validation delegate method
will be called
but is more interesting delegate message
send confession delegate which used for
connection level of education if you
connected to a website
that had FL encryption
we're gonna call your session level
authentication
challenge Ambler to asked whether or not
you wanna continue connecting to a site
we're going from multiple requests on
the fame socket we're not going to
making soccer and of challenging for
each request I think I'm gonna do it one
I'm on the basis for beach
path up on his request there's a manager
of a Russian pastel again
me that the fingers are building on top
of one another
the most important thing that this time
again response to his did finish
a loading with their and again if the
air is nil that mean
rapid response was valid and you should
deal with the data if the air is not
known in something happen
that captor through me or transfer your
request
there's of the request authentication
handling here if the server serve
for a particular request I don't know
how to deal with you and even potential
for this request
have you have any other questions this
request band bat
challenge request will come through biff
half delegate
David Elliott ban extend for half
delegate it got a couple method bat are
interesting
first did receive a response frazier
downloading file of a network
down a bit of a network and you look at
the content I when you get a response
back
the content type thing this is a diff
image well you probably want to read the
disk image on a memory
so the completion routine for this
delegate method
allows you to specify the this data
cache should become a downward path
and that's exactly what happened
recruited downward path to replace your
data cache
and for reading the file to their and
when the file is completely written
we treat miffed after the F word Erica
and we
notify you in the file's location
by back are read of a network then are
sent
to you and gear if you get a call at
there are more did receive data call
back
one thing you know you don't have to
copy them statements you can keep track
of them you can reference
fam but you know me to copy them by
future boosting its me 100
scenes PDF contiguous tnf-a you should
use the chemist in a discontinuous
nearer application API incentive
requesting the
by pointer to the starting data and that
from a true democracy parents and
producing dated today
we had a friend were trying to fix
things to govern beekeeping
discontinuous memory which is a big
performance when
family to download that look at
extend for passed down again it doesn't
receive the by receives notification on
the bike
and in the end it receives a a delegate
message that says
here in the file location: for
Dana we just transferred so one quick
thing we talk about
in the delegate cue that use create a
profession where
we created my own 7 and Mac with an
average
as a serial killer every time a bit and
have had something to do
it would calling here delegate may
prevent a return
and on to the next after had some work
to do the problem with this approach
in fact the F anyone in your delegate
stalled for some reason
by in happening here then we have to
wait for that dominated return
before the next half can come along
through america with Pam are your family
and I will pay
we're now going to treat your QS
concurrent if it is a concurrent you
know is why did you know specified
so all these past three or call into
your delegate that one
I and no matter what ordered a fair
national delegates me
finish at different times we're always
gonna be able to link you
work for the next task and that that's a
good thing
there is a little bit of new EP are
going to talk about national fashion
this be resolved revolves around storage
object
Mike at the end of each to be cocky
storage and you're a potential storage
and the initial cash as well as initial
particle
in each of these cases we found any with
insufficient
for the accessories for the storage
object received Jeff
the URL people who were fed questionings
object
wanted but actor path that was asking
the question
so there's a new category manager of
fashion half conditions
I if you look in the header around the
entire URL
my break arm even if you have category
show up
and providing synchronous get I and
presumably
even if that job at an implementation
detail
will take anything should be cookie
storage for example for two new method
to get
store cookies forecast here's an array
of cooking
am doing it be if they've passed cares
you look
the implementation will look in the past
look at her request
your ally back and do that work get
cookies for tariff
works the same way I would like the
cookies turn off caps
at Infineon synchronously responding
here the completion hammer once you've
got
those cookies invoke the completion
handler and
you don't have to block me the three rd
the beers are available
on a anything because the store national
credential animus real cash
so as I mentioned earlier arm
3 mickey no the river flow I with had
one little
little bit love interesting stuff in it
and I'd like their
stock you coming up and tell us about a
new protocol support
thank you Steve hello everyone I'm Scott
and 3 I'll be talking about new protocol
support
in foundation networking we've been
working hard to improve the performance
of our
HEB implementation for developers you
guys
and a popular request at last year's
WWDC
was to add support for the speedy
protocol her so today we're pleased to
announce that
the speed protocol is now supported by
an issuer all session
on our tenure Sammy and Iowa State so
not only does this mean that it's
available in Safari for your day to day
browsing
but it's also available for direct use
in your app's
and even if you don't use an issue are
also russian
directly in your applications keep in
mind
that species also leverage to other
Apple frameworks like you I web de which
you might use
in Europe's so for those who viewed the
don't know
with speedy is already it's a protocol
that is
designed to make the web faster and
essentially what it does is it changes
the on wire format HTTP 1.1
but the semantics HTTP 1.1 stay the same
so you know about request types like get
post
put those are the same response codes
like 200 OK
that's still the same caches cookies
credentials those are also all the same
speedy is also serving as the base for
the HTTP 2.0 draft specification
and I'm actually come back to that point
a little bit later on
but it's interesting to see where
technology any sort of
development specifications is heading as
a result of the speedy work
now the way speedy works very serve high
level is that it allows for the exchange
multiple HTTP messages both requests and
responses
simultaneously and potentially out order
all over single TCP connection
so if you'd like to use P D in your
applications here's what you need to
know
as I mentioned it's avail on both oath
and your family and I was a
and we support three versions the speedy
protocol to
3 and 3.1
and what we decided to do is make it
supported transparently by an issue of
session
and so this goes along the lines of loss
to be happy we have
which is that we will always pick the
best best protocol we should use
when communicating with your server so
currently that means we're gonna decide
if it's going to be
HTTP 1.1 or speedy and the versions be
that we're going to use
but this could also hold true in the
future for some other protocol
so what this means for you is that no
source changes are needed
it will just work and so we look at its
source code example here
what you do first courses create your
URL for whatever resource you be
interested in
an obsession from your server and then
you'd construct a session to ask
in this case it were using data task in
this case also with the shirt session
and then having a completion handler
with the day you receive the response
and
transmission error there was one
and of course you don't have to resume
the task to start
what you'll notice about this code
sample is there's nothing different here
because be is going to be used
there isn't some code that I added
changed or otherwise removed
to support speeding in fact this example
should look very similar wants to show
you not more than a couple minutes ago
not intentional so I dive into some
speed benefits you can understand how to
actually impact your app's
so the way to be worked as a house a
single long-lived TCP connection
between the client and the server and
for this actually helps mitigate latency
penalties oftentimes that are seen when
you
ask for additional resources because
traditionally we may have had to open an
additional socket and TCP connection to
get the data
back but now we have the one correction
it's open for a longer period of time
which helps to get rid of that latency
it also means that since we're only
opening one connection to your server
that any given op instance now should be
using fewer resources on your server
which is
a big win for you
speedy supports the concept and
multiplexing which is where
a request in response can be interleaved
potentially multiple requests responsive
community leaves over a single
connection
and so this gets rid of what's known as
a headline blocking
and this is where while you're in the
process of receiving the response for
one object
that you can't receive responses for
other objects on the same connection
so for example you might be in the
process of downloading a large image
and they're actually then gets in the
way of your ability to download say a
smaller and more important
a JavaScript file or CSS file
finally he supports the notion of
priorities until now the order in which
you
issue requests no longer have to dictate
the order in which responses are
actually received by your application
so wanna sort of show you a diagram of
how this works
keep in mind that this is going to be
forgiven ideal network where there's no
latency
and perfect in with utilization and
we're gonna first start by looking at
how how one blocking is present in HD
v1.1
without pipelining so
imagine you issue request three requests
for three resource
an image a style sheet and sectional
data
to the first thing all happened course
is will send out the GET request
for the image and then you wait a while
as all the bites in the 200 OK response
come back
that image back to your apt meanwhile
noticed nothing has happened for the
style sheet or the actual data
then we can set up the request with
Style Sheets
receive its response and then do the
same for the actual data
you can see here that during the time
when you are receiving the response
bytes for the image
we can't make any forward progress
with the style she or the XML data
now pipelining make the situation a
little bit better but it doesn't get rid
of headline blocking still
let's see what that looks like
now request can get sent out one after
another
but responses are still blocked by the
previous response
and had a blind walking still an issue
you know if you are using pipe laying
the multiplexing changes that with
speedy
so let's look at the same three
resources now
but this time with multiplexing
so we'll start by sending request for
the image that should look no different
than before
and like before with pipelining we can
actually send the request for the style
sheet
immediately after the request for the
image and of course we can start making
progress by receiving bytes
for the image but here's where things
get different
because the style sheet is higher
priority then D
image the certainly will start sending
back respond plates
for the style sheet instead a response
bytes for the image
and then once the request for the actual
data has gone out because it is the
highest priority object
we receive its response bites in
looooove the image bytes for the 1000
bytes
you'll also notice in this diagram that
them amount of data we're receiving for
the actual data
is a larger chunk than that of the style
sheet or the image
that's intentional oftentimes a speedy
implementation the
responses are weighted by priority and
so
we let this progra sort of progress to
continue what we end up seeing is that
we can we see the entire
style she directional data before the
image even though those resources were
asked for
after we asked for the image
so you might be wondering why should I
dot p
and the plain and simple reason is that
it can give a better user experience and
that's what we're all after
I would pink and so there sir two
reasons as is the case the first is that
as I mentioned it reduces latency for
having a single long live connection
open
between the client and server as to what
this means is that over the lifetime if
you're up
as more and more requests were issued we
don't have to continually open new
connections which helps to get rid of
that latency
it means that your up can have much more
interactive behavior
even when using a cellular connection
in our own performance measurements we
found the speedy could be up to 25
percent faster than
HTTP 1.1 and I'll come back to this a
little bit later on
there's also some more subtle points I
want to to raise about performance and
speedy and and
its benefits because it's only opening a
single TCP connection it also only have
to do a single SSL handshake
and that means that your Apple have less
CPU use
and overtime better battery life on the
device
it also means that when you're out
becomes the next big app on the App
Store
and a big hit that you may not have to
roll out as much server-side
infrastructure to support
the increased number appliance because
each client has fewer
connections going back your server right
it's one incentive many
so I already told you that
if you'd like to make use a speedy you
don't need any client side country
coach Ames but there are a few other
points with respect to speed option I do
wanna talk about
the first we are planning to add API for
setting priorities on session tasks
you'll see that in the future seed it's
not currently available
we also welcome any other feedback from
you during either the networking lab
sessions or through
a bug report if you believe there's
other API be useful
that that you don't currently see
while you don't need to have any client
side code changes to support speedy keep
in mind
speed does require server side support
and this all happens when the client is
negotiating with the server using
the TRS handshake the reason this is
important is that
all the URL's for requests that you
issue from your application
need to have HTTPS and not HTTP
others point out that there's a fair
amount of existing web server software
and content delivery networks that
already supports PD
and so you may already have the support
and have to do nothing at all to turn it
on
on your server
finally many have you might have been an
issue for all
protocol subclass or maybe perhaps
multiple in your application
I do want to note that our speedy
implementation is not going to interfere
with your protocol subclasses
regardless of whether or not they're
adding support for speedy or some other
protocol
entirely
so I mention that we found that speedy
could be up to 25 percent faster than
HD HTTP 1.1 and I wanna go into a little
more detail about
sort of performance and and expectations
so now actually parallel TCP connections
in some cases can be fastened to be
single connection
and what we found is that whether or not
speed is going to be faster is dependent
on both network conditions and your
workload
and in general our guidance is that if
you are going to issue many requests
particularly request for small size
objects you're gonna see a performance
GameSpy
but if you're reading app it's
downloading handful files perhaps
though also downloading large files such
as movie
speedy is not going to be advantageous
for you
and so keep in mind that you control
whether or not
he's going to be used by based on
whether or not it's turned on your
server
I also wanna know that the speech
specification indicates
that HTTP headers can be compressed to
boost performance
but it turns out this is actually
susceptible to the crime on our ability
which you can read about online
and so in our implementation as is in
many
comments be implementations we'd
actually disabled is for user privacy
you're not going to see a performance
boost from compress hatter's
finally I want to point out speedy is
not an IETF recognized standard
that we see it is protocol is paving the
way for HTTP 2.0 now
in particular gives you developers the
opportunity to get a jump start
on using a protocol that relies on a
singalong with connection with
multiplexing which is the same direction
that HTTP 2.0 is heading
so I want to wrap up and talk about some
best practices for working speedy
keep in mind these are not necessarily
hard-and-fast rules we always have to
follow but these are good suggestions
just two
giving back your mind as you work with
PD to the first is
its best if you can issue your request
as soon as you want the resources so in
other words what I mean is
you might have previously held back and
actually manually schedule request to
try to avoid have one blocking
but because her one blocking is no
longer concerned
we ask that you think you all your crust
requests right away and what
multiplexing do what it meant to do
also you might spread your content
across multiple host names
called hostname charting so some
resources might have been like on CSS to
apple.com someone I've been on images to
apple.com and so on
and for HDB 1.1 this made sense would
cause us to open multiple TCP
connections which would boost
performance
but since PD relies on a single long
live connection
which gives us optimal collection
reviews its actually best if you I'm
chard and consolidate all your content
to a single host name
and single port so we can have that one
long live connection give you the best
experience possible so I'd like to turn
things over to dan
he's gonna be talking about back on
networking and extensions
good afternoon everyone I'm down and as
Scott said
I'm gonna be talking up background
networking sold steve mentioned before
that you can enable background
networking in your applications using
industrial session if you use the
background session configuration with
identifiers factory method
so I want to give you a brief overview
of what I'm to be talking about today
first I'm gonna go over why you'd want
to use background sessions and
background networking in your
applications
tying in with this I'll talk about using
back on sessions an app extensions which
is a new feature in Iowa State
anti-western your sanity often talk
about discretionary networking was it
which is a feature
background networking that allows us to
schedule tasks when it's and appropriate
given current power conditions
and finally I'll talk about using back
on sessions properly in your
applications going over a couple use
cases and talking about
some common pitfalls and best practices
so why do you want to use background
sessions in your applications
well the main benefit particularly on
iowa's is for multitasking
in a background session file-based
upload and download can continue out a
process
even while your app isn't running this
means that your out can crash
even you can be terminated or NIOS it
can be suspended
and those file based upon and downloads
will still continue
and will actually wake up your app on
iowa's in the background to handle
things like authentication challenges
and the completion of all the tasks in
your sessions
another benefit is that in a background
session we monitor
the network in power environment for you
so this means that we cover things like
network reachability in connectivity for
you so you don't have to use the
reachability API's at all
we won't attempt to establish a
connection to we know that the servers
reachable
and similarly if the user is performing
a download and
steps on up wifi normally that house
with an fail with a transmission error
but in a back room session will actually
recover from that automatically in retry
it
and resume where we left off if the
download is resumable
and you won't hear about the air
for discretionary tasks we also perform
some battery monitoring
so that we don't perform a task if the
usually low on battery not charging
and will also do bandwidth monitoring
and what this means is that
if the user's 10 let's say I really
flaky WiFi network and
isn't making really be sufficient
throughput then we'll stop and just
retry automatically when network
conditions are better
so I'd like to talk about using back
from sessions in ap extensions which
they said our new feature I've
bioassay anti-western your sanity now
extensions are very short-lived
processes
generally they're only gonna be running
while they're actually active on screen
that can be a very short period of time
usually
a so in process networking really isn't
sufficient in a nap extension
if you need to do any moderate to large
size at uploader download
but if you use a background session then
that task to actually perform are back
on demand
so your app extension can exit or be
suspended
and i OS when that task completes or
authentication is required
well actually launch the app that your
extension shipped with in order to
handle those events
so essentially your app extensions your
caps can share
I background sessions and this leads us
to a couple
constraints when using background
sessions an app extensions
the first is that normally use a
background session in an app extension
you need to use a share data container
now the reason for this is that by
default
an app and any extensions that ships
with are indifferent data containers and
won't have access to the same said two
files
but Xcode you can create an application
group
and you using the capabilities tab and
if you create an application group you
can tell us the identifiers love that
outgroup that group container and will
download anti container
and I'll show you how to do that
momentarily
another caveat is that only one process
can be connected to the background
session
at a time this means if that if your app
is running in the background
and then another app launches and blah
brings up your extension
it won't be able to use that same
background session
now a background session is essentially
defined by the identifiers that you use
when you create your background session
configuration object
so we recommend here is that you use a
different background session identifiers
for your app and for each extension that
you ship with the only time that you
should take advantage of the fact that
your ap and your extensions can share
back concessions
is when we launch your apt to handle
events for that session
now I mention that you need to use a
share data container when
are using background sessions ap
extensions and you can
specify that using the share container
identify our property on an issue of
such in configuration
so what you do is you just create a
configuration object using the
background session configuration with
identify our factory method that's the
show you before
and you set per share container identify
our property to the identify RUV your
shared group container
than you can create an issue of session
from that configuration object and
create tasks in that session
now would like to switch gears and talk
about discretionary networking which is
something that
some background tasks can use I
in order to a perform tasks at power
optimal times
and what this means is that we will take
into account things like whether or not
we're on a WiFi network or using
cellular data
and also take into account the current
battery state whether or not we're
charging
where and how much a what percentage the
battery is charged
we also take into account things like
how often your app is launched
if it's something that use our own shit
launches really frequently we'll
be more likely to treat a task more
urgently since the users more likely to
notice
when those resources are downloaded
on why improvement that we've made NIOS
eight for discretionary transfers
is that tasks are treated with more
urgency as time goes on
in Iowa 7 discussion it transfers were
limited to wifi only
and now while we may limit discriminate
track discretionary transfers to run
while while there's wifi and plugged in
at first
these constraints will relax as time
goes on so as we
approach the resource timeout have that
specified in your configuration object
will be more likely to relax these
conditions
and allow and transfers over battery in
cellular data
there a couple different ways that you
can use discretionary networking in a
background session
but one ways by explicitly opting in
using the discretionary property which
is just a boolean
on initial session configuration this
was made available on iowa 7
and is now available in OS 10 your
sanity
you might wanna do this for any task
aren't really user initiated
so let's say you have you know an app
that lets users watch
episodes of a TV series and they're
watching an episode
that they've downloaded already and
maybe you want a prefetch the next one
so it's ready for them
but when they're finished watching the
current episode now that's not something
the user explicitly
requested so that something that you
might wanna tree is discretionary
similarly if you haven't happened the
user is modifying a document
I you might wanna upload that document
to your
app servers that it's accessible from
the user's other devices
and this might also be something that's
discretionary
on i OS there are also times when we
will treat tacit discretionary
automatically
and this happens when your app is
running in the background
in Iowa 7 we introduced a few new
multitasking API's most notably
background patch updates and handling
sound push notifications for your app
gets a limited amount of time
on the order of 30 to 60 seconds to run
in the background to make updates
and when you think this is really great
when used in conjunction with background
uploads and downloads
but because the user doesn't know that
your app is running at this time
any download the or upload that UN cue
will need to be discreet will be treated
discretionary automatically
be if this were can't be user initiated
because the user doesn't know that
you're running
now what improvement that we've made
here in Iowa State is that
any of these past that we automatically
treatise discretionary will be calm
non-discretionary if the user
launches the app and brings it to the
foreground
I've mentioned a couple times that on
iowa's will launch shops in the
background to handle events like
authentication
and the completion of all your tasks i
wanna talk a little bit about how you
handle those events
so when I was 7 we introduced a new
method on you application delegate
called application handle events for
backgrounds were all session completion
handler
when this is called you'll be provided
with the identifiers
up the session that needs your attention
at this point you should reconnect
that session by creating a background
configuration object with that
identifiers
and then an initial session from that
configuration object
at this point you're immediately begin
receiving the delegate messages
that you missed maybe authentication
challenge challenges worded complete
with a recall backs
and and after finished handling these
events you want to call the completion
handler
that this that that was provided here
you application delegate
this completion handler allows us to
take a snapshot of your you why
to show up in the app switcher split up
to date when the user double clicks the
home button
and also allows us to suspend your app
now when your watch to handle events for
background sessions
your again be live given a limited
amount of time to run in the background
around 30 to 60 seconds
if you don't call your completion
handler within this time your Apple be
terminated meaning it won't have
an up-to-date snapshot and it'll be
slower to launch the next time the user
wants to launch a wrap
so it's important you college completion
hella co-opted suspended has up to date
you I
on once you're finished receiving all
the pending events from your initial
session
will deliver the URL session did finish
events for background you're all session
message to your an issue of session
Dahlia and this is an indication of when
it's a good time to call
your completion handler pastor you
application delegate
I'd also like to talk about using data
tasks in background sessions
steve mentioned earlier that data tasks
instead of downloading to a file
or done desk will just deliver on
did receive data call backs in memory
now data tasks were unavailable in
background sessions
in Iowa 70 west and maverick's but
they're now available and I was 8
and Western you're somebody with like
this that one restriction
which is that we were only perform a day
to task in the background sessions
why your app is actually running if your
apt it suspended or is terminated
then there's no one to deliver that data
to so it makes no sense for us to
continue performing at
however you can convert it to a download
when you receive a response and Steve
alluded to this perlier when talking
about the did receive response call back
and that delegate message provide a
completion handler
and you can pass an issue of session
response become download
to that completion handler and then
we'll start streaming the bites to a
filing describing in memory
and once you do that this is becomes a
download that can be continued even if
after your app a suspended or exits
now I'd like to talk about a couple
common pitfalls that we've seen perhaps
in the past when using background
sessions
on one common pattern that we've seen
that we'd like develop urs to avoid is a
pattern where they create one task at a
time
so you might for instance be downloading
a large video from your server that
split up into many different smaller
segments
each a separate file if you download all
of these
and if you that's a create a download
task for the first task
for the first asset and then create a
second download half the next ass at
once the first one completes
this is a really bad pattern
particularly because if the user
suspends the app by going to the by
going to Home screen at any point
then you actually need to be relaunched
in the background in order for
went once their current download
finishes before you came to your next
one
and this means because it running in the
background it will automatically be
treated as discretionary
which means we won't guarantee that it
will start right away
in particular even if conditions are
great where r a hundred percent charged
and on
connected to a power source and we have
were connected to a great WiFi network
we still make no guarantees that will
start right away
and in particular the system will take
measures to prevent your out from being
watched too frequently
and you can't rely on launches for
background sessions for any sort of
regular
launch events and tying in with this
it's much better if instead of
downloading muchas blot a small assets
like this
if you can set these up on your server
into one large zipped asset that's much
more efficent
a fishing for a background download and
finally blocking
while waiting for transfers to complete
is just a really bad idea when doing any
kind of networking
but particularly bad in a back room
session where we recover from network
failures automatically and don't tell
you about them
and again for discretionary transfers
were not guaranteed to start right away
I'd also like to go over a couple best
practices for using background sessions
and also
initial session in general one common
mistake that we think
some people have made in the past is
that they've assume that when
running in the background to handle
things like a background patch update
for a solid push notification
that they've been required to use da
concessions now using background
uploader downloads with these forms have
multitasking
and works really well on this but in
particular for large downloads
when you're running for a background
patch update Arsalan push notification
as I said you'll have about 30 to 60
seconds to run in the background
now if you have any small networking
tasks
that could finish with this time it's
perfectly OK to do the minute in
processor to fault
an issue all session and so if you have
something like a Twitter client that's
gonna be downloading a few tweets for a
background patch update
that's totally doable in process on the
other hand
if you want to download you know the
next episode of a TV series that
something but
that fairly large in probably not gonna
finish within the 32nd
the 62nd you have to run and that should
be done a background session
and it's also important but you support
resumable downloads on your servers
as I mentioned in a back room session we
retry automatically after network
failures if the user goes off have wifi
for instance
so if you support resume all downloads
we don't have to redownload bites we've
already received
and but if you don't then we have to
start from the beginning
now supporting resumable downloads is
generally just as simple as supporting
range get requests on your servers and
most
servers should support this
configuration at the box
finally it's very important that you
handle launch events properly
and as I talked about before this means
when you get
and launch to handle a back run session
you should reconnect to that background
session
and handle any a and messages this is
particularly important with
authentication
because if you don't responded
authentication challenge then
that task will timeout and fail and
that's not what the user wants
finally be sure to call the completion
handler that's called that Pastor you
application delegate
as I said before this allows your you
like to be up to date on the app
switcher
and makes it so ya Perseus pended after
it's completed instead of being
terminated
I before wrap up I just like to give a
brief summary a
what we discussed today so first we
talked about new API's industry
management service
I we gave a review of an issue of
abusing an issue of session
and from what we talked about last
year's Derby BBC session
we talked about speedy and new protocol
support
and went over on some new features and
best use cases in
a background networking and
so in case you don't have to get the
chance to ask us any questions in person
this week while you're here
appalled and bold is our technologies
evangelist
and he's a great person to ask for any
questions that you might have that you
don't get a chance to ask us
while you're here on there we also have
plenty of documentation available at
developer tap about.com including
for an issue all session and the Apple
Developer forms another great place to
ask questions that you don't get to ask
why you're here
an I'd also like to point you in a
couple related sessions
that are going on this week in
particular you might be interested India
extensions sessions there are two a bum
and you can learn more about creating ap
extensions and we'll also talk a little
bit about using background sessions in
ap extensions and with that I'd like to
thank you all for coming and we look
forward to seeing the groom a synapse
you create with Iowa State
anti-western yosemite