afternoon everybody
hi so my name is Dan Curtis I today
my colleague Rick Dickson and I will be
talking about what's new and I was
notifications
Nyassi so I before getting told a great
new features a bioassay
with lay down some foundation about what
notifications are
and how you've been using them in Iowa
seven today so
when I mention notifications I'm
actually talking about two different
types and notifications really
we've got user notifications and we got
family notifications
so what sort of abuse or notifications
what are these
so using notifications are really just
things that the user can interact with
see or hear
on their device and they're coming
directly from your app
so for instance with the Messages icon
appear on the top left hand corner the
screen
what say that these are happy to receive
a message from one of their friends
when the app is currently not in the
foreground what we've got three
different options
up for using notifications that we could
use to let them know that there's new
information
first one that we could do is badge the
app icon
having that little red circle with the
number one in their informs the user
that they've got a one new message now
for times that the user happen
throughout that device in your pocket
and they might not be able to see the
screen
we could instead playing found all
informing the user that they've got a
new message and lastly
we have alerts which ticked down as a
banner from top of the screen
with a little preview message what that
message actually campaigns
so that these are not even have to a tap
on the Messages icon
to check out what's there so we have bad
as we have sounds
we have alerts and for alerts
they can actually appear in different
forms in different places as well
depending on how the user happen to set
other settings for your app in the
notifications under settings
are these alerts that are being those
banners that tick down and then go away
automatically
they could appear as model alerts the
stayed up there on the screen to these
are happens interact with them
and then we also have alerts that they
could be displayed in the Notification
Center drag down
as well as for the time that these are
happen have the device in your pocket
and the screen was of when they happen
receive an alert next time they turn it
on
waiting right there form in the lock
screen so
where do these notifications come from
well for use in notifications they can
come from
to different places I first thought they
could be coming directly from your app
that is your app uses you I local
notification API
to present a notification to the user
alternatively
are you can also have user notifications
that are triggered in response to remote
push payloads you can EP in a server the
about their on the Internet
in coordination with the Apple Push
services you send
a push payload that defines in this case
and AlertNet ok
sorry that result in Miller
up on the a double appear up on the
screen now
I got a little builder eager there we've
also got another typing notification
I mention we had user notifications and
family notifications
silent notifications they are just push
payloads that are sent from your EP in a
server but instead of
I presenting a user notification like an
alert for sound
or a bad on the screen I US when it
receives that push with said wake up
you're up in the background
that Europe can do some background up
background
image processing for information
processing this case
your app is fetching content from server
so that the next time user happens to
tap on your app icon
bring into the foreground that
information is there and ready
so nobody has to weigh for loading
spinner to complete know that other
stuff
that notifications in Iowa 7
got user types we've got silent types
user
I notifications can come from locally on
the app I
remote notifications they can only be
coming from
push payloads so let's talk about
the new features a bioassay
notifications
we're gonna be talking about for create
new topics today
offer some gonna be talking about using
notifications what's changed about them
in Iowa State specifically with
registration
then read is gonna come up and he's
gonna talk about a great new feature
notification actions these are those
interactive notifications
to make europe interactive even without
it being there on foreground and scream
number gonna pass the baton again I'm
gonna come back talk about remote
notifications
some changes that we have their for
registering
then finally we're gonna talk about one
last new feature location-based
notifications
user notifications that are triggered in
response to the user changing their
location like Iran
to the very first topic using
notifications
so in I will see regardless of whether
your app is going to display remote
user: notifications
or local user notifications Europe must
first register
to use those notifications in this is
going to result in a lil in an alert
that is going to be presented to the
user asking them if it's okay P wrapped
the present
notifications to them so what does this
code look like how do we register
your app you were to take advantage
abuse or notifications
the code is actually pretty
straightforward the very first thing you
need to do is to clear the types of
these notifications
you wish to present from within your at
this case the sap is actually going to
present
all the different types notification to
possibly can it's going to be showing
badges
on the icon loss to be playing sounds
as well as displaying alerts now once we
decided the types that were actually
going to be presenting
we're gonna create are you are using
notification settings object
passing these types the settings for
types categories
now but second parameter the categories
parameter Hill no definite no here
don't worry about it that has something
to do with notification actions
rats gonna talk about those later
finally once we've created the settings
object
we're just gonna pass it to the shared
application instance in registries
notification settings
and at that point assuming this is the
very first time your app is called this
method
the user is going to be displayed an
alert asking them if it's okay
for your apt to present user
notifications to them
now they're gonna they're gonna say okay
or maybe not now
but no matter what they do they could
always at a later time back on the rapid
change the preferences and settings
so this isn't the last time I that you
have a chance in order to present
notifications to the user
so once they've actually replied to that
alert your
app delegate is gonna get a call back
application
did registry is a notification settings
that notification settings object that
we pass back to you
represents the user's up to date most
current
preferences for displaying notifications
and at that point all you need to do is
check what types in notifications you're
allowed to present to the user
so again like I mentioned before there
is the possibility that the user could
always background your app
going to settings and change their
preferences any stay on topic this
you don't wanna be doing any unnecessary
processing per se preparing
a alert tight notification when you
don't really need to
so we have a PI in UI application as
well
this current user notification settings
method
that is available in the UI application
instance will give you the most
up today user notification preferences
and from there you can make sure that
you're not doing any
unnecessary work to prepare for
notifications that are going to be
displayed to the user anyway
so that use notifications are really
it's just a registration method to state
that your app wishes to use user
notifications
and to do this you just need to call
registry. is a notification settings on
the UI application shared instance
anytime you need to get the most current
user preferences
you just have to call current
notification settings on UI application
in order creepy settings are jacks at
the time of registering
you just call settings for tights
categories
your college for the categories was nil
in the previous sample slide
and that has something to do with
notification actions
Saretsky to come up on stage and talk
about notification actions a great new
feature in iowa say
I can't wait to see you guys take
advantage of affect
thanks then my name is red Dixon and I'm
gonna talk about notification actions
a great new feature I was a that we're
really excited about
firsts let's talk about notification
actions and I was seven
but on the lockscreen Notification
Center
banners or more alerts
you get one default action when you
swipe a tap on the notification
the launch the application in the
foreground
and I West 8 in addition to that
defaultaction
when you swipe to the left on lockscreen
you get to know actions
likewise the Notification Center when
you swipe to the left
to new actions in banners when you pull
down
to more actions and more alerts when you
tap on the Options button
you get up to former actions
so you sort of occasion actions in your
application unit follow three steps
you need to first register your actions
you need two seconds
send a push for schedule local
notification
and finally once the user has seen these
actions and tapped on one
need to handle the action
to illustrate the steps and then use the
calendar invite example
with reactions except maybe and decline
let's first look at registering actions
you start off by creating our action
he then set the identifiers interaction
the same identify we passed back to you
when you handle the action
you then set the title this is a
localized string they'll be shown to the
user
you then set the activation mode this
will determine
if your application is launched in the
foreground or the background
if you need to show you why his shoes
for ground you don't need to interrupt
the user
mission said jews background if you do
run in the background
you have on the order of seconds not
minutes to run
he then said whether the action is
destructive if this is yes
the actual be shown as red on the lock
screen and the Notification Center
finally set whether authentication is
required
if this is yes and the device is locked
these will have to enter into passcode
when the tap on the action
interaction as a background action is
important to note that the device does
not
actually unlock secure application
accesses any files on
desk need to be sure that they belong in
the crack data protection class
for more information and data protection
will point you toward some
more resources at the end of the session
so here's an example if the except
invite action
it does need to show you I so it can run
in the background
its not destructive SoCon on blue in
Notification Center and on the
lockscreen
and because accepting an invite is
relatively harmless units require
authentication
on the other hand if you had a trash
male action also doesn't need to show
you I
so I can run in the background it is
destructive
so will be shown in red on the lock
screen in Notification Center
and because you want someone to be able
to pick up your phone and delete all
your email
authentication is required
finally we have reply actions this
does need to show you why so we'll need
to run for ground
again it's not destructive so will be
shown as blue
and because it's a foreground action if
the device is locked the user will have
to enter enter passcode
so in this case the authentication
required property has no effect
so now that you've to find her actions
need to group them into a category
a category is simply a type of
notification with associated actions
for example you can have the invite
category with except maybe in decline
actions
you don't have a new male category with
marks reading trash
where take category with like comment
and attack
start using no categories the first
create one
you then set the identifiers will
include the side in the fire
in apush payload your local notification
you then set the actions on the category
for inaction context
there to action contacts the first the
default action contact
supports up to four actions the second
the minimal action context
is used when there's only room for two
actions
the for example if you said these three
actions except may be in decline
for the default action contacts and if
this notification was then presented on
lockscreen
you would see the first two actions
except maybe
if you wanted a different set of actions
such as except in decline
you could set those on the minimal
action contact
then when this notification is presented
on the lockscreen
you would see except in decline when the
same notification
is presented as a modeler because this
is the default
action context you would see the fourth
reactions except may be in decline
22 finder categories you now need to
register them
you do this by first grouping them
together in a Sat
providing them to your user notification
settings the sword and left us off
and then registering those settings with
a shared application instance
now average their actions the next thing
to do send a push notification
or schedule local notification to show
those actions
in the remote notification case unit
include the category identifiers
in their push payload will use this to
determine what actions to show when you
present your notification
roth a very excited to announce that the
previous size limit have 256 bytes for
push payload
has now been increased 22 kilobytes
compare
so in the
local notification case you create a
notification is normal
you then set the category of the actions
you like shown
family is scheduled of cation as normal
wants you sent to push notification or
scheduled local notification
and these arrests in this and tapped on
an action if any to handle that action
to handle the default action when a user
to swipes or taps on a notification
launch application in the foreground and
call application did finish watching
with options
will pass in the local notification or
the remote notification
the remote remote notification case will
also call
application did receive remote
notification that completion handler
if your application is
already in the foreground we won't
actually show the notification
instead will either call
application did receive local
notification or application did receive
remote notification
with its completion handler if you've
been permitted that otherwise will call
the fair
at the version without the completion
handler find me
to handle the new additional actions and
I was 8 you need to implement at least
one of two new methods and application
delegate
in either case
will pass to the action identifiers you
can use this to determine what action
was tapped on
of the past few
either the remote notification or the
local notification
and you can use this to I retrieve any
information you need to handle that
action
family will pass you the completion
handler
which you must call when you finish
handling the action
for the summer I S
to use notification actions in your
application you first need to register
your actions
this involves defining your actions
ripping them into a category
and in registering those categories with
you use a notification settings
you then need to send a push
notification
or schedule local notification including
the category identifiers
the actions you like shown you then need
to handle the action with these are has
tapped on it by implementing one of the
new methods on your application delegate
notification actions are a great new
feature
we can't wait to see what you're going
to do with them I'm not gonna pass it
back to dan
to talk about remote notifications pay
on fourth talk about what's new
with remote notifications in iowa say so
recall we got two different types to
promote notifications
we have user type remote notifications
that's when European a server
sends a push notification to the device
were in the payload we've gotten this
case an alert that results
any user notification being presented to
the user as it was coming from
the ap its running are installed right
there on the device
we've also got silent types
government notifications this is when
you're APNs
server is sending a push notification
with the content available flag
contained in it and then instead a bus
presenting a user notification
I on the device instead ilsa is gonna
come in
weekly wrap up in the background you can
go and fetch whatever content that needs
to or do whatever info processing is
necessary
that when the user next launch the app
all that info is right they're ready for
them to ingest
so
for user notifications that our source
from remote payloads
on just like for local notifications
you must make sure that your app calls
register using notification settings
before any alerts or badges for sounds
are actually gonna be presented
by you will need to also register for a
more pushes
more show how to get into that later I
now for filing notifications just like
in Iowa seven before
you need to I to find your info Key West
file
are you white background mode iraq and
that are a must contain an entry
remote notification and so user
notification family notifications these
are not mutually exclusive
Europe actually can use both i mix and
match them
to whatever makes most sense for your
users NP rap
so for remote notifications are you must
make sure
that you are registering before you can
receive any pushes from European a
server
now in Iowa 7 I win you would register
for remote notifications
you would ask the user for permission
but now since we have separated the
concept registering for user
notifications which does require
permission
from remote notifications that could be
UserType or silent type
we actually are opting your app's into
being able to receive remote
notifications have any payload type
by default however keep in mind
%ah okay for have
banks I keep in mind however that these
are could anytime
going to the Settings app and change the
preferences
so how do we actually register for
remote notifications
in Iowa seven before we ask you to call
this
method here register for remote
notification types
that's now deprecated because we've
changed the way
we define user notifications and remote
notifications
all you need to do is calling you
application
register for remote notifications
now again this wall op love your apt to
receive remote payloads that are coming
from the APNs server
but if you want user notifications to be
presented in response to those payloads
if you've got say
an alert defined in those payloads you
also must make sure that you call
register user notification settings as
explained earlier in the talk
so once you've called register for
remote notifications
as well as optionally register user
notification settings
your app delegate needs to implement
application did register for remote
notifications
with device token the factually isn't
new API
this is something that has existed 907
previously
I just letting you know that you still
need to implement this for handling
remote notifications
what this call back does is a provides
your app with the device token
were once you receive but token you need
to go and pass it off
tear EPNS ever your call
you need to make sure that you've always
got the most up-to-date device token
registered with your EPNS server
otherwise pushes may not make their way
to the user's device
so in the case but these are happened to
disable I your app from using remote
notifications
or for any other failure case recalled
that the app delegate
also needs to implement application did
fail to register for remote
notifications affair
and at this point all you need to do is
take that dare object process it
appropriately
make sure you disable any logic within
your application that hymns of a
perceiving remote notifications
you don't want to be doing any
unnecessary processing within your app
for notifications aren't going to be
coming at disgracefully
to grade
so that's what's new with remote
notifications on IRC
again I just like before you do have to
register for remote notifications before
you can actually receive them
I however now in IRC
the user will be opted into being a 4
receiving a remote notifications and
they could go into settings later in the
feebleness
however does still require you to call
this registration API
while the PPIs change we've simplified
it I N
have named register for my notifications
you can call their on the UI application
shared instance
call so let's get into the last topic up
today
location-based notifications something
we're very excited about we've been
working with the core location team for
this feature
very happy to talk about it today so
let's say that you've got a nap
and you want to notify the user when
they happen to arrive at some certain
geographic location
so the users on their device and they
happen to wander into that area and you
wanna show say
an alert what you could do this in Iowa
them before but it required a lot of
hoops to jump through
and also could make for some a confusing
user experience
Nyassi however we've streamlined this
API
all it is is simple additions on top at
the UI local notification API class
and what you can do is define core look
Asian region objects
and attach them to the notification so
that the notification of fire when the
user happens to
coming year enter exit region
now you can make it so that these
notifications are presented only the
very first time that these are happens
into this region
or you could have a fire always if that
makes sense for your app
and again census features so tightly
integrated with core location
I does require little bit of colour
location registration on your part
let's take a look at what that
registration code is before we get into
how we can actually schedule
these notifications so here we are
I what we need to do is create a
co-location manager instance
then we just need to set the delegate on
this manager the delegate is going to
receive call backs
notifying whether your app is allowed to
were not allowed to track users
locations
then finally in order to enable these
location-based notifications
on the location manager incense you need
to call request when in use
authorization
so what does this mean when in use
essentially if the user says OK will
allow your app to track the user's
location
or know about the user's location when
your app is running in the foreground
however recall these notifications are
going to be appearing on the user's
device
even if you're app is in the background
were suspended
and they might be able to see these
alerts well that's okay
because even if your app has been
disabled for core location
and even if the user is seeing those
alerts your app won't be receiving any
call backs
until these are actually interactive
hurdler in Europe is still allowed
to track the user's location so we're
requesting or when in use authorization
from CL location manager
assuming this is the very first time
that the that your app is called this
code
the user is going to be presented with
the permission alert
just basically saying is it okay for
this app to track your location
when it's running for gramm notice
however in that alert we've got that
usage tax stamp allowing smaller font
this is actually something that our apt
has to find on its own
and you need to make sure that your apt
the fines this usage tax as well
so to do that in your info pls
a file hopefully this makes easier to
read
I'm we've got and its location when you
see is this description
just gotta find the ski the values gonna
be a string
and this is the actual usage tax that's
going to appear in that alert
are recall however that if your app is
running in different locales in
different languages
you need to make sure that this string
is localized appropriately for all those
other languages
so make sure that you define values for
the street up for this key
in urine popular strings file as well
now we've asked the user if it's OK
for your app to track your location when
it's running the foreground
now we actually need to handle the call
back from CL location manager
and to do this your I your managers
delegate
is going to receive this call back
location manager
did change authorization status: that
point all you need to do
it's just make sure the status is the
when in use status
if you're authorized for tracking the
user's location when in use
and at that point you can start
scheduling his location base
notifications
so how do we actually schedule these
location-based notifications
take a look at some sample code how we
could skip our schedule notification
that triggers in response to the user
entering the region
very first thing you need to do just
like any other UI local notifications
that would
otherwise be triggered by it the for a
time you first go to create an instance
the view I local notification
in to find what type of notification
this is going to be
in this case we're just saying this is
going to be an alert when user happened
sent to that region
assuming the app isn't running the
foreground they're gonna get a little
pop up saying
hey you have arrived
then specific to region type core
location type
user I you I local notifications
were stating here that we only want this
notification to trigger the very first
time
these are happens to enter exit this
region now this is actually the default
behavior
so it's a little bit sharper superfluous
here however you could set this to know
if that makes sense for your users and
for your app
next you just need to create a field
region instance
and set it on the region property at the
UI local notification
so in this case for defining feel
circular region here and we're just
giving it some
arbitrary cornet with some radius so
that when the user enters the circle
arm this a notifications gonna be
triggered
however I did say that this is a seal
region property
see you can also use feel beacon regions
or any other type of seal region
subclass
if you want to find out more about how
you can use caller location
especially in combination with you I
local notification
I've got some resources to point you
towards at the end of the stock
finally a new UI application shared
incense you just need to cost schedule
local notification
passing this notification just like you
would any other
UserType local notification
so call now we've actually got this
notification scheduled
assuming that your app is running in the
background or suspended rather
end-user happens enter into that region
they're going to be presented with an
alert
saying hey you've arrived at your
destination in your app can handle that
local notification
in the application did finish launching
with options
alternatively if your app is running in
the foreground and user happens
enter into that region your app delegate
is going to be called back with
application did receive local
notification
so the two different our method here
application did finish launching
verses application did receive local
notification the logic is very very
similar
let's just take a look at the latter Sat
for the latter part
so we've been informed that the user is
entered into a region
are or rather that the user has received
a local notification
and we wanna check whether this is
actually a region-based notification
while you I local notification has a
region property now
to see if that region happens to not be
male
an IFS in if it isn't we've got a
location-based notification
and we can do whatever makes sense tell
all the user's friends where they've
arrived
so that's location-based notifications
it's very very simple API that added on
to you I local notification
and it's so simple because we've
integrated directly with core location
however because we've been together with
us this week or location
are we do require some core location
registration logic
now again I this is all
as well about keeping the user's privacy
first place in mind
so if the user happens with ever
disabled your app from being able to
track
their location even when your app is in
the foreground you're not going to be
receiving call backs like application
did receive local notification
4 location-based notifications
these are my launcher app in response to
an alert that was presented at the local
be our location this notification
but still your app isn't going to know
that and that was a lot of stuff that we
talked about today
on biggest thing we've been talking
about that notification actions wrecking
appear talk about this great new feature
for IRC
so psyched to see you guys use it making
your app's
interactive even when they're not
running the foreground really
new in powerful ways I some simple
changes
behind user and remote notification
registration
I again we separated the concept of
having to register for different remote
notification types
and instead ask you to register for that
user notification types
that Europe is going to use and then we
had
location-based notifications integrating
tightly with core location
to schedule user notifications
in response to the user entering or
exiting regions
South a lot of stuff on and we've got
great resources for you guys check out
Paul gambled his our core OS
technologies evangelist he is a great
guy
in you can send him letters at ample
that Apple dot com
I we've also got documentation at
developer DAP about.com
while the DEP forms talk to like minded
developers I
find out how other people are using
these great new features ask your
questions get them answered
by but by this is WWDC
and we've also got other sessions now
the sessions happen previously
what's new in poor location as well as
taking carlocation: indoors happened
yesterday
but these are available online as well
as protecting the user's data
ret hinted at that data class protection
well in 2012 we had a session on these
as well
and you can check out these videos
online too
so you guys been great thank you so much
for coming to da WWDC
hope you have a great nephew