okay good morning everybody welcome to
the WWDC 2014 pretty fashion I'm Howard
Miller on the
engineering manager for everything
printing Apple I
today we are pretty straightforward
agenda review a little bit over an
update on AirPrint
were spent the majority of our session
on I O S printing
we're gonna show you the new IRS
printing technology that in iowa saying
we're going to give you a demo that
so I know everybody probably went to the
parties last night so we gotta wake
everybody up
how many people here have applications
that already print
all right we've got a good good number
how many here
have applications that you want to have
print are right
by the time you guys leave today your
applications will be able to print
I know you can write the code while
sitting right there cuz it's going to be
that easy
but if you don't get it done we have
allowed that follows a string come down
and we will get your code printing today
so they give you an update about
AirPrint
what is AirPrint you know this
technology was released with IRS 4.2
several years ago
in our primary goal was to provide a
great
outstanding user experience pretty was a
pain
really was painful and we worked on the
back to make it simpler but it still
wasn't super simple we gotta I US
we had to have no drivers no software to
install no configuration
user just wants to put their printer
connected to the network and then when
they go to print there's the printer
they print you don't need fifty million
options the printer should be smarter
the printing system should be smarter
and that's what we did
but we didn't sacrifice output quality
with AirPrint you get the fall
print quality that Apple's come become
known
to deliver for for the last couple
decades it is as good or in some cases
better than what you can get from the
desktop
no compromises were made your printer
manufacturer Prince a protocol
standards-based plus a little apple
secret sauce on the side
and if you're if you're a technology
provider a server vendor
I we will license you all this
technology zero cost
I am printers
you know we introduced with with the
dozen or so players from HPI I'm proud
to report that we have a hundred times
as many printers now
I if you go in any staples or fries or
or pick your favorite electronic store
virtually every network printer they
sell now has AirPrint
in it I'm by my read about how for the
world's install base for printers have
AirPrint n/a a yeah almost cannot
find a printer that your mom would want
doesn't have AirPrint last year all the
enterprise vendors came on
Kia Sarah sharp Toshiba all have
AirPrint throughout their product line
as I mentioned AirPrint
is available as a printing system and i
OS 4.2 in later
for those who've done the math that
means they're more than $700 million
users that have the same printing system
on it that's more than any other
printing system in the history the
computing industry so AirPrint spring
system
is the most prevalent printing platform
out there then of course the most
important thing is you're out and you
just gotta believe this I the Microsoft
guys released a beautiful product
they left once more feature how and they
heard about it right away on day one
and by the end of that week I was on the
phone with their engineers
telling him to check out the last WWDC
presentation
within a couple days their app was then
printing course it to come by
the better part of a month to release it
we're gonna get outta there
what you need to know about airplane is
it super super easy
the user interface is easy the user
action is easy
but equally important and probably more
important for you
is that that the API said that we have
is not some random walk through a
hundred different things
we have a very very focused survey PI's
that are very efficient to get you right
down to what you need to know
in with a little work and a little help
from your application
bring system smart enough to know what
to do with your output
we can get super high quality output
without having to have a bunch for user
interaction
so let's talk about about what's gone on
with AirPrint
we started with consumer inkjet we got
consumer laser we got enterprise
lasers we've got some servers I'll after
we talked about brothers
first role for printer and as things go
there are always new classes for
printers coming
and we're getting into some other
specialty printers are in store with one
of my new favorites
this is probably not what your mom can I
get home this is the Astra mad tuff
rider 5 the reason I like this
is because it's native spot
is on the cockpit of an airplane there
it is set in its native
747 environment I but this will end up
on C-seventeens with the military lined
up and and
commercial but what's interesting is
iPad and iPhones are everyplace
applications need to print in the
printer manufacturers ok all types are
responding
I am this is a curiosity and then there
probably won't be millions are these
printer sold
but it shows that airport is pretty much
every corner of the world now
another printer that I'm really happy to
talk about is the brother Roger
forty 40 this is a very small
battery-powered
receded label printer I it will support
AirPrint soon
and I will have a demo that later today
so let's talk about what we've added we
have added some new API's and higher
with
a these are to support
specialty printers in applications
if you look at what we did in AirPrint
so far
every time you print the user has to see
our print dialog which means they get to
pick a printer
if you're doing an application I am
for the lucky store checkout counter we
certainly don't want the clerk
every day picking their printer every
time they print every receipt for the
customer
here at Luckys least my lucky
they have to printers their one printer
prints the receipt yet on Prince those
coupons and they tear them off and they
give you both
the survey guys will allow you to have
multiple sets up earners
pre-configured by an administrator I
that at runtime: the user the
application can select which printer
without the user having to get involved
so
will have a bunch to take talk about
that in a minute I select the talk about
some hence
first of everybody's designing their
applications for the screen we've got
some beautiful iPad with Retina displays
but for those worse in the print world
that's pretty low resolution output
also output that is backlit
when we start talking about paper you
have a lil much larger
campus a much larger space to utilize
and that means the you wanna lay out
your stuff too
to make effective use to the space you
want to provide
higher quality graphics you really need
higher resolution graphics than what
you're showing on screen if you want the
the output to be truly spectacular that
I want you to think about readability
you know they don't print book
that people are gonna sit on the couch
and read
with no margins there's always a big
margin so your big fat
some can be there and you can still read
the words
consider what paper is it's gonna be
reflective
lights gonna come off a bit gray looks
awesome on screen gray looks
awful when it comes to print it hard to
reconsider the contrast
consider the margin consider the fund's
consider the spacing
papers a little different than screen
and little just a little bit
aforethought you can get spectacular
printed output
I with respect to the Print System it's
a smart printing system we do a huge
amount of stuff
to help your app if you tell us that
it's a photo for example
we will automatically pick the photo
trying
pic photo print mode picked the highest
quality print mode
skill the item to fit on the page
centered in print
you're gonna tell us what you're trying
to print were gonna work all the magic
behind the scenes in the Print System to
make sure the user gets the best output
okay there are few data objects that
we're gonna hand you your hand us back
and I just it's
you know the caviar don't roll around in
those in train tweak stuff don't respect
these opaque objects we may change
something in fact we probably will and I
don't wanna breaker up in the future
and then the last hit if there's anybody
here who test the Raptors anybody to
stir up
okay least a few if you do you don't
have to go by
all 1200 AirPrint printer models that
are available in the world
go back to the the 2012 WWDC session we
spent about 15 minutes on something
called the printer simulator
which is part of your Xcode release
it allows you to simulate every comment
I printer including changing some other
printers
parameters so inkjet printers laser
printers row for printers
you don't have to buy more by one and
use the
printer simulator to do your work okay
let's get to the focus of today's
meeting again our goal is by the time
you leave here today you can create an
app that Prince
and for the media this presentation I'm
gonna bring upon my engineers
tara Lynn and he is going to
take you through everything you need to
know to make your print
thanks Howard I'm tied it when I
apron engineer and the lead on me I was
planning system so we're gonna talk
about
am I was burning here a personal talk
about picking what to print
next we'll go over the API's had had
actually get
output will talk about to the different
pinning you I options
so first this is our motto I think
we made this clear but I was praying as
easy but powerful
we designed the AirPrint protocol to
scale from
you know a small consumer printers all
the way up to big
enterprise-class printers and everything
in between and with every IRS really is
we've been adding an expanding the types
of things you can do for my last
but we kept it really easy so we want
the user
interaction to be really really simple
and basic we haven't
added Diane added an added include
really try to keep
feature creep down so providing good
content for printing this is really the
most important part
I'm what we're looking for is bring it
up but thats useful
attractive and high-quality I would like
to thank you this is like
high and graphic design I'll it's best
that
design your output I'm like a graphic
designer word and then use our classes
to
make that happen that have approaching
it the other way around we're just
looking at all the classes and trade
tweaking what you'd what you wanna do
first design and then use our classes
as howard said what looks good on screen
than I look good
on paper we also want you to make you so
the dynamic braking system so
I'm paper size can be anything and we
actually talk to the air print printer
I'm we figure out what side burner
papers are available
some printers actually have paper size
sensors that can tell what
papers in an or the user can turn on the
front panel what papers loaded
and so the print system is designed to
be dynamic to have
it sense at all the way up to your app
if your app is dynamic about its content
laying it out
then you get the full benefit that
printer hardware margins also very quite
a bit
sometimes bottom margin might be large
them margins on
other side might be really really small
so for all these reasons it's really
best not to produce a fixed size PDF and
send it to the printing system
also another thing to keep in mind is
there's really two major document sizes
for paper in the world US letter which
is very is in the US
and then there's a for which is used a
lot of other
regions around the world so if you
design your output based only on the the
paper size that your region uses you
might be missing out on a whole other
markets so it's good to think about all
these different paper sizes
and like we set the printer simulator
you can use to simulate these different
conditions
so good example have pretty
is this map dictionary for kids this is
an app that
let's you eat look at different
definitions of math terms
in this case for a look at the Las
arithmetic and if you're a teacher and
you want to make like a hand out at this
you can print it out and without you get
looks really nice that would be suitable
to hand out to all the students in a
classroom
have the night header and footer there's
the page number at the bottom
the examples our next call out boxes
that are different color
an Italian poet actually even looked
really good on a black and white printer
and if the the
quivers printing had US legal out in
their printer and the the printer
I'll reported that back to the brink
system this app is dynamic
an at fits all the content on one page
it stretches out it looks good
so this is a good example a being
dynamic about to
about content okay so let's
step right into the FBI's here the basic
steps to printing with
you I this is a standard printing I
first your Apple get the print
controller
or the activity controller sure she'd
your setup attributes for the job like
job name in the type of job
then you provide the content for praying
and we'll go over that
later me a present the UI at this point
I was takes over it communicates with
the AirPrint printer
figures out all the relevant information
and the Damon takes over managing the
job
if there's I'm if the job needs a
username a password that brings
authentic scare that if
paper around our incomes irony in that
kinda stuff that are managed by the day
Damon's hereafter need to deal with any
of that stuff
so here's the classes were gonna be
focusing on
first you I print and file the just the
general
I'm sorta meta data about the print job
the job name in a type a job
you I put paper which this represents
sheet of paper at the printer
a pretty for matter which knows how to
format content for she
you a pre-paid render which lets you
take full control over drying
than for showing you I am here and I
managing the job we have you I printer
actually controller
or you I activity view controller which
is the share she
the first let's go for you I print and
file every print job should have
are you I put in for a set up for it
first thing I do is that the jobname
now this job name appears on the front
panel when the user printer printer
are when he's a prince a job but also
appears I
in Perth Center if these are on to
cancel their job
if they're planning to a server are like
a press release server
this is how you use is going to be
identifying their job
that needs to be really specific if it's
something generic like just print job
that doesn't really help users identify
which jobs there's such are important to
make sure this is
specific as possible next we have output
type:
this just tell the principal about the
type of content that you're pretty
that lowers the the panic that them to
make appropriate choices for paper size
pic quality mode I we also make you I
decisions about what to show for the UI
based on apartheid we have four these
first one just the general up you I prim
and proper
general this is like you know mix text
and graphics
like a web page are showing here
will tell the printer to print it normal
quality isn't that gonna do high quality
and take a really long time
I'll by departures the document paper
size like
a four-letter the UI lowers
duplex to be shown on page arranged to
next one we have the document grayscale
this is very similar to the previous one
but this is optimized for
monochrome like text and and monochrome
graphics
this case you get improved print speed
cuz we can tell the printer
this is just black and white the data
over the network can be last
and all silent many cases reduce their
money Inc but it's used because the
printer will go into a black only mode
and like the previous example die I am
duplex allowed and paid range controls
will be allowed in and UI
next one is photo like Howard Mintz you
can tell us your printing a photo
will choose high quality will tell the
printer this is a photo printer
highest quality which is a photo paper
size based on the region
if the printer allows borderless
printing will choose borderless printing
and because duplex unpaid range I make
sense for a photo we don't show those in
the IC get a really really simple you
and then similarly we have high quality
grayscale
which is in all in most cases arm in
most ways at the same as the previous
one
but some printers have a high quality
great game modes some have
from graying Lincoln turned on pic a
photo in grayscale really really nicely
so we'll tell the printer to do that so
choose this if you what your
photo to come out and I really high and
grayscale way
okay so that you I print and file X will
talk about you I print paper
the really simple class just basically
have the paper act that represents
the fact that the full sheet of paper
have at 00:00 on
just directing oversized sheet an
insider that we have the printable
racked
this is the image malaria on its
the where the printer can actually image
content so it's basically the
the full page minus the hardware margins
okay next we'll talk about providing
content so this is really that the meter
that the presentation here
and there's three levels here we have
are
the easiest way then there's a little
bit more it still simple but a little
bit more involved and then
fully custom ROM pages the first the
easy
is PDF files image files things that are
ready
are basically ready to print
protease it could be a single item or
you can be a real items like dad a bunch
of photos you want to print you could
primary
I'm it could be like I said PDF J pegs
any image type that I was understands
it can be in the form have an ass URL to
like a file on
desk or they can be in memory in the
form of an enhanced data
you I am CIA image it can even be
something in the photo library like an
ass
a laugh at cornell URL I'm interpreting
system knows how to
go into the former librarian grab that
if you provide an array of items each
one of those items will be a separate
job
so here's all the car that it would take
to print a PDF file it's pretty simple
this method just take then you're out to
a PDF file on desk
first we asked the UI interaction
controller
if it can print this URL and some
examples of when it would be able to
print it I'll
if the PDF hat was password-protected
offers now formed in some way
next week grab the you I pretty
interaction controllers
it's a shared objects we just grabbed a
share print controller
with that the printing item property to
be this URL to our PDF
if there was an array of items its
there's a different property company
items
the it set to be arraigned
men we set up are you a pic info like I
said we'll do this for every job
was at the upper type to be you I
pretend for a pic general because PDF
typically have
mix text and graphics the job name will
be
just the file name other the PDF north
at the prison for property
up the UI printer actually controller to
be the print and for that we just
created
next that the show is paid range
property to be yes
by default but it's now but for PDF
usually users are going to want to be
able to specify paid range within the
PDF to print
and i was just call present animated
yes completion handler with no
completion handler
at this point IRS takes takeover you
don't have to do anything else on your
app
like I said if there's issues you know I
kinda paper any accounts that are
managed by the system you don't have to
handle any
scares me
okay so that's a easy level
next is basic principal content
we have just text or if you I'm written
your whole proudly outraged and now
those issues when it is provided
formatter classes
so for matters but will be using
now what is a formatter it's pretty
basic it just
basically takes and in the abstract and
to take from data in your app
and some rectangle honest and I'll put a
sheet of paper
and it knows how to format sounds pretty
pretty basic
so in this case I guess being attacked
say we have the Gettysburg Address
in an ass string we can use a you a
simple text formatter
it knows how to take that string and to
lay it out onto a page
into this rectangle now the whole string
doesn't fit on this one paid so far
matter
know it's just keep going and tell all
the content
and all the data did used up
so you can use for matters directly with
you I printer actually controller or the
you activity controller the share she to
format for a whole page
you can also use for matters as a helper
and a full render
we'll talk about that later for plain
text
use this you a simple text formatter
that allows you to specify fontcolor
linemen you know can't control the text
how you want to look on the page
for HTML markup you use the UI mark-up
text formatter
and it knows had format you know based
on its generals using WebKit
so the layout by default I'm here's our
paper like we share before
I to file that uses the printable racked
which is the original area
but that might be really really close
the add to the page some printers
you know only have like oh attend two
minutes on edge the campaign
like howard mentioned that's not a good
thing you don't want are content to be
that closed added page so that's we've
provided I
a property on the format and you can use
and new this year we have
per page content inset the lets you
specify
left top right bottom on every page
so will you little
keep going until other content used up
and an honor those margins everything a
page
previously we had a continent that which
is all behaved a little bit differently
and we think this is a little better
I'm that'll allow you to get nice top
and bottom margins
and that are consistent every single
page
so here's a a quick code sample love
using a formatter
and this is all the code you would need
if you had your print layout
design HTML this is really all you need
to do
as this this method here into the matter
text HTML text
as a parameter we create are you a
mark-up text formatter
initialize it with the text that was
past 10
next week setup are per page content at
which is a UI agent that so I'll call
you added make
ok but three quarters-inch top I top
left bottom right
and then we'll just set the printer
formatter property on the controller to
be the formatter we just created
they will set up are you I pretend to
like we always do
just that up a general bud job name will
be there web pages
URL field
and you put that so that's all you need
to do
now view for matters I'm every view an
eye on has applied for matter that
knows how to get that cunt an interview
on the page
I'm I was whether really designed for to
be view based
printing go by some viewers are really
useful for this
so this example a map if you want to get
that content that a
the map but in a MapView are you need to
do is call
the view print formatter on your map you
and you can have this right to your pad
controller in
and prep another view that's really
useful
out to to use the view prepared for
matter is a WebView
if you have a baby you in your apt and
you want to get that content print
I need to call it that you print
formatter so you don't need initialize
it on your own you just grab it from the
view
okay so that's our print for matters
so that the intermediate level I'm
the basic level next is you know little
bit more advanced
fully custom ROM pages this is the view
this is for if you want to really take
total control over the drying and will
be rendering the pages with content
using render is mostly but you can also
use them for matters like we just
went over in render
surrenders I'm what is a render well
here's our
i render object and its really
responsible for at least two things
first in which is responding to number
pages saw it happen now
how many pages that total reprinting
netscape
to a response to next thing I have to be
have to do is when it's called drug
content for page at index
interact so the pretty let them tell
that draw the first page
and it gets to use any drying methods
better at it
disposal so I any screen drying methods
car graphics core tax
on you like it drying methods
net told rather second page because
we've had two pages and so it just gets
to do
however wants to drop so this is what
you do for
you know elaborate on put it up
so your subclass you I paid render like
I said at the minimum you override
number of pages
and drug content for page index it also
has
the other method you can override like
dry header dropped footer things like
that
I'm another documented you'll set the UI
premier actual controllers pet page
render a property
to be this at your instantiated object
to your custom
you a pager underclass or you can add
that object to the Rev actively items
if you're using this year she you can
also add for matters by calling at print
formatter
starting at page index because they
approach formatter can start and end
page
how would you use a formatter with a
render kinda maybe a little bit
complicated to think about but it really
pretty basic on so here's i render and
when it's told to drop page
all it's doing is just its gonna drop
from flourishes on the top and the
bottom
in the middle we want to drop tact so
the render have the UI simple text
formatter
here's a rectangle that we've set up or
what that text ago
and our gettysburg address again you a
simple text formatter just formats in
the middle
some the one year's for matter to for
T you know to HTML in a party your page
but then you want full over full control
over drying up restive it you can do
that
okay so showing you I and there's a
couple different options
pretty from the share sheet as probably
where most people expect burning up if
it's sharing
some general content and pretty is one
of the options
this is where burning appears in most to
the built-in app smile ass
like here in Safari
to do that it's really basic am will
just when we set up our
activity items wildest at a print and
file
which has job name job type and all that
you can add down to render like
this case and for the for this example
were like sharing a web page
and most the time when you're sure web
page you're sharing the actual URL
but in the case for printing you want
actually render out the whole web page
that's
example showing now I'll just
initialize are you activity view
controller with activity items that we
just created
and no application activities some
pretty good always and activity item at
an application activity
an analyst for that using a standard
view controller methods
Sony other case spring with like a a
print button and
you create and set up the UI print
interaction controller like we did in
are examples for standard presentation
your car present animated completion
handler
and for a popover presentation present
from racked
in view or present from by about 9 a.m.
animated
completion
so happening at the menu item if you
wanna embed the pretty you I in your own
UI
like in this case pages for you select
the print button
at flights over get pushed into it like
a nap controller
%um you'll set your class as a delegate
for the shared my printer action
controller
you implement interaction controller
parent view controller
so you'll tell printer action controller
which you should be apparent
then when the user taps painting your UI
you'll just call present animated
completion handler
on the UI contractual controller and
then
if you're class that you've told that is
the parent is a UN irrigation controller
will get a push
and if it some other UI view controller
I'll just give him oral presentation
but really they navigation controllers
with this is not useful
now controlling paper size I'm if you if
your app is designed with specific paper
size as mine
like a document center cap white pages
where the user's actually
laying out their content I'm your Apple
have to provide its on paper selection
you I
this is a example for pages here where
you get to choose a couple different
paper sizes
when you use the delegate method print
interaction controller choose paper
as call after the user selects a printer
we've communicated with the printer with
the we figured out the papers that are
available
and you then we'll ask for a paper size
that's a good match to the one at the
user-selected
if the paper had if the printer has
paper sensors or if the user inputted
exactly what paper they're loading the
array that get return will only be the
ones that are detected
those are the only options available
so here's a quick example have our
delegate method for
on choose paper
this case were looking for it in half by
eleven sheet of paper so I'll just
created CG size
page size
and then we'll use you I print papers
best paper for page size
with papers from her a method so we've
provided this method for you on your
iPad paper because
texted pretty complicated to match am
for a destination
for a target paper size from the left
the papers I'm
kinda complicated and we've mediafir
easy we just recommended
call this next up is roll paper
on this was new and I'll 7 on its
similar to choose paper
and that you can have a delegate method
called cut like for paper
this is this method only be called after
the user selects a printer that actually
have a role loaded and
it'll have a you a pic paper passed into
it with the with
up the role and the high to the paper
will be the maximum height
that that the printer allows by default
if you don't have this
the delegate method which must act want
and the and
if the user chooses a printer that has a
role loaded the coupling will just be
proportional to their whatever default
paper would be used for that job
okay next up the a new thing and I was a
parade
happy to announce I'm as pretty without
showing you I'm
now the opens up the opportunity for
new types of running applications or
really excited about that
on wEDC this year's all about enabling
developers to do
new I'm interesting thing for you
weren't able to do before so we're
excited to have this
on but what does not for as for aP's
provide their own custom paint panel
I wasn't designed for that and in some
ways you're not going to be able to do
that
so here's our standard for and why I was
just break it down into some steps
first what the user uses issue I to do
is to select their printer
then the fat from options like copies or
duplex
things like that and then they can't
print money actually wanna prep
so what we really done a separated
decided to things
is still the these are still going to
select the printer
but that's done up front and so for that
we have a printer picker
and then to replace the settings that
they would be using we have ap
controlled setting
an API and then we have a new
print method on you I print interaction
controller that you'll be calling
so it's kinda separated into things the
initial setup
and then when you actually print so the
basic steps for printing without you I
first your Apple include a setting for
setting the printer the prison
the app setting somewhere Settings
button somewhere
so to do that you first get the printer
selector this new class
your present that you I then you'll save
the printer
chosen by the users these are all be
choosing a prayer your caps
responsibilities save that
then whenever appropriate when your app
decides to print
the Apple then get the print controller
the UI panache a controller
of that up the attributes for the job
and provide content just like we did
before
but I'll send the job with this new
print controller method just sentence
without showing you like
this point like before I left indicates
that the printer in the Damon takes over
Europe doesn't have to deal with any
that
so here's the classes will be using for
I'm back company
first the new class you a prayer picker
controller that you'll be presenting
NAUI printer object that your Apple be
saving
instantiating between runs and providing
apt to the UI printer action controller
so everything that we've talked about
with
you have been a interactions are still
though applies
that your your Apple is required to use
this year I prefer picker controller to
pick the printer
I'm it its complicated to show all the
different corners and sometimes
uni using it on lock bernard has are
using a password all that kind of stuff
is handled by the system so
will use your printer picker controller
has the same presentation options
as the printer actually controller so
you can present it as a popover
or she eat or you can embed nap
controller
then like I said your Apple be
responsible for saving Apr between runs
you'll save the URL
and the nuanced and she ate a new you I
printer with justice
URL the unsaved also this guy printer
picker controller allows you to filter
out printers
if your app is designed for just a
specific type of printer
and we'll talk about that later
like it that you created set up the
opener picker controller I'm you can
present
with standard presentation present
animated or pop over presentation
with present from Tractor present from
by about 9 a.m.
I'm the completion handler though for
these methods
will I tell you whether the user
actually did like to printer
if the if they didn't you know that they
could just cancel that so that all say
that they didn't like the printer
but then your app is responsible for
saving that pratt was elected
so when you happens ready to print them
at the appropriate moment you'll use the
USB connector controller and your call
the new method print to printer with
this year I project
completion handler be away from her past
like I said can be obtained from the
opener picker control it directly
or you could instantiated it with the
savior of
okay so that's my printer picker
controller on
your printer new class in Iowa State
first it has a contact her method so
this is used if your stance eating it
you wanna make sure that this printer is
there and to fill out the rest of the
property is for the printer
you have to contact you'll pass in a
block but the result black that'll tell
you whether the printer is available or
not
might not be on anymore so it'll no
return no in that case
next is the URL which is a read-only
property this is what you be
saving out went once you get your
initial you April be saving us
actually have display name which this is
our standard pretty you I
the display name is you know they're the
name of the printer appropriate for you
to show in your UI
display location which is the smaller
tax attorney
name you can use this for display in
your eyes while
and then from various things about
though the printer like support a job
types such as a bit field
and that of a like whether it supports
photo printing receive training were
ample a brain
different types a job that supports and
make and model and
and some other capabilities
so here's a quick accorded ample using
you I printer to show like the printer
name in a location near you I
so first let's grab the saved for know
you're all from a previous
run the application here just getting it
from the user defaults
if we got one back from user defaults
will initialize
with your partner printer with URL with
the same for neuro
and then likely contact the printer
black that we will pass in we'll see if
it's available
then we'll set our printer name label to
be the display name the printer
and the panel location able to be the
display location:
so these the printer name and location
unavailable until it actually been
contacted
that's why we do that in our in this
block
the pair is not available will have some
connection gone indicator ap
if you want to have that this is what
you this is how you do itself
like a little red indicator to let tell
users that their printers not available
as a side
okay so like I said you can use you can
filter out printers in the pair picker
I'm for that this is you know offered
app design with specific parent in mind
if you really only want your apt to be
used with receipt printers are with
you know specific type of fat burner
this is what you do I'm any one of those
properties
on you I printer you can use to filter
I when you present the UI printer pick a
controller you're just use the delegate
method should show printer
your return yes or no whether it should
be shown so this is called for every
printer
as it gets discovered and you can choose
whether a good show online
so we're really excited about that on we
really do think this will enable a new
class a pretty applications that were
possible
on and to talk about some other new
types aP's I'd like to bring up
I Cody Roberts opening system engineer
hello everyone my name is Claudia
Robertson this is my colleague Charles
dick
exciting thing about you I was printing
is that it opens up the door to a wide
range of printing application
whatever most requested features right
with a with two laps the ability to
print receipts about showing the print
dialog
in a few minutes child to demonstrate
how to do just that using a cash
register
we encourage you think more broadly
thing cover photo booth app that
automatically print out your personal
photos
or a label printing out to be you that
conference sign in table
the fact that we're letting you say
printers means that you can help
reconfigure
up to print a more than one printer this
is a great feature that can be used in
setting up multiple printers
for each make very different function
think airline kiosk ap
the person traveling check then enters
the number bad they're traveling life
and after finalizing their information
one designated printer prints out the
badge labels
and another print out their boarding
pass all about ever having to traverse
or even see
the print you I today
to illustrate the power to new feature
and demonstrate just how easy it is
to add you I whispered into your app we
have created
a hypothetical cash register
it catches ur Abbas something you'd find
animals any retail store
and using the print the prin- paradigm
in Iowa 7 pretty northeast me know
lot unnecessary interaction at the print
you I and there is really no way of
getting around it
after finalizing a fail in this demo app
it takes one
to you three steps
to print out a receipt each time the
clerk at the finish sale
attic your side effect people and have
used for in less than ideal situation
so what we know to be chair for the vote
for the most part in a given day at the
shop
the creek or almost always print to the
same receipt printer
dust we started our behavior the ability
to simply tap on the finish sale by an
and have our dedicated receipt printer
print out the receipt so the customer
can quickly be
on his or her way I'll now handed over
to Charles
who will demonstrate how to update this
cash register up with the necessary code
changes to achieve the desired behavior
makes Claudia so what I have here
is the code for the cash register app
that call you to show you
and I want to update this to use these
new API's
so i cud said there's really to basic
steps
to printing without the OI the first to
selecting and saving a printer
and the second is telling I'll ask which
printer we'd like to save two
so in order to do this I'm first going
to want to create a place
to save the you I printer object then
I'm going to get
when at a property here to my receive U
controller using the new UI printer
class
this is what I was his to represent the
printer
arm throughout the printing system
next I'm going to add a place for an
administrator can go
and set up the cash register in order to
let the let the app now this is the plan
on going to be predicted
so will do that in the Settings button
so I'm going to go to my
Settings button pressed method which is
a
arm try which is the target action
%uh a telling but in the app and I'm
going to go ahead
and create he you I printer you a
printer pick a controller
used willie create you a printer picker
control using printer picker controller
with initially selected printer to
scroll the controller to
maybe a printer that we've already set
up
next I'm going to use the you I printer
picker control method present from
wrecked
in view animated incompletion himmler
and when the pews and goes and select
the printer
will go ahead and check to see that they
did selected
and if they didn't cancel the operation
save the printer that they selected
in the property that we just created
now I'm going to go ahead and update my
apt to use these
new API
so you can see our print method as exist
in Iowa 7 we
do all the standard printing things we
create a print page render
we create a UI print info sets and Rob
options
and get the shared print controller set
the options on the job
and then presenting using the present
API's actual notice look
almost exactly the same as the methods
on you I printer picker control
so what we can actually do now this is
what kinda lied about this API
is delete sum up this code because we
don't need it will no longer presenting
anything we're just gonna print to
printer
we go then we can go ahead and delete
that little bit of
auto-generated Co and it's really just
that easy
also on the completion handlers the same
and we're now going to be a blueprint
with that you are so I'm going to go
ahead
and fire after the simulator here so we
can show the steel
and something that I
didn't get a chance to talk about here
but it could be a logical extension
is maybe filtering based on
the typeof fenner that we're going to
use we we want to use
only receipt printers at this out but
you know maybe a shop also as a photo
printer
arm and you wouldn't want to you
wouldn't want to
print to that or you wouldn't want to
show that to the administrator when they
were setting up the printer
alright now we have our app and let's go
ahead let so maybe maybe we're in a
coffee shop so
let's get you know San Francisco coffee
and the you know maybe a bagel
heaps yeah okay wanna home
I it's let's get you know it weird were
splurging on today also
maybe we'll get cream cheese arm let's
go ahead and say for sale
hoops I don't select the printer let's
go ahead
and look for this notice we're gonna
pick this brother printer that we have
here
so wifi-enabled battery-powered receipt
printer
now will go ahead and click Finish sale
and now I was will take over the job
communicating with the printer on you
know getting all the options at cetera
and in a moment should be seeing the
paper come out at the front
and with that I'll headed back to Howard
who will
pick it up I'm today what I hope you've
learned that is
adding printing to your application
regardless asylum application is
really easy for a lot of the content
10 lines of code if you have pictures
HTML web to use maps
you're set 10 lines to cope with really
nine if you count and I look at the
route
I super super easy I am
if you need more control a lotta stuff
you can now do with for matters now that
we have the per page
inserts we think our web viewing app sir
or a lot about $3 each
email based will only need those tens
lines code to print and print
well but if you do need the full power
for control what you're doing
you can always use a renderer which can
use any of the common to the printing
API's
are per graphics API to do print
I and then you can combine for matters
with runners to make it super easy
and the new and IOSA we as we
demonstrated you can now do
separate the picking up the printer from
the actual active printing
so more information are technology
evangelist as polled ambled
for those who don't know the name poll
has been in printing for longer than I
have which makes it twenty three years
I and he is readily available and can
answer many questions
I we put up a new website this week
developer Apple dot com slash
AirPrint this is your source for all
I was printing related stuff there are a
handful sample aP's there
all the documentation all the reference
document stuff that you're going to need
is also a link to the list every I
AirPrint printer in the world
every model order for printer in the
world I'm as well as
information on licensing up the air
print technology so developer Apple com
slash
airport will get you everything then of
course if you've got some ongoing
questions you're always welcome to use a
Apple's developer forms and then there's
a another point for AirPrint basics
which lists all the printers
know you guys are all probably pretty
experienced a
application writers already but if you
if you still got a few details I do
strongly encourage you to go back and
watch the video for the
what's new and Cocoa Touch
so that's it thank you very much